<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Created with Liquid XML 2016 Editor Edition 14.0.1.6408 (http://www.liquid-technologies.com) -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>
<pai>
    <agency toc="yes">
        <name>Federal Election Commission</name>
        <abbrev>
            FEC
        </abbrev>
        <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
            <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
        </previousPubs>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-23/pdf/2021-27885.pdf</url>
            <title>Technical Corrections.</title>
            <date year="21" month="12" day="23" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-28/pdf/2021-28222.pdf</url>
            <title>Reasonable Accommodations for the Federal Election Commission (FEC); FEC-17.</title>
            <date year="21" month="12" day="28" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <section id="fec1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Advisory Opinions Process.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified; some records are public.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Office of General Counsel, Policy Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have submitted correspondence to the FEC requesting an advisory opinion under the Federal Election Campaign Act and FEC regulations; individuals who have submitted comments regarding advisory opinion drafts; current and former FEC staff assigned to handle requests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The records in this system include paper and electronic correspondence, staff notes, Commissioners' comments, and advisory opinion drafts. May include the name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, employment information, political activity, and financial records of the correspondents.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(7) and 437f.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as amended, requires that the FEC render advisory opinions to persons with regard to subjects arising under the Act. <i>See</i> 2 U.S.C. 437f. The FEC gathers or creates the records in this system in the course of accepting and responding to requests for such advisory opinions. Commissioners and staff use this system to respond to requests for advisory opinions, and the documents are maintained for use as a reference in subsequent requests for advisory opinions. Advisory opinions issued before 2001 are available to the public online at Commission's Public Records Office. Advisory opinions, requests, draft opinions, amendments considered by the Commission in public session, public comments, and similar documents issued after 2001 are available to the public at e Public Records Office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To the news media or the general public, factual information the disclosure of which would be in the public interest and which would not constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.
</p><p>4. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>5. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>6. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>7. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>8. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>9. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>10. To the Office of Personnel Management for matters concerned with oversight activities (necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally-authorized Government-wide personnel management programs and functions) and in their role as an investigation agency.
</p><p>11. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>12. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>13. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Paper records; microfilm; electronic format on agency computer networks.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Microfilm and paper records are indexed and retrievable by name of requester, date of opinion, request number, subject, citation, or phrase, and, as applicable, by microfilm roll and frame number.
</p><p>Records maintained in electronic form on agency computer networks may be retrieved by agency personnel using Case Management System software, the Office of General Counsel (OGC) Internal Index, or the Commission's Web site and are retrievable by name of requestor, request number, date of opinion, subject, citation, phrase, and name of current or former staff who handled the request.
</p><p>The Commission's published advisory opinions are available for public review in the Commission's Public Records Office and on the FEC's Internet web page and are indexed by request number and are full-text searchable. All advisory opinions and many requests and draft opinions are also available on microfilm. Members of the public may retrieve any advisory opinion online. For opinions issued after 2001, members of the public may view in the Public Records Office, the requests, draft opinions, and amendments considered by the Commission in public session, public comments, and similar documents. These documents are also available on the Commission's Web site.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system of records are under the custody of designated employees of the Commission. Access to the records is limited to employees requiring access to the information contained therein to further the agency's mission. Electronic records that are not available on the Commission's Web site are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper copies are retained for at least four years from date of receipt and subject to disposal thereafter. Electronic and microfilm copies are available indefinitely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Associate General Counsel for Policy, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1650).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Associate General Counsel for Policy, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Associate General Counsel for Policy, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Associate General Counsel for Policy, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by individual requesters of advisory opinions, persons submitting comments to the FEC with regard to the request, and FEC staff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>

</section>
<section id="fec2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Audits and Investigations.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified; some records are public.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Audit Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Candidates required to file statements and reports under the Federal Election Campaign Act; treasurers or other representatives of political committees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Documents related to audits and investigations. The records contained in this system may include the name, address, telephone number, and financial data of the subjects of audits and investigations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(9), 437g(a)(2), (5) and 438(a)(8), (9); 26 U.S.C. 9007, 9038.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The information contained in the records maintained in this system is used to verify compliance with the Federal Election Campaign Act and to verify compliance with, and eligibility for, funds pursuant to the Presidential Campaign Matching Fund Act and the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To disclose them to the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To the general public but only to the extent the information is contained in, or relates to, a proposed Final Audit Report considered by the Commission in public session or is contained in an approved Final Audit Report.
</p><p>4. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>5. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>6. To any source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.
</p><p>7. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>8. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>9. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Paper records; CD-Rom storage; and electronic format on agency networks.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Indexed by name of auditee. The public may retrieve approved Final Audit Reports from a page on the Commission's Web site.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are retained in locked safes in limited access locations. Access is limited to FEC staff on a restricted basis and to appropriate law enforcement agencies as directed by the Commission. Auditors in the field keep their audit documents under personal supervision or in locked cases. CD-ROMs are kept in locked file cabinets. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1200).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by the candidate's authorized campaign committee, political committees, and political action committees. Information also may be obtained by subpoena from vendors and other individuals.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>With respect to open audits, this system is exempt pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C 552a(k)(2). See 11 CFR 1.14. When the audit is closed, copies of final reports are available on the public record.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Compliance Actions.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified; some material is public.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Office of General Counsel, Complaints Examinations &amp; Legal Administration Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have filed complaints under the Federal Election Campaign Act (2 U.S.C. 431 <i>et seq.</i>) (complainants); individuals who are the subjects of complaints (respondents), including treasurers of respondent political committees, and counsel; candidates filing late or inaccurate reports, or no reports; witnesses and other individuals providing information with respect to a compliance matter; and current and former FEC personnel, including RAD analysts, auditors, attorneys and investigators.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Complaints, sua-sponte submissions, referrals, and responses thereto; documents generated in the course of internally-generated investigations of reports on file at the Commission; documents generated and received in the course of investigations of complaints and referrals, including General Counsel's Reports, briefs, deposition and transcripts, interrogatories and responses thereto, hearing records, Subpoenas and orders, documents received from other government agencies, other documentary evidence, documents in the course of conciliation, and memoranda and notes created by agency personnel with respect to investigations. May include the name, address, Social Security Number, telephone number, e-mail address, employment information, education, political activity records, tax records, travel records, and financial records of the subjects of compliance actions or other individuals covered by the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1), (2), (4) and (5); 438(a)(7) and 438(b); 26 U.S.C. 9006 and 9038.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as amended, requires that the FEC enforce the provisions of the Act. The FEC gathers or creates the records in this system in the course of investigating and acting as civil prosecutor for alleged violations of the Act. While any compliance action is active, these records are maintained as the agency's working or investigative file for the Matter Under Review (MUR). Based upon information contained in the file, recommendations are made to the Commission as to the disposition of a case, and the Commission acts upon those recommendations. The Associate General Counsel assigns compliance actions to an attorney and/or to appropriate staff for investigation. Administrative action pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 437g and civil litigation are handled by the General Counsel's Office. Upon the closing of the compliance matter, certain documents are placed on the public record.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To the Attorney General of the United States to refer evidence of knowing and willful violations of the law.
</p><p>4. Upon the closing of the compliance matter, to place certain documents on the public record of the agency, pursuant to guidance promulgated by the Commission. Before the documents are released to the public, Commission personnel review and redact information that is not disclosable under the Freedom of Information Act, such as personal information (i.e., home addresses, home telephone numbers, and bank account numbers).
</p><p>5. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law for purposes of reporting the information to those authorities pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(9) or as otherwise necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>6. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>7. To any source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.
</p><p>8. To a Federal, State, local, foreign, tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a request supported by written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.
</p><p>9. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>10. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>11. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>12. To the Office of Personnel Management for matters concerned with oversight activities (necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally-authorized Government-wide personnel management programs and functions) and in their role as an investigation agency.
</p><p>13. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>14. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>15. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), records can be disclosed to consumer reporting agencies as they are defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Records are maintained in electronic form on agency computer networks, on
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Microfilm and paper records are indexed and retrievable by name of complainant or respondent, by compliance action number, or by microfilm roll and frame number, as appropriate.
</p><p>Electronic records are maintained on agency computer networks and may be retrieved using software systems that support the agency's compliance mission. The Case Management System (CMS), Concordance, and Docs open databases are available only to agency personnel. When a compliance matter has been closed, certain records are placed on the agency's public record, and may be retrieved by the public through the agency's Web site using the Enforcement Query System.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system of records are under the custody of designated employees of the Commission. Access to the records is limited to employees requiring access to the information contained therein to further the agency's compliance mission. Paper and microfilm records in this system are kept in locked filing cabinets in limited access areas under personal surveillance during working hours, and in locked filing cabinets in locked rooms at other times. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties. Prior to making documents publicly available through the Electronic Query System, the Office of General Counsel thoroughly reviews each record to remove information deemed to be exempt under the Freedom of Information Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Special Counsel for Complaints Examinations &amp; Legal Administration, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1650).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Special Counsel for Complaints Examinations &amp; Legal Administration, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Special Counsel for Complaints Examinations &amp; Legal Administration, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Special Counsel for Complaints Examinations &amp; Legal Administration, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is obtained from a variety of sources, including but not limited to complainants, respondents, third parties who have been requested, or subpoenaed, to produce relevant information, referrals, other Federal, State, or local authorities, financial institutions, and the Federal Election Commission. Information is also obtained from individuals covered by the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>With respect to open investigations, the system is exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). See 11 CFR part 1.14.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Candidate Reports and Designations.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Public.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Public Disclosure Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Candidates for Federal office required to file reports of contributions and expenditures; sources of receipts and recipients of disbursements, including contributors and vendors; and treasurers of Candidate Committees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Reports and Statements of candidates; reports by delegates and other persons making contributions or independent expenditures; and designations on behalf of a Federal candidate but not through a political committee, candidate, or authorized committee or agent of a candidate. May include the name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, employment information, political affiliation and financial records of the candidate or treasurer. May include the name, address, occupation, name of employer, and amounts of contribution of any person who contributes more than $200 in a calendar year to a Federal political committee (or $200 in an election cycle, in the case of contributors to the authorized committee of candidates for Federal office).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 432(e), 434, 437b(a)(1), and 438(a)(4).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The information contained in the records maintained in this system is used to inform the public of the amounts raised and spent by authorized committees of candidates for Federal office and other Federal political committees as well as the sources from which the amounts are raised and the recipients of the amounts spent; also, to verify compliance with the Federal Election Campaign Act. The Commission is required to make this information public pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 438(a)(4).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>None involving nonpublic information. All records in this system are public pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 438(a)(4).
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Paper records, microfilm, electronic format on agency computer networks, and on the Internet at the FEC's web page.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper and microfilm records are retrievable by candidate name, candidate identification (ID) number, committee name, committee ID number, or by the State in which candidate seeks election; electronic records are retrievable by candidate name, candidate ID number, committee name, committee ID number, or by the State or district in which the candidate seeks election.
</p><p>All electronic searches may be conducted by any member of the public using the Commission's Web site.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Original copies of records in this system are located in locked filing cabinets or are maintained on password protected agency computer networks. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Reports are preserved for a 10-year period except that reports relating solely to candidates for the House of Representative are preserved for 5 years from the date of receipt. Microfilm and electronic records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Staff Director for Disclosure, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1120).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Disclosure, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Disclosure, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Assistant Staff Director for Disclosure, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Candidate committee disclosure reports and designations filed with the FEC.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Certification for primary matching funds and general election campaign funds.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified; some records are public.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Audit Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Candidates for nomination or election to the Office of President of the United States and contributors whose contributions are matched under the Matching Payment Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Certification forms and supporting data requesting matching funds or election funds including the candidate agreement. May include the name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, employment information, political activity or affiliations and financial records of the candidates. May include the names, addresses, occupations, names of employers, and dates and amounts of contributions of contributors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>26 U.S.C. 9003, 9006; 26 U.S.C. 9033, 9036, 9037.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To assist the Commission in facilitating the primary matching funds and general election campaign funds programs for Presidential primary candidates and nominees. Presidential candidates who seek matching funds must submit information about matchable contributions to the FEC for review. These files are available to the public and are placed on the FEC's Internet site. Before receiving matching funds, candidates must also provide a letter of agreement (candidate agreement) stating they accept the conditions for receiving matching grants.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To the news media or the general public, factual information the disclosure of which would be in the public interest and which would not constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy. However, under 2 U.S.C. 438a(4), any information copied from financial disclosure reports shall not be sold or utilized by any person for the purposes of soliciting contributions or for any commercial purpose.
</p><p>4. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>5. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>6. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>7. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>8. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>9. To the Department of Treasury in connection with issuing matching funds to qualified recipients.
</p><p>10. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), records can be disclosed to consumer reporting agencies as they are defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Paper records; CD-Rom storage; electronic format on agency computer networks.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Indexed and retrievable by name of candidate, committee ID, and candidate ID. Matching funds submissions are retrievable by members of the public on a page on the agency's public Web site.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records and CD-ROMs are kept in locked file cabinets in limited access areas under personal surveillance during working hours and in locked rooms at other times. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-3440).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Assistant Staff Director for Audit, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Certification reports and candidate agreements filed with the Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Payroll records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Finance Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463 and on a computer system located in the Department of Agriculture's National Finance Center, New Orleans, Louisiana.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All FEC employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Varied payroll records, including, among other documents, time and attendance cards; payment vouchers; comprehensive listing of employees; health and other benefit records; requests for deductions; tax forms; W-2 forms; headcount data; overtime requests; leave data; and retirement records. May include names, addresses, telephone numbers, marital status, date of birth, e-mail addresses, employment and education history, health and financial information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>31 U.S.C., generally. Also, 2 U.S.C. 437c(f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by the Commission to maintain adequate payroll information on Commission employees, to measure employee performance, record time and attendance, and file reports with appropriate authorities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>4. To a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision in the matter.
</p><p>5. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>6. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>7. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>8. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency.
</p><p>Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>9. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>10. To the Office of Personnel Management in accordance with the agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.
</p><p>11. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>12. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>13. To debt collection contractors to collect debts owed to the Government, as authorized under the Debt Collection Act of 1982, 31 U.S.C. 3718, and subject to the Privacy Act safeguards.
</p><p>14. To the Office of Child Support Enforcement Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services Federal Parent Locator Service (FPLS) and Federal Tax Offset System for use in locating individuals and identifying their income sources to establish paternity, establish and modify orders of support and for enforcement action.
</p><p>15. To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Social Security Administration for verifying Social Security Numbers in connection with the operation of the FPLS by the Office of Child Support Enforcement.
</p><p>16. To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Department of Treasury for purposes of administering the Earned Income Tax Credit Program (Section 32, Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and verifying a claim with respect to employment in a tax return.
</p><p>17. To officers and employees of a Federal agency for purposes of an audit.
</p><p>18. To the General Accounting Office for audits; to the Internal Revenue Service for investigation; and to individual representatives, pursuant to a power of attorney.
</p><p>19. To audit firms or other contractors conducting audits or studies of FEC's financial or computer systems or processes in accordance with the Accountability of Tax Dollars Act of 2002, other laws, or special studies requested by management.
</p><p>20. To a State and city, or other local jurisdiction that is authorized to tax the employee's compensation, a copy of an employee's Department of Treasury form W-2, wage and tax statement. The record will be provided in accordance with a withholding agreement between the State, city, or other local jurisdiction and the Department of the Treasury, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 5516, 5517, or 5520, or, in the absence thereof, in response to a written request from an appropriate official of the taxing jurisdiction to the Accounting Officer, Federal Election Commission, Washington, DC 20463. The request must include a copy of the applicable statute or ordinance authorizing the taxation of compensation and should indicate whether the authority of the jurisdiction to tax the employee is based on place of residence, place of employment, or both.
</p><p>a. Pursuant to a withholding agreement between a city and the Department of Treasury (5 U.S.C. 5520), copies of executed city tax withholding certificates shall be furnished to the city in response to a written request from an appropriate city official to the Accounting Officer.
</p><p>b. In the absence of a withholding agreement, the Social Security Number will be furnished only to a taxing jurisdiction that has furnished this agency with evidence of its independent authority to compel disclosure of the Social Security Number, in accordance with Section 7 of the Privacy Act.
</p><p>21. To the Department of Agriculture, National Finance Center, to credit Thrift Savings Plan deductions and loan payments to employee accounts.
</p><p>22. To the Department of Treasury to issue checks, make payments, make electronic funds transfers, and issue U.S. Savings Bonds.
</p><p>23. To the Department of Labor in connection with a claim filed by an employee for compensation due to a job connected injury or illness.
</p><p>24. To the Internal Revenue Service; Social Security Administration; and State and local tax authorities in connection with the withholding of employment taxes.
</p><p>25. To the Combined Federal Campaign in connection with payroll deductions for charitable contributions.
</p><p>26. To State Unemployment Offices in connection with a claim filed by former employees for unemployment benefits.
</p><p>27. To the Office of Personnel Management and to Health Benefit carriers in connection with enrollment and payroll deductions.
</p><p>28. To the Office of Personnel Management in connection with employee retirement and life insurance deductions.
</p><p>29. To the Office of Management and Budget and Department of the Treasury to provide required reports on financial management responsibilities.
</p><p>30. To provide information as necessary to other Federal, State, local or foreign agencies conducting computer matching programs to help eliminate fraud and abuse and to detect unauthorized overpayments made to individuals. When disclosures are made as part of computer matching programs, FEC will comply with the Computer Matching and Privacy Protection Act of 1988.
</p><p>31. To the Internal Revenue Service in connection with withholdings for tax levies.
</p><p>32. To the General Services Administration, which has been engaged to assist the agency in processing and administering certain functions related to this system of records.
</p><p>33. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Paper records and electronic format on agency computer networks. Primary computer files stored on server hard-drives with tape backup for all records located at 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC and at the National Finance Center in New Orleans, Louisiana.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are accessible via last name or Social Security Number. Employees have online access to portions of their own files via their last name and/or Social Security Number and/or PIN through the National Finance Center Web site.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper Records are kept in locked file cabinets located in a cipher-locked room. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Disposition of records shall be in accordance with the HB GSA Records Maintenance and Disposition System (OAD P 1820.2).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Accounting Officer, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1230).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Accounting Officer, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Accounting Officer, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Accounting Officer, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington DC, 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The subject individual; the Federal Election Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Litigation Actions.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified; some material may be made public as part of court filings or other judicial proceedings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Office of General Counsel, Litigation Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals, and their counsel, who have brought judicial action against the Commission and individuals, and their counsel, against whom the Commission has brought judicial action pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 437g or 437h, 26 U.S.C. 9011 or 9041, 5 U.S.C. 552 or any other statute; witnesses, and their counsel; individuals or organizations filing amicus briefs; current and former FEC staff assigned to handle the matter.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>All documents incident to a lawsuit, including pleadings, discovery materials, motions, briefs, inter-office communications, memoranda, orders, and correspondence with opposing counsel, joint counsel or the Department of Justice. May include the name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, employment information, political activity or affiliations and financial records of any individual covered by the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(6), 437g(a)(8), 437g(a)(11), and 437h; Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act of 2002, Pub. L. 107-155, 116 Stat. 81, sec. 403.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as amended, authorizes the FEC to prosecute and defend certain litigation in the Federal courts. <i>See, e.g.</i>, 2 U.S.C. 437g(a). The FEC gathers or creates the records in this system in the course of prosecuting or defending such litigation. These records are maintained for historical purposes and for consultation as precedent in subsequent judicial or administrative actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To the news media or the general public, factual information the disclosure of which would be in the public interest and which would not constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.
</p><p>4. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>5. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>6. To any source or potential source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation concerning the retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), or the retention of a security clearance, contract, grant, license, or other benefit, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.
</p><p>7. To a Federal, State, local, foreign, tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a request supported by written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.
</p><p>8. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>9. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>10. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>11. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>12. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>13. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Paper record; microfilm; electronic form on agency computer networks or other electronic recording media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Microfilm and paper records are indexed by name of party litigant and, as applicable, by microfilm roll and frame number.
</p><p>Electronic records may be retrieved using the agency computer network and shared drawers, Case Management System (CMS), LSI Imaging system, Docs open, DVDs, and Concordance databases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to the records is limited to employees with a need to know the information to conduct civil litigation on behalf of the agency or to ensure legal consistency in other proceedings.
</p><p>Microfilm and paper records are kept in locked filing cabinets or in limited access areas under personal surveillance during working hours, and in locked rooms at other times.
</p><p>All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Associate General Counsel for Litigation, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1650).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Associate General Counsel for Litigation, Office of General Counsel, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Associate General Counsel for Litigation, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Associate General Counsel for Litigation, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is obtained from a variety of sources, including but not limited to individual party litigants and counsel, witnesses, third parties, other agencies, court personnel and the Federal Election Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are exempt from individual access under 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(5).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Letter File. Public Communications.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Information Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have written to the FEC requesting answers to specific questions related to the Federal Election Campaign Act, as amended; current and former FEC staff assigned to handle requests for information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for information and FEC responses thereto. May include name, address, telephone number, e-mail address of the requestors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 438(a).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Commission staff maintain these records to respond to and manage inquiries directed to the Commission. The documents are also retained for use as a reference in subsequent requests for information and to keep track of the types of inquiries received by the Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>4. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>5. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>6. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>7. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>8. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>9. To the Office of Personnel Management for matters concerned with oversight activities (necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally-authorized Government-wide personnel management programs and functions) and in their role as an investigation agency.
</p><p>10. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>11. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>12. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Records are maintained in electronic form on agency computer networks and as paper records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are under the custody of designated employees of the Commission. Access to the records is limited to employees requiring access. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name of the requester.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained in-house for one year; shipped afterward to general storage in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Staff Director for Information, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1100).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Information, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Assistant Staff Director for Information, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Assistant Staff Director for Information, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who submit requests for information to the Commission in writing.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Contributor Name Index System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Public.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Information Technology Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have been listed on campaign finance reports as having given an aggregate amount in excess of $200 or more in a calendar year to a candidate for Federal office required to file reports of contributions and expenditures, sources of receipts and recipients of disbursements.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names of contributors, City, State and zip code, occupation, employer, and contribution amount.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 434 and 441a.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The information contained in this system of records is used to inform the public of the amounts raised and spent by candidates for Federal office, as well as the source from which the amounts are raised and the recipients of the amounts spent; also to verify compliance with the Federal Election Campaign Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>None involving nonpublic information. All records in this system are public.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Electronic format on agency computer networks on the Internet at the FEC's web page.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Indexed by last name of contributor and by name of recipient committee. Retrieval may be accomplished by any member of the public using the Commission's Web site.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Deputy Staff Director/Chief Information Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1250).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Deputy Staff Director/Chief Information Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Deputy Staff Director/Chief Information Officer, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Deputy Staff Director/Chief Information Officer, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual contributors, candidate and political committees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Inspector General Investigative Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Office of the Inspector General (OIG), 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who are the subjects of complaints relating to the programs and operations of the Commission. Subjects include, but are not limited to, current and former FEC employees; current and former employees of contractors and subcontractors in their personal capacity, where applicable; and other persons whose actions affect the FEC, its programs or operations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Complaints, referrals from other agencies, correspondence, investigative notes, interviews, statements from witnesses, transcripts taken during investigation, affidavits, copies of all subpoenas issued and responses thereto, interrogatories and responses thereto, reports, internal staff memoranda, staff working papers and other documents and records or copies obtained or relating to complaints and investigations. May include the name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, employment information, and financial records of the subjects.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Inspector General Act Amendments of 1988, Pub. L. 100-504, amending the Inspector General Act of 1978, Pub. L. 95-452, 5 U.S.C. app. 3.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used to document the conduct and outcome of inquiries, complaints, and investigations concerning allegations of fraud, waste, and abuse that affect the FEC. The information is used to report the results of investigations to FEC management, contractors, prosecutors, law enforcement agencies, Congress, and others for an action deemed appropriate. These records are used also to retain sufficient information to fulfill reporting requirements and to maintain records related to the OIG's activities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed by the Inspector General, after careful review, to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the Inspector General determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Inspector General determines that, after careful review, the use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the Inspector General determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To the appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authority responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, when information indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, if the information disclosed is relevant to any enforcement, regulatory, investigative or prosecutorial responsibility of the receiving entity.
</p><p>4. To any source or potential source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation concerning the retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), or the retention of a security clearance, contract, grant, license, or other benefit, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.
</p><p>5. To a Federal, State, local, foreign, tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a request supported by written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.
</p><p>6. To the White House in response to an inquiry made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained. Disclosure will not be made until the White House has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>7. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>8. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>9. To agency or OIG contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency or OIG in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency or OIG. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>10. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>11. To the Office of Personnel Management for matters concerned with oversight activities (necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally-authorized Government-wide personnel management programs and functions) and in their role as an investigation agency.
</p><p>12. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>13. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>14. To debt collection contractors to collect debts owed to the Government, as authorized under the Debt Collection Act of 1982, 31 U.S.C. 3718, and subject to the Privacy Act safeguards.
</p><p>15. To officials who have been engaged to assist the Office of Inspector General in the conduct of inquiries, complaints, and investigations who need to have access to the records in order to perform the work. This disclosure category includes members of the President's Council on Integrity and Efficiency and the Executive Council on Integrity and Efficiency, and officials and administrative staff within their chain of command. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act.
</p><p>16. Information may be disclosed to officials charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessment reviews of internal safeguards and management procedures employed in investigative operations. This disclosure category includes members of the President's Council on Integrity and Efficiency, Executive Council on Integrity and Efficiency, and officials and administrative staff within their investigative chain of command, as well as authorized officials of the Department of Justice and the Federal Bureau of Investigation. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act.
</p><p>17. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>We may disclose the record or information from this system, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), to consumer reporting agencies as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. 1681a(f) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966, as amended, 31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3), in accordance with section 3711(f) of Title 31.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Records are stored in both a paper and electronic format.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The records may be retrieved by the name of the subject of the complaint/investigation or by a unique control number assigned to each complaint/investigation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are maintained in limited access areas within the building. Access is limited to Office of Inspector General employees whose official duties require access. The paper records and electronic information not stored on computers are maintained in lockable cabinets in a locked room. Information stored on computers is on a restricted access server located in a locked room. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>These records will be maintained permanently until disposition authority is granted by the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA). Upon approval, the records will be retained in accordance with NARA's schedule and disposed of in a secure manner.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Inspector General, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1015).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the FEC Inspector General, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the FEC Inspector General at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the FEC Inspector General at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Complaints, subjects, third parties who have been requested to produce relevant information, referring agencies, and OIG personnel assigned to handle complaints/investigations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>System exempt under 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2).
</p><p>See 11 CFR 1.14.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Travel Records of Employees.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Administration Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All FEC employees who travel pursuant to authorized official agency business.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel authorizations; travel advance requests; E-travel profiles, and travel vouchers, including receipts for hotels, car rentals, meals, phone calls, mileage reimbursement and other allowable expenses. May include: Name, address, Social Security Number, telephone number, job title, grade salary level, security clearance, e-mail address, and government credit card information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel Expense Amendments Act of 1975 (Pub. L. 94-22).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To facilitate the timely reimbursement to employees for authorized and official travel for the FEC.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>4. To any source or potential source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation concerning the retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), or the retention of a security clearance, contract, grant, license, or other benefit, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.
</p><p>5. To a Federal, State, local, foreign, tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a request supported by written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.
</p><p>6. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>7. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>8. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>9. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>10. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>11. To the Office of Personnel Management for matters concerned with oversight activities (necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally-authorized Government-wide personnel management programs and functions) and in their role as an investigation agency.
</p><p>12. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>13. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>14. To the General Services Administration, which has been engaged to assist the agency in processing and administering certain functions related to this system of records.
</p><p>15. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Paper and electronic records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Indexed by employee name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are locked in file cabinets located in a cipher-locked room. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel records are maintained for seven years and then disposed of in accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Accounting Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1215).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Accounting Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Accounting Officer, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Accounting Officer, Federal Election Commission, at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The subject individual; the Federal Election Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Alternative Dispute Resolution Program.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified; some material may be made public after cases are closed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Alternative Dispute Resolution Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have filed complaints under the Federal Election Campaign Act (2 U.S.C. 431 <i>et seq.</i>) (complainants); individuals who are the subjects of complaints (respondents), including treasurers of respondent political committees, and counsel; candidates filing late or inaccurate reports, or no reports; witnesses and other individuals providing information with respect to a compliance matter; agency personnel, including attorneys and investigators.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Complaints, referrals, and responses thereto; documents generated in the course of internally-generated investigations of reports on file at the Commission; documents generated and received in the course of investigations of complaints and referrals, including depositions, interrogatories and responses thereto, other documentary evidence, and memoranda and notes created by agency personnel with respect to investigations. May include the name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, employment information, political activity and financial or tax records of the subjects.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1), (2), (4) and (5); 438(a)(7) and 438(b); 5 U.S.C. 572; 26 U.S.C. 9006 and 9038.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) Office maintains active files on complaints forwarded to it from Commissioners, the Reports Analysis Division, the Audit Division, or the Office of General Counsel, including matters stemming from audits for cause. The Commission determines whether the case is appropriate for the ADR program. Resolutions reached in negotiations are submitted to the Commissioners for final approval. If a resolution is not reached in bilateral negotiation, the case may proceed to mediation. Upon the closing of the ADR matter, certain documents are placed on the public record.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. Upon the closing of the ADR matter, to place certain documents on the public record of the agency, pursuant to guidance promulgated by the Commission. Personal information is redacted from documents before they are made public.
</p><p>4. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>5. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>6. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>7. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>8. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, mediators, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>9. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>10. To the Office of Personnel Management for matters concerned with oversight activities (necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally-authorized Government-wide personnel management programs and functions) and in their role as an investigation agency.
</p><p>11. To officials of labor organizations when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.
</p><p>12. To agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State government after receipt of request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee's disciplinary or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). The agency will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.
</p><p>13. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Records are stored in both paper and electronic form and on microfilm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By ADR case number or name of the respondent.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>This system is kept in locked filing cabinets in limited access areas under personal surveillance during working hours, and in locked filing cabinets in locked rooms at other times. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained and disposed of on accordance with FEC records control schedules.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Alternative Dispute Resolution Office, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/219-1670).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Director, Alternative Dispute Resolution Office, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Director, Alternative Dispute Resolution at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Director, Alternative Dispute Resolution, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Complainants, respondents or committee treasurers, witnesses, and the Federal Election Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>With respect to open investigations, the system is exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). See 11 CFR part 1.14.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">FEC Freedom of Information Act System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified; some material may become public under 5 U.S.C. 552.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Election Commission, Office of General Counsel, General Law and Advice Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons requesting information from the Commission pursuant to provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 5 U.S.C. 552, and persons who are the subjects of FOIA requests.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests, response letters, appeals, appeal determinations and electronic tracking data.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552; 5 U.S.C. 301; Executive Order 13392.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To enable Commission staff to process FOIA requests and appeals; and to prepare an annual report to the Department of Justice on the Commission's FOIA activity.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in the records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. To employees of other Federal agencies when a FOIA request must be referred to such an agency for response.
</p><p>4. To appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>5. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>6. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>7. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>8. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>9. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Records are stored in both a paper and electronic format. Requests received by e-mail are stored on the FEC's e-mail server.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Indexed by name of requester.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked filing cabinets in limited access areas under personal surveillance during working hours and in locked rooms at other times. All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>FOIA requests are retained in accordance with General Records Schedule 14, as approved by National Archives and Records Administration (NARA).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief FOIA Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, (202/694-1650)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Chief FOIA Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the Chief FOIA Officer, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Chief FOIA Officer, Federal Election Commission at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons requesting information from the Commission pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act and employees processing the requests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="fec16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">HSPD-12: Identity Management, Personnel Security, Physical and Logical Access Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive but unclassified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Data covered by this system is maintained at the Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Individuals who require regular, ongoing access to agency facilities, information technology systems and networks, including applicants for employment or contracts with the FEC, agency employees, contractors, students, interns, volunteers, affiliates, and individuals formerly in any of these positions. The system also includes individuals authorized to perform or use services provided in agency facilities (e.g., Health Unit).
</p><p>(2) Individuals who have been issued HSPD-12 compliant credentials from other Federal agencies who require access to agency facilities.
</p><p>(3) Visitors and other individuals who require infrequent access to agency facilities including services provided in agency facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Copies of Forms SF-85, SF-85P, SF-86, SF-87A and FD 258 as supplied by individuals covered by the system.
</p><p>(2) Enrollment records to be maintained in the system on individuals applying for the Personal Identity Verification (PIV) program and a PIV credential. May include the following data fields: full name, former names, birth date, birth place, Social Security Number, signature, home address, phone numbers, employment history, residential history, education and degrees earned, applicant ID number, digital color photograph, names of associates and references and their contact information, citizenship, names of relatives, birthdates and places of relatives, citizenship of relatives, names of relatives who work for the Federal government, criminal history, mental health history, drug use, financial information, fingerprints, biometric template (two fingerprints), organization/office of assignment, employee affiliation, work e-mail address, work telephone number(s), office address, copies of identity source documents, employee status, military status, summary report of investigation, results of suitability decisions, Government agency code, requests for appeal and PIV issuance location. Additional records include copies of letters of transmittal between the FEC and the Office of Personnel Management concerning the individual's background investigation; copies of certification clearance status and briefing and/or copies of debriefing certificates signed by the individual, as appropriate and copies of PIV application forms as supplied by individuals covered by the system.
</p><p>(3) Records maintained on individuals issued credentials by the agency. May include the following data fields: hair color; eye color, height; weight; agency affiliation (i.e., employee, contractor, volunteer, etc.); telephone number; PIV card issuance and expiration dates, personal identification number (PIN); Cardholder Unique Identifier (CHUID); card management keys; results of background investigation; PIV request form; PIV registrar approval signature; PIV card serial number; digital certificate(s) serial number; copies of I-9 documents used to verify identification or information derived from those documents such as document title, document issuing authority, document number, document expiration date, or document other information; computer system user name; user access and permission rights, authentication certificates; and digital signature information.
</p><p>(4) Individuals enrolled in the PIV managed service will be issued a PIV card. The PIV card contains the following mandatory visual personally identifiable information: name, photograph, employee affiliation, organizational affiliation, PIV card expiration date, agency card serial number, and color-coding for employee affiliation. Additional information may include cardholder physical characteristics (height, weight, and eye and hair color). The card also contains an integrated circuit chip which is encoded with the following mandatory data elements which comprise the standard data model for PIV logical credentials: PIV card PIN, cardholder unique identifier (CHUID), PIV authentication digital certificate, and two fingerprint biometric templates. The PIV data model may also include the following logical credentials: digital certificate for digital signature, digital certificate for key management, card authentication keys, and card management system keys. All PIV logical credentials can only be read by machine.
</p><p>(5) Records maintained on visitors and other individuals who require infrequent access to agency facilities. May include the following data fields: Name, signature, image (photograph), Social Security Number (or one of the following: driver's license number, "green card" number, visa number, or other ID number), images of relevant ID document(s), U.S. Citizenship (yes or no/logical data field), date of entry, time of entry, location of entry, time of exit, location of exit, purpose of entry, agency point of contact, company name, security access category, and access status.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301; Executive Order 10450; Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12 (HSPD-12), Policy for a Common Identification Standard for Federal Employees and Contractors, August 27, 2004; the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended; and Presidential Memorandum on Upgrading Security at Federal Facilities, June 28, 1995.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The primary purposes of the system are:
</p><p>(1) To document and support decisions regarding:
</p><p>(a) Clearance for access to sensitive but unclassified information;
</p><p>(b) Suitability, eligibility, and fitness for service of applicants for Federal employment and contract positions, including students, interns, or volunteers to the extent their duties require access to Federal facilities and/or information technology systems and their occupants and users;
</p><p>(2) To ensure the safety and security of agency facilities and/or information technology systems, and their occupants and users;
</p><p>(3) To verify that all persons entering agency facilities and/or agency information technology systems with or without smart cards are authorized to enter them;
</p><p>(4) To provide for interoperability and trust in allowing physical access to individuals entering Federal facilities; and
</p><p>(5) To allow logical access to Federal information systems, networks, and resources on a government-wide basis.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and the information contained in these records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Department of Justice when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed, after careful review, by the Federal Election Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>2. To disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear when:
</p><p>a. The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency, or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Federal Election Commission determines that, after careful review, use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that the agency determines that disclosure of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>3. Except as noted on Forms SF-85, SF 85-P and SF-86, to appropriate Federal, foreign, State, local, tribal, or other public authorities responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting civil or criminal violations of law or as necessary to facilitate parallel investigations or to assist the other agency with the investigation or prosecution of a matter within its jurisdiction.
</p><p>4. To any source or potential source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation concerning the retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), or the retention of a security clearance, contract, grant, license, or other benefit, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.
</p><p>5. To a Federal, State, local, foreign, tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a request supported by written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.
</p><p>6. To Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and private security contractors, as appropriate, to enable them to protect the safety of Commission employees and visitors and the security of the Commission's workplace; and to assist investigations or prosecutions with respect to activities that affect such safety and security or activities that disrupt the operation of Commission facilities.
</p><p>7. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained (e.g., a constituent request). Disclosure will not be made until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request.
</p><p>8. To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2903 and 2904.
</p><p>9. To contractors (including employees of contractors), grantees, experts, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the agency. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>10. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p>11. To the Office of Personnel Management for matters concerned with oversight activities (necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally-authorized Government-wide personnel management programs and functions) and in their role as an investigation agency.
</p><p>12. To an official of another Federal agency to provide information needed in the performance of official duties related to reconciling or reconstructing data files, in support of the functions for which records were collected and maintained.
</p><p>13. To an approved shared service provider in fulfillment of the terms of the HSPD-12 shared services agreement. Note: Although the shared service provider will manage the system that produces the identity credentials used by the agency, the shared service provider will not have access to the content of the data provided by the agency except to the extent that is required to provide for its integrity, reliability and security.
</p><p>14. To other Federal agencies providing enrollment services to the shared service provider when the shared service provider has entered into agreements with these agencies to provide enrollment services to their employees, contractors, etc. but not identification credentials, through third party enrollment brokers serving as links in the secure chain of custody for the HSPD-12 process.
</p><p>15. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the agency suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Commission or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>16. To designated agency personnel for controlled access to specific records for the purposes of performing authorized audit or authorized oversight and administrative functions. All access is controlled systematically through authentication using PIV credentials based on access and authorization rules for specific audit and administrative functions.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), records can be disclosed to consumer reporting agencies as they are defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Records are stored on paper and electronically in a secure location.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by name of employee or covered individual, Cardholder Unique Identification Number, Applicant ID, Social Security Number, and/or by any other unique individual identifier.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to records covered by the system will be permitted only to authorized personnel in accordance with requirements found in agency Privacy Act regulations. Persons given roles in the PIV process must complete training specific to their roles to ensure they are knowledgeable about how to protect individually identifiable information regardless of how and where it is stored. Paper records will be maintained in locked filing cabinets in limited access areas within the Office of Human Resources and Labor Relations under personal surveillance during working hours and in locked rooms at other times. Access to the records will be limited to those employees who have a need for them in the performance of their official duties. All agency electronic records will be protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties. Should the shared service provider be another Federal agency, records maintained by that agency may also be subject to the safeguards outlined in that agency's systems of records notice.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Paper personnel security records relating to individuals covered by the system are generally retained and disposed in accordance with General Records Schedule 18, Item No. 22, approved by the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA).
</p><p>(2) In accordance with HSPD-12, PIV cards are deactivated within 18 hours of cardholder separation, loss of card, or expiration. The information on PIV cards is maintained in accordance with General Records Schedule 11, Item No. 4. PIV cards are destroyed by cross-cut shredding no later than 90 days after deactivation.
</p><p>(3) Building security records relating to persons covered by this system are retained in accordance with General Records Schedule 18, Item No. 17. Unless retained for specific ongoing security investigations:
</p><p>(a) Records relating to individuals other than employees are destroyed two years after ID security card expiration date;
</p><p>(b) Records relating to date and time of entry and exit of employees are destroyed two years after date of entry and exit; and
</p><p>(c) All other records relating to employees are destroyed two years after ID security card expiration date.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) For personnel security: Personnel Security Manager, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p><p>(2) For physical security: Administrative Services Manager, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p><p>(3) For logical security: Information Systems Security Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for notification of the existence of personnel security records may be made in person or in writing and addressed to the FEC personnel security manager identified in (1), above. A request for notification of the existence of physical security records may be made in person or in writing and addressed to the FEC physical security manager identified in (2), above. A request for notification of the existence of logical security records may be made in person or in writing and addressed to the FEC logical security manager identified in (3), above. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual interested in gaining access to a personnel security record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the FEC personnel security manager identified in (1), above at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. An individual interested in gaining access to a physical security record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the FEC physical security manager identified in (2), above at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. An individual interested in gaining access to a logical security record pertaining to him or her may make a request in person or in writing to the FEC logical security manager identified in (3), above at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their personnel security records or the denial of access to such information should notify the FEC personnel security manager identified in (1), above at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their physical security records or the denial of access to such information should notify the FEC physical security manager identified in (2), above at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their logical security records or the denial of access to such information should notify the FEC logical security manager identified in (3), above at the following address: 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. For additional information regarding contesting initial denials for access to or amendments of Privacy Act records, refer to the Commission's regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is obtained from a variety of sources including the employee, contractor, or applicant via the use of the SF-85, SF-85P, or SF-86 and personal interviews; employers' and former employers' records; other Federal agencies supplying data on covered individuals; FBI criminal history records and other databases; financial institutions and credit reports; medical records and health care providers; and educational institutions. Information is also obtained from individuals covered by the system, supervisors, and designated approving officials, as well as other Federal agencies issuing HSPD-12 compliant cards, and HSPD-12 compliant cards carried by individuals seeking access to Commission and other Federal facilities occupied by agency employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
        <section id="fec17" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">
                FEC 17:  Reasonable Accommodations.
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Sensitive but unclassified.</p>
                  </xhtmlContent>
     </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are maintained by the Equal Employment Opportunity ("EEO") Office at the Federal Election Commission, 1050 1st St. NE, Washington, DC 20463.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>EEO Director, EEO Office at the Federal Election Commission, 1050 1st St. NE, Washington, DC 20463.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 U.S.C. 701,791, 794; Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42 U.S.C. 2000e; 29 CFR 1605 (Guidelines on Discrimination Because of Religion); 29 CFR 1614 (Federal Sector Equal Employment Opportunity); 29 CFR 1614.203 (Regulations to Implement the Equal Employment Provisions of the Americans With Disabilities Act); 5 U.S.C. 302, 1103; Executive Order 13164, Requiring Federal Agencies to Establish Procedures to Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation (July 26, 2000); Americans with Disabilities Act Amendments Act (ADAAA) of 2008; and Executive Order 13548, Increasing Federal Employment of Individuals with Disabilities (July 26, 2010).
                    </p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The purpose of this system of records is to allow FEC to collect and maintain records on applicants for employment, employees and other individuals who participate in FEC programs or activities who request or receive reasonable accommodations or other appropriate modifications from FEC for medical or religious reasons; to process, evaluate, and make decisions on individual requests; and to track and report the processing of such requests agency-wide to comply with applicable requirements in law and policy.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Current and former FEC employees (including unpaid interns and other similarly situated individuals), and prospective employees of the FEC, who make a request for and/or receive a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modifications from the FEC for a disability or sincerely held religious belief, practice, or observance.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records in this system include identifying information regarding persons needing a reasonable accommodation (e.g., name, title/series/grade, telephone number, date of request, e-mail address, office, description of accommodation requested, and reason for request); requester’s name and contact information (if different than the employee or prospective employee who needs an accommodation); and the status of the response within the FEC.  Records in this system may include: the original written request; the FEC’s response; the name, title and telephone number of office or staff members deciding or referring the matter; related letters or memoranda; copies of any enclosures/attachments, including medical records or information related to religious belief and exemption; the date an accommodation request was approved or denied; the reason a request was denied; the date an accommodation was provided; whether the recommended time frames were met as outlined in the Reasonable Accommodation Procedures; the reason the reasonable accommodation was needed; the type(s) of reasonable accommodation requested; the type(s) of accommodation provided; the source of technical assistance; whether medical or other appropriate supporting information was required to process the request, and if so, an explanation of why it was required; and other request-related information.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information is obtained from the individuals who request and/or receive a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modification from OPM, directly or indirectly from an individual's medical provider or another medical professional who evaluates the request, directly or indirectly from an individual's religious or spiritual advisors or institutions, and from management officials.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), these records and information contained in the records may be disclosed outside of the FEC as a routine use pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of the Privacy Act as follows:</p>
                    A.	<p>To a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member’s behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                    B.	<p>To the General Services Administration and National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    C.	<p>Where a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law, to any civil or criminal law enforcement authority or other appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local, foreign, or tribal, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such a violation or enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order.</p>
                    D.	<p>In an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or regulatory body when records are determined by the FEC to be arguably relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                    E.	<p>To an actual or potential party to litigation or the party’s authorized representative for the purpose of negotiation or discussion on such matters as settlement, plea bargaining, or in informal discovery proceedings.</p>
                    F.	<p>To a federal agency or entity that requires information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conduct of a security or suitability investigation, or pursuit of other appropriate personnel matter.</p>
                    G.	<p>To contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the Federal Government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to FEC employees.</p>
                    H.	<p>To a former employee of the FEC for purposes of: responding to an official inquiry by a federal, state, or local government entity or professional licensing authority, in accordance with applicable FEC regulations; or facilitating communications with a former employee that may be necessary for personnel-related or other official purposes where the FEC requires information and/or consultation assistance from the former employee regarding a matter within that person’s former area of responsibility.</p>
                    I.	<p>To such recipients and under such circumstances and procedures as are mandated by federal statute or treaty.</p>
                    J.	<p>A record from this system may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Department of Labor (DOL), Office of Personnel Management (OPM), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), Office of Special Counsel (OSC) or the Department of Justice (DOJ), or other agencies to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements related to reasonable accommodation.</p>
                    K.	<p>A record from this system may be disclosed to physicians or other medical professionals to provide them with or obtain from them the necessary medical documentation and/or certification for reasonable accommodation.</p>
                    L.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to provide information to the OPM and/or MSPB for review, audit, or reporting purposes.</p>
                    M.	<p>To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the FEC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the FEC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach, there is a risk of harm to individuals, FEC (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the FEC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    N.	<p>To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the FEC determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    O.	<p>To first aid and safety personnel if the individual's medical condition requires emergency treatment.</p>
                    P.	<p>To a Federal agency or entity authorized to procure assistive technologies and services in response to a request for reasonable accommodation</p>
                    Q.	<p>
                        To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engages in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who requested a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modification
                    </p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Storage:</p>
                    <p> The records in this system of records are stored electronically on the FEC's local area network or with FedRAMP-authorized cloud service providers segregated from non-government traffic and data, with access limited to a small number of personnel.  In addition, paper records are stored in locked file cabinets in access-restricted offices at 1050 1st St. NE, Washington, DC 20463.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        The records are retrieved by the name of the individual making a request for
                        reasonable accommodation or for whom the accommodation was requested (if different than the individual making the request); in the case of electronic databases, information may possibly be retrieved by other identifying search terms.
                    </p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records in this system of records are under the custody of designated employees of the Commission.  Paper records are kept in locked file cabinets.  All electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards.  These safeguards include the application of appropriate access control mechanisms to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of those records and that they are only accessed by those with a need to know and dictated by their official duties.  In general, records and technical equipment are maintained in buildings with restricted access.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Records are retained under the NARA’s General Records Schedule 2.3: Employee Relations Records, Item 020, Reasonable accommodation records, Reasonable accommodation program files, and Item 021, Reasonable accommodation employee case files. Destroy 3 years after being superseded, but longer retention is authorized if required for business use (Item 020). Destroy 3 years after employee separation from the agency or all appeals are concluded, whichever is later, but longer retention is authorized if required for business use (Item 021).</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>A request for notification of the existence of records may be made in person or in writing to the Federal Election Commission, Attn: Co-Chief Privacy Officers, 1050 1st St. NE, Washington, DC 20463, or by emailing privacy@fec.gov.  For additional information, refer to the Commission’s access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> An individual interested in gaining access to a record pertaining to them must make a request in writing addressed to the Federal Election Commission, Attn: Co-Chief Privacy Officers, 1050 1st St. NE, Washington, DC 20463, or by emailing privacy@fec.gov.  The envelope and letter should be clearly marked ‘‘Privacy Act Access Request.’’ The request should include a general description of the records sought must be signed and must include the requestor’s full name, current address, reason the requester believes the records contains their PII, and date. For additional information, refer to the Commission's access regulations at 11 CFR parts 1.1-1.5, 41 FR 43064 (1976).</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals interested in contesting the information contained in their records or the denial of access to such information should notify the Co-Chief Privacy Officers at the Federal Election Commission, 1050 1st St. NE, Washington, DC 20463.  For additional information, refer to the Commission's regulations for contesting initial denials for access to or amendment of records, 11 CFR parts 1.7-1.9, 41 FR 43064 (1976).</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> None.</p>
              </xhtmlContent>
             </subsection>
                    <subsection type="HISTORY">
                        <xhtmlContent>
                            <p> None.</p>
                      </xhtmlContent>
         </subsection>
        </section>


        <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="11">
<heading>Federal Elections </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="I">
<heading> Federal Election Commission </heading>
<regulationsPart number="1">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>1.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>1.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>1.3 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</p>
<p>1.4 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</p>
<p>1.5 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</p>
<p>1.6 Special procedure: Medical records. [Reserved]
</p>
<p>1.7 Request for correction or amendment to record.
</p>
<p>1.8 Agency review of request for correction or amendment of record.
</p>
<p>1.9 Appeal of initial adverse agency determination on amendment or correction.
</p>
<p>1.10 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</p>
<p>1.11 Fees.
</p>
<p>1.12 Penalties.
</p>
<p>1.13 General exemptions. [Reserved]
</p>
<p>1.14 Specific exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 41 FR 43064, Sept. 29, 1976, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.1
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The purpose of this part is to set forth rules informing the public as to what information is maintained by the Federal Election Commission about identifiable individuals and to inform those individuals how they may gain access to and correct or amend information about themselves.
</p>
<p>(b) The regulations in this part carry out the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579) and in particular 5 U.S.C. 552a as added by that Act.
</p>
<p>(c) The regulations in this part apply only to records disclosed or requested under the Privacy Act of 1974, and not to requests for information made pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552, the Freedom of Information Act, or requests for reports and statements filed with the Federal Election Commission which are public records and available for inspection and copying pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4) (C) and 438(a)(4).
</p>
<p>[41 FR 43064, Sept. 29, 1976, as amended at 45 FR 21209, Apr. 1, 1980]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>As defined in the Privacy Act of 1974 and for the purposes of this part, unless otherwise required by the context, the following terms shall have these meanings:
</p>
<p><i>Act</i> means the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as amended and chapters 
</p>
<p><i>Commission</i> means the Federal Election Commission, its Commissioners, and employees.
The Commission is located at 1050 First Street, NE, Washington, DC 20463. The
Commission’s website is www.fec.gov.
</p>
<p><i>Commissioner</i> means an individual appointed to the Federal Election Commission pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 437c(a).

</p>
<p><i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
</p>
<p><i>Maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use or disseminate.
</p>
<p><i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by an agency, including but not limited to his or her education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history and that contains his or her name, or the identifying number, symbol or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as finger or voice print or a photograph.
</p>
<p><i>Routine use</i> means the use of such record for a purpose compatible with the purpose for which the information was collected.
</p>
<p><i>Commission</i> means the Federal Election Commission, its Commissioners and employees.

</p>
<p><i>Systems of Records</i> means a group of any records under the control of the Federal Election Commission from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.



</p>
<p>[41 FR 43064, Sept. 29, 1976, as amended at 75 FR 30, Jan. 4, 2010]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.3
 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual may request the Commission to inform him or her whether a particular record system named by the individual contains a record pertaining to him or her. The request may be made in person or in writing at the location and to the person specified in the notice describing that record system.
</p>
<p>(b) An individual who believes that the Commission maintains records pertaining to him or her but who cannot determine which record system contains those records, may request assistance by mail or in person from the Chief Privacy Officer, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463 during the hours of 9 a.m. to 5:30 p.m.
</p>
<p>(c) Requests under paragraphs (a) or (b) of this section shall be acknowledged by the Commission within 15 days from the date of receipt of the request. If the Commission is unable to locate the information requested under paragraphs (a) or (b) of this section, it shall so notify the individual within 15 days after receipt of the request. Such acknowledgement may request additional information to assist the Commission in locating the record or it may advise the individual that no record or document exists about that individual.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 43064, Sept. 29, 1976, as amended at 50 FR 50778, Dec. 12, 1985; 75 FR 31, Jan. 5, 2010]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.4
 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</b></p>
<p>(a) After being informed by the Commission that a record system contains a record pertaining to him or her, an individual may request the Commission to disclose that record in the manner described in this section. Each request for the disclosure of a record or a copy of it shall be made at the Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463 and to the system manager identified in the notice describing the systems of records, either in writing or in person. Requests may be made by specifically authorized agents or by parents or guardians of individuals.
</p>
<p>(b) Each individual requesting the disclosure of a record or copy of a record shall furnish the following information with his or her request:
</p>
<p>(1) The name of the record system containing the record;
</p>
<p>(2) Proof as described in paragraph (c) of this section that he or she is the individual to whom the requested record relates;
</p>
<p>(3) Any other information required by the notice describing the record system.
</p>
<p>(c) Proof of identity as required by paragraph (b)(2) of this section shall be provided as described in paragraphs (c) (1) and (2) of this section. Requests made by an agent, parent, or guardian, shall be in accordance with the procedures described in &#167; 1.10.
</p>
<p>(1) Requests made in writing shall include a statement, signed by the individual and either notarized or witnessed by two persons (including witnesses? addresses). If the individual appears before a notary, he or she shall submit adequate proof of identification in the form of a drivers license, birth certificate, passport or other identification acceptable to the notary. If the statement is witnessed, it shall include a sentence above the witnesses? signatures that they personally know the individual or that the individual has submitted proof of his or her identification to their satisfaction. In any case in which, because of the extreme sensitivity of the record sought to be seen or copied, the Commission determines that the identification is not adequate, it may request the individual to submit additional proof of identification.
</p>
<p>(2) If the request is made in person, the requestor shall submit proof of identification similar to that described in paragraph (c)(1) of this section, acceptable to the Commission. The individual may have a person of his or her own choosing accompany him or her when the record is disclosed.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 43064, Sept. 29, 1976, as amended at 50 FR 50778, Dec. 12, 1985]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.5
 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Upon submission of proof of identification as required by &#167; 1.4, the Commission shall allow the individual to see and/or obtain a copy of the requested record or shall send a copy of the record to the individual by registered mail. If the individual requests to see the record, the Commission may make the record available either at the location where the record is maintained or at a place more suitable to the requestor, if possible. The record shall be made available as soon as possible but in no event later than 15 days after proof of identification.
</p>
<p>(b) The Commission must furnish each record requested by an individual under this part in a form intelligible to that individual.
</p>
<p>(c) If the Commission denies access to a record to an individual, he or she shall be advised of the reason for the denial and advised of the right to judicial review.
</p>
<p>(d) Upon request, an individual will be provided access to the accounting of disclosures from his or her record under the same procedures as provided above and in &#167; 1.4.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.6 Special procedure: Medical records. [Reserved]</b></p>

<p><b>&#167; 1.7
 Request for correction or amendment to record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual who has reviewed a record pertaining to him or her that was furnished under this part, may request the Commission to correct or amend all or any part of that record.
</p>
<p>(b) Each individual requesting a correction or amendment shall send the request to the Commission through the person who furnished the record.
</p>
<p>(c) Each request for a correction or amendment of a record shall contain the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) The name of the individual requesting the correction or amendment;
</p>
<p>(2) The name of the system of records in which the record sought to be amended is maintained;
</p>
<p>(3) The location of the system of records from which the individual record was obtained;
</p>
<p>(4) A copy of the record sought to be amended or corrected or a sufficiently detailed description of that record;
</p>
<p>(5) A statement of the material in the record that the individual desires to correct or amend;
</p>
<p>(6) A statement of the basis for the requested correction or amendment including any material that the individual can furnish to substantiate the reasons for the correction or amendment sought.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.8
 Agency review of request for correction or amendment of record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Commission shall, not later than ten (10) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays) after the receipt of the request for a correction or amendment of a record under &#167; 1.7, acknowledge receipt of the request and inform the individual whether information is required before the correction or amendment can be considered.
</p>
<p>(b) If no additional information is required, within ten (10) days from receipt of the request, the Commission shall either make the requested correction or amendment or notify the individual of its refusal to do so, including in the notification the reasons for the refusal, and the appeal procedures provided in &#167; 1.9.
</p>
<p>(c) The Commission shall make each requested correction or amendment to a record if that correction or amendment will tend to negate inaccurate, irrelevant, untimely, or incomplete matter in the record.
</p>
<p>(d) The Commission shall inform prior recipients of any amendment or correction or notation of dispute of such individual?s record if an accounting of the disclosure was made. The individual may request a list of prior recipients if an accounting of the disclosure was made.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.9
 Appeal of initial adverse agency determination on amendment or correction.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual whose request for a correction or amendment has been denied in whole or in part, may appeal that decision to the Commissioners no later than one hundred eighty (180) days after the adverse decision is rendered.
</p>
<p>(b) The appeal shall be in writing and shall contain the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) The name of the individual making the appeal;
</p>
<p>(2) Identification of the record sought to be amended;
</p>
<p>(3) The record system in which that record is contained;
</p>
<p>(4) A short statement describing the amendment sought; and
</p>
<p>(5) The name and location of the agency official who initially denied the correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>(c) Not later than thirty (30) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays) after the date on which the Commission receives the appeal, the Commissioners shall complete their review of the appeal and make a final decision thereon. However, for good cause shown, the Commissioners may extend that thirty (30) day period. If the Commissioners extend the period, the individual requesting the review shall be promptly notified of the extension and the anticipated date of a decision.
</p>
<p>(d) After review of an appeal, the Commission shall send a written notice to the requestor containing the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) The decision and, if the denial is upheld, the reasons for the decision;
</p>
<p>(2) The right of the requestor to institute a civil action in a Federal District Court for judicial review of the decision; and
</p>
<p>(3) The right of the requestor to file with the Commission a concise statement setting forth the reasons for his or her disagreement with the Commission denial of the correction or amendment. The Commission shall make this statement available to any person to whom the record is later disclosed, together with a brief statement, if appropriate, of the Commission?s reasons for denying the requested correction or amendment. The Commission shall also send a copy of the statement to prior recipients of the individual?s record if an accounting of the disclosures was made.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.10
 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual who desires to have a record covered by this part disclosed to or mailed to another person may designate such person and authorize such person to act as his or her agent for that specific purpose. The authorization shall be in writing, signed by the individual and notarized or witnessed as provided in &#167; 1.4(c).
</p>
<p>(b) The parent of any minor individual or the legal guardian of any individual who has been declared by a court of competent jurisdiction to be incompetent, due to physical or mental incapacity or age, may act on behalf of that individual in any matter covered by this part. A parent or guardian who desires to act on behalf of such an individual shall present suitable evidence of parentage or guardianship, by birth certificate, certified copy of a court order, or similar documents, and proof of the individual?s identity in a form that complies with &#167; 1.4(c) of this part.
</p>
<p>(c) An individual to whom a record is to be disclosed in person, pursuant to this part may have a person of his or her own choosing accompany him or her when the record is disclosed.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.11
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Commission shall not charge an individual for the costs of making a search for a record or the costs of reviewing the record. When the Commission makes a copy of a record as a necessary part of the process of disclosing the record to an individual, the Commission shall not charge the individual for the cost of making that copy.
</p>
<p>(b) If an individual requests the Commission to furnish a copy of the record, the Commission shall charge the individual for the costs of making the copy. The fee that the Commission has established for making a copy is ten cents ($.10) per page.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.12
 Penalties.
</b></p>
<p>Any person who makes a false statement in connection with any request for a record, or an amendment or correction thereto, under this part, is subject to the penalties prescribed in 18 U.S.C. 494 and 495.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.13 General exemptions. [Reserved]</b>

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1.14
 Specific exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) No individual, under the provisions of these regulations, shall be entitled to access to materials compiled in its systems of records identified as FEC audits and investigations (FEC 2) or FEC compliance actions (FEC 3). These exempted systems relate to the Commission?s power to exercise exclusive civil jurisdiction over the enforcement of the Act under 2 U.S.C. 437d (a)(6) and (e); and to defend itself in actions filed against it under 2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(6). Further the Commission has a duty to investigate violations of the Act under 2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(2); to conduct audits and investigations pursuant to 2 U.S.C. 438(b), 26 U.S.C. 9007 and 9038; and to refer apparent violations of the Act to the Attorney General or other law enforcement authorities under 2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(5) and 437d(9). Information contained in FEC systems 2 and 3 contain the working papers of the Commission staff and form the basis for either civil and/or criminal proceedings pursuant to the exercise of the powers and duties of the Commission. These materials must be protected until such time as they are subject to public access under the provision of 2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4)(B) or 5 U.S.C. 552, or other relevant statutes.
</p>
<p>(b)(1) Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), records contained in FEC 12, Office of Inspector General Investigative Files, are exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a, except subsections (b), (c) (1) and (2), (e)(4) (A) through (F), (e) (6), (7), (9), (10), and (11) and (f) , and the corresponding provisions of 11 CFR part 1, to the extent this system of records relates in any way to the enforcement of criminal laws.
</p>
<p>(2) Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), FEC 12, Office of Inspector General Investigative Files, is exempt from 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f), and the corresponding provisions of 11 CFR part 1, to the extent the system of records consists of investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes, except for material that falls within the exemption included in paragraph (b)(1) of this section.
</p>
<p>(c) The provisions of paragraph (a) of this section shall not apply to the extent that application of the subsection would deny any individual any right, privilege or benefit to which he or she would otherwise be entitled to receive.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 43064, Sept. 29, 1976, as amended at 45 FR 21209, Apr. 1, 1980; 60 FR 4073, Jan. 20, 1995; 75 FR 31, Jan 4. 2010]


</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
