<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="govman.xsl"?>
<GovernmentManual>
    <accessId>GOVMAN-2022-12-31-074</accessId>
    <Entity EntityId="74" ParentId="0" SortOrder="7">
        <EntityType>Parent</EntityType>
        <Category>Legislative Branch</Category>
        <IntroductoryHeader/>
        <IntroductoryParagraph/>
        <AgencyName>United States Botanic Garden</AgencyName>
        <Addresses>
            <Address EntityAddressId="29" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email>usbg@aoc.gov</Email>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.usbg.gov</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Address>Office of Executive Director, 245 First Street SW., Washington, DC 20024</Address>
                <Phone>202-226-8333</Phone>
                <Phone2/>
                <Fax/>
            </Address>
            <Address EntityAddressId="30" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Address>Conservatory, 100 Maryland Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20001</Address>
                <Phone/>
                <Phone2/>
                <Fax/>
            </Address>
            <Address EntityAddressId="31" SortOrder="3">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Address>Production Facility, 4700 Shepherd Parkway  SW., Washington, DC 20032</Address>
                <Phone>202-226-4780</Phone>
                <Phone2/>
                <Fax/>
            </Address>
        </Addresses>
        <LeaderShipTables>
            <LeaderShipTable EntityLeaderShipTableId="328" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.aoc.gov/organization/acting-architect</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>ACTING DIRECTOR</Header>
                <HeaderParagraph/>
                <NameColumnHeader/>
                <ShowFootNote>Yes</ShowFootNote>
                <ShowHeader>Yes</ShowHeader>
                <ShowHeaderParagraph>Yes</ShowHeaderParagraph>
                <ShowNameColumnHeader>Yes</ShowNameColumnHeader>
                <ShowTitleColumnHeader>Yes</ShowTitleColumnHeader>
                <TitleColumnHeader/>
                <LeaderShipTableValues>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="5015" SortOrder="1">
                        <NameColumnValue/>
                        <TitleColumnValue>(vacancy)</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                </LeaderShipTableValues>
            </LeaderShipTable>
            <LeaderShipTable EntityLeaderShipTableId="17" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer>The above list of key personnel was updated 10–2019.</Footer>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/staff/saharah-moon-chapotin-phd</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR</Header>
                <HeaderParagraph/>
                <NameColumnHeader/>
                <ShowFootNote>Yes</ShowFootNote>
                <ShowHeader>Yes</ShowHeader>
                <ShowHeaderParagraph>Yes</ShowHeaderParagraph>
                <ShowNameColumnHeader>Yes</ShowNameColumnHeader>
                <ShowTitleColumnHeader>Yes</ShowTitleColumnHeader>
                <TitleColumnHeader/>
                <LeaderShipTableValues>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="312" SortOrder="1">
                        <NameColumnValue/>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Saharah Moon Chapotin</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                </LeaderShipTableValues>
            </LeaderShipTable>
        </LeaderShipTables>
        <MissionStatement>
            <Heading/>
            <Record>
                <Paragraph MissionStatmentId="96" SortOrder="1">The United States Botanic Garden demonstrates the essential contribution that plants make aesthetically, culturally, ecologically, economically, and therapeutically, to the well-being of humankind, and it supports partnerships, nationally and internationally, by fostering exchanges of information and ideas.</Paragraph>
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Footer/>
                </FooterDetails>
            </Record>
        </MissionStatement>
        <OrganizationChart/>
        <LegalAuthority>
            <Heading/>
        </LegalAuthority>
        <OrganizationStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </OrganizationStatement>
        <ProgramAndActivities>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="212" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName/>
                <Program ProgramAndActivitiesId="440" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading>ESTABLISHMENT AND ORGANIZATION</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="660">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://founders.archives.gov/?q=%20Author%3A%22Washington%2C%20George%22&amp;s=1211311113&amp;r=2118</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The U.S. Botanic Garden (USBG) has a long root that runs deep
                                in the soil of the Nation's history. On October 21, 1796, while
                                addressing some gentlemen in a letter from Mount Vernon, President
                                George Washington conceived that "a Botanical Garden would be a good
                                appendage to the Institution of a University" in the "Federal City."
                                Twenty-four years later, that conception blossomed, when President
                                James Madison helped establish a botanic garden in the U.S. Capital
                                under the auspices of the Columbian Institute, a society dedicated
                                to promoting the arts and sciences. This early botanic collection
                                served as the core of what would grow to become the Nation's future
                                botanic garden.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="661">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.loc.gov/law/help/statutes-at-large/27th-congress/session-2/c27s2ch205.pdf</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The U.S. Congress also supported establishing a national
                                botanic garden. By an act of August 26, 1842, it made provision for
                                the safekeeping and arrangement of dried and living specimens that
                                Lieutenant Charles Wilkes's expedition had collected while exploring
                                the Pacific Rim. Congress enacted that the enlarged collection
                                should be placed under the stewardship of its Joint Committee on the
                                Library and that it should be kept in the upper room of the Patent
                                Office (5 Stat. 534).</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="3" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="662">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.loc.gov/law/help/statutes-at-large/31st-congress/session-1/c31s1ch10.pdf</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>When the old Patent Office was expanded in 1849, a new
                                location for the plants and greenhouse had to be found. Congress
                                again intervened and, by an act of May 15, 1850, funded the
                                construction of a new greenhouse and the collection's removal and
                                relocation to a "suitable site on the public grounds" of the
                                Capitol. The Joint Committee on the Library, with supervision from
                                the Commissioner of Public Buildings, managed the project (9 Stat.
                                427). A new national botanic garden opened on the National Mall, at
                                the west end of the Capitol Grounds, later that year.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="4" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="663">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/brief-history-us-botanic-garden</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>By 1856—the collection had been named officially the United
                                States Botanic Garden, Congress was providing an annual
                                appropriation for its upkeep, and the Joint Committee on the Library
                                had assumed responsibility for both its direction and maintenance.
                                To satisfy the McMillan Commission's plan for a large, open mall,
                                the USBG relocated one block south, to its present site, in 1933.
                                The Joint Committee on the Library maintains oversight of the USBG
                                through the Architect of the Capitol, who holds the title of Acting
                                Director.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Program>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1284" SortOrder="2">
                    <Heading>ACTIVITIES</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="2728">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/about-us</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The USBG highlights botanical diversity worldwide and informs
                                people about plants' aesthetic, cultural, ecological, economic, and
                                therapeutic significance. The agency promotes appreciation of plants
                                and stimulates interest in botany through artistic plant displays,
                                education programs, exhibits, and curation of a large plant
                                collection. It supports conservation by serving as a repository for
                                endangered plant species. It also encourages the exchange of ideas
                                and disseminates mission-relevant information to national and
                                international visitors and policymakers.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="2729">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/hours-and-location-0</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Three USBG sites are open year-round to the public: the
                                Conservatory, the National Garden, and Bartholdi Park. The
                                production facility is periodically open for public programs and
                                tours.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
        </ProgramAndActivities>
        <SourceOfInformationDetails>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2301" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/sites/default/files/attachments/agriculture_and_the_future_of_food_-_the_role_of_botanic_gardens.pdf</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>America's Agricultural Experience</Header>
                <Paragraph>Based on a meeting that the U.S. Botanic Garden helped to organize of the Nation's leading agricultural and botanical educators, "Agriculture and the Future of Food: The Role of Botanic Gardens" presents a series of educational narratives that promote the reconnection of people and plants through the American agricultural experience. The document is available online in Portable Document Format (PDF).</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2462" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/programs-and-events</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Calendar of Events</Header>
                <Paragraph>The USBG offers children and family programs, lectures, special tours, and workshops, as well as free theater, concerts, cooking demonstrations, and more. An events calendar is posted on the "Programs and Events" page, and a Portable Document Format (PDF) version is available for downloading.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="3128" SortOrder="3">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/know-your-impact</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Carbon Footprint</Header>
                <Paragraph>A small step can lead to a big change. A carbon, or ecological, footprint helps demonstrate the effect that lifestyle has on Earth systems. Most people can reduce their carbon footprint (i.e., the amount of emitted greenhouse gases that lifestyle governs) by shifting to sustainable practices and products. The USBG posted a list of suggestions for developing a more sustainable lifestyle, a lifestyle that leaves behind a smaller carbon footprint. The list includes suggestions for bottled water, coffee grounds, driving less, eating locally, junk mail, planting trees, plastic bags, and washing clothes.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="998" SortOrder="4">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/opportunities-us-botanic-garden</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Career Opportunities</Header>
                <Paragraph>Information on career and volunteer opportunities is available online.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="3127" SortOrder="5">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/contact-us-botanic-garden</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Contact Information</Header>
                <Paragraph>The USBG welcomes feedback: comments, concerns, and questions. Got a growing plant question? Select the "Plant Hotline" option in the "Inquiry Type" field of the electronic comment form.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="999" SortOrder="6">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/exhibits</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Exhibits</Header>
                <Paragraph>The USBG creates exhibits that not only delight and educate visitors, but that inspire them to become more active and better stewards of the plants supporting life on Earth. It posts Information on current and upcoming exhibits online.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2297" SortOrder="7">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/gardening-fact-sheets-0</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Factsheets</Header>
                <Paragraph>Gardening factsheets are available online.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2299" SortOrder="8">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/kids-are-welcome-us-botanic-garden</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Kids</Header>
                <Paragraph>The USBG is a child-friendly living plant museum.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2461" SortOrder="9">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.sustainablesites.org</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Land Development and Management</Header>
                <Paragraph>An interdisciplinary partnership led by the USBG, American Society of Landscape Architects, and the Lady Bird Johnson Wildflower Center, the Sustainable Sites Initiative™ improves land development and management practices with a voluntary rating system for sustainable land design, construction, and maintenance practices. Architects, designers, developers, engineers, landscape architects, policymakers, and others use SITES to align land development and management with sustainable design. SITES supports the creation of ecologically resilient communities, and it benefits property owners, local and regional communities and their economies, as well as the environment. Certification covers development projects on land where buildings are absent or present.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2459" SortOrder="10">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://landscapeforlife.org</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Landscaping</Header>
                <Paragraph>A collaboration between the USBG and the Lady Bird Johnson Wildflower Center, Landscape For Life™ promotes an approach to landscaping that respects nature. Irrespective of location—downtown, suburbia, or the farm—every landscape or garden can protect and even restore the environment, without sacrificing visual appeal. The Landscape for Life website contains a trove of information—getting started, materials, human health, plants, soil, and water—for transforming an environmentally ambivalent landscape into a healthy, sustainable one.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2300" SortOrder="11">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/search-collection</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Living Collections Database</Header>
                <Paragraph>An online tool is available to search the USBG's living collections database.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2460" SortOrder="12">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/national-garden-native-plant-recommendations</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Native Plant Recommendations</Header>
                <Paragraph>The USBG posts lists of selected plants to grow in the garden. The lists are available in Portable Document Format (PDF) for downloading.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1098" SortOrder="13">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Plant Hotline</Header>
                <Paragraph>Questions about a garden plant? Call the Plant Hotline. Phone, 202-226-4785.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2298" SortOrder="14">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/pollinator-information</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Pollinators</Header>
                <Paragraph>Learn about the role birds and bees, as well as other creatures like bats, beetles, butterflies, flies, moths, and even wasps, play in the life cycle of plants.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1099" SortOrder="15">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/us-botanic-garden-production-facility</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Production Facility</Header>
                <Paragraph>The production facility opens periodically for public programs and tours. An annual open house allows visitors to meet the gardeners, ask questions, and explore the facility.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2458" SortOrder="16">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/gardens/rare-and-endangered-plants-gallery</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Rare and Endangered Plants</Header>
                <Paragraph>USBG experts bank seeds of rare plants, introduce rare plants to the horticultural trade, maintain live specimens, and study wild plants at risk of endangerment or extinction. The website maintains a gallery of plants whose threat levels are vulnerable, threatened, and endangered.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2456" SortOrder="17">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/sitemap</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Site Map</Header>
                <Paragraph>The website map allows visitors to look for specific topics or to browse content that aligns with their interests.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2457" SortOrder="18">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.facebook.com/usbotanicgarden</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Social Media</Header>
                <Paragraph>The USBG has a Facebook account.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="3126" SortOrder="19">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/staff-directory</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Staff Directory</Header>
                <Paragraph>Approximately 65 employees work at the USBG in four divisions: Administration, Horticulture, Operations, and Public Programs.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="3129" SortOrder="20">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.usbg.gov/visit</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Visitor Guide</Header>
                <Paragraph>More than a million visitors come to see the USBG each year. A visitor guide is available in Arabic, Chinese, English, French, German, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Russian, and Spanish.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
        </SourceOfInformationDetails>
        <FooterDetails>
            <Footer>The Sources of Information were updated 10–2019.</Footer>
            <Email/>
            <WebAddress/>
        </FooterDetails>
    </Entity>
</GovernmentManual>
