<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="govman.xsl"?>
<GovernmentManual>
    <accessId>GOVMAN-2022-12-31-084</accessId>
    <Entity EntityId="84" ParentId="81" SortOrder="3">
        <EntityType>SubEntityLevelOne</EntityType>
        <Category>Judicial Branch</Category>
        <IntroductoryHeader/>
        <IntroductoryParagraph/>
        <AgencyName>United States District Courts</AgencyName>
        <Addresses/>
        <LeaderShipTables/>
        <MissionStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </MissionStatement>
        <OrganizationChart/>
        <LegalAuthority>
            <Heading/>
        </LegalAuthority>
        <OrganizationStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </OrganizationStatement>
        <ProgramAndActivities>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="371" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName/>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="905" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading/>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1484">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The Nation's district courts are the trial courts of
                                        general Federal jurisdiction. These courts resolve disputes
                                        by determining the facts and applying legal principles to
                                        decide which party is right. Each State has at least one
                                        district court, and large States have as many as four. There
                                        are 89 district courts in the 50 States, plus one in the
                                        District of Columbia and another in the Commonwealth of
                                        Puerto Rico. Three other U.S. Territories also have courts
                                        that hear Federal cases: Guam and the Northern Mariana and
                                        Virgin Islands.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1485">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>At present, each district court has from 2 to 28
                                        Federal district judgeships, depending upon the amount of
                                        judicial work within its territory. Only one judge is
                                        usually required to hear and decide a case in a district
                                        court, but in some limited cases it is required that three
                                        judges be called together to comprise the court (28 U.S.C.
                                        2284). The judge senior in commission who is under 70 years
                                        of age (65 at inception of term), has been in office for at
                                        least 1 year, and has not previously been chief judge,
                                        serves as chief judge for a 7-year term. There are 645
                                        permanent district judgeships in the 50 States and 15 in the
                                        District of Columbia. There are seven district judgeships in
                                        Puerto Rico. District judges hold their offices during good
                                        behavior as provided by Article III, section 1, of the
                                        Constitution. However, Congress may temporary judgeships for
                                        a court with the provision that when a future vacancy occurs
                                        in that district, such vacancy shall not be filled. Each
                                        district court has one or more United States magistrate
                                        judges and bankruptcy judges, a clerk, a United States
                                        attorney, a United States marshal, probation officers, court
                                        reporters, and their staffs. The jurisdiction of the
                                        district courts is set forth in title 28, chapter 85, of the
                                        United States Code and at 18 U.S.C. 3231.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="3" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1486">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.uscourts.gov/about-federal-courts/court-role-and-structure</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Cases from the district courts are reviewable on
                                        appeal by the applicable court of appeals.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
        </ProgramAndActivities>
        <SourceOfInformationDetails/>
        <FooterDetails>
            <Footer/>
            <Email/>
            <WebAddress/>
        </FooterDetails>
    </Entity>
</GovernmentManual>
