<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="govman.xsl"?>
<GovernmentManual>
    <accessId>GOVMAN-2022-12-31-070</accessId>
    <Entity EntityId="70" ParentId="0" SortOrder="1">
        <EntityType>Parent</EntityType>
        <Category>Legislative Branch</Category>
        <IntroductoryHeader/>
        <IntroductoryParagraph/>
        <AgencyName>Congress</AgencyName>
        <Addresses>
            <Address EntityAddressId="210" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.congress.gov</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Address>ONE HUNDRED AND SEVENTEENTH CONGRESS</Address>
                <Phone/>
                <Phone2/>
                <Fax/>
            </Address>
        </Addresses>
        <LeaderShipTables/>
        <MissionStatement>
            <Heading/>
            <Record>
                <Paragraph MissionStatmentId="126" SortOrder="1">The Congress of the United States was created by Article I, section 1, of the Constitution, adopted by the Constitutional Convention on September 17, 1787, providing that “All legislative Powers herein granted shall be vested in a Congress of the United States, which shall consist of a Senate and House of Representatives."</Paragraph>
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Footer/>
                </FooterDetails>
            </Record>
            <Record>
                <Paragraph MissionStatmentId="130" SortOrder="2">The first Congress under the Constitution met on March 4, 1789, in the Federal Hall in New York City. The membership then consisted of 20  Senators and 59 Representatives.*</Paragraph>
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Footer>* New York ratified the Constitution on July 26, 1788, but did not elect
                        its Senators until July 15 and 16, 1789. North Carolina did not ratify the
                        Constitution until November 21, 1789; Rhode Island ratified it on May 29,
                        1790.</Footer>
                </FooterDetails>
            </Record>
        </MissionStatement>
        <OrganizationChart/>
        <LegalAuthority>
            <Heading/>
        </LegalAuthority>
        <OrganizationStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </OrganizationStatement>
        <ProgramAndActivities>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="450" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName/>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1087" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading>Congressional Record</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1797">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Proceedings of Congress are published in the Congressional
                                Record, which is issued each day when Congress is in session.
                                Publication of the Record began March 4, 1873. It was the first
                                record of debate officially reported, printed, and published
                                directly by the Federal Government. The Daily Digest of the
                                Congressional Record, printed in the back of each issue of the
                                Record, summarizes the proceedings of that day in each House and
                                each of their committees and subcommittees, respectively. The Digest
                                also presents the legislative program for each day and, at the end
                                of the week, gives the program for the following week. Its
                                publication was begun March 17, 1947.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="3103">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/crecb</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Congressional Record (Bound), 1873–2016</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="3" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="3104">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/CREC</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Congressional Record (Daily), 1994–Present</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1088" SortOrder="2">
                    <Heading>Sessions</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1798">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.archives.gov/founding-docs/constitution-transcript#toc-section-4-</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Article I, section 4, of the Constitution makes it mandatory
                                that "The Congress shall assemble at least once in every Year. . .
                                ." Under this provision, also, the date for convening Congress was
                                designated originally as the first Monday in December, "unless they
                                shall by Law appoint a different Day." Eighteen acts were passed, up
                                to 1820, providing for the meeting of Congress on other days of the
                                year. From 1820 to 1934, however, Congress met regularly on the
                                first Monday in December. In 1934 the 20th amendment changed the
                                convening of Congress to January 3, unless Congress "shall by law
                                appoint a different day." In addition, the President, according to
                                Article II, section 3, of the Constitution "may, on extraordinary
                                Occasions, convene both Houses, or either of them, and in Case of
                                Disagreement between them, with Respect to the Time of Adjournment,
                                he may adjourn them to such Time as he shall think proper. . .
                                ."</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1089" SortOrder="3">
                    <Heading>Powers of Congress</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1799">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.archives.gov/founding-docs/constitution-transcript#toc-section-8-</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Article I, section 8, of the Constitution defines the powers
                                of Congress. Included are the powers to assess and collect
                                taxes—called the chief power; to regulate commerce, both interstate
                                and foreign; to coin money; to establish post offices and post
                                roads; to establish courts inferior to the Supreme Court; to declare
                                war; and to raise and maintain an army and navy. Congress is further
                                empowered "To provide for calling forth the Militia to execute the
                                Laws of the Union, suppress Insurrections and repel Invasions;" and
                                "To make all Laws which shall be necessary and proper for carrying
                                into Execution the foregoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by
                                this Constitution in the Government of the United States, or in any
                                Department or Officer thereof."</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1090" SortOrder="4">
                    <Heading>Amendments to the Constitution</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1800">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Another power vested in the Congress is the right to propose
                                amendments to the Constitution, whenever two-thirds of both Houses
                                shall deem it necessary. Should two-thirds of the State legislatures
                                demand changes in the Constitution, it is the duty of Congress to
                                call a constitutional convention. Proposed amendments shall be valid
                                as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures or by
                                conventions of three-fourths of the States, as one or the other mode
                                of ratification may be proposed by Congress.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1091" SortOrder="5">
                    <Heading>Prohibitions Upon Congress</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1801">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.archives.gov/founding-docs/constitution-transcript#toc-section-9-</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Article I, section 9, of the Constitution also imposes
                                prohibitions upon Congress. "The Privilege of the Writ of Habeas
                                Corpus shall not be suspended, unless when in Cases of Rebellion or
                                Invasion the public Safety may require it." A bill of attainder or
                                an ex post facto law cannot be passed. No export duty can be
                                imposed. Ports of one State cannot be given preference over those of
                                another State. "No money shall be drawn from the Treasury, but in
                                Consequence of Appropriations made by Law. . . ." No title of
                                nobility may be granted.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1092" SortOrder="6">
                    <Heading>Rights of Members</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1802">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.archives.gov/founding-docs/constitution-transcript#toc-section-6-</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>According to Article I, section 6, Members of Congress are
                                granted certain privileges. In no case, except in treason, felony,
                                and breach of the peace, can Members be arrested while attending
                                sessions of Congress "and in going to and returning from the same. .
                                . ." Furthermore, the Members cannot be questioned in any other
                                place for remarks made in Congress. Each House may expel a Member of
                                its body by a two-thirds vote.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="1093" SortOrder="7">
                    <Heading>Enactment of Laws</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1803">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>In order to become law, all bills and joint resolutions,
                                except those proposing a constitutional amendment, must pass both
                                the House of Representatives and the Senate and either be signed by
                                the President or be passed over the President's veto by a two-thirds
                                vote of both Houses of Congress. Section 7 of Article I states: "If
                                any Bill shall not be returned by the President within ten Days
                                (Sundays excepted) after it shall have been presented to him, the
                                Same shall be a Law, in like Manner as if he had signed it, unless
                                the Congress by their Adjournment prevent its Return, in which Case
                                it shall not be a Law." When a bill or joint resolution is
                                introduced in the House, the usual procedure for its enactment into
                                law is as follows: assignment to House committee having
                                jurisdiction; if favorably considered, it is reported to the House
                                either in its original form or with recommended amendments; if the
                                bill or resolution is passed by the House, it is messaged to the
                                Senate and referred to the committee having jurisdiction; in the
                                Senate committee the bill, if favorably considered, may be reported
                                in the form as received from the House, or with recommended
                                amendments; the approved bill or resolution is reported to the
                                Senate, and if passed by that body, is returned to the House; if one
                                body does not accept the amendments to a bill by the other body, a
                                conference committee comprised of Members of both bodies is usually
                                appointed to effect a compromise; when the bill or joint resolution
                                is finally approved by both Houses, it is signed by the Speaker (or
                                Speaker pro tempore) and the Vice President (or President pro
                                tempore or acting President pro tempore) and is presented to the
                                President; and once the President's signature is affixed, the
                                measure becomes a law. If the President vetoes the bill, it cannot
                                become a law unless it is re-passed by a two-thirds vote of both
                                Houses.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
        </ProgramAndActivities>
        <SourceOfInformationDetails/>
        <FooterDetails>
            <Footer/>
            <Email/>
            <WebAddress/>
        </FooterDetails>
        <Childrens/>
    </Entity>
</GovernmentManual>
