<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="govman.xsl"?>
<GovernmentManual>
    <accessId>GOVMAN-2022-12-31-198</accessId>
    <Entity EntityId="198" ParentId="0" SortOrder="106">
        <EntityType>Parent</EntityType>
        <Category>International Organizations</Category>
        <IntroductoryHeader/>
        <IntroductoryParagraph/>
        <AgencyName>World Bank Group</AgencyName>
        <Addresses>
            <Address EntityAddressId="154" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Address>Headquarters: 1818 H Street NW., Washington, DC 20433</Address>
                <Phone>202-473-1000</Phone>
                <Phone2/>
                <Fax>202-477-6391</Fax>
            </Address>
        </Addresses>
        <LeaderShipTables>
            <LeaderShipTable EntityLeaderShipTableId="12" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer>The above personnel table was updated 5–2022.</Footer>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/leadership/managers</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <HeaderParagraph/>
                <NameColumnHeader/>
                <ShowFootNote>Yes</ShowFootNote>
                <ShowHeader>Yes</ShowHeader>
                <ShowHeaderParagraph>Yes</ShowHeaderParagraph>
                <ShowNameColumnHeader>Yes</ShowNameColumnHeader>
                <ShowTitleColumnHeader>Yes</ShowTitleColumnHeader>
                <TitleColumnHeader/>
                <LeaderShipTableValues>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="274" SortOrder="1">
                        <NameColumnValue>David R. Malpass</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>PRESIDENT</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                </LeaderShipTableValues>
            </LeaderShipTable>
        </LeaderShipTables>
        <MissionStatement>
            <Heading/>
            <Record>
                <Paragraph MissionStatmentId="147" SortOrder="1">The World Bank Group promotes shared global prosperity and seeks to end extreme poverty.</Paragraph>
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Footer/>
                </FooterDetails>
            </Record>
        </MissionStatement>
        <OrganizationChart/>
        <LegalAuthority>
            <Heading/>
        </LegalAuthority>
        <OrganizationStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </OrganizationStatement>
        <ProgramAndActivities>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="33" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName/>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="31" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading/>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="2039">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/what-we-do</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The World Bank Group (WBG) comprises five institutions: the
                                International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD), the
                                International Development Association (IDA), the International
                                Finance Corporation (IFC), the Multilateral Investment Guarantee
                                Agency (MIGA), and the International Centre for the Settlement of
                                Investment Disputes (ICSID). These WBG institutions work together to
                                help developing countries find answers to tough global and local
                                development challenges that range from climate change adaptation to
                                food security, to fighting corruption and more.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="2633">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/leadership</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The IBRD and the IDA serve as the WBG's primary economic and
                                social development institutions. Together, these two development
                                banks constitute the World Bank. Donor countries and countries with
                                borrowing rights, a total of 189 countries, support and benefit from
                                the World Bank. The activities of the IFC, MIGA, and ICSID
                                complement those of the IBRD and IDA.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
        </ProgramAndActivities>
        <SourceOfInformationDetails>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2181" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/topic</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>A–Z Topics</Header>
                <Paragraph>An alphabetical list of topics helps visitors learn about the WBG's many and diverse activities.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2748" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/access-to-information</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Access to Information</Header>
                <Paragraph>In 2010, the World Bank adopted its landmark disclosure policy: The World Bank Policy on Access to Information. It also has undertaken numerous initiatives to inform and educate the public. These open access initiatives include Open Data, Open Finances, and Open Knowledge Repository.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2174" SortOrder="3">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://blogs.worldbank.org</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Blog</Header>
                <Paragraph>The World Bank posts items by featured bloggers on its website.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="996" SortOrder="4">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/careers</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Career Opportunities</Header>
                <Paragraph>The WBG typically hires people with strong academic backgrounds, a broad understanding of development issues, and international work experience. In more than 170 countries, it employees professionals who specialize in economics, education, engineering, finance, public health,  and many other fields. About 40 percent of World Bank staff members work in more than 110 developing countries.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="8009" SortOrder="5">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/gasflaringreduction/about</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Climate Change</Header>
                <Paragraph>GAS FLARING—The World Bank's Global Gas Flaring Reduction Partnership is a multidonor trust fund whose purpose is to end routine gas flaring at oil production sites around the world. Participating in the partnership are governments, multilateral organizations, and oil companies.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2745" SortOrder="6">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.climateinvestmentfunds.org/</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>INVESTMENT FUNDS—Since the inception of this climate finance mechanism, donor countries have contributed over 8 billion dollars in support of scaling up mitigation and adaptation action in developing and middle-income countries. The World Bank holds these public resources in trust and disburses them as grants, concessional loans, and risk mitigation instruments to recipient countries through multilateral development banks.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2742" SortOrder="7">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2018/03/19/meet-the-human-faces-of-climate-migration</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>MIGRATION—The World Bank report "Groundswell: Preparing for Internal Climate Migration" (2018) found that by midcentury the adverse effects of climate change in three densely populated regions of the world could force more than 140 million people to relocate within their respective countries. Concerted action, including global reductions in greenhouse gas emissions and development planning, could reduce internal migration by as much as 80 percent.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2747" SortOrder="8">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/contacts</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Contact Information</Header>
                <Paragraph>General information for contacting the World Bank is available on its website.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2176" SortOrder="9">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/country</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Countries / Regions</Header>
                <Paragraph>The "Where We Work" web page allows visitors to browse WGB locations by region or country group.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2171" SortOrder="10">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://data.worldbank.org</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Data</Header>
                <Paragraph>The World Bank's website allows free and open access to global development data.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2179" SortOrder="11">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://microdata.worldbank.org/index.php/home</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>The microdata library facilitates access to data collected through sample surveys of households, business establishments, and other facilities. These sets of microdata may also be derived from agricultural, housing, or population censuses or through an administrative data collection processes. The Library also contains supporting documentation from censuses and surveys that the World Bank and other international organizations, statistical agencies, and other agencies in low and middle-income countries conducted or supported.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2178" SortOrder="12">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/business-enabling-environment</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Enabling Business</Header>
                <Paragraph>The World Bank Group is formulating a new approach to assessing the business and investment climate in economies around the world.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="8010" SortOrder="13">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/speech/2022/04/19/remarks-by-world-bank-group-president-david-malpass-to-the-u-s-treasury-s-event-on-tackling-food-insecurity-the-challeng</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Food Security</Header>
                <Paragraph>On April 19, 2022, at an event that the U.S. Department of the Treasury hosted, WBG President David R. Malpass delivered remarks on “Tackling Food Insecurity: The Challenge and Call To Action." His remarks included the following paragraph: "We see a deepening of the crisis in the following numbers: The World Bank food price index reached an all-time high, rising 11.5 percent in March, a year-on-year increase of 37 percent. Fertilizer prices also surged in March, up nearly 20 percent since January. The cost of urea has tripled since January 2021. We also see a shift in relative prices, with food prices going up more than CPI. Projections show this trend continuing."</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2757" SortOrder="14">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/history</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>History</Header>
                <Paragraph>Founded in 1944, and not long thereafter referred to as the World Bank, the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) expanded to become a group of five development institutions. In the aftermath of World War II, IBRD loans helped countries overcome the devastation and rebuild. Over time, the Bank's focus shifted from reconstruction to development, particularly to development of infrastructure: dams, electrical grids, irrigation systems, and roads. To learn more about the inception and growth of the World Bank, visit the "History" web page.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2173" SortOrder="15">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/archives</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>The "World Bank Group Archives" website supports the institutional memory of the World Bank Group and provides access to records of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the International Development Association. The website also features online historical resources and information products: exhibits on the Archives' collection and World Bank history, General International Standard Archival Description (ISAD(G)) finding aids, and transcripts of oral history interviews.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2177" SortOrder="16">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://library.worldbankimflib.org/en/about-us.html</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Libraries</Header>
                <Paragraph>The Library Network is a group of libraries and resource centers that support the work of the World Bank Group (WBG) and International Monetary Fund (IMF). The libraries are located in Washington, DC; however, their services extend to resident missions and country offices.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2172" SortOrder="17">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/news</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>News</Header>
                <Paragraph>The World Bank posts press releases and other newsworthy items on its website.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2182" SortOrder="18">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://olc.worldbank.org</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Open Learning Campus</Header>
                <Paragraph>The Open Learning Campus offers educational opportunities that allow diverse audiences to learn at their own pace. It helps prepare people seeking to address the tough development challenges of the 21st century.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2743" SortOrder="19">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://pubdocs.worldbank.org/en/404071412346998230/wbg-org-chart.pdf</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Organizational Chart</Header>
                <Paragraph>The World Bank posts its organizational chart in Portable Document Format (PDF) for viewing and downloading.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2746" SortOrder="20">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/partners</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Partnerships</Header>
                <Paragraph>The World Bank participates in global partnerships. Visit the "Partners" web page to learn about some of them.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2175" SortOrder="21">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/news/multimedia?multimedia_class_exact=Audio&amp;qterm=&amp;lang_exact=English</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Podcasts</Header>
                <Paragraph>The World Bank's "All Multimedia" web page allows visitors to access a trove of podcasts on diverse topics: climate change, energy development, food, indigenous communities, immigration and forced displacement, pollution, sanitation, sustainability, tourism and more.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2749" SortOrder="22">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://pip.worldbank.org/home</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Poverty / Inequality</Header>
                <Paragraph>The "Poverty and Inequality Platform" is a website that allows visitors to access the World Bank Group's most recent data on inequality, poverty, and shared prosperity.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2180" SortOrder="23">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://projects.worldbank.org</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Projects</Header>
                <Paragraph>The "Projects and Operations" web page allows visitors to browse or search for projects by country or area, sector, or theme.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="997" SortOrder="24">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/reference</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Publications / Research</Header>
                <Paragraph>The "Open Knowledge Repository" allows users to browse and search for thousands of publications.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2185" SortOrder="25">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.facebook.com/worldbank</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Social Media</Header>
                <Paragraph>FACEBOOK—The World Bank has an account.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2184" SortOrder="26">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://twitter.com/worldbank</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>TWITTER—The World Bank tweets announcements and other newsworthy items.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2186" SortOrder="27">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.youtube.com/WorldBank</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>YOUTUBE—The World Bank posts videos on its channel.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2183" SortOrder="28">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email>speakersbureau@worldbank.org</Email>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.worldbank.org/en/about/speakers-bureau</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Speaker's Bureau</Header>
                <Paragraph>The Speaker's Bureau serves as the official liaison between the World Bank Group and its visitors, who include business leaders, governmental representatives, students and teachers, youth organizations, and other professionals.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="8011" SortOrder="29">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer>The Sources of Information were updated 5–2022.</Footer>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph/>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
        </SourceOfInformationDetails>
        <FooterDetails>
            <Footer/>
            <Email/>
            <WebAddress/>
        </FooterDetails>
        <Childrens/>
    </Entity>
</GovernmentManual>
