<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="govman.xsl"?>
<GovernmentManual>
    <accessId>GOVMAN-2022-12-31-243</accessId>
    <Entity EntityId="243" ParentId="124" SortOrder="8">
        <EntityType>SubEntityLevelOne</EntityType>
        <Category>Executive Branch: Departments</Category>
        <IntroductoryHeader/>
        <IntroductoryParagraph/>
        <AgencyName>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration</AgencyName>
        <Addresses>
            <Address EntityAddressId="161" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Address>1200 New Jersey Avenue SE., Washington, DC 20590</Address>
                <Phone>202-366-9550</Phone>
                <Phone2>888-327-4236</Phone2>
                <Fax/>
            </Address>
        </Addresses>
        <LeaderShipTables>
            <LeaderShipTable EntityLeaderShipTableId="158" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer>The above list of key personnel was updated 9–2021.</Footer>
                    <Footer>[For the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration statement of organization, see the Code of Federal Regulations, Title 49, Part 501]</Footer>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/about-nhtsa/nhtsa-leadership</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <HeaderParagraph/>
                <NameColumnHeader/>
                <ShowFootNote>Yes</ShowFootNote>
                <ShowHeader>Yes</ShowHeader>
                <ShowHeaderParagraph>Yes</ShowHeaderParagraph>
                <ShowNameColumnHeader>Yes</ShowNameColumnHeader>
                <ShowTitleColumnHeader>Yes</ShowTitleColumnHeader>
                <TitleColumnHeader/>
                <LeaderShipTableValues>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="2481" SortOrder="1">
                        <NameColumnValue>Steven Cliff, Acting</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>ADMINISTRATOR</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="2482" SortOrder="2">
                        <NameColumnValue>(vacancy)</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Deputy Administrator</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="4446" SortOrder="3">
                        <NameColumnValue>Jack Danielson</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Executive Director</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                </LeaderShipTableValues>
            </LeaderShipTable>
        </LeaderShipTables>
        <MissionStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </MissionStatement>
        <OrganizationChart/>
        <LegalAuthority>
            <Heading/>
        </LegalAuthority>
        <OrganizationStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </OrganizationStatement>
        <ProgramAndActivities>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="145" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName/>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="244" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading/>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="355">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration
                                        (NHTSA) was established by the Highway Safety Act of 1970
                                        (23 U.S.C. 401 note) to reduce the number of deaths,
                                        injuries, and economic losses resulting from motor vehicle
                                        crashes on the Nation's highways.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="356">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The Administration administers motor vehicle and
                                        related equipment safety performance programs;
                                        co-administers the State and community highway safety
                                        program; regulates the Corporate Average Fuel Economy
                                        program; issues Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards
                                        (FMVSS) that prescribe safety features and levels of
                                        safety-related performance for vehicles and vehicular
                                        equipment; rates the safety of passenger vehicles in the New
                                        Car Assessment Program; monitors and participates in
                                        international vehicle safety forums to harmonize the FMVSS
                                        where appropriate; investigates and prosecutes odometer
                                        fraud; administers the National Driver Register Program;
                                        conducts studies and operates programs to reduce economic
                                        losses in motor vehicle crashes and repairs; performs
                                        studies, conducts demonstration projects, and issues
                                        regulations requiring manufacturers to provide motor vehicle
                                        consumer information; promotes programs to reduce impaired
                                        driving, to reduce risky driver behaviors, and to increase
                                        seat belt use; and issues theft prevention standards for
                                        passenger motor vehicles.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="146" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName>Activities</ProgramName>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="246" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading>Research and Program Development</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="357">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/Research</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The Administration helps develop motor vehicle and
                                        highway safety program standards. It analyzes data and
                                        researches, develops, tests, and evaluates motor vehicles,
                                        motor vehicle equipment, and advanced technologies, and it
                                        collects and analyzes crash data. NHTSA activities are broad
                                        in scope with respect to safety: The Administration
                                        encourages industry to adopt advanced motor vehicle safety
                                        designs, increases public awareness of safety issues, and
                                        provides a base for vehicle safety information.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="247" SortOrder="2">
                    <Heading>Regional Operations and Program Delivery</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="358">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/highway-safety-grants-program</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The NHTSA administers State highway safety grant
                                        programs that the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient
                                        Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users authorized.
                                        The Highway Safety formula grant program provides funds to
                                        States, Indian nations, and the territories each year to
                                        support safety programs, particularly in the following
                                        priority areas: data and traffic records, emergency medical
                                        services, impaired driving, motorcycle safety, occupant
                                        protection, pedestrian and bicycle safety, police traffic
                                        services, roadway safety, and speed control. Incentive
                                        grants are also used to encourage States to implement
                                        effective data improvement, impaired driving, motorcycle
                                        safety, and occupant protection programs.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="248" SortOrder="3">
                    <Heading>Rulemaking</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="359">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/laws-regulations</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The Administration issues FMVSS that prescribe safety
                                        features and levels of safety-related performance for
                                        vehicles and vehicular equipment. The Administration
                                        participates in the United Nations World Forum for the
                                        Harmonization of Vehicle Regulations (WP.29). It also
                                        oversees the New Car Assessment Program and the Government's
                                        Five Star Safety Rating Program, which evaluates the safety
                                        performance of light trucks, passenger cars, vans, and child
                                        seats (https://www.nhtsa.gov/ratings). These evaluations are
                                        highly publicized—star ratings must be visible on the price
                                        labels of new vehicles. The Administration also educates
                                        consumers on topics such as driving while distracted, as
                                        well as the proper use of vehicle safety features and child
                                        restraint seats. To promote fuel economy, it manages a
                                        program establishing and revising fleet average fuel economy
                                        standards for passenger car and light truck manufacturers
                                        (https://www.nhtsa.gov/laws-regulations/corporate-average-fuel-economy).
                                        The Administration also runs an antitheft program. Under
                                        this program the NHTSA issues rules requiring that certain
                                        passenger motor vehicles meet parts-marking requirements,
                                        and it calculates and publishes annual motor vehicle theft
                                        rates.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="2538">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph/>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="250" SortOrder="4">
                    <Heading>Enforcement</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="360">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/recalls</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The Administration's Office of Enforcement assures
                                        that all new vehicles sold in the U.S. meet applicable
                                        FMVSS. Under its compliance program, the Office conducts
                                        random tests and collects consumer complaints to identify
                                        and investigate problems with motor vehicles and vehicular
                                        equipment. If a vehicle or equipment suffers from a
                                        safety-related defect or does not meet all applicable FMVSS,
                                        the Office seeks a recall, which requires manufacturers to
                                        notify owners and to remedy the defect free of charge. The
                                        Office monitors recalls to ensure that owners are notified
                                        in a timely manner and that the scope of the recall and the
                                        remedy are adequate. The Office also assures that all motor
                                        vehicles subject to the Corporate Average Fuel Economy
                                        (CAFE) regulations meet their respective targets, and it
                                        enforces violations of Federal odometer fraud regulations by
                                        criminally prosecuting offenders.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="251" SortOrder="5">
                    <Heading>National Center for Statistics and Analysis</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="361">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/research-data/national-center-statistics-and-analysis-ncsa</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The NHTSA maintains a collection of scientific and
                                        technical information on motor vehicle safety. It also
                                        operates the National Center for Statistics and Analysis,
                                        whose activities include the development and maintenance of
                                        national highway-crash data collection systems and related
                                        statistical and economic analyses. The public and the
                                        private sector and universities and Federal, State, and
                                        local agencies rely on these motor vehicle safety
                                        information resources for documentation.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="253" SortOrder="6">
                    <Heading>Communications and Consumer Information</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="362">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.trafficsafetymarketing.gov/ciot</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The Office of Communications and Consumer Information
                                        develops, directs, and implements communication strategies
                                        based on NHTSA policy and programs, including campaigns to
                                        support high visibility enforcement efforts. It promotes
                                        safety messages for NHTSA vehicle-related issues. The Office
                                        also manages NHTSA Web sites and the toll-free Vehicle
                                        Safety Hotline. Information received from calls to the
                                        hotline forms the basis of investigations, which can lead to
                                        recalls if safety-related defects are
                                        identified.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
        </ProgramAndActivities>
        <SourceOfInformationDetails>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1919" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.safercar.gov/parents/CarSeats/Car-Seat-Glossary-of-Terms.htm?view=full</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Car Seats</Header>
                <Paragraph>A car seat glossary is available on the Parents Central Web site.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1920" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.safercar.gov/cpsApp/crs/index.htm</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>The car seat finder is an online tool that uses date of birth, height, and weight to find a car seat type that properly fits a child.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="882" SortOrder="3">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/Jobs</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Career Opportunities</Header>
                <Paragraph>Information on job openings is available on the "Jobs at NHTSA" Web page.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2670" SortOrder="4">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://bestplacestowork.org/BPTW/rankings/detail/TD10</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>In 2016, the NHTSA ranked 290th among 305 agency subcomponents in the Partnership for Public Service's Best Places To Work Agency Rankings.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1924" SortOrder="5">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/research-data</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Data</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA posts factsheets, reports, research notes, statistics, and studies on its Web site.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1915" SortOrder="6">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/Driving-Safety</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Driving Safety</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA Web site features a trove of safety information and resources. Disabled, older, and teen drivers, as well as motorcyclists and others can find Web pages dedicated to improving their driving habits and addressing their safety needs.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1918" SortOrder="7">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/events</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Events</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA hosts meetings and forums to explore new approaches to highway safety. Information and materials from these event are available online.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1922" SortOrder="8">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/about-nhtsa/foia</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA is required to disclose records that are properly requested in writing by any person. A Government agency may withhold information pursuant to one or more of nine exemptions and three exclusions contained in the FOIA. The act applies only to Federal agencies and does not give a right of access to records held by Congress, the courts, State or local government agencies, and private entities.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1923" SortOrder="9">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/about-nhtsa/electronic-reading-room</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA maintains an electronic reading room. Before submitting a FOIA request, an information seeker should search for the desired document or record in the reading room to determine whether it may be available immediately, without charge. The NHTSA also operates a service center for answering FOIA-related questions. Phone, 202-366-2870.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1926" SortOrder="10">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/About-NHTSA/Press-Releases</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>News</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA posts press releases on its Web site.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1927" SortOrder="11">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/speeches-presentations</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA posts speeches, press events, and testimonies on its Web site.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1925" SortOrder="12">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email>TrafficTech@dot.gov</Email>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/About-NHTSA/Traffic-Techs</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Publications</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA disseminates information on traffic safety programs in "Traffic Techs." The publication, starting with the year 1995, is available online. Staring with the years 2005 and 2006, "Traffic Techs" becomes available in Portable Document Format (PDF).</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1917" SortOrder="13">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.safercar.gov/rs/index.html</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Recalls</Header>
                <Paragraph>The Recalls Spotlight monitors high-profile recalls and provides resources finding and addressing vehicle recalls.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1916" SortOrder="14">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www-odi.nhtsa.dot.gov/owners/SearchSafetyIssues</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA's Web site features a search tool that allows the user to enter a vehicle's identification number (VIN) to learn whether it has been repaired as part of a safety recall in the last 15 years.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="2357" SortOrder="15">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/nhtsa/whatis/regions</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Regional Offices</Header>
                <Paragraph>Contact information for the NHTSA's 10 regional offices is available on the "Regional Offices" Web page.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1928" SortOrder="16">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/Research</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Research</Header>
                <Paragraph>The Office of Vehicle Safety Research strategizes, plans, and implements research programs to reduce crashes, fatalities, and injuries. The NHTSA's Web site contains a trove of information related to these programs.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1914" SortOrder="17">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.safercar.gov/parents/index.htm</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Resources for Parents</Header>
                <Paragraph>The Parents Central Web site features resources to help parents protect their children and educate them on car and road safety and becoming responsible drivers.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1921" SortOrder="18">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nhtsa.gov/Vehicle-Safety</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Vehicle Safety</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NHTSA Web site features a trove of information on and resources for vehicle safety. Topics include defects and recalls, odometer fraud, theft protection, and tires.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="881" SortOrder="19">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>https://www-odi.nhtsa.dot.gov/VehicleComplaint</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <Paragraph>To report suspected safety defects in vehicles, vehicle equipment, and child restraint seats, call the Vehicle Safety Hotline. English- and Spanish-speaking representatives are available on weekdays, excluding Federal holidays. Phone, 888-327-4236. TTY, 800-424-9153.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
        </SourceOfInformationDetails>
        <FooterDetails>
            <Footer>For further information, contact the National Highway Traffic Safety
                        Administration, Office of Communications and Consumer Information, 1200 New
                        Jersey Avenue SE., Washington, DC 20590. Phone, 202-366-9550.</Footer>
            <Email/>
            <WebAddress>https://www.nhtsa.gov/about-nhtsa/contact-us</WebAddress>
        </FooterDetails>
    </Entity>
</GovernmentManual>
