<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes"> 
<name>Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</name>
<abbrev>
ATBCB
</abbrev>
    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-16/pdf/2021-24907.pdf</url>
        <title>USAB.001 - Reasonable Accommodation Records</title>
        <date year="21" month="11 " day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <section id="usab.001" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>.001</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>USAB.001 - Reasonable Accommodation Records.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>U.S. Access Board, 1331 F Street, NW, Suite 1000, Washington, D.C. 20004.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director of Administration, U.S. Access Board, 1331 F Street, NW, Suite 1000, Washington, D.C. 20004.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 301; 29 U.S.C. 791 et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 2000bb et seq.; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 29 CFR 1605, 1614; Executive Order (E.).) 13164 (July 28, 2000); and E.O. 13548 (July 10, 2010).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is intended to support the receipt, review, evaluation of requests made to the Access Board for reasonable accommodations (regardless of type of accommodation), the outcome of such requests, and the implementation of approved accommodations. Additionally, this record system is also intended to track and report the processing of requests for USAB-wide reasonable accommodations to comply with applicable laws and regulations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals covered by this system include prospective, current, and former Access Board employees (including, but not limited to, full-time and part-time employees, temporary hires, interns, and co-op students.) who have requested reasonable accommodations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Name and employment information of current or prospective employee needing an accommodation; requester's name and contact information (if different than the employee who needs an accommodation); date request was initiated; information concerning the nature of the disability or religious belief, practice, or observance and the need for accommodation, including appropriate medical or other documentation; occupational series; pay grade; essential duties of the position; details of the accommodation request, such as: type of accommodation requested, how the requested accommodation would assist in job or allow job performance while accommodating the disability or religious belief, practice, or observance; the sources of technical assistance consulted in trying to identify alternative reasonable accommodation; any additional information provided by the requester relating to the processing of the request; whether the request was approved or denied; whether the accommodation was approved for a trial period; and, documentation between the employee and his/her supervisor(s) regarding the accommodation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; individual making the request (if different than the subject individuals); medical and equal employment opportunity professionals; and the subject individuals' supervisor(s).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, disclosures outside the agency may be made as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>1.  Law Enforcement – In the event that a system of records maintained by the Access Board to carry out its functions indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records may be disclosed to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
                <p>2.  Disclosure When Requesting Information – A record from this system of records may be disclosed to a federal, state, or local agency or to another public or private source maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, if and to the extent necessary to obtain information relevant to an Access Board decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, personnel security (e.g., suitability/fitness determinations), or the letting of a contract.</p>
                <p>3.  Disclosure of Existence of Record Information – With the approval of the Access Board Executive Director, the Director of Administration (or his or her designee), the fact that this system of records includes information relevant to a federal agency’s decision in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, personnel security (e.g., suitability, fitness determinations), retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit may be disclosed to that federal agency.</p>
                <p>4.  Disclosure in Litigation – A record from this system of records may be disclosed in a proceeding before a court or other adjudicative body in which the Access Board, an employee of the Access Board in his or her official capacity, or an employee of the Access Board in his or her individual capacity if the Access Board (or the Department of Justice ("DOJ")) has agreed to represent him or her is a party, or the United States or any other federal agency is a party and the Access Board determines that it has an interest in the proceeding, if the Access Board determines that the record is relevant to the proceeding and that the use is compatible with the purpose for which the Access Board collected the information.</p>
                <p>5.  Disclosure to the Department of Justice in Litigation – When the Access Board, an employee of the Access Board in his or her official capacity, or an employee of the Access Board in his or her individual capacity whom the Access Board has agreed to represent is a party to a proceeding before a court or other adjudicative body, or the United States or any other federal agency is a party and the Access Board determines that it has an interest in the proceeding, a record from this system of records may be disclosed to the DOJ if the Access Board is consulting with the DOJ regarding the proceeding or has decided that the DOJ will represent the Access Board, or its interest, in the proceeding and the Access Board determines that the record is relevant to the proceeding and that the use is compatible with the purpose for which the Access Board collected the information.</p>
                <p>6.  Congressional Inquiries – A record from this system of records may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p>7.  Disclosure in Response to a Federal Data Breach – A record from this system of records may be disclosed to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) the Access Board suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the Access Board as determined that, as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach, there is a risk of harm to individuals, the Board (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with Access Board efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>8.  Contractors, Experts, and Consultants – To contractors, experts, consultants, and the agents of thereof, and others performing or working on a contract, service, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the Access Board when necessary to accomplish an agency function. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to Access Board employees.</p>
                <p>9.  Records Management – To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>10. Gathering Information – To any source from which information is requested in the course of processing a grievance, investigation, arbitration, or other litigation, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p>11. Disclosure to a Federal Agency – To disclose information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, issuing a security clearance, conducting a security or suitability investigation of an individual, or classifying jobs, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>12.  Assistance to Federal Agencies and Entities – To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the Access Board determines that information from this system is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in: (a) Responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (b) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, program, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>13.  Medical Providers – To physicians or other medical professionals to provide them with, or obtain from them, the necessary medical documentation and/or certification for reasonable accommodations.</p>
                <p>14.  Decisions Concerning Reasonable Accommodation – A record in this system of records may be disclosed, but only to the extent necessary, to individuals involved in processing a request for reasonable accommodation or in providing any accommodation granted, including medical professionals; agency counsel; individuals consulted outside of the Access Board, such as employees of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission or other federal agencies concerning the Access Board’s legal obligations; and vendors of assistive technology or other devices needed as accommodations.</p>
                <p>15.  Alternative Dispute Resolution – To appropriate third-parties contracted by the Access Board to facilitate mediation or other alternative dispute resolution procedures or programs.</p>
                <p>16.  Medical Emergency – To medical personnel to meet a bona fide medical emergency.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system consist of electronic and/or hard-copy (paper) records.  Paper files are maintained in locked file cabinets.  Electronic records are maintained in restricted access folders on the Access Board’s internal, cloud-based General Support System (GSS), which is Fed-RAMP compliant.  Access is limited to the system owner(s) and other agency personnel who have an official need for access to perform their duties (e.g., IT administrators, agency litigation counsel).  Access Board policy requires new employees to read and acknowledge the rules of behavior applicable to all agency information technology systems (including appropriate protection and handling of personally identifiable information) before getting access to these systems and complete annual cybersecurity awareness training.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                >
                <p>Records are retrievable by a variety of fields including, but not limited to, the individual’s name, date of request, and nature of accommodation request.  Records are typically retrieved by requester name.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Electronic and paper records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA)’s General Records Schedule 2.3, Employee Relations Records, Item ## 020 (administrative program files) and 021 (employee case files), which prescribes a three-year retention period.  For administrative program files, the retention period dates from file supersession.  For employee case files the retention period dates from either employee separation from the agency or conclusion of any appeals, whichever is later.  When eligible for destruction, electronic records are securely destroyed or erased using methods prescribed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology.  Hard-copy records are permanently destroyed by shredding or burning.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Access to system records is restricted to authorized Access Board personnel who are system owners or have an official need to access such records to perform their duties.  Electronic records are stored in restricted-access folders on the Access Board’s internal, cloud-based GSS.  Access to electronic records is controlled by technical safeguards through assignment of system roles and permissions, secure log-ins, time-out features, firewalls, and cybersecurity monitoring systems.  Access Board policy also requires all emails, email strings, and attachments that contain sensitive personally identifiable information to be protected by encryption or password protection before transmission, absent express waiver from an agency privacy officer.  Paper records are maintained in locked file cabinets with access limited to those personnel whose official duties require access.  When paper records containing personally identifiable information are photocopied, faxed, or scanned, care is taken to ensure that no copies are left unattended where they could be viewed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking access to, or notification of, any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may inquire in writing in accordance with instructions appearing in the Access Board's Privacy Act Implementation rule, 36 CFR part 1121, which also appear on the Access Board’s website at www.access-board.gov/privacy.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Record Access Procedures," above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Record Access Procedures," above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="atbcb1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Payroll Records-Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board></subsection>

<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>General Services Administration (GSA), National Payroll Center, Kansas City, Kansas; copies held by the Board. (GSA holds records for the ATBCB under contract.)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees and public members of the Board.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Varied payroll records, including, among other documents, time and attendance cards; payment vouchers; comprehensive listing of employees; health benefits records; requests for deductions; tax forms; W-2 forms; overtime request; leave data; retirement records. Records are used by the Board and GSA employees to maintain adequate payroll information for the Board employees, and otherwise by the Board and GSA employees who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>31 U.S.C. "Money and Finance" , generally.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>See appendix. Records also are disclosed to GAO for audits; to the Internal Revenue Service for investigation; and to private attorneys, pursuant to a power of attorney.</p><p>A copy of an employee's Department of the Treasury Form W-2, Wage and Tax Statement, also is disclosed to the State, city, or other local jurisdiction which is authorized to tax the employee's compensation. The record will be provided in accordance with a withholding agreement between the State, city or other local jurisdiction and the Department of the Treasury pursuant ot 5 U.S.C. 5516, 5517, or 5520, or, in the absence thereof, in response to a written request from an appropriate official of the taxing jurisdiction to the Executive Director, ATBCB, 330 C Street, SW, Room 1010, Washington, DC 20202. The request must include a copy of the applicable statute or ordinance authorizing the taxation of compensation and should indicate whether the authority of the jurisdiction to tax the employee is based on place of residence, place of employment, or both.</p><p>Pursuant to a withholding agreement between a city and the Department of the Treasury (5 U.S.C. 5520), copies of executed city tax withholding certificates shall be furnished to the city in response to written request from an appropriate city official to the Executive Director.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
  <xhtmlContent>
      <p></p>
  <p>Storage:</p><p>Paper and microfilm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Social Security number.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Stored in guarded building; released only to authorized personnel, including among others, GSA liaison staff and finance personnel; and the Board administrative staff.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Disposition of records shall be in accordance with the HB GSA Records Maintenance and Disposition System (OAD P 1820.2).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Director, ATBCB, 330 C Street, SW, Room 1010, Washington, DC 20202.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
  <p>The subject individual; the Board.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="atbcb2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> General Financial Records--Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board.</subsection>

<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>GSA, National Capital Region; copies held by the Board. (GSA holds records for the ATBCB under contract.)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees of the Board.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>SF-1038, Application and account for advance of funds; vendor register and vendor payment tape. Information is used by accounting technicians to maintain adequate financial information and by other officers and employees of GSA and the Board who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>31 U.S.C. "Money and Finance" , generally.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>See Appendix. Records also are released to GAO for audits; to the IRS for investigation; and to private attorneys, pursuant to power of attorney.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper and tape.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Manual and automated by name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Stored in guarded building; released only to authorized personnel including among others, GSA liaison staff, finance personnel and the Board administrative staff.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Disposition of records shall be in accordance with the HB GSA Records Maintenance and Disposition.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Director, ATBCB, 330 C Street, SW, Room 1010, Washington, DC 20202.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
  <p>The subject individual; the Board.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
    <section id="atbcb3"
             toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>3</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName"> General Unofficial Personnel Files--Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board.</subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>ATBCB offices.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Biographic information; correspondence with members of the Board; personnel actions; position descriptions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Title 5, U.S.C. "Government Organization and Employees,"  generally.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See appendix.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>Paper.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Manual.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Stored in lockable file cabinets, released only to authorized personnel, including among others, GSA liaison staff and the Board administrative staff.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Retained until no longer needed, then discarded.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Executive Director, ATBCB, 330 C Street, SW, Room 1010, Washington, DC 20202.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The subject individual; the Board.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

   <section id="atbcb4" toc="yes">
       <systemNumber>4</systemNumber>
       <subsection type="systemName"> Mailing List--Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board.</subsection>
       <subsection type="systemLocation">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>ATBCB offices and the Fairfax Computer Center, Fairfax.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Architect or designer; Health Care; Transportation; Consumer, self help, or social service; Federal government; Private organization or firm, professional association; College, university, or trade school; Trade association; Media; Legal profession; Contractor or engineer; Manufacturer or industry; State/local government; Library; Veterans organization; Congress; Voluntary standard/code group.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="systemLocation">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Same as above.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>29 U.S.C. 792.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Bimonthly newsletter (all categories), technical bulletins (varying categories), publications (varying categories), announcements (varying categories). The purpose of these mailings is to inform the general public and/or specific groups of Board activities.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Storage:</p>
               <p>Magnetic tape.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="retrievability">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Category, last name, zip code.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="safeguards">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Information can only be retrieved from the system by authorized personnel.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Ongoing process of changes, deletions and additions to list.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="systemManager">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Executive Director, ATBCB, 300 C Street, SW, Room 1010, Washington, DC 230202.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Contact Executive Director or refer to the Board access regulations contained in 36 CFR part 1121.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
       <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
           <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Same as mentioned previously.</p>
           </xhtmlContent>
       </subsection>
   </section>
<appendix id="appa" toc="yes" >
   <title>Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</title>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>1. In the event that a system of records maintained by this agency to carry out its functions indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigation or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a "routine use"  to a Federal, state or local agency maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit.</p>
<p>3. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to a Federal Agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision in the matter.</p>
<p>4. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the United States Office of Personnel Management in accordance with the agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
<p>5. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to officers and employees of a Federal agency for purposes of audit.</p>
<p>6. A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to a member of Congress or to a congressional staff member in response to an inquiry of the congressional office made at the request of the individual about whom the record is maintained.</p>
<p>7. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to officers and employees of the GSA in connection with administrative services provided to the ATBCB under agreement with GSA.</p>
<p>8. In the event the Board deems it desirable or necessary, in determining whether particular records are required to be disclosed under the Freedom of Information Act, disclosure may be made to the Department of Justice for the purpose of obtaining its advice.</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>


<regulations id="reg1" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="36">
<heading> Parks, Forests, and Public Property</heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XI">
<heading> Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</heading>
<regulationsPart number=" 1121">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT IMPLEMENTATION</heading>
<xhtmlContent>

<p>Sec.
</p><p>1121.1 Purpose and scope.
</p><p>1121.2 Definitions.
</p><p>1121.3 Procedures for requests pertaining to individuals' records in a records system.
</p><p>1121.4 Times, places, and requirements for the identification of the individual making a request.
</p><p>1121.5 Access to requested information to the individual.
</p><p>1121.6 Request for correction or amendment to the record.
</p><p>1121.7 Agency review of request for correction or amendment of the record.
</p><p>1121.8 Appeal of an initial adverse agency detemination on correction or amendment of the record.
</p><p>1121.9 Notification of dispute.
</p><p>1121.10 Disclosure of record to a person other than the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p><p>1121.11 Accounting of disclosures.
</p><p>1121.12 Fees.
</p><p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a; Pub. L. 93-579.
</p><p><b>Source:</b> 50 FR 3905, Jan. 29, 1985, unless otherwise noted.</p><p>
       <b>&#167; 1121.1
            Purpose and scope. </b></p>
<p>The purposes of these regulations are to:
</p><p>(a) Establish a procedure by which an individual can determine if the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board, hereafter known as the Board or ATBCB, maintains a system of records which includes a record pertaining to the individual; and
</p><p>(b) Establish a procedure by which an individual can gain access to a record pertaining to him or her for the purpose of review, amendment and/or correction.</p>
<p>
   <b>&#167; 1121.2
        Definitions.</b>
</p>
<p>For the purpose of these regulations--
</p><p>(a) The term individual means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
</p><p>(b) The term maintain includes maintain, collect, use or disseminate.
</p><p>(c) The term record means any item, collection or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by the Board, including, but not limited to, his or her employment history, payroll information, and financial transactions and that contains his or her name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as social security number.
</p><p>(d) The term system of records means a group of any records under control of the Board from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p><p>(e) The term routine use means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p><p>(f) The term authorized representative means a person who acts on an individual's behalf for purposes of these regulations, pursuant to written, signed instructions from the individual.</p>
<p>
   <b>&#167; 1121.3
        Procedures for requests pertaining to individuals' records in a records system.
   </b>
</p>
<p>An individual or authorized representative shall submit a written request to the Administrative Officer to determine if a system of records named by the individual contains a record pertaining to the individual. The individual or authorized representative shall submit a written request to the Executive Director of the ATBCB which states the individual's desire to review his or her record.</p>
<p>
   <b>&#167; 1121.4
        Times, places, and requirements for the identification of the individual making a request.
   </b>
</p>
<p>An individual or authorized representative making a request to the Administrative Officer of the ATBCB pursuant to &#167; 1121.3 shall present the request at the ATBCB offices, 330 C Street, SW., Room 1010, Washington, DC 20202, on any business day between the hours of 9 a.m. and 5:30 p.m. The individual or authorized representative submitting the request should present himself or herself at the ATBCB's offices with a form of identification which will permit the ATBCB to verify that the individual is the same individual as contained in the record requested. An authorized representative shall present a written document authorizing access. The document must be signed by the individual.</p>
<p>
   <b>&#167; 1121.5
        Access to requested information to the individual.
   </b>
</p>
<p>Upon verification of identity the Board shall disclose to the individual or authorized representative the information contained in the record which pertains to that individual. Nothing in this section shall allow an individual access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.</p>
<p>
   <b>&#167; 1121.6
        Request for correction or amendment to the record.
   </b>
</p>
<p>The individual or authorized representative should submit a request to the Administrative Officer which states the individual's desire to correct or to amend his or her record. This request is to be made in accord with provisions of &#167; 1121.4.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1121.7
 Agency review of request for correction or amendment of the record.</b>
</p>
<p>Within ten working days of the receipt of the request to correct or to amend the record, the Administrative Officer will acknowledge in writing such receipt and promptly either--
</p><p>(a) Make any correction or amendment of any portion thereof which the individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete; or
</p><p>(b) Inform the individual or authorized representative of his or her refusal to correct or to amend the record in accordance with the request, the reason for the refusal and the procedures established by the Board for the individual to request a review of that refusal.</p>
<p>
   <b>&#167; 1121.8
        Appeal of an initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment of the record.
   </b>
</p>
<p>An individual who disagrees with the refusal of the Administrative Officer to correct or to amend his or her record may submit a request for a review of such refusal to the Executive Director, ATBCB, 330 C Street, SW., Room 1010, Washington, DC 20202. The Executive Director will, not later than thirty (30) working days from the date on which the individual requests such review, complete such review and make final determination, unless, for good cause shown, the Executive Director extends such thirty-day period. If, after his or her review, the Executive Director also refuses to correct or to amend the record in accordance with the request, the Board shall permit the individual or authorized representative to file with the Executive Director a concise statement setting forth the reasons for his or her disagreement with the refusal of the Executive Director and shall notify the individual or authorized representative that he or she may seek judicial review of the Executive Director's determination under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1)(A).</p>
<p>
   <b>&#167; 1121.9
        Notification of dispute.
   </b>
</p>
<p>In any disclosure pursuant to &#167; 1121.10 containing information about which the individual has previously filed a statement of disagreement under &#167; 1121.8, the Board shall clearly note any portion of the record which is disputed and provide copies of the statement and, if the Executive Director deems it appropriate, copies of a concise statement of the reasons of the Executive Director for not making the amendments requested.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1121.10
 Disclosure of record to a person other than the individual to whom the record pertains.
</b></p>
<p>The Board will not disclose a record to any individual or agency other than the individual to whom the record pertains, except to an authorized representative, unless the disclosure has been listed as a "routine use" in the Board's notices of its systems of records, or falls within one of the special disclosure situations listed in the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)).</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1121.11
 Accounting of disclosures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Board shall, except for disclosure made under sections (b)(1) and (b)(2) of the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a) keep an accurate accounting of--
</p><p>(1) The date, nature and purpose of each disclosure of a record to any person or another agency made pursuant to &#167; 1121.10; and
</p><p>(2) The name and address of the person or agency to whom the disclosure is made.
</p><p>(b) This accounting shall be retained for at least five years or the life of the record, whichever is longer, after the disclosure for which the accounting is made;
</p><p>(c) The Board shall make this accounting available to the individual named in the record at his or her request, except for disclosures made under section (b)(7) of the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a).
</p><p>(d) The Board shall inform any person or other agency to whom disclosure has been made pursuant to &#167; 1121.10 about any correction or notation of dispute made by the Board.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1121.12
 Fees.
</b></p>
   <p>If an individual or authorized representative requests copies of his or her record, he or she shall be charged ten cents per page, excluding the cost of any search for review of the record, in advance of receipt of the pages.
   
   
   </p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
