<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
    <agency toc="yes">
        <name>Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service</name>
        <abbrev>FMCS</abbrev>
        <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
            <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
        </previousPubs>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-10-26/pdf/2020-23651.pdf</url>
            <title>FMCS-1-FOIA/PA</title>
            <date year="20" month="10" day="26" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-08-19/pdf/2021-17807.pdf</url>
            <title>FMCS-0003</title>
            <date year="21" month="8" day="19" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-09-21/pdf/2021-20352.pdf</url>
            <title>FMCS-0004</title>
            <date year="21" month="9" day="21" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-10-27/pdf/2021-23408.pdf</url>
            <title>FMCS-0005 Religious Accommodation System</title>
            <date year="21" month="10" day="27" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-10-27/pdf/2021-23409.pdf</url>
            <title>FMCS-0006 Ethics Records</title>
            <date year="21" month="10" day="27" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-23/pdf/2021-25488.pdf</url>
            <title>FMCS-0005 Reasonable Accommodation System</title>
            <date year="21" month="11" day="23" />
        </previouslyPublished>
        <section id="fmcs1" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>1</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName"> FMCS-1-FOIA/PA</subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Unclassified. </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 250 E Street, SW, Washington, DC 20427; AINS 806 W. Diamond Avenue Gaithersburg, MD 20878.
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        Sarah Cudahy, General Counsel, FMCS 250 E Street, SW, Washington, DC 20427.
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 29 U.S.C. 172, et seq.; Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552; The Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a; 5 U.S.C. 301.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of processing access requests and administrative appeals under the FOIA (including system access records for requesters and staff), and access and amendment requests and appeals  under the Privacy Act; corresponding with the Office of Information Policy (OIP) in the Department of Justice regarding federal agency compliance with the FOIA; and for the purpose of assisting FMCS in carrying out any other responsibilities under the FOIA and the Privacy Act.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals filing requests for access to information under the FOIA and Privacy Act, maintaining an account through which to file FOIA requests and appeals, and FMCS staff assigned to help process, consider, and respond to such requests, including any appeals.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  The system consists of records created or compiled in response to FOIA and Privacy Act requests and appeals, including: the original requests and administrative appeals; responses to such requests and administrative appeals; all related memoranda, correspondence, notes, other supporting documentation, and system access records for both requesters and FMCS staff (usernames and passwords). Information collected and maintained about individuals includes name, contact information, phone numbers, email addresses, and mailing addresses. Records may contain information about people named in them. This system also consists of records related to inquiries submitted to OIP regarding federal agency compliance with the FOIA, and all records related to the resolution of such inquiries. </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals about whom the record is maintained, and agency staff assigned to help process, review, or respond to the access request, including any appeal. Records pertaining to accessing the FOIA processing system will also be included in this records system</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        (a)	To a federal, state, or local agency or entity for the purpose of consulting with that agency or entity to enable FMCS to make a determination as to access to or correction of information; for the purpose of verifying the identity of an individual or the accuracy of information submitted by an individual who has requested access to or amendment of information.
                        (b)	To a federal agency or entity that furnished the record or information for the purpose of permitting that agency or entity to make a decision as to access or correction of the record or information, or to a federal agency or entity for purposes of providing guidance or advice regarding the handling of particular requests.
                        (c)	To a submitter or subject of a record or information in order to obtain assistance to FMCS in making a determination as to access or amendment.
                        (d)	To the National Archives and Records Administration for the purpose of adjudicating an appeal from an FMCS denial or a request.
                        (e)	To appropriate agencies for the purpose of resolving an inquiry regarding FMCS compliance with the FOIA.
                        (f)	To the National Archives and Records Administration, Office of Government Information Services (OGIS), to the extent necessary to fulfill responsibilities under 5 U.S.C. 552(h) to review administrative policies, procedures, and compliance with the FOIA, and to facilitate OGIS’ offering of mediation services to resolve disputes between persons making FOIA requests and administrative agencies.
                        (g)	To contractors, experts, consultants, and others performing or working on a contract service agreement, or other assignments for the federal government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.
                        (h)	To a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member’s behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.
                        (i)	To any component of the Department of Justice for the purpose of representing FMCS, or its components, officers, employees, or members in pending or potential litigation to which the record is pertinent.
                        (j)	In an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative body, when FMC determines the records are relevant to the proceeding; or in an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.
                        (k)	To the news media and the public, unless it is determined that the release of specific information in the context of the particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of privacy.
                        (l)	To such recipients and under such circumstances and procedures as are mandated by federal statute or regulation.
                        (m)	To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the Commission suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records,· (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the Commission (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
                        (n)	To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the Commission determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to Individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            	<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  Records are maintained electronically using a commercial software application run on the agency’s internal servers and shared drives run on the agency’s internal servers. Hardcopy records are maintained in a locked file cabinet that require two badged access points.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Indexed by name of requesting party and subject matter of request. Records can also be searched by name, address, phone number, fax number, and email of the requesting party, subject matter of the request, requestor organization, FOIA number, and staff members assigned to the request.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            	<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 4.2, issued by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            	<subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Access to nonpublic system records is restricted to FMCS personnel or contractors whose responsibilities require access. Nonpublic paper records are temporary, maintained in lockable file cabinets or offices, and destroyed once the request and appeal process is complete. Access to electronic records is controlled by a ‘‘user ID’’ and password combination and other electronic access or network controls (e.g., firewalls). FMCS buildings are guarded and monitored by security personnel, cameras, ID checks, and other physical security measures.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> See 29 CFR 1410.3 - Individual access requests. Requests can be submitted via the fmcs.gov website, via email to privacy@fmcs.gov or via mail at Chief Privacy Officer at FMCS 250 E Street SW Washington, D.C. 20427. </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            	<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  See 29 CFR 1410.6 Appeals from denials of requests can be submitted via email to privacy@fmcs.gov or via mail at Chief Privacy Officer at FMCS.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            	<subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> See 29 CFR 1410.3(a), et seq.  Individuals who desire to know whether the agency maintains a system of records pertaining to them by submitting a written request to the Chief Privacy Officer at privacy@fmcs.gov or Chief Privacy Officer, FMCS 250 E Street, SW Washington, D.C. 20427. </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            	<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> None. </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="fmcs0003" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>3</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">FMCS-0003</subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Unclassified.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 250 E Street, SW, Washington, DC 20427.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Greg Raelson, Director of Congressional and Public Affairs, email graelson@fmcs.gov, or send mail to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 250 E Street Southwest, Washington, DC 20427, Attn: Greg Raelson.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 29 U.S.C. § 172, et seq.; Departmental Regulations, 5 U.S.C. § 301.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The purposes of the system are as follows:</p>
                    (a)	<p>The records are used for internal and external communications, and to provide the public with contact information and biographies of the employees who carry out FMCS’s mission and activities.</p>
                    (b)	<p>To digitize FMCS photographic files in support of preserving the materials.</p>
                    (c)	<p>To be used for reproduction by FMCS employees organizing such events as awards, ceremonies, farewell ceremonies and receptions, FMCS anniversary ceremonies and receptions, conferences, workshops, speaking engagements, and FMCS training and education programs.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>All current and former FMCS employees, clients, visitors from other agencies, and members of the public.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>These records consist of digital photographs, digitized images of photographic prints, negatives, and slides, and indexing data including name, geographical district, biographies, business title, business email, business cell phone and office number, business office address, business address of events, and dates of events.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Photographs and biographical information are provided by FMCS employees on an ongoing basis.  Donors include FMCS employees, FMCS clients, and visitors from the public or other agencies.  Other records such as contact information are obtained from FMCS records.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the Agency as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                    (a)	<p>As communication material at conferences, trainings, and speaking engagements where FMCS employees participate in their official capacity to demonstrate the experience and background of FMCS employees.</p>
                    (b)	<p>To current and prospective FMCS clients including other federal agencies to provide background information on individuals for public knowledge and awareness.</p>
                    (c)	<p>To a Congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the Congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                    (d)	<p>To respond to subpoenas in any litigation or other proceeding.</p>
                    (e)	<p>For distribution and presentation for news, public relations, official agency social media, community affairs, and client services purposes.</p>
                    (f)	<p>In support of research activities conducted by FMCS employees and other agencies.</p>
                    (g)	<p>To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) FMCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records, (2) FMCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, FMCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with FMCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    (h)	<p>To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when FMCS determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are stored electronically on the public facing website located here.  Also, records are stored on FMCS’s shared and internal hard drives and on the FMCS’s Microsoft Office 365 SharePoint site both accessible only to FMCS employees.  Hard copies of photographs are also displayed in FMCS’s offices.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records on the public facing website can be searched by name, geographic district, and zip code.  Records on the FMCS’s shared and internal drives can be searched by name, and date and name of the event.  On SharePoint, records can be searched by the date and name of the event.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are updated as needed and retained until no longer needed for business use.  All records are retained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 6.4, issued by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Electronic records on FMCS’s shared and internal drives, and on SharePoint are safeguarded in a secured environment and are maintained in a secure, password-protected electronic system that will utilize commensurate safeguards that may include firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention systems, and role-based access controls.  Hard copy records are accessed in FMCS facilities that are limited to authorized personnel with official duties requiring access.  FMCS facilities are equipped with security cameras and 24-hour security guard service.  These records are kept in limited access areas in locked offices.  All records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, operational, and technical safeguards.  These safeguards include restricting access to authorized personnel who have a "need to know", using locks, and password protection identification features.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Same as above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See 29 CFR § 1410.6, Requests for correction or amendment of records, on how to contest the content of any records.  Privacy Act requests to amend or correct records may be submitted to the Chief Privacy Officer at privacy@fmcs.gov or Chief Privacy Officer, FMCS 250 E Street, SW Washington, D.C. 20427.  Also, see https://www.fmcs.gov/privacy-policy/.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See 29 CFR § 1410.3(a), Individual access requests.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="fmcs4" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>4</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">
                <p>FMCS-0004.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Unclassified.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 250 E Street, SW, Washington, DC 20427.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Doug Jones, Director of Information Technology, email djones@fmcs.gov, or send mail to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 250 E Street Southwest, Washington, DC 20427, Attn: Doug Jones.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 29 U.S.C. 172, et seq.; The Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a; The National Labor Relations Act, 29 U.S.C. § 151, et seq.; Administrative Dispute Resolution Act, 5 U.S.C. §§ 571-584; Negotiated Rulemaking Act of 1990, 5 U.S.C.  561-570.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The case records management system is maintained for the purposes of processing records of notices, recording modification/termination of collective bargaining agreements, and/or existence of certain disputes sent by unions and employers under the National Labor Relations Act, as well as recording other activities for such purposes. SharePoint is maintained for the purposes of processing, monitoring, approving, modifying/canceling, signing, and closing agreements with other federal agencies. Microsoft Outlook is used to store party communications requesting and scheduling mediations and trainings. Cloud-based systems such as Zoom.gov and Microsoft Teams are used to record meetings and trainings. The Agency’s internal drives are also maintained for the purpose of processing Freedom of Information requests.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Encompasses all individuals, and parties, receiving mediation, training, or any other external FMCS services.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>These records consist of notices, agreements, case status information, and data regarding parties to mediations and trainings. This data includes name, title, business address, business email, cell phone number, business telephone and fax numbers, and IP address.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Parties to labor agreements/disputes, mediations, or those requesting training submit notices and requests. Agencies requesting services submit agreements, and FMCS personnel and official representatives receive case and agreement information.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The files in this system are used to process, track, review, and evaluate requests for mediation, training, and other alternate dispute resolution services, and to respond to Freedom of Information Act requests. Data from this system may be used for training, presentation, and research purposes. The files from this system will also be used in the preparation of internal agency reports, the agency’s budget requests, and reports to Congress.</p>
                    <p>1) Requests for mediation or training completed by parties to include the Agency Form F-7, available on www.fmcs.gov. Contact information for parties requesting services. These documents are used to assign FMCS employees to cases, to respond to Freedom of Information Act requests, and to inform FMCS clients and parties of FMCS-sponsored events, trainings, conferences, and announcements.</p>
                    <p>2)  Processing documents sent to or from parties to a mediation: Agency confirmation letters sent to parties assigning mediators to cases or trainings, mediation agreements, FMCS terms and conditions, ethics waivers pertaining to specific cases, strike notices, picket notices, notice of intent to strike, and reports and invoices regarding mediations and training.</p>
                    <p>3) Internal processing documents: checklists of steps needed during the life of cases, correspondence with parties, and status updates for mediation cases. These documents are used to assess case progress, FMCS employee activity, and personnel needs. These documents produce summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies, and data for management information. These statistics and studies are used for related personnel management functions, other federal agency studies, congressional reports, budget reports, and workforce assessments.</p>
                    <p>4) These documents or information contained therein may be sent to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) FMCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records, (2) FMCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, FMCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with FMCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>5) These documents or information contained therein may be sent to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when FMCS determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The case records management system will store records electronically using a commercial software application run on the Customer Relationship Management (CRM) platform, Microsoft Dynamics, which require a username and password. SharePoint is used to store the IAAs, which requires a username and password. Temporary paper files, notices received through mail, are destroyed once they are scanned into the agency’s internal drives which also require a username and password. Communications regarding mediations and trainings are stored in accordance with the Agency’s record retention schedule in Microsoft Outlook. Meetings and trainings that are recorded via Zoom.gov are stored in the Cloud on ZoomGov servers requiring a username and password. Meetings recorded in Microsoft Teams are stored on the FMCS employee’s OneDrive which requires a username and password. Third-party recording of meetings or trainings on FMCS platforms is not permitted.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Mediation case records are indexed by name of party, type of notice, case number, case type, date, and assigned mediator or geographic region. Mediation case records can also be searched by name, address, phone number, fax number, and email of a party on the case records management system. On SharePoint, case records are indexed by form name and number, agency and office that need services, type of service, assigned FMCS personnel, expiration date of service, service amount, and status.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are stored in the system for seven years from the date the case is closed, plus the current year. Records older than this will be archived and sent to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA). Records on the agency’s internal drives are stored for seven years and then destroyed. On SharePoint, records are stored temporarily until business uses cease and then records are destroyed. All records are retained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 1.1 and 4.2, issued by NARA.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Case records and agreements are accessible to restricted FMCS personnel or contractors who require access. Access to these electronic records occurs through a web browser to the Internet or on the agency’s internal drives both requiring a username and password for login. FMCS buildings are guarded and monitored by security personnel, cameras, ID checks, and other physical security measures.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Members of the public seeking access to FMCS records would need to submit a Freedom of Information Act request via the Agency’s public website portal, https://palfmcs.efoia-host.com/. FMCS personnel must login to the agency’s network and database using agency credentials to access these records.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See 29 CFR 1410.6, Requests for correction or amendment of records, on how to contest the content of any records. Privacy Act requests to amend or correct records may be submitted to the Chief Privacy Officer at privacy@fmcs.gov or Chief Privacy Officer, FMCS 250 E Street, SW Washington, DC 20427. Also, see https://www.fmcs.gov/privacy-policy/.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See 29 CFR 1410.3(a), Individual access requests.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="fmcs5" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>0005</systemNumber>
               <subsection type="systemName">
                    <p>FMCS-0005 Reasonable Accommodation System.</p>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="securityClassification">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Unclassified.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="systemLocation">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, Office of General Counsel (OGC), 250 E Street, SW, Washington, DC 20427.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="systemManager">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Angie Titcombe, Director of Human Resources, and Natalie Samuels, Benefits and Retirement Specialist.  Doug Jones, Director of Information Technology, will not access content in the internal folder, will only troubleshoot any technical issues regarding electronic files. Send mail to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, 250 E Street Southwest, Washington, DC 20427.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>29 U.S.C. 172, et seq.; Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42 U.S.C. 2000e, et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 12101; The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 U.S.C. 701, 791, 794; E.O. 13164, as amended by E.O. 13478; E.O. 13548; E.O. 14043; 29 C.F.R. part 1605; 29 C.F.R. part 1614; 29 C.F.R. part 1615; 29 C.F.R. part 1630.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="purpose">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>The purpose of this system is to provide a system for collecting, processing, and maintaining religious and medical accommodation requests on applicants for employment, employees, and other individuals who participate in FMCS programs or activities who request or receive reasonable accommodations or other appropriate modifications from FMCS for medical or religious reasons; to process, evaluate, and make decisions on individual requests; details of request, including final determinations, and any supporting documentation; and to track and report the processing of such requests in FMCS to comply with applicable requirements in law and policy.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>The categories of individuals covered in the system of records includes both current and former Federal employees who have requested religious and medical accommodations, applicants for employment, and other individuals who participate in FMCS programs or activities who request or receive reasonable accommodations or other appropriate modifications from FMCS for medical or religious reasons.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>These records contain the following:</p>
                        <p>●Requester’s name;</p>
                        <p>●Requester’s status (applicant or employee);</p>
                        <p>●Requester’s contact information (addresses, phone numbers, and email addresses);</p>
                        <p>●Date of the request;</p>
                        <p>●Employee’s position title, grade, series, step;</p>
                        <p>●Description of religious belief and how it will impact the ability to comply with agency requirements and perform official duties;</p>
                        <p>●Description of the medical condition or disability and any medical documentation provided in support of the request;</p>
                        <p>●Supplemental medical records or medical certification documents in support of the request or determination;</p>
                        <p>●Description of the accommodation being requested;</p>
                        <p>●Description of previous requests for accommodation;</p>
                        <p>●Whether the request was granted or denied, and if denied the reason for the denial;</p>
                        <p>●Documentation of how the request was made;</p>
                        <p>●Documentation of any extenuating circumstances that prevent FMCS from meeting relevant timeframes;</p>
                        <p>●The sources of technical assistance consulted in trying to identify a possible reasonable accommodation;</p>
                        <p>●Any reports or evaluations prepared in determining whether to grant or deny the request; and</p>
                        <p>●Any other information collected or developed in connection with the request for a reasonable accommodation.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Information in this system of records is provided by:</p>
                        <p>1. The Federal employee, applicant, or other individual submitting an accommodation form.</p>
                        <p>2. FMCS Human Resources officials who provide confirmation approval or denial of requests.</p>
                        <p>3. Supervisors who provide information regarding how the requests would impact agency operations.</p>
                        <p>4. Medical providers or professionals who evaluate the request or who provide supplemental or supporting documentation.</p>
                        <p>5. Religious or spiritual advisors or institutions who evaluate the request or who provide supplemental or supporting documentation.</p>
                        <p>Additional record source categories could include documents pertaining to the employee’s religion and religious practices, and medical requests.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed to authorized entities, as is determined to be relevant and necessary, outside the FMCS as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                        <p>a. To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule regulation or order where FMCS becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal laws or regulations.</p>
                        <p>b. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for use in its records management inspections; to the Government Accountability Office (GAO) for oversight purposes; to the Department of Justice (DOJ) to obtain that department’s advice regarding disclosure obligations under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA); or to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to obtain that office’s advice regarding obligations under the Privacy Act.</p>
                        <p>c. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) or the General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                        <p>d. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, detailees, and other non-Government employees performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the Federal Government when necessary to accompany an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                        <p>e. To officials of labor organizations recognized under 5 U.S.C. Chapter 71 upon receipt of a formal request and in accordance with the conditions of 5 U.S.C. 7114 when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting working conditions.</p>
                        <p>f. To disclose information to a Member of Congress or a congressional office in response to an inquiry made on behalf of, and at the request of, an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                        <p>g. To disclose information when FMCS determines that the records are relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                        <p>h. To disclose information to another Federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.  Such disclosure is permitted only when it is relevant and necessary to the litigation or proceeding.</p>
                        <p>i. To any agency, organization, or person for the purposes of performing audit or oversight operations related to the operation of this system of records as authorized by law, but only information necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                        <p>j. To disclose information to a spiritual leader, religious scholar, medical professional, or medical provider when necessary to obtain information relevant to the request.</p>
                        <p>k. To another Federal agency, including but not limited to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and the Office of Special Counsel to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements related to reasonable accommodation.</p>
                        <p>l. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engages in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who requested a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modification.</p>
                        <p>m. To a Federal agency, FMCS personnel, or entity authorized to procure assistive technologies and services in response to a request for reasonable accommodation.</p>
                        <p>n. To FMCS clients needing to accommodate FMCS employees performing official duties.</p>
                        <p>o. To first aid and safety personnel if the individual’s medical condition requires emergency treatment.</p>
                        <p>p. To another Federal agency pursuant to a written agreement with FMCS to provide services (such as medical evaluations), when necessary, in support of reasonable accommodation decisions.</p>
                        <p>q. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) FMCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records, (2) FMCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, FMCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with FMCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                        <p>r. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when FMCS determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>These records are maintained in hard copy and electronic form in locations only accessible to authorized personnel. Electronic records are stored on the agency’s internal servers with restricted access to authorized Human Resources staff and designated deciding officials as determined by agency policy.  Hard copy records are stored in a locked cabinet accessible to authorized Human Resources staff and designated deciding officials as determined by agency policy.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retrievability">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to an individual in the electronic database and paper filing system.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>All records are retained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 2.3, issued by the National Archives and Records Administration. Records are updated as needed, retained for three years after separation and/or for the entirety of the employee’s active employment, and destroyed by shredding or deleting.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="safeguards">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records are located in a locked file storage area or stored electronically in locations only accessible to authorized personnel requiring agency security credentials. Access is restricted, and accessible to limited Human Resources officials, and/or individuals in a need-to-know capacity.  FMCS buildings are guarded and monitored by security personnel, cameras, ID checks, and other physical security measures.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>If an employee would like access to their Religious or Medical Accommodation Form, please send a request with the specific information needed to the resource mailbox at FMCSMedicalInfo@fmcs.gov.  A copy of the requested information will be provided via email in an encrypted file.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>See 29 CFR 1410.6, Requests for correction or amendment of records, on how to contest the content of any records. Privacy Act requests to amend or correct records may be submitted to the Privacy Office at privacy@fmcs.gov, FMCS 250 E Street, SW Washington, DC 20427. Also, see https://www.fmcs.gov/privacy-policy/.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>See 29 CFR 1410.3(a), Individual access requests.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>None.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="history">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>This amended SORN deletes and supersedes the SORN published in Federal Register on October 27, 2021, at 86 FR 59389.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="fmcs6" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>0006</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">
                <p> Ethics Records.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        Unclassified.
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, Office of General Counsel (OGC), 250 E Street, SW, Washington, DC 20427.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Sarah Cudahy, Designated Agency Ethics Official and Deputy General Counsel, email scudahy@fmcs.gov, or send mail to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, Office of General Counsel (OGC), 250 E Street Southwest, Washington, DC 20427, Attn: Sarah Cudahy.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>5 U.S.C. app. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); E.O. 12674 (as modified by E.O. 12731); 5 C.F.R. part 2634.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>These records are collected and maintained to meet the requirements of Executive Order 12674, as modified, 5 CFR part 2634, and subsequent agency regulations, as well as section 107 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, as amended, concerning the filing of confidential financial disclosure reports. Confidential financial disclosure reports are required to assure compliance with ethics laws and regulations, and to determine if an actual or apparent conflict of interest or impartiality issue exists between the employment of individuals by the Federal Government and their outside employment financial interests.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Officers and employees in the executive branch whose positions have been designated as confidential financial disclosure filing positions or alternative financial disclosure filers in accordance with 5 C.F.R. 2634.904 and 5 U.S.C. app. 107. In addition, all executive branch special Government Employees (SGE) as defined in 18 U.S.C. 202(a) and 5 C.F.R. 2634.105(s) are required to file unless they are required to file public financial disclosure reports, or their positions have been excluded from filing. The system of records includes both current and former Federal employees in these categories.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>These records contain statements and amended statements of personal and family holdings and other interests in property, income, gifts, reimbursements, liabilities, agreements, arrangements, outside positions, retirement products, pensions, and other information related to conflict-of-interest determinations. These statements include completed copies of the Office of General Ethics (OGE) Form 450 and alternate 450 forms and supplemental agency ethics documents.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Information in this system of records is provided by:</p>
                    1.	<p>The Federal employee or a designated person such as a trustee, accountant, banker or relative.</p>
                    2.	<p>Federal officials who review the statements to make conflict-of-interest determinations.</p>
                    3.	<p>Persons alleging conflicts of interest or other violations of ethics laws and persons contacted during any investigation of the allegations.</p>
                    4.	<p>FMCS clients who complete notice documents in the waiver process.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    a)	<p>To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule regulation or order where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal laws or regulations.</p>
                    b)	<p>To disclose information to any source when necessary to obtain information relevant to a conflict-of-interest investigation or determination.</p>
                    c)	<p>To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) or the General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    d)	<p>To disclose information to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.</p>
                    e)	<p>To disclose information when the disclosing agency determines that the records are relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                    f)	<p>To disclose the confidential financial disclosure report or certificate of no new interest and any accompanying documents to reviewing officials in a new office, department or agency when an employee transfers or is detailed from a covered position in one office, department or agency to a covered position in another office, department, or agency.</p>
                    g)	<p>To disclose information to a Member of Congress or a congressional office in response to an inquiry made on behalf of, and at the request of, an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                    h)	<p>To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, detailees, and other non-Government employees performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the Federal Government when necessary to accompany an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                    i)	<p>To disclose the existence of a potential or actual impartiality concern to an Agency party or client to resolve a concern under 5 CFR 2635.502.</p>
                    j)	<p>To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) The agency maintaining the records suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the agency maintaining the records has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>These records are maintained in paper and electronic form in locations only accessible to authorized personnel.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to an individual.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In accordance with the NARA’s General Records Schedule (GRS) 2.8 Employee Ethics Records, these records are retained for six years after filing, except when filed by or with respect to a nominee and the nominee ceases to be under consideration for the position. If any records are needed in an ongoing investigation, they will be retained for the duration of the investigation. Records are destroyed by shredding or deleting.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        Records are located in a locked file storage area or stored electronically in locations requiring agency network access via username and password. FMCS buildings are guarded and monitored by security personnel, cameras, ID checks, and other physical security measures.
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should contact the Office of General Counsel (OGC). Individuals must provide the following information for their records to be located and identified: (1) Full name, (2) Dates of employment, and (3) A specific description of the record content requested. Individuals requesting access to records maintained at the Office of Government Ethics OGE) must also follow OGE’s Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and access to records (5 C.F.R. part 2606).</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are updated on a periodic basis; most record corrections can be handled through established administrative procedures. Contact the Office of General Counsel (OGC) for contesting records under the provisions of the Privacy Act.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See 29 CFR § 1410.3(a), Individual access requests.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>


    </agency>
    </pai>
