<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Peace Corps</name>
<abbrev>
PC</abbrev>

    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-19/pdf/2021-25327.pdf </url>
        <title> Reasonable Accommodation Requests, PC-37</title>
        <date year="21" month="11 " day=" 19" />
    </previouslyPublished>


    <routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
		  <xhtmlContent><p><b>Notice of Systems of Records Preliminary Statement</b></p>


<p>The term "Agency" when used in this notice refers to the Peace Corps.

</p><p>Operating Units--The names of the operating units within the Agency to which a particular system of
records pertains are listed under the system manager and address section of each system notice.

</p><p>Official Personnel Files--Official personnel files of Federal employees in the General Schedule in the
custody of the Agency are considered the property of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM). Access to such
files shall be in accordance with such notices as are published by OPM. Access to such files in the custody
of
the Agency will be granted to individuals to whom such files pertain upon request to the Director, Office of
Personnel Management, Peace Corps, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20526.

</p><p>Files of employees serving under Peace Corps appointing authorities, i.e., Foreign Service and
Expert/consultant, which are not specifically covered by the OPM publication, are inter-filed with all other
personnel files and treated in the same manner. The OPM publication of notice for official personnel files is
therefore adopted by reference for Peace Corps personnel files in the custody of the Agency provided however
that
access, contests and appeals as to any such record shall be processed as provided in Peace Corps regulations
under the Privacy Act.

</p><p>Various offices in the Agency maintain files which contain miscellaneous copies of personnel material
affecting Peace Corps employees. This would include copies of standard personnel forms, evaluation forms,
etc.
These files are kept only for immediate office reference use and are considered by the Agency to be part of
the
personnel file system. The Agency's internal regulations provide that such information is a part of the
general
personnel files and can only be disclosed through the Director, Peace Corps Office of Personnel Management in
order that he or she may insure that any material to be disclosed is relevant, materials, current, and fair
to
the individual employee. It is also the policy of the Agency to limit the use of such files and to encourage
the
destruction of as many as possible.

</p><p><b>Statement of General Routine Uses</b></p>
<p>The following general routine uses are incorporated by this reference into each system of records set
forth herein, unless such incorporation is specifically limited in the system description.</p>

<p>A. <i>Disclosure for Law Enforcement Purposes.</i> Information may be disclosed to the appropriate
Federal, State, local, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or
implementing a
statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information indicates a violation or potential violation of civil
or
criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.
</p><p>B. <i>Disclosure Incident to Requesting Information.</i> Information may be disclosed to any source
from which additional information is requested (to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform
the
source of the purpose(s) of the request, or to identify the type of information requested); when necessary to
obtain information relevant to a Peace Corps decision concerning retention of an employee or other personnel
action (other than hiring), retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or
retention of a grant or other benefit. </p>
<p>C.  <i>Disclosure to Requesting Agency. </i> Information may be disclosed to a Federal, State, local, or
other
public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the requesting
agency's
retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance
or
retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a
request supported by the written consent of the individual for part or all of the record if it so chooses. No
disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a
referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil,
administrative,
personnel, or regulatory action.
</p><p>D.  <i>Disclosure to Office of Management and Budget. </i> Information may be disclosed to the Office
of
Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with
private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.  </p>
<p>E. <i>Disclosure to Congressional Offices. </i> Information may be disclosed to a congressional office
from
the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of
the
individual.</p>
<p>F.  <i>Disclosure to Department of Justice. </i> Information may be disclosed for purposes of
litigation,
provided that in each case the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were
collected.
Disclosure for these purposes may be made to the Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court,
adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Peace Corps is authorized to appear. This
disclosure may be made when: 1. The Peace Corps, or any component thereof; 2. Any employee of the Peace Corps
in
his or her official capacity; 3. Any employee of the Peace Corps in his or her individual capacity where the
Department of Justice or the Peace Corps has agreed to represent the employee; or 4. The United States (when
the
Peace Corps determines that litigation is likely to affect the Peace Corps or any of its components) is a
party
to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice
or
the Peace Corps is deemed by the Peace Corps to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.
</p><p>G. <i>Disclosure to the National Archives. </i> Information may be disclosed to the National Archives
and
Records Administration in records management inspections.  </p>
<p>H.  <i>Disclosure to Contractors, Grantees, and Others. </i> Information may be disclosed to contractors,
grantees, consultants, or Volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative
agreement,
job, or other activity for the Peace Corps and who have a need to have access to the information in the
performance of their duties or activities for the Peace Corps. When appropriate, recipients will be required
to
comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974 as provided in 5 U.S.C. 552a(m).  </p>
<p>I. <i>Disclosures for Administrative Claims, Complaints, and Appeals. </i> Information may be disclosed to
an
authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator,
arbitrator, or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance,
complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee, but only to the extent that the information is relevant and
necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not
limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board,
Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p>
<p>J. <i>Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management. </i> Information may be disclosed to the Office of
Personnel Management pursuant to that agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal
personnel
management. </p>
<p>K. <i>Disclosure in Connection with Litigation. </i> Information may be disclosed in connection with
litigation or settlement discussions regarding claims by or against the Peace Corps, including public filing
with
a court, to the extent that disclosure of the information is relevant and necessary to the litigation or
discussions and except where court orders are otherwise required under Section (b)(11) of the Privacy Act of
1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(11).  </p>
<p>L. <i>Disclosure to U.S. Ambassadors. </i> Information from this system of records may be disclosed to a
U.S.
Ambassador or his or her designee in a country where the Peace Corps serves when the information is needed to
perform an official responsibility, to allow the Ambassador to knowledgeably respond to official inquiries
and
deal with in-country situations that are within the scope of the Ambassador's responsibility. </p>

<p>M. To all appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) The Peace Corps suspects or has confirmed
that
the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Peace
Corps
has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic
or
property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other
systems
or programs (whether maintained by the Peace Corps or another agency or entity) that rely upon the
compromised
information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to
assist in connection with the Peace Corps' efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and
prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p><b>Location of Domestic and Overseas Offices</b></p>
<p>The Agency maintains three Service Centers and Area Recruiting Offices in which certain systems or parts
of
systems are maintained. The Service Centers, their addresses, and the States within their jurisdictions are
listed below. In the event of any doubt as to whether a record is maintained in a Service Center or Area
Recuiting Office, a query may be directed to the Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps,
Washington, DC 20526, who shall furnish all assistance necessary to locate a specific record.

</p><p>New York Service Center, Peace Corps, 26 Federal Plaza, Room 1605, New York, New York 10278 (States
serviced: Massacusetts, Vermont, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, Delaware, New Jersey, Georgia, Tennessee,
Mississippi, Alabama, South Carolina, Florida, District of Columbia, Maryland, North Carolina, Kentucky, West
Virginia and Virginia).

</p><p>Chicago Service Center, Peace Corps, 3rd Floor, 10 W. Jackson, Chicago, Illinois 60604 (States
serviced:
New Mexico, Oklahoma, Louisiana, Texas, Arkansas, Illiniois, Indiana, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Kansas, Missouri,
Iowa, Nebraska, Michigan and Ohio).

</p><p>San Fransciso Service Center, Peace Corps, Room 533, 211 Main Street, San Francisco, California 94105
(States serviced: California, Nevada, Hawaii, Colorado, Montana, South Dakota, North Dakota, Utah, Wyoming,
Washington, Oregon, Idaho, Alaska and Arizona).

</p><p>The Peace Corps has offices overseas and the number fluctuates from time to time as programs are added
or
withdrawn. A complete list with specific addresses will be provided upon request to the Director, Office of
Administrative Services, Peace Corp, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20526. Any particular country
in
which Peace Corps maintains a program may be addressed by writing to the Country Director, c/o the American
Embassy in such country.

</p><p>Notification--Individuals may inquire as to whether any system contains information pertaining to them
by
addressing the System Manager in writing. Such request should include the name and address of the individual,
his
or her social security number, and any relevant data concerning the information sought and, where possible,
the
place of assignment or employment, etc. In case of any doubt as to which system contains a record, interested
individuals may contact the Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, Washington, DC 20526,
who
has overall supervision of records systems and who will provide assistance in locating and/or identifying
appropriate systems.

</p><p>Access and Contest--In response to a written request by an individual, the appropriate System Manager
shall arrange for access to the requested record or advise the requester if no such record exists. If an
individual wishes to contest the content of any record, he/she may do so by addressing a written request to
Director, Administrative Services, Peace Corps, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20526. The
Director
shall provide all necessary information regarding such contest and appeal.

</p></xhtmlContent></routineUses>

<section id="pc1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Accounts Receivable (Collection of Debts Claims Records).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Fiscal Services Division, Office of Financial Services,
Peace
Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any former or current Peace Corps employee,
Volunteer, or other individual erroneously overpaid by the Peace Corps or who has an advance outstanding from
the
Peace Corps.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names and addresses of individuals indebted to Peace
Corps including the date of the debt, claim number, amount of the debt, related correspondence, and a copies
of
checks and the date the debt was paid if payment has occurred
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>31 U.S.C. 3711 et seq.; Pub. L. 104-134; and the
Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p><p>Purpose(s):
</p><p>To record information and resolution of erroneous payments and outstanding advances made by the Peace
Corps (Last revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K,
and L
apply to this system.
</p><p><i>RECORDS MAY ALSO BE DISCLOSED TO:</i></p>
<p>1. The Department of Justice in cases of administrative error involving overpayment or outstanding
advances or
situations in which the Peace Corps has been unable to collect a debt; or
</p><p>2. The Department of Treasury for debt collection.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:</p>
<p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or claim number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept until settlement of a claim and
then
retired to the Federal Records Center to be destroyed in accordance with General Records Schedule 6.1.2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Fiscal Services Division, Office of Financial
Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p><p>NOTIFICATION, ACCESS, AND CONTESTING RECORD PROCEDURES:
</p><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her,
who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps offices making payments or travel
advances.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="pc2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Congressional Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Congressional Relations, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Members of Congress and Peace Corps Volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Bio-data and voting records of Members of Congress,
incoming and outgoing correspondence with Members of Congress; and records regarding concerns of Members of
Congress affecting the Peace Corps.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To track communications with members of Congress and
congressional
concerns affecting the Peace Corps (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>
  General routine uses A, E, F, G, K, and L apply to this system.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, congressional committee, Congress member, or
state.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept on-site for five years, then
retired to
the Federal Center to be stored for ten years and then destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Congressional Relations, Peace Corps, 1111 20th
St.,
NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p><p>NOTIFICATION, ACCESS, and CONTESTING RECORD PROCEDURES:
</p><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her,
who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject, Peace Corps staff, and
publications
such as the Congressional Record, periodicals, and standard reference publications.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Contractors and Consultants Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Center for Field Assistance and Applied Research, Peace
Corps,
1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Contractors or consultants for Peace Corps
programs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondence, resumes, and other materials
pertaining
to personal services contractors or consultants.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To identify and track personal services contractor or consultants
for
Peace Corps program needs (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, J, K,
and L
apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, address, telephone number, social security
number,
salary history, skill categories, performance evaluations, and country to which work pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept on-site for four years after
becoming
inactive and then destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Resource Development Division, Center for Field
Assistance and Applied Research, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p><p>NOTIFICATION, ACCESS, AND CONTESTING RECORD PROCEDURES:
</p><p>To the extent permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system has been
exempted
from the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. The Peace Corps may, in its
discretion, fully grant individual requests for access and correction if it determines that the exercise of
these
rights will not interfere with an interest that the exemption is intended to protect. The exemption from
access
is limited in some instances by law to information that would reveal the identity of a confidential source.
Any
individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants
access
to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the
System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license,
employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in
some
instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective
action
sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject and persons consulted as
references.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>PURSUANT TO 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), THIS SYSTEM IS EXEMPT
FROM
THE FOLLOWING PROVISIONS OF THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974, SUBJECT TO THE LIMITATIONS SET FORTH IN THAT SUBSECTION:
</p><p>U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), and (f ).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Discrimination Complaint Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>American Diversity Program, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St.,
NW,
Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any employee, volunteer, or applicant for
employment
or Volunteer service who has filed a complaint of discrimination against the Peace Corps.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Complaints, copies of personnel records,
investigatory
materials and affidavits, correspondence related to complaints, and information as to how the complaint was
resolved.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>22 U.S.C. 2504(a); 42 U.S.C. 2000e-16; 42 U.S.C.
5057; 29 U.S.C. 206; 29 U.S.C. 633a; 29 U.S.C. 791; 29 U.S.C. 794a; E.O. 11478, and 29 CFR 300 and 1614.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record actions taken on complaints of discrimination against
the
Peace Corps (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K,
and L
apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By employee name and case number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets.
Computer
records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are maintained in secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept until settlement of a claim and
then
retired to the Federal Records Center to be destroyed in accordance with General Records Schedule 6.1.2.
Records
are destroyed four years after the close of the case.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, American Diversity Program, Peace Corps, 1111
20th
St., NW, Washington, DC 20526.
</p><p>NOTIFICATION, ACCESS, AND CONTESTING RECORD PROCEDURES:
</p><p>To the extent permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) and (5), this system has
been
exempted from the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. The Peace Corps
may,
in its discretion, fully grant individual requests for access and correction if it determines that exercise
of
these rights will not interfere with an interest that the exemption is intended to protect. The exemption
from
access is limited in some instances by law to information that would reveal the identity of a confidential
source. Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her,
who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document, Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject, Peace Corps staff and Volunteers,
and
others with information relevant to resolving discrimination complaint.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) and (5), this system is
exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, subject to the limitations set forth in
those
subsections:
</p><p>5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee and Volunteer Occupational Injury and Illness Reports.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Medical Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St.,
NW.,
Washington, DC 20526; in Peace Corps offices in eleven U.S. cities; and in countries with Peace Corps
programs
while the record subject is serving as a volunteer there.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps employees who have job-related
injuries
or illnesses; and Volunteers who have service-related injuries or illnesses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, telephone number, date of birth,
social
security number, FECA, case file number, sex, dates of service, country in which served, reports of
occupational
injuries and illnesses and associated medical reports including x-rays.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>29 U.S.C. 668; 5 U.S.C. 8101 et seq.; and the
Peace
Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record information and resulting actions pertaining to
employee
and Volunteer occupational injuries and illnesses (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J,
K,
and L apply to this system.
</p><p>RECORDS MAY ALSO BE DISCLOSED TO:
</p><p>1. The record subject upon the subject's request;
</p><p>2. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration, Department of Labor, for employment- or service-
related injuries or illnesses; or
</p><p>3. The Office of Workers' Compensation Programs, Department of Labor, for workers' compensation
claims.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, social security number, FECA case file number,
and
country of service.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in a lockable file room. Computer
records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are maintained in secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Workers' compensation records are retained on-site
until
inactive, then retired to the Federal Records Center for 15 years, after which they are destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Medical Services, Peace Corps, 1111
20th
St., NW., Washington, DC 20526; Director, Peace Corps regional offices; and Country Director in countries
with
Peace Corps programs.


</p><p>NOTIFICATION, ACCESS, AND CONTESTING RECORD PROCEDURES:
</p><p>To the extent permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system has been
exempted
from the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. The Peace Corps may, in its
discretion, fully grant individual requests for access and correction if it determines that the exercise of
these
rights will not interfere with an interest that the exemption is intended to protect. The exemption from
access
is limited in some instances by law to information that would reveal the identity of a confidential source.
Any
individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants
access
to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the
System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license,
employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in
some
instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective
action
sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject, Peace Corps supervisors,
physicians
and other health care providers, other medical sources including laboratories, and debt collection agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system is exempt
from
the following provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, subject to the limitations set forth in that subsection:
5
U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Pay and Leave Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resource Management, Peace Corps, 1111
20th
St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel actions, savings bond applications,
allotment
advices, IRS tax levels, notice of deduction for health insurance, Combined Federal Campaign contributions,
union
dues withholdings applications, educational allowances for children of overseas employees, records concerning
collections for overpayments, and time and attendance records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 5525 et seq.; 5 U.S.C. 5501 et seq.; 5
U.S.C. 5701; 5 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.; and 31 U.S.C. 3512.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record moneys paid, allotments authorized, leave earned and
used,
and retirement benefits earned (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J,
K,
and L apply to this system.
</p><p>RECORDS MAY ALSO BE DISCLOSED TO:
</p><p>1. The Treasury Department for the purpose of payroll, savings bonds or other deductions, or effecting
administrative offset against the debtor to recoup a delinquent debt to the U.S. Government by the debtor;
</p><p>2. To the Internal Revenue Service for tax matters;
</p><p>3. To participating insurance companies holding policies with respect to Peace Corps employees; or
</p><p>4. To a Federal agency to perform payroll services for the Peace Corps.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name and social security number (computer data base
only).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets.
Computer
records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are maintained in secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained for three years after
an
employee terminates employment with the Peace Corps and then destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Human Resource Management, Peace Corps,
1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p><p>NOTIFICATION, ACCESS, AND CONTESTING RECORD PROCEDURES:
</p><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her,
who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Peace Corps Volunteers: Reasons for Resignation.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Planning, Policy, and Analysis, Peace Corps,
1111
20th St., NW, Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Peace Corps volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, social security number, codes reflecting the
reasons for resignation as identified by the volunteer and Country Staff, training class, country of service,
projected close of service date, and actual close of service date.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide feedback from Peace Corps volunteers for improving
agency
programs and services. To provide a basis for assessing the record subject's suitability for Peace Corps
staff
employment, employment as a personal services contractor, or volunteer service. (Last revised: August 2000).


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses E, F, H, and K apply to this
system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or identifying number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained until data is entered
into
the computer system; electronic records are maintained for the life of the agency.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Planning, Policy, and Analysis, Peace
Corps, 1111 20th St., NW, Washington, DC 20526.
</p><p>NOTIFICATION, ACCESS AND CONTESTING RECORD PROCEDURES:
</p><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her,
who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedure are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of the General Counsel, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW,
Washington, DC 20526.
</subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps staff, volunteers, and applicants for
employment or volunteer service.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records pertaining to employee administrative and EEO
grievances, wage garnishments, appeals from adverse actions, claims by and against staff members, claims by
and
against volunteers, litigation involving Peace Corps staff or volunteers, and legal queries from staff
members.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To support legal representation of the Peace Corps and to provide
legal counsel to the Director of the Peace Corps, the Director's designees, and Peace Corps staff (Last
Revised:
August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K,
and L apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets.
Computer
records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are maintained in secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are retired to the Federal Records Center
consistent with the Peace Corps Records management Handbook where they are maintained for 30 years and then
destroyed.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager">
<xhtmlContent><p>General Counsel, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">Notification, access, and contesting, record procedures:
<xhtmlContent><p>To the extent permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a (k) (1), (2), and (5),
this
system has been exempted from the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction.
Any
individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants
access
to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the
System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license,
employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in
some
instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective
action
sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject, and correspondence and reports
from
persons and agencies dealing with the Peace Corps.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k) (1), (2), and (5), this
system
is exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, subject to the limitations set forth in
those
subsections: 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Payment Records: Transportation, Travel Authorizations, and Household
Storage.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Fiscal Services Division, Office of Financial Services,
Peace
Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any current or former Peace Corps employee,
volunteer
or other individual traveling for Peace Corps and paid through contract, purchase order, or travel order.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Invoices received, amount paid, payment vouchers and
associated documents, schedule number, contract or purchase order number, type of payment (advance, partial,
or
final), travel authorizations, travel vouchers, receipts, and other materials related to official travel.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 5701 et seq.; 31 U.S.C. 3512; 31 U.S.C.
3901
et seq.; and the Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p><p>Purposes:
</p><p>To record payments made as a result of purchase orders, travel authorizations, or other authorization
documents (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, and
L
apply to this system.
</p><p>Records may also be disclosed to:
</p><p>1. The Department of Treasury for disbursement to vendors and travelers; or
</p><p>2. To a household storage vendor in the event of a discrepancy between the vendor's and Peace Corps'
records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By employee name or schedule number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept until settlement of a claim and
then
retired to the Federal Records Center to be destroyed in accordance with General Records Schedule 6.1.2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"> <xhtmlContent><p>System Manager(s) and
address:
</p><p>Director, Fiscal Services Division, Office of Financial Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this
system of records contains
a record about him or her, who wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a
record, should make a
written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such
as a driver's license,
employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in
some instances. Requests
for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete
Peace Corps Privacy
Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject and Peace Corps authorizing
offices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of Private Sector Initiatives Database.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Not applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Private Sector Initiatives, Peace Corps, 1111
20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals making donations to Peace Corps
partnership projects or inquiring about partnership projects; volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For donors: name, address, telephone number, e-mail
address, donor number, and contribution amount. For volunteers: name, address, and close of service date.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 <i>et
seq</i>.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record and track donations to the Peace Corps and to provide
program and project updates to donors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A through M apply to this
system.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By donor name, donor number, project name or project
number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in a
secure,
access-controlled area.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept until three years after completion
of
project, and then retired to the Federal Records Center to be maintained and destroyed in accordance with
General
Records Schedule 6.1.2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Private Sector Initiative, Peace Corps,
Office of Private Sector Initiatives, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any individual who wants notification that this system of records contains a record about him or her
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants access to his or her
record
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to contest the
contents
of a record should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide
adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must
identify
the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Donor and Peace Corps volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personal Services Contracts.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Contracts, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal services contractors for the Peace
Corps.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>History of service or performance, including earning
records of individuals hired as personal services contractors.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.; and
Federal Acquisition Regulations, 48 CFR Chapters 1-99.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>For determining personal services contractor's eligibility for
employment and pay determinations; for determining accountability and liability of parties under the personal
services contract, and other contract issues (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, K, and
L
apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or contract number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked file cabinets in a
secure
room. Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are
maintained
in secure, access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the system are maintained on site for one
year after the closing date of the contract, then sent to the Federal Records Center where they are
maintained
for three years if the contract amount is $25,000 or less, and for six years and three months if the contract
amount is greater than $25,000, and then destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, Office of Contracts, 1111 20th St., N.W., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>To the extent
permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system has been exempted from the
provisions
of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. However, the Peace Corps may, in its
discretion,
fully grant individual requests for access and correction if it determines that the exercise of these rights
will
not interfere with an interest that the exemption is intended to protect. The exemption from access is
limited in
some instances by law to information that would reveal the identity of a confidential source. Any individual
who
wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to his or
her
record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the System
Manager.
Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license, employee
identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in some
instances.
Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought.
Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject, Peace Corps staff, and outside
sources
used as references for those applying as contractors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system is exempt
from
the following provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, subject to the limitations set forth in that subsection:
</p><p>5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Property Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>At each overseas Peace Corps office and in Administrative
Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, room number, and country of assignment for
Peace Corps staff and volunteers who have physical property assigned to them.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>U.S. Government property assigned to Peace Corps
staff or
volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"> <xhtmlContent>
<p>40 U.S.C. 483(b) and (c); and the Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501, et seq.
</p><p>Purpos(e):
</p><p>To record and account for U.S. Government property assigned to Peace Corps staff and volunteers (Last
Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, and
L
apply to this system. Records may also be discovered to the Department of State or General Services
Administration to account for the disposition of Federal property.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
<xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in computerized databases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, room number, or country.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained at overseas posts for two years
after the Peace Corps staff member or volunteer terminates assignment, then destroyed. Headquarters records
are
retained for five years, then retired to the Federal Records Center and destroyed after 20 years.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>For overseas records, Country Directors in each country in which Peace Corps maintains a program. For
headquarters records, Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW.,
Washington,
DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>
Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants
access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request
to
the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's
license,
employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in
some
instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective
action
sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps staff and volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Some classified information may be included in
this
system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Security Office, Office of Human Resource
Management/Security
Office, Peace corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former applicants for Peace Corps
staff
employment and volunteer service; and individuals considered for access to classified information or
restricted
areas and/or personnel security determinations as contractors and experts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Investigative information regarding an individual's
character, conduct, background, and behavior.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>E.O. 10450; The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501
et
seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record information used to determine eligibility or
suitability
for employment or volunteer service, including eligibility to serve as a Peace Corps contractor. (Last
Revised:
August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J,
K,
and L apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
<xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>On Page and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Available only to employees with appropriate security
clearance
and a need to know. Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. Paper
records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in secure, access-controlled
areas
or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in the Security Office in the
Office of Human Resources for seven years from the date of the last investigative activity and then
destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Personnel Security Staff, Office of Human Resource Management, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St.,
NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>To the extent permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k) (1), (2), and (5), this system has
been exempted from the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. The Peace
Corps
may, in its discretion, fully grant individual requests for access and correction if it determines that the
exercise of these rights will not interfere with an interest that the exemption is intended to protect. The
exemption from access is limited in some instances by law to information that would reveal the identity of a
confidential source. Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about
him
or her, who wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make
a
written request to the System Manager. Requester will be required to provide adequate identification, such as
a
driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying document that includes the requester's
social security number and full signature. Additional information may be required in some instances. Requests
for
correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete
Peace
Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subjects; Federal agencies; employers,
schools,
references, and other sources of information about the record subject.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k) (1), (2), and (5), this
system
is exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, subject to the limitations set forth in
those
subsections: 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(H), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Administrative Grievance Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resource Management, Peace Corps, 1111
20th
St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps staff who have filed an
administrative
grievance or grievance appeal or have filed a complaint with the Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal
Labor
Relations Authority, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, or other organization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Grievance, appeal, and arbitration files containing
petitions, complaints, charges, evidentiary materials, records of hearings or other matters regarding
administrative grievances or arbitration.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. chapters
71-79; and E.O. 11491.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To resolve administrative complaints or grievances (Last Revised:
August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J,
K,
and L apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
<xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or social security number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in Lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retired to the Federal Records Center to
be
maintained and then destroyed 25 years after the close of the case.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Human Resource management, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To the extent permitted under the Privacy
Act
of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system has been exempted
from the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. The Peace Corps may, in its
discretion, fully grant individual requests for access and correction if it determines that the exercise of
these
rights will not interfere with an interest that the exemption is intended to protect. The exemption from
access
is limited in some instances by law to information that would reveal the identity of a confidential source.
Any
individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants
access
to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the
System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license,
employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in
some
instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective
action
sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subjects; witnesses to any occurrences
giving
rise to a grievance, appeal or other action; hearing records and affidavits and other documents used or
usable in
connection with grievance, appeal, and arbitration hearings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system is exempt
from
the following provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, subject to the limitations set forth in that subsection:
5
U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G) (e)(4)(H), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Overseas Executive Selection and Support.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Overseas Executive Selection and Support, Peace Corps,
1111
20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Applicants for Peace Corps Country Director
positions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, telephone number, social security
number,
professional resume, letter of interest, personal essay, and other background information regarding
qualifications for Peace Corps Country Director.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps
Act,
22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To supply qualified applicants for Country Director positions
with
the Peace Corps (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, D, E, F, G, I, J, K, and L
apply
to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
<xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked file cabinets in a
secure
room. Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are
maintained
in secure, access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications not resulting in appointment are
destroyed
after two years. Applications resulting in appointment are forwarded to the Official Personnel Folder
maintained
by Human Resource Management and disposed of in accordance with the record schedule for Official Personnel
Folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Overseas Executive Selection and Support, Peace Corps, 111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC
20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>To the extent
permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system has been exempted
from the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. The Peace Corps may, in its
discretion, fully grant individuals requests for access and correction if it determines that the exercise of
these rights will not interfere with an interest that the exemption is intended to protect. The exemption
from
access is limited in some instances by law to information that would reveal the identity of a confidential
source. Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her,
who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject and personal references.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system is exempt
from
the following provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, subject to the limitations set forth in that subsection:
5
U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Travel Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Transportation Division, Office of Administrative
Services,
Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526, and domestic and overseas field offices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any Peace Corps employee, volunteer, contractor,
or
other individual engaged in authorized official travel for the Peace Corps.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel authorizations; itineraries; Government Bills
of
Lading; packing letters and passport numbers for overseas travel; passports for staff, trainees and
volunteers;
and other travel related material.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 5701 et
seq.; 31 U.S.C. 3512; 31 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.; and the Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et
seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To account for, and issue payments as a result of, authorized
official Peace Corps travel (Last Revised; August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, and K
apply
to this system. Records may also be disclosed to transportation carriers for providing transportation
services.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
<xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or by country.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All
records are maintained in secure, access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at Peace Corps headquarters
and
domestic and overseas field offices for three years after the individual leaves the agency or performs the
travel, and are then destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Transportation Division, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW.,
Washington, DC 20526 and the office heads of Peace Corps' domestic and overseas field offices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who
wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
drivers
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject, supervisors, or other Peace Corps
staff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Volunteer Applicant and Service Records System.

</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>This system is made up of subsystems which are located
agencywide in Peace Corps offices. These locations are (a) Headquarters, (b) three Service Center offices and
area and sub-area Recruitment offices, and (c) each Peace Corps overseas program office. The number of Peace
Corps overseas offices fluctuates as programs are added or withdrawn. Specific addresses will be provided
upon
request to the Director of Administrative Services. Any particular country in which Peace Corps maintains a
program may be addressed by writing to the Country Director, Peace Corps, c/o The American Embassy in the
country.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Peace Corps volunteers,
trainees
and applicants for volunteer service including Peace Corps United Nations Volunteers. A record may exist in a
subsystem depending on whether a record was established as part of the application, selection, placement, and
service process.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This major system covers a number of temporary and
permanent records established during the applicant, selection, placement, training and service stages. Most
information maintained in this system is furnished by the individual. Generally, the individual is aware of
any
necessary investigations being conducted and is either counseled or authorizes such investigations. As the
record
progresses through the subsystems, generally, the following folders may be established: PCV Applicant File;
Medical File; and Trainee/Volunteer Service File. If certain situations warrant, a Special Services file may
be
established. These records are explained in detail in the following paragraphs. At the processing and program
support desk levels temporary day to day sets of records may be used or set up to meet the needs of work
processes. This information is usually extracted from the official record or is a duplicate of information
contained in the official record and is utilized only as long as needed for a particular decision, project or
period of service. Upon completion of the use of such records they are destroyed or, in the case of a
permanent
document or record, are forwarded to the Peace Corps Records Center for retirement.

</p><p>(1) Volunteer Applicant Folder and Computer Based Record: This record contains forms related to the
applicant process such as the application, references, overseas suitability assessments, invitation to
training,
trainee enrollment forms correspondence relating to the application, copies of other application documents,
such
as a Peace Corp background investigation form, evaluator-recruiter interview forms. Information is extracted
from
the official record hard copy to create a computer record which is used to track progress, issue labels for
correspondence to the applicant and account for the establishment, retirement and ultimate destruction of the
individual record. Statistical information, without personal identifiers, is used from the computer record.

</p><p>(2) Trainee and Volunteer Service Pay Folder and Computer based record: This record contains
correspondence, forms related to pay allowances, travel and service such as, the Oath, designation of
beneficiary, address, social security number, duty station, next of kin, trainee registration form, service
and
termination documents. Information is coded from hard copy documents to create a computer record for pay and
verification of service purposes.

</p><p>(3) Medical Folder: The medical record contains medical examination forms and fitness for duty
reports,
medical claims, correspondence and cables, medical histories, payment records, record of the consulting
physician, treatment, hospitalization and disposition of the case, and history of psychiatric or
psychological
treatment.

</p><p>(4) Special Services Folder: This record contains information pertaining to any unusual or
extraordinary
action or circumstances happening during service or causing the termination of the volunteer or trainee.
These
records contain details of reenrollments, reinstatements, death or termination. Details include name, country
of
assignment, program number, dates of the action, and supportive documentation. Supportive documentation would
include termination reports, staff recommendations, cables, financial information, travel arrangements and
medical clearance. Death cases may also include an autopsy report, documentation of account of the death,
designation of beneficiary, policy report, death certificate, correspondence related to final arrangements,
money
payments and other financial matters.

</p><p>(5) Overseas Post Service and Medical Records: Contain correspondence and forms relating to in country
service such as records of all payments or accrued credit to volunteers and trainees, advances or other items
due
to the government from volunteers or trainees, monthly living allowances, leave allowances, settling in
allowances, property assignments. The medical record is maintained at post by the Peace Corps Health
Official. It
contains the entrance physical and dental examination records and record of treatment received while in Peace
Corps.

</p><p>(6) United Nations Volunteer Records: These records contain applications, correspondence related to
the
applicant/placement process, other records connected with the application, training and placement of persons
wishing to serve or serving as United Nations Volunteers. For short periods of time references furnished by
the
applicant in support of the UNV application are kept in the UNV folder until the PC Applicant folder is
received
from the Office of Placement by Multilateral Programs. Then the UNV references, along with the UNV
application,
are forwarded to Geneva/UNV. Medical history forms for UNV applicants are forwarded by the examining facility
to
Peace Corps Office of Medical Services, who, after medical clearance by Peace Corps, forward them to the
Medical
Office, Geneva/UNV At the end of service or inactivation of the record the UNV record is forwarded to the
Peace
Corps Record Center for combining and retirement as regular Peace Corps volunteer records.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq., and
The
Budget and Accounting Act of 1950.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system was established to maintain records of individuals
who
apply for Peace Corps Volunteer service and to record resulting actions taken on the applications and
service.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The contents of these records may be disclosed and
used
as follows:

</p><p>(a) As stated in our general routine uses unless specifically exempted under this heading.

</p><p>(b) To Peace Corps Volunteer host country officials to obtain visas, inform of pending arrival of the
trainee/volunteer and for review of their qualifications for a program.

</p><p>(c) To the trainee/volunteer's family or next of kin so that he or she may be located in case of
emergency.

</p><p>(d) To the Social Security Administration for crediting of social security accounts and reports
withholdings.

</p><p>(e) To the Internal Revenue Service to report on taxes paid and for income purposes.

</p><p>(f) To Federal agencies having a need to verify volunteer eligibility for Federal employment under
provision of Executive Order 11103.

</p><p>(g) To the Treasury Department for purposes of issuing payroll checks, readjustment allowance checks
or to
report overpayments.

</p><p>(h) To appropriate overseas U.S. Government agencies for monthly payroll preparation.

</p><p>(i) To verify active or former volunteer service.

</p><p>(j) Regarding the United Nations Volunteers records: In addition to our general routine uses the
contents
of these records may be disclosed and used as follows: 1. To designated officers and employers of the United
Nations having a responsibility for the selection and placement of U.N. Volunteers. 2. To officials of a
proposed
host country desiring the assignment or placement of U.N. Volunteers.

</p><p>(k) Regarding medical records: Notwithstanding subsections (a) through (j), in addition to our general
routine uses the medical records may be disclosed or used only as follows: 1. To the Office of Workers'
Compensation Programs, U.S. Department of Labor in connection with claims under the Federal Employee's
Compensation Act. 2. To a physician or other medical personnel treating or involved in the medical treatment
and/or care of an applicant, trainee or volunteer and having a need for such records for the provision of the
medical treatment or care. In situations where it is practicable, the individual's consent will be obtained
before releasing such information. 3. To psychiatrists or clinical psychologists when necessary for
treatment. To
the extent practicable disclosure will not be made without approval of the individual. 4. In death cases to
notify designated life and/or personal property insurance companies to obtain payment of insurance benefits;
to
notify the Office of the Vice President for the preparation of condolence letters; to the family and next of
kin;
and Department of State.
</p><p>(l) To any educational institutions with which the Peace Corps has a Fellows/USA or Masters
International
agreement which requires access to Volunteer or Returned Peace Corps Volunteer contact information in order
to
meet the terms of the agreement.
</p><p>(m) To Returned Peace Corps Volunteer organizations furthering the Peace Corps' recruiting or third
goal
activities. The information released will be limited to contact information.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">

<xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Records are maintained in folders, log books, cards, magnetic tape or disc packs with tape backup and
are
filed in metal filing cabinets with manipulation proof combination lock or in a room with a combination lock
in
the door, or in a locked room when not in use.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The majority of the subsystem records are retrievable
alphabetically by the last name. A few are retrievable by the social security number; by subject headings but
access may be gained by reference to an alphabetical name index; or by alphabetical order by country of
assignment.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are generally available only to Peace Corps employees
with
specifically assigned duties which require working with the records on a day to day basis. They are available
to
other Peace Corps employees having the need for such records in the performance of their official duties.
Personnel screening is employed to prevent unauthorized disclosure. Officials or employees having access to
the
security investigation records are required to have an appropriate security clearance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Most volunteer records are kept no longer than seven
years. The Volunteer Personnel and Payroll Computer Record and the Volunteer Description of Service records
are
kept permanently. Medical records are destroyed as follows: (1) Records of rejected applicants are destroyed
after 18 months; (2) records of trainees who do not become volunteers and records of individuals who enroll
as
volunteers are destroyed 25 years from the completion of service or termination date. Applicant records are
destroyed as follows: (1) Immediately rejected applicant records are destroyed in six months; (2) records of
applicants rejected before reporting to training are destroyed in one year; and (3) records of individuals
who
report to training are destroyed seven years from the completion of service or termination date.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>As the record flows from one state to another, or if a
record
is established for a specific purpose, the system manager is the agency official responsible for that
particular
function. People unsure about whom to contact, may contact the Peace Corps' FOIA/Privacy Officer at 1111 20th
St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.

</p><p>(1) The following system managers are located at 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526: Director of
Placement and Staging; Chief of Health Benefits and Analysis Division; Chief of Volunteer and Staff Payroll
Services Branch; Director, Management Information and Assessment Division; Supervisor, Medical Records
Manager in
the Division of Volunteer Support;

</p><p>(2) The following system managers can be contacted at the overseas post of assignment: Peace Corps
Country
Directors Overseas; Peace Corps Medical Officers Overseas.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary Statement above in this notice.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the
Preliminary Statement above in this notice.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Record Access Procedures."

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is obtained from the individual;
sources
whom the individual has named; Peace Corps employees and other volunteer/trainees; medical personnel who have
treated an applicant/trainee/volunteer or reviewed their medical records; medical contractors; U.S.
Government
investigative agencies, including the Office of Personnel Management; The Merit Systems Protection Board and
its
Special Counsel; the Federal Labor Relations Authority; local law enforcement officials; Peace Corps Host
Country
Nationals; Peace Corps Country American Embassy and Consulates, United Nations Staff; and job supervisors.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>These records or portions of these records may be
exempted by
authority of 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(5).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Former Volunteer/Staff Resource Record.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps, Office of Volunteer Recruitment and Selection, 806 Connecticut Avenue NW, Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All former staff and volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual former staff and former volunteer files containing the following information about the particular individual: Name; current address; current phone number; social security number; date of birth; next of kin name and address; pre-service, service, and post-service education; employment and training experience; trade skills; language skills; educational level; teaching experience; current interest in voluntary service; type of volunteer/staff duty assignment; and location of assignment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2501, et seq.).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this file will be used by the Peace Corps agency to involve former staff and volunteers with policy formation, program evaluation, recruitment, foreign and domestic disaster relief, and to keep up-to-date addresses for mailing publications and public affairs releases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Files are maintained on magnetic discs and tapes which are stored in a locked room when not in immediate use in a building with a 24-hour guard.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by categories such as skills, social security number, and alphabetical order.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the system are available only to appropriate officials of the Peace Corps with the need for access to such records for the performance of their duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are begun following the end of staff and/or volunteer services and retained for the "life" of the volunteer/staffer. These records have no present destruction date and are now expected to be destroyed 50 years after establishment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Coordinator, Former Volunteer List Program, Peace Corps, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to see information in their records, inquire if the system of records contains information about them, or contest/correct information, should provide their name, any former name, date of birth, social security number, dates of service, if known, location of service and type of service (whether volunteer or staff). Individuals should address their inquiries to the Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, Washington, DC 20526. All inquiries should have "Privacy Act Request" noted on the envelope.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information supplied by former staff and former volunteers.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-18</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Former Volunteer/Staff Resource Record.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps, Office of Volunteer Recruitment and Selection, 806 Connecticut Avenue NW, Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All former staff and volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual former staff and former volunteer files containing the following information about the particular individual: Name; current address; current phone number; social security number; date of birth; next of kin name and address; pre-service, service, and post-service education; employment and training experience; trade skills; language skills; educational level; teaching experience; current interest in voluntary service; type of volunteer/staff duty assignment; and location of assignment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2501, et seq.).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>
The contents of these records may be disclosed: (a) To any educational institutions
with which the Peace Corps has a Fellows/USA or Masters International
agreement which requires access to Volunteer or Returned Peace Corps Volunteer contact information in order
to meet the terms of the agreement.</p><p>
(b) To Returned Peace Corps
Volunteer organizations furthering the
Peace Corps’ recruiting or Third Goal
activities. The information released will
be limited to contact information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Files are maintained on magnetic discs and tapes which are stored in a locked room when not in immediate use in a building with a 24-hour guard.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by categories such as skills, social security number, and alphabetical order.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the system are available only to appropriate officials of the Peace Corps with the need for access to such records for the performance of their duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are begun following the end of staff and/or volunteer services and retained for the "life" of the volunteer/staffer. These records have no present destruction date and are now expected to be destroyed 50 years after establishment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Coordinator, Former Volunteer List Program, Peace Corps, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to see information in their records, inquire if the system of records contains information about them, or contest/correct information, should provide their name, any former name, date of birth, social security number, dates of service, if known, location of service and type of service (whether volunteer or staff). Individuals should address their inquiries to the Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, Washington, DC 20526. All inquiries should have "Privacy Act Request" noted on the envelope.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information supplied by former staff and former volunteers.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Peace Corps Response Database.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Crisis Corps, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington,
DC
20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>All applicants for Volunteer service with the Peace Corps Response.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, telephone number, education, country
of
service, dates of service, volunteer assignment area, technical skills, language proficiencies, and
suitability
for assignment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain records of individuals who apply for Peace Corps
Response Volunteer service and to record resulting actions taken on the
applications and service.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A through L apply to this
system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, address, telephone number, education, country of
service, dates of service, volunteer assignment area, technical skills, language proficiencies, and
suitability
for assignment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained at Peace Corps headquarters
until
declared inactive, then retired to the Federal Records Center, where they are retained for five years and
then
destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Crisis Corps,
Peace
Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who
wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to his or
her
record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the System
Manager.
Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license, employee
identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in some
instances.
Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought.
Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="pc20" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-20</systemNumber>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemName">Financial Management System (FMS).

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>The financial system is located at the Peace Corps
Headquarters. Authorized staff in Peace Corps offices, including those overseas, can access the automated
system
or its components. The Peace Corps office locations include Headquarters; Regional Recruitment offices; and
Peace
Corps overseas Posts. The number of Peace Corps recruiting offices is 11. The number of overseas offices
(posts)
fluctuates, from about 67 to about 71.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals the Peace Corps owes money to or who
receives a payment from the Peace Corps and those who owe money to the United States. These individuals
consist
of current and former Employees; Peace Corps Volunteers, Crisis Corps Volunteers; United Nations Volunteers;
and
returned Volunteers; Personal Services (PSC) and Other Contractors, Consultants, and Vendors who travel or
perform certain services for PC; Donors; and Individuals whom Peace Corps Volunteers and Crisis Corps
Volunteers
have designated to receive their W-2 forms.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>When applicable, information in the system includes,
but
is not limited to: Name, address, country of assignment, employee number, vendor number, social security
number;
Taxpayer Identification Number (TIN), including background and supporting documentation for most categories
of
individuals; banking data, PSC vendor Data Universal Numbering System (DUNS) number; contract numbers and
contracts, invoice and payment records; travel payment records; Peace Corps, Crisis Corps, and United Nations
Volunteer ID number, telephone numbers; date of birth, contacts, account numbers and payment records; claims,
donors (Federal and non-federal), donor numbers and donation history.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950;
Federal
Managers Financial Integrity Act; and the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular A-127, The Peace
Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501, et seq., Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996.</p>
<p>Purpose:

</p><p>To support the financial functions required to track financial events, provide financial information
significant to the financial management of Peace Corps and/or required for the preparation of financial
statements and other federally-mandated reports and for the issuance of payments.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps general routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F,
G, H,
I, J, K and L apply to this system. Records may also be disclosed to:

</p><p>1. The Department of Treasury for disbursements to vendors and travelers; or

</p><p>2. The Department of State for disbursements to vendors and travelers.

</p><p>3. The Department of Treasury for debt collection and to conduct a computer matching program in order
to
collect debts.

</p><p>4. The Internal Revenue Service for tax reporting and submission of W-2 and 1099 information.

</p><p>5. General Services Administration for Federal Procurement Data System (FPDS) reporting on contracts
awarded.

</p><p>6. Other Federal agencies with whom PC has established Interagency/Reimbursable Agreements.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Policies and practices
for
storing, retrieving, accessing, retaining, and disposing of records in the system:

</p><p>Storage:

</p><p>In a computerized database with background documentation or reports available on paper.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, Volunteer ID number, SSN, contract or purchase
order
number, invoice number, payment batch number, customer number or vendor number, DUNS number. Paper records
are
retrieved according to Volunteer name, country location code, purchase order number, contract number, project
number, vendor name, and SF1166 Schedule of Payments number.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computerized records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected computer system. These records are available to Peace Corps employees and contractors with assigned
duties requiring work with the records on a day-to-day basis. The office supervisors authorize the
appropriate
level of FMS record access for each user. FMS databases are backed up nightly. The domestic back-up media is
stored in a data center until delivered to GSA/DOD-approved facilities for offsite storage. Back-up media in
overseas PC offices is stored on site in fire-proof containers. Paper records are maintained in lockable file
cabinets. The paper records and computer media are maintained in secure, access-controlled areas or
buildings.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Computerized records are stored within the FMS
database
and are being retained for a minimum of 8 years. The paper records of vouchers, contracts (with award amounts
greater than $25,000), procurement files, and schedules of payments are retained for up to 6 years and 3
months
after the fiscal year of the award or after the final payment has been issued; Volunteers/Trainees records
are
retained up to 7 years and 3 months after the Volunteer/Trainee has terminated or closed service; and records
of
donors are held for up to 7 years unless they are no longer needed.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Financial Officer, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, U.S. Peace Corps, 1111 20th
St.,
NW., Washington, DC 20526-0001.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about himself or
herself,
who wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a
written
request to the System Manager or Privacy Act Officer. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying document.
Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment
must
identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act
procedures
are set out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject and Peace Corps staff.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">

<xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc21" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-21</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Health Benefits Program for Peace Corps Volunteers.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Medical Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St.,
NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps Volunteers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, telephone number, social security
number,
volunteer identification number, date of birth, sex, medical and dental history, dates of service, country of
service, x-rays and reports from physicians and other health care providers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>22 U.S.C. 2504(e); and the Peace Corps Act, 22
U.S.C.
2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To authorize health care for volunteers, pay health care bills,
provide eligibility lists to health care contractors and insurance carriers, and to confirm volunteer
eligibility
for service (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses F and K apply to this system.
Records may also be disclosed to:
</p><p>1. Peace Corps health benefits contractors to administer health care to Volunteers; and
</p><p>2. The Office of Workers' Compensation Programs, Department of Labor, for workers' compensation
claims.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:
</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, social security number, and volunteer
identification
number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in a lockable file room. Computer
records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are maintained in secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained at the Office of Administrative
Services at Peace Corps headquarters for two years, then retired to the Federal Records Center, where they
are
maintained for 25 years, and then destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Medical
Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual
who
wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to his or
her
record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the System
Manager.
Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license, employee
identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be required in some
instances.
Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought.
Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject, physicians or other health care
providers, and other medical sources including laboratories.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Privacy and Freedom of Information Act Requests.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th
St.,
NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who request access to records
containing
personally identifiable information subject to the Privacy Act and/or individuals who request copies of
records
under the Freedom of Information Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names and addresses of individuals making requests,
including date of request, related correspondence, and Peace Corps' response to request.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq., the
Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a, and the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record requests for records made under the Privacy Act and/or
the
Freedom of Information Act (Last Revised: August 2000).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses
A,
E, F, H, G, K, and L apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database. Records reflecting requests made by individuals
under
the Privacy Act are initially created and maintained by the Office of Administrative Services. Records
reflecting
requests made by members of the public under the Freedom of Information Act are logged in and responded to by
the
Office of the Executive Secretariat; the records are maintained by the Office of Administrative Services once
responses to requests are completed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or date of request.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept onsite as long as active and then
retired to the Federal Records Center to be destroyed after six years in accordance with General Records
Schedule
14.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual who
wants
to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals making requests under the Privacy
and/or
Freedom of Information Acts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Early Termination and Special Action.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Special Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St.,
NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Peace Corps volunteers and
trainees who were subject to early termination or a special action.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, country of assignment, program number,
termination
reports, staff recommendations, cables, financial information, travel arrangements, and documentation of
special
actions taken in regard to family and/or friends of volunteers or trainees who have died, disappeared, or
become
severely ill or injured.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act,
22
U.S.C. 2501 et seq.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record any unusual or extraordinary action or circumstances
happening during service or leading to the early termination of the volunteer or trainee?
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, D, E, F, H, I, K, and L
apply
to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p><p>On paper and/or in a computerized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in
secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept on-site for the duration of the
volunteer's service in-country, and then destroyed after five years.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, Office of Special Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who
wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures
may be
required in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and
the
corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Records subject, family members and their legal
representatives, Peace Corps supervisors, physicians or other health care providers, and the Department of
State.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="pc26" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Peace Corps Computer Systems Activity and Access Records.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps offices (and other sites utilized by the Peace
Corps) throughout the world. Headquartered at Peace Corps, Office of Information Resource Management, 1111
20th
Street, NW., Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All or any individuals who access Peace Corps
network
computers or mainframe/enterprise servers, including individuals who send and receive electronic
communications,
access Internet sites, or access system databases, files, or applications from Peace Corps computers or
sending
electronic communications to Peace Corps computers; and individuals attempting to access Peace Corps
computers or
systems without authorization.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system of records may include:
Records on
the use of interoffice and Internet e-mail systems, including the e-mail address of the sender and receiver
of
the e-mail message, subject, date, and time; records on user access to Peace Corps networks, including user
ID,
date and time of log on and log off, and denials of access to unauthorized files or directories; records of
Internet access from a Peace Corps computer, such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer being
used to initiate the Internet connection, the site accessed, date, and time; records relating to
mainframe/enterprise server access, such as user ID of the individual accessing the mainframe, date and time,
and
the process being run on the mainframe; records relating to verification or authorization of an individual's
access to systems, files, or applications, such as user IDs, passwords, user names, title, and agency.

</p><p>Logs of Internet access from a Peace Corps computer do not contain names or similar personal
identifiers.
However, for official government business purposes, a name may be associated with an IP address.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Computer Security Act of 1987, 49 U.S.C. 1441
note, requires Federal agencies to plan for the security and privacy of their computer Systems nad the Peace
Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501, et seq.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The underlying raw data in this system of records is used by the
Peace Corps' systems and security personnel, or persons authorized to assist these personnel, to plan and
manage
system services and to otherwise perform their official duties. Authorized Peace Corps managers may use the
records in this system to investigate improper access or other improper activity related to computer system
access; to initiate disciiplinary or other such action; and/or where the record(s) may appear to indicate a
violation or potential violation of the law, to refer such record(s) to the appropriate investigative arm of
Peace Corps, or other law enforcement agency for investigation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. Disclosure for Law Enforcement Purposes.
Information
may be disclosed to the appropriate Federal, State, local, or foreign agency responsible for investigating,
prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information indicates a
violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the
receiving
entity.

</p><p>B. Disclosure Incident to Requesting Information. Information may be disclosed to any source from
which
additional information is requested (to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of
the
purpose(s) of the request, or to identify the type of information requested); when necessary to obtain
information relevant to a Peace Corps decision concening retention of an employee or other personnel action
(other than hiring), retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or
retention
of a grant or other benefit.

</p><p>C. Disclosure to Requesting Agency. Information may be disclosed to a Federal, State, local, or other
public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the requesting
agency's
retention of an employee, the retnetion of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance
or
retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a
request supported by the written consent of the individual for part or all of the record if it so chooses. No
disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a
referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil,
administrative,
personnel, or regulatory action.

</p><p>D. Disclosure to Office of Management and Budget. Information may be disclosed to the Office of
Management
and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordiantion and clearance process in connection with private
relief
legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.

</p><p>E. Disclosure to Congressional Offices.Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the
record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the
individual.

</p><p>F. Disclosure to Department of Justice. Information may be disclosed for purposes of litigation,
provided
that in each case the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
Disclosure
for these purposes may be made to the Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative
body, or other administrative body before which the Peace Corps is authorized to appear. This disclosure may
be
made when: 1. The Peace Corps, or any component thereof; 2. Any employee of the Peace Corps in his or her
official capacity; 3. Any employee of the Peace Corps in his or her individual capacity where the Department
of
Justice or the Peace Corps has agreed to represent the employee; or 4. The United States (when the Peace
Corps
determines that litigation is likely to affect the Peace Corps or any of its components); is a party to
litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or
the
Peace Corps is deemed by the Peace Corps to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.

</p><p>G. Disclosure to the National Archives. Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and
Records
Administration in records management inspections.

</p><p>H. Disclosure to Contractors, Grantee, and Others. Information may be disclosed to contractors,
grantees,
consultants, or Volunteer performing, or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job,
or
other activity for the Peace Corps and who have a need to have access to the information in the performance
of
their duties or activities for the Peace Corps. When appropriate, recipients will be required to comply with
the
requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974 as provided in 5 U.S.C. 552a(m).

</p><p>I. Disclosures for Administrative Claims, Complaints, and Appeals. Information may be disclosed to an
authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator,
arbitrator, or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance,
complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee, but only to the extent that the information is relevant and
necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not
limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board,
Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.

</p><p>J. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management. Information may be disclosed to the Office of
Personnel Management pursuant to that agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal
personnel
management.

</p><p>K. Disclosure in Connection with Litigation. Information may be disclosed in connection with
litigation or
settlement discussions regarding claims by or against the Peace Corps, including public filing with a court,
to
the extent that disclosure of the information is relevant and necessary to the litigation or discussions and
except where court orders are otherwise required under section (b)(11) of the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C.
552a(b)(11).

</p><p>In addition to the routine uses stated above in A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, and K, the following
shall
apply to this system.

</p><p>Disclosure to provide information to any person(s) and authorized to assist in an approved
investigation
of improper usage of Peace Corps systems.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">

<xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Records are stored in electronic and/or paper form.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by user name, user ID, e-mail
address, or other identifying search term employed, depending on the record category. The Peace Corps does
not
usually connect IP addresses with a person. However, in some instances, for official government business
purposes, the Department may connect the IP address with an individual, and records may be retrieved by IP
address.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access is limited to those who have an official need to know.
Specifically, only systems and security personnel or persons authorized to assist these personnel have access
to
automated records and magnetic storage media. These records are kept in a locked room with controlled entry.
The
use of password protection identification features and other automated data processing system protection
methods
also restrict access. All records are located in buildings with restricted access.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records of verification, authorization, computer
system
access, and other activities generated by the system shall be retained no longer than one year, unless
required
for management review. After one year, they are destroyed or deleted. (Records retention schedule pending
approval by the Archivist of the United States.)

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Information Resource Management, Peace Corps,
1111
20th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>

<p>To the extent permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system is exempted
from
the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974 that permit access and correction. Individual notification of this
system and declaration of acceptance of this policy appears in the form of a Privacy Screen that must be
acknowledged by each individual before access is granted to use a Peace Corps computer. This prompt appears
with
every beginning access or initiation of systems on the computer.

</p><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her,
who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of records, should make a written
request
to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification such as a driver's
license
or employee identification card, or other identiying document. The written request should provide name,
assigned
computer location, and a description of information being sought, including the time frame during which the
record(s) may have been generated. Provide verification of identity. Identify the information being
contested,
the reason for contesting it, and the correction requested. In general, this information is computer-
generated
and is not subject to contest.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See Notification Procedures above.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See Notification Procedures above.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Most records are generated internally, i.e.,
computer
activity logs; individuals covered by the system; and management officials.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="pc27" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-27</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Antimalaria Tolerance Survey.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Medical Services, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St.,
NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps Volunteers (PCVs) who serve in areas
with
widespread chloroquine-resistant P. falciparum (CRPF) malaria.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal identifiers, geographical region and
country,
names of medications, possible side effects from medication, and behavioral activities.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>

<p>To study and better understand the factors that influence antimalarial medication compliance. These
records will be used by the staff of the Surveillance and Epidemiology Unit of the Office of Medical Services
to
collect, analyze and evaluate data from the surveys to determine the effectiveness of in-country health care.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses E, F, G, and H apply to this
system.

</p><p>Records may also be disclosed to:</p>

<p>1. The data from the surveys may be disclosed to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).

</p><p>2. Data in aggregate form may be disclosed to the Department of State and the Department of Defense.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage:</p><p>On paper and in a computerized database.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By personal identifier, assigned country, type of
medication,
side effects, behavioral activity types.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in a lockable cabinet. Computer
records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. All records are maintained in secure,
access-controlled areas or buildings.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records will be maintained for three years after
completion of the study. The records will be destroyed in accordance with the Peace Corps records management
policy.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Medical Services, Peace Corps, 1111
20th
Street, NW, Washington, DC 20526.

</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="pc28" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-28</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Applications for Employment.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Management, Human Resources Management, 1111
20th
Street NW., Washington DC 20526. Occasionally located on a temporary basis in domestic offices and overseas
Posts. Electronic records are stored offsite by a contracted agent of the agency in a secure facility.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All applicants for employment with the Peace
Corps
(including unsuccessful applicants).

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To the extent that an agency utilizes an automated
medium
in connection with maintenance of records in this system of records.

</p><p>Application forms, resumes and related correspondence. Position vacancy announcement information such
as
position title, series and grade level(s), office and duty location, opening and closing date of the
announcement, and dates of referral and return of lists of qualified candidates; applicant personal data such
as
name, address, social security number, date of birth, sex, veterans' preference and federal competitive
status;
and applicant qualification and processing information such as qualifications, grade level eligibility,
reason
for ineligibility, referral status, and dates of notification.

</p><p>Related correspondence may include referral letters and memoranda relating to the application process;
education and training related documentation; employment history and earnings; honors, awards or fellowships;
military service; convictions or offenses against the law; names of relatives employed in the Federal
service;
qualification determinations; employment consideration; priority groupings; correspondence relating to the
consideration of the individual for employment. These records may also include copies of correspondence
(electronic and otherwise) between the applicant and the office or agency and other items provided by
applicants
but not specifically requested by the agency.

</p><p>The system also includes any Peace Corps employment application materials established for making
appointments outside a register; or reassignments, promotions, reinstatements, or transfers of Federal
employees
into positions at Peace Corps.

</p><p>The records also contain information on the ranking of an applicant, his or her placement on a list of
eligibles, what certificates/rosters applicant's names appeared on, requests for office approval of or
opposition
to an eligible's qualifications and the office's decision in the matter, an office's request for approval for
the
agency to pass over an eligible and the office's decision in the matter, and an agency's decision to
object/pass
over an eligible when the agency has authority to make such decisions. Reasons for when the objection/pass
over
decision applies to a compensable preference eligible with 30 percent or more disability. Records may also
include: Agency applicant file systems where the agency retains applications, resumes, and other related
records
for hard-to-fill or unique positions for future consideration. Records and statements related to an
applicant's
involvement in intelligence related activities.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act,
22
U.S.C. 2501, et seq., including 22 U.S.C. 2506 and 22 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.
(Foreign Service Act of 1980).

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J,
and K
apply to this system.

</p><p>Records may also be disclosed to:

</p><p>(a) Evaluate qualifications of potential candidates by the Director, Human Resource Management and
his/her delegates, Executive Staff, Hiring Managers and their delegates, other supervisors and personnel
security
staff. These records also may be reviewed by staff with internal audit responsibilities. The records are
available to personnel specialists who review the applicants' qualifications and consider them for
appropriate
agency vacancies;

</p><p>(b) Persons named as references, and present or former supervisors, for purposes of commenting upon,
rating or verifying information about past performance submitted as part of job application;

</p><p>(c) Other Federal agencies, state governments, foreign governments and international organizations
where
employees are being considered for detail, assignment or secondment;

</p><p>(d) Attorneys, union representatives or other persons designated by employees in writing to represent
them
in complaints, grievances, appeals, litigation cases, or administrative processes;

</p><p>(e) The Department of Labor, Department of Veterans Affairs, Social Security Administration,
Department of
Defense, or any other Federal agency that has special civilian employee retirement and disability programs;
or to
a national, state, county, municipal, or other publicly recognized charitable or income security,
administration
agency (e.g., State unemployment compensation agencies), when necessary to adjudicate a claim under the
retirement, insurance, unemployment or health benefits programs of the agency or an agency cited above, or to
an
agency to conduct an analytical study or audit of benefits being paid or to be paid under such programs;

</p><p>(f) Offices within Peace Corps with an official need to know;

</p><p>(g) Other persons, entities, or organizations, as specified in the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1)
-(b)(12).

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage:</p><p>The records are stored by electronic means and hard copy. Records are maintained on data
storage devices,
lists, forms and hard copy record files. Electronic records are maintained within Peace Corps on proprietary
systems or within an automated application system on data storage devices. Information contained in the
automated
system is housed offsite in a secure location as government owned and retrievable information.

</p><p>Retrieval:

</p><p>The records may be retrieved by the names of the individuals on whom they are maintained or by vacancy
announcement number. In the Personnel Office, the records are recorded by name and vacancy announcement
number.
They can also be retrieved, by any common identifier in the automated application. These may be by individual
name, social security number, vacancy announcement, demographic fields, veteran's status, current grade,
grade
applied for, or any other data fields completed by the applicant. Records are generally retrieved by the name
with the social security number or date of birth as a secondary identifier when necessary.

</p><p>Accessibility/Safeguards:

</p><p>All Peace Corps employees have undergone background investigations. Access to the Agency is controlled
by
security guards and admission is limited to those individuals possessing a valid identification card or
individuals under proper escort. The Human Resource Management (HRM) office is in a secondary secured area
where
even Peace Corps employees not within the HRM organization are required to have escorts. All records
containing
personal information are maintained in secured file cabinets or in restricted areas, access to which is
limited
to authorized personnel. Access to computerized files is password-protected and under the direct supervision
of
the system manager. The system manager and contractor have the capability of printing audit trails of access
through the computer media, thereby permitting regular and ad hoc monitoring of system usage. Automated media
is
access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access. Access to and use of these records are
limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. Systems administered by contractors are
secured by password and through a permissions based system. Permission is granted by a system administrator.
Remote data storage facilities are secured through physical and system-based safeguards. Electronic files are
password protected and accessible only by authorized personnel. Data maintained electronically at Peace Corps
is
on network servers and located in a locked room with physical access limited to authorized personnel.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications from individuals who are selected for
positions with the Peace Corps are placed on the permanent side of the employee's Official Personnel Folder.
Paper applications rejected in the initial review because they do not meet requirements for Agency employment
and
applications which appear to meet requirements for Agency employment, but which are subsequently rejected,
are
retained for two years and then destroyed. Electronic media files are maintained indefinitely. These files
remain
available for the Agency when searching for qualified applicants for the variety of positions available
agency-
wide. Paper files on applicants may also be retained indefinitely. In divisional or regional offices, the
paper
records may be retained for an indefinite period of time. They are then forwarded to HRM or discarded.
Applicant
records, whether electronic media or hard copy will be maintained until they become inactive at which time
they
will be retired or destroyed in accordance with published records schedules of the Peace Corps or as approved
by
the National Archives and Records Administration. Most records are retained for a period of 2 years. Some
records
are destroyed by shredding or burning while magnetic tapes or disks are erased.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Human Resources Management OR Records Management
Officer Peace Corps Headquarters, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to known whether this
system
of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest
the
contents of a record, should make a written request to the System Manager. Request should be accepted for
processing if they contain sufficient information to convince the System Manager that the requester is the
subject of the records, including identifying information needed to locate your record and a brief
description of
the item or items of information required. Requesters will be required to provide adequate information, such
as a
driver's license, employment identification card, passport, or other identifying documents. Requests for
correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete
Peace
Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as
indicated in the notification section above. Individuals who wish to amend records pertaining to themselves
should also address their requests as described in the Notification section above.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to contest or amend
information maintained in this system should specify the information being contested, the reasons for
contesting
it, and the proposed amendment to such information. Individuals have the right to request that we amend a
record
pertaining to them when it is believed to be inaccurate, or lacks relevance, timeliness, or completeness. At
the
time we grant access to a record, we will furnish guidelines on how to make a request to amend a record.

</p><p>Requests for amendments to records must be in writing and mailed or delivered to the FOIA/Privacy Act
Officer, FOIA/Privacy Act Office, Peace Corps Headquarters, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526, who
will
coordinate the review of the request to amend the record with the appropriate office(s). Such requests must
contain, at a minimum, identifying information needed to locate the record, a brief description of the item
or
items of information to be amended, and the reason for the requested change. The requester should submit as
much
documentation, arguments or other data as seems warranted to support the request for amendment. We will
review
all requests for amendments to records within 20 working days of receipt of the request and either make the
changes or inform you of our refusal to do so and the reasons.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are normally submitted by the
individuals seeking employment. Some records could come from individuals or employment agencies sponsoring
the
applications. Information in this system of records is provided by:

</p><p>(a) The individual to whom the information pertains;

</p><p>(b) Peace Corps officials;

</p><p>(c) Other sources contacted to provide additional information about the individual. System exempted
from
certain provisions of the Privacy Act: Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(4), records contained within this system
that
are required by statute to be maintained and used solely for statistical purposes are exempted from 5 U.S.C.
552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I), and (f). Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), certain records
contained within this system contain confidential source information and are exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)
(3),
(d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I), and (f). Pursuant to 552a(k)(6), records that contain testing or
examination
material the release of which may compromise testing or examination procedures are also exempted from 5
U.S.C.
552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc29" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-29</systemNumber>



<subsection type="systemName">Coverdell World Wise Schools System.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Coverdell World Wise Schools, Office of Domestic Programs,
Peace Corps, 1111 20th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Currently serving Peace Corps Volunteers, Returned Peace Corps Volunteers, and Educators.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>When applicable, information in the system includes,
but
is not limited to: Name; social security number; approximate end of service date; type of assignment; country
of
assignment; region of assignment; home of record city, state, and zip code; e-mail address; address; home
phone;
work phone; dates of service; school name; school street address, city, state, zip code; school phone; fax
number; ethnic makeup of student body; special request information; how the educator heard about the program;
RPCV status; participation status in the Correspondence Match Program; grade level taught; number of students
participating; preferences for Peace Corps Volunteer match; dates of program activity; release for Peace
Corps to
release school information; release to quote educator in Coverdell World Wise Schools materials; year the
educator was matched to a Peace Corps Volunteer.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act,
22
U.S.C. 2501, et seq.

</p><p>Purpose:</p><p>To administer the Correspondence Match Program, which pairs currently-serving Peace
Corps
Volunteers with
U.S. educators in support of the third goal of the Peace Corps: To increase U.S. citizens' understanding of
other
countries and cultures. Through the Correspondence Match Program, U.S. educators and students receive
letters, e-
mails, telephone calls, photographs, and artifacts from the Peace Corps Volunteer in their country of
service. To
administer the Speakers Match Program, which provides returned Peace Corps Volunteers and U.S. educators for
the
purposes of classroom presentations. To support other activities of the Coverdell World Wise Schools Program,
including, but not limited to, educator conferences and print and online resource publication.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps general routine uses A through L apply
to
this system.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage:</p><p>On paper and in computerized databases.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper files are retrieved by Educator name and year the
educator was matched to a Peace Corps Volunteer. Computerized Database files are retrieved for Peace Corps
Trainees and Volunteers by name; social security number; participation status in the Correspondence Match
Program; approximate end of service date; type of assignment; country of assignment; region of assignment;
home
of record city, state, and zip code; and e-mail address. For Returned Peace Corps Volunteers, by name;
address;
home phone; work phone; e-mail address; country of service; type of assignment; and dates of service. For
Educators, by name; school name; school street address, city, state, zip code; school phone; fax number; home
phone; e-mail address; ethnic makeup of student body; special request information; how the educator heard
about
the program; RPCV status; participation status in the Correspondence Match Program; grade level taught;
number of
students participating; preferences for Peace Corps Volunteer match; dates of program activity; release for
Peace
Corps to disclose school information; and release to quote educator in Coverdell World Wise Schools
materials.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. The office supervisors authorize the appropriate level of record access for each user.
Databases
are backed up nightly. The domestic back-up media is stored in a data center until delivered to General
Services
Administration/Department of Defense-approved facilities for offsite storage. Paper records are maintained in
lockable file cabinets. The paper records and computer media are maintained in secure, access-controlled
areas or
buildings.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are retained by Coverdell World Wise
Schools for five years, then retired to the Federal Records Center and destroyed after 20 years. Volunteer
Electronic records are retained until two years after Peace Corps Volunteers' completion of service, at which
point they are automatically deleted from the database. Returned Peace Corps Volunteer electronic records are
stored indefinitely in Speakers Match database.

</p><p>Educator records are retained until two years after their last activity, at which point they are moved
to
the electronic archives of the Correspondence Match database.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, Coverdell World Wise Schools, Office of Domestic Programs, Peace Corps, 1111 20th Street, NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who
wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed
and
the corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc30" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-30</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Shriver E.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Information Officer, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St.,
NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.

</p><p>Categories of individuals covered by the system:

</p><p>Prospective applicants, school administrators, and the general public.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>First name, last name, email address, the zip code,
city
and state.

</p><p>Authority for maintenance of the system (includes any revisions or amendments):

</p><p>Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 <i>et seq.</i></p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system allows Peace Corps staff to host online meetings over the Internet. Known as
web-
conferences,
these meetings allow Peace Corps staff to converse, give presentations, show videos, chat with participants
in
the meeting.

</p><p>Name and e-mail addresses are collected so that the Web-conference instructions and logon information
can
be emailed to the participants. First names and last names are used to identify users when they log into the
Web-
conferencing meeting. City, State and Zip code are used to track geographic locations of attendees for the
purpose of analyzing attendance trends.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps general routine uses A, H, I, K, L and
M.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">

<xhtmlContent ><p>Storage: In a computerized database.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By first name, last name, email address, the zip code,
city
and state.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system. All records are maintained in secure, access-controlled areas or buildings.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is deleted from the system every six
months. Ninety-days after deletion, the information is physically deleted from the servers. Data is deleted
from
all backup tapes once they are overwritten via incremental backup, six months after the time it is collected.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Information
Officer,
Peace Corps Headquarters in Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who
wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who
wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written
request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a
driver's
license, employee identification card, or other identifying document. Additional identification may be
required
in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the
corrective
action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="pc31" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-31</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Peace Corps 50th Anniversary Archive.

</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>

Not applicable.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps Office of Communications, Peace Corps, 1111
20th
St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Former Peace Corps volunteers or their next-of-kin who have voluntarily contributed materials to the
digital library and members of the public.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, e-mail address, telephone number, volunteer ID,
country of service, dates of service, volunteer assignment area, descriptive information about items they
have
voluntarily submitted to the digital library (i.e., personal narratives, stories, digital photographs).
Correspondence files related to submissions and requests for information from the database.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501, <i>et
seq.</i></p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>To build a collection of stories, historical documents and photographs that help convey the history of
Peace Corps and the experiences of former Volunteers, to be used as source material for articles, events and
exhibits honoring the 50th anniversary of Peace Corps in 2011.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A-M apply to this system.

</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:

</p><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage:</p><p>We are accepting only electronic submissions of stories and digital photos. Should
photographic
prints
and documents be sent to us, they will be stored in a locked file room in the Peace Corps Office of
Communications until they are returned to the submitter after digitization. Name, contact information and
service
information of contributors will be stored in a password protected computerized database.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, country of service, dates of service, volunteer
ID,
volunteer assignment area, format, and subject(s) of voluntarily submitted materials.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Photographic prints, newsletters and journals will be stored
in a
locked file room in the Peace Corps Office of Communications. Digital records and indexing data will be
stored on
secure servers. Server access is limited to authorized personnel whose duties require such access.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are permanent per the existing schedule. An
extract of the electronic files, with the contact information and volunteer ID removed for privacy
protection,
will be retired to the National Archives and Records Administration upon approval of an updated records
schedule
covering anniversary records.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>50th Anniversary Archive Project Manager, Office of
Communications, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526. E-mail: <i>
archive@peacecorps.gov</i>.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Any individual who wants notification that this system of records contains a record about him or her
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants access to his or her
record
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to contest the
contents
of a record should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide
adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must
identify
the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.




</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc32" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-32</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Volunteer Language Testing Scores System.

</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Not applicable.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Overseas Training Division, Training and Staff Development
Unit, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any Peace Corps Trainee or currently serving
Volunteer.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, Volunteer Identification Number, gender,
country of
service, region of service, date of birth, project type, project name or assigned sector, language
background,
notes, test date, language code, tester code, length of pre-service training, Educational Testing
Services/Teaching of Foreign Language rating, certificate of language proficiency, and reason not tested, if
applicable.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 <i>et
seq.</i></p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record Educational Testing Services/Teaching of Foreign
Language
rating of Peace Corps Volunteers.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A-M apply to this system.

</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:

</p><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage:</p><p>In a computerized database.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, region, gender, assigned sector, or date tested.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password-
protected
computer system.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the computerized database are kept for
seven
years after swear in and five years after close of service.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Chief of Overseas Training, Center for Field Assistance and Applied Research, 1111 20th St., NW.,
Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Any individual who wants notification that this system of records contains a record about him or her
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants access to his or her
record
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to contest the
contents
of a record should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide
adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must
identify
the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record subject and official records of Educational
Testing Services/Teaching of Foreign Language rating.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.



</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="pc33" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-33</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Consolidated Incident Reporting System (CIRS).

</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Not applicable.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Chief Information Officer and the Office of
Safety and Security, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526, as well as Peace Corps overseas
offices.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps Volunteers, Trainees, Peace Corps
Response Volunteers, alleged offenders, and witnesses.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Volunteer name; Volunteer contact information,
including
phone number, address, and/or e-mail address; Volunteer Tag (system-generated ID associated with the
Volunteer's
name); race/ethnicity; sex; country of incident; country of service; sector of assignment; marital status;
age;
Volunteer site; type of incident; date of incident; date incident was reported to post; time of incident;
personnel notified; incident location; size of population of community (i.e., urban, intermediate, rural);
nature
and details of the incident; alcohol use by Volunteer at time of incident; weapon use by alleged offender;
injury
sustained; medical/counseling support provided; victim's intention to prosecute; and alleged offender's
motive
for committing incident; name of alleged offender; age range of alleged offender; gender of alleged offender;
relationship of alleged offender to victim; alcohol use by alleged offender at time of incident; whether
alleged
offender was apprehended; information on witnesses, such as name and contact information; and post follow up
or
changes to original incident report, as noted in the updates section.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Peace Corps Act , 22 U.S.C. 2501 <i>et
seq.</i></p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide a single central facility within the Peace Corps for
tracking crimes against Volunteers; analyzing trends; and responding to requests from executive, legislative,
and
oversight bodies, as well as the public, for statistical crime data relating to criminal and other high-
interest
incidents. The Peace Corps will use this information for programmatic and training purposes in order to make
informed decisions about potential changes in policy and/or programs. The system notifies in a timely manner
Peace Corps headquarters and overseas staff who have a need to know when a crime has occurred against a
Volunteer. Such staff make safety and security, medical, or management decisions regarding the Volunteer
victim.
The system also notifies the U.S. Embassy's Regional Security Officers covering the post whenever a crime
against
a Volunteer occurs so that they may initiate investigative procedures, as necessary.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General routine uses A through M apply to this
system.
In addition to general routine uses, the Peace Corps will use the data collected via the CIRS for
programmatic
and training purposes and to make informed decisions about potential changes in policy and/or programs.

</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:

</p><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:

</p><p>In a protected database and in a locked file cabinet in a locked room.






</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by any, all, or any combination of
the
following data fields: Volunteer name; contact information; Volunteer Tag; race/ethnicity; sex; country of
incident, country of service; sector of assignment; marital status; age; Volunteer site; type of incident;
date
of incident; date incident was reported; time of incident; date of incident; names of personnel notified;
size of
population of community; incident location; nature and details of the incident/offense; alcohol use by
Volunteer
at time of incident; whether weapons were involved; type of injury; medical support provided; updates to the
incident report; victim's intention to prosecute; and motive for committing incident; name of alleged
offender;
age range of alleged offender; gender of alleged offender; relationship of alleged offender to victim;
alcohol
use by alleged offender at time of incident; and whether alleged offender was apprehended; any available
information on witness.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Names and social security numbers have been redacted from
paper
records that were collected until 2006. After 2006, social security numbers were no longer collected on the
Volunteer. The crime incident database does not collect or store previously collected social security
numbers.
Accounts are created for Peace Corps staff for whom a business need exists, i.e., select staff in Director's
office, Safety and Security, Regions, and Volunteer Support. Regional Security Officers and Assistant
Regional
Security Officers at the U.S. Embassy at post also receive CIRS accounts. Embassy officials must complete a
Technology Access Agreement form to receive an account. All CIRS accounts require a user name and password.
Access to Volunteer names and addresses in the reports is restricted to only those CIRS users who have a need
to
know. These include reporting post staff, Office of Volunteer Support staff who are responsible for medical
support, and Regional Security Officers with the U.S. Embassy.

</p><p>Information is encrypted using 128-bit SSL and AES encryptions standards. The system platform went
through
the accreditation process in February 2008 (i.e., accreditation with the WebTrust seal) and through a
SAS-70 Type II audit performed by a third party auditor.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>As there is no records disposal schedule for this
information, electronic and paper records are being retained indefinitely. Records are retained to allow for
historical data and trends analysis. Paper files are redacted to remove Volunteer names and social security
numbers. The annual Safety of the Volunteer report is kept on file permanently for historical reference.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Social Science Analyst, Office Safety and Security, Peace
Corps, 1111 20th St., NW., Washington, DC 20526.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any individual who wants notification that this system of records contains a record about him or her
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR Part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants access to his or her
record
should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR Part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to contest the
contents
of a record should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide
adequate
identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation.
Additional identification may be required in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must
identify
the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are
set
out in 22 CFR Part 308.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record Subject.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>




	<section id="pc34" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-34</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Volunteer/Trainee Sexual Misconduct Complaint Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification">
    <xhtmlContent>
        <p>Not applicable.</p>
    </xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Office of the General Counsel, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St. NW., Washington, DC 20526.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Peace Corps Volunteers or Trainees who are complainants or accused under the Peace Corps IPS 1-12
Procedures for Handling Complaints of Volunteer/Trainee Sexual Misconduct, or the section of the Peace Corps
Manual into which its provisions are subsequently incorporated.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Names and contact information of participants, country of service, complaints, Office of Inspector General
investigative report, waivers of confidentiality, confirmation of declinations from the Department of Justice as
necessary, hearing panel or Regional Director records including but not limited to notices, evidentiary
documents, transcripts, written submissions, witness lists, hearing panel reports, Regional Director decisions,
requests for additional action, appeals and responses, Deputy Director decision, and any other records of the
proceeding.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>

<p>The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501, et seq.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>

<p>To record actions taken on complaints made under the Peace Corps IPS 1-12 Procedures for Handling
Complaints of Volunteer/Trainee Sexual Misconduct or the section of the Peace Corps Manual into which its
provisions are subsequently incorporated.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
    <p>
        General routine use K applies to this system.
    </p>
<p>
        Information in a record of a particular proceeding will be releasable to the complainant and to the accused in
        that proceeding. Information will be released pursuant to a written consent by either the complainant or the
        accused only where the written consent specifically references this system of records.
    </p>
    <p>
        As set out in IPS-1-12 .10(d), any resignation in lieu of administrative separation and any final
        decision that the accused Volunteer/Trainee has been found to have engaged in Sexual Misconduct shall also be
        placed in the Trainee/Volunteer Service File of the accused Volunteer/Trainee.
    </p>
<p>Disclosure to agency staff will be only as set out in IPS 1-12 or the section of the Peace Corps Manual
into which its provisions are subsequently incorporated.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p>
<p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage: During the pendency of the proceeding, documents will be stored in a password-protected electronic
file on a secure server accessible only to Peace Corps staff members with a formal role in the proceeding as
described in IPS 1-12 or the section of the Peace Corps Manual into which its provisions are subsequently
incorporated. At the termination of the proceeding, documents will be stored in a password-protected file on a
secure server accessible only to the Office of the General Counsel. Documents may be stored in a locked file
cabinet in a locked file room in the Office of the General Counsel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>By name of complainant and accused, and by country.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access by agency staff will require permission of the Office of the General Counsel. Documents
will be stored in a locked file cabinet in a locked file room or in digital form in a password-protected file on
a secure server. Server access is limited to authorized personnel whose duties require such access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
    <p>
        Documents in this system of records will be retained for 30 years.
    </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Office of the General Counsel, Peace Corps, 1111 20th St. NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any individual who wants notification that this system of records contains a record about him or her should
make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification,
such as a driver’s license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional
identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22
CFR Part 308. See also MS 897, Attachment B.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
    <xhtmlContent>
        <p>Any individual who wants access to his or her record should make a written request to the System Manager.</p>
        <p>
            Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver’s license, employee
            identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional identification may be required in some
            instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.
        </p>
    </xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any individual who wants to contest the contents of a record should make a written request to the System
Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver’s license, employee
identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional identification may be required in some
instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action
sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Participants in the proceeding.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Documents originating from the Office of Inspector General will be handled under the applicable Office of
Inspector General System of Records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    <section id="pc35" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-35</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PCLive (also referred to as "Peace Corps Live").
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of the Chief Information Officer,  Peace Corps,  1111 20th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20526.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Any current Peace Corps employees or Volunteers.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Volunteers: Name, country of service, years of service (start year and end year), e-mail address, and Sector.  Staff: Name, job title, and e-mail address.  If staff is also a returned Volunteer: country of service and years of service (start year and end year).</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> To serve as a centralized, knowledge-sharing platform for the global Peace Corps community.  Users (Peace Corps staff and Volunteers) will create user profiles on PCLive. These users create profiles for the purpose of connecting with other staff and Volunteers around the world (sharing information, best practices, and institutional knowledge).   </p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>General routine uses A through M apply to this system. In addition to general routine uses, the Peace Corps will use the data collected during the account registration process to confirm the user is a current Peace Corps employee or Volunteer.  </p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>In a password protected electronic database.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>By name, email address, username or a unique identifier (which is assigned at registration).</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. Only server administrators have access to the physical database where this information is stored.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>All user profile data will be stored in an electronic database and retained for a period of up to 24 months (pending National Archives disposition authority) after the Peace Corps Volunteer or staff member has separated from service or employment.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Overseas Programming &amp; Training Support (OPATS), Peace Corps, 1111 20th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20526.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Any individual who wants notification that this system of records contains a record about him or her should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Any individual who wants access to his or her record should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional identification may be required in some instances. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Any individual who wants to contest the contents of a record should make a written request to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional identification may be required in some instances. Requests for correction or amendment must identify the record to be changed and the corrective action sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id=" pc-36 – PEACE CORPS " toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/-36--</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Personnel Accountability System – Not Covered by Notices of Other Agencies.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Peace Corps Headquarters, Peace Corps, 1111 20th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20526.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Peace Corps domestic and overseas personnel which includes employees, contractors, interns, work study students, and Peace Corps Volunteers.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The agency-wide system covers all Peace Corps personnel accountability locator systems, emergency contact records and systems, telework contact records, or administrative contact lists not covered by OPM/GOVT-1 that contain Peace Corps personnel and organizational information.  Information for Peace Corps personnel includes the individual’s first name, last name, position staff title, employment type, work email address, work phone number, office location, home email address, personal phone number, unique Peace Corps staff identification number, photograph (optional), and country in which the individual works.  Peace Corps Volunteer information includes personal email address, personal phone number, volunteer identification number, Post site location and residence address, and the longitude and latitude coordinates of the country site residence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 6 U.S.C. 501-521, National Emergency Management; as amended; 6 U.S.C. 572, National Emergency Communications Plan; Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006, 6 U.S.C. 701, et. Seq., National Emergency Management; 22 U.S.C. 2501, et. seq., the Peace Corps Act; Public Law 87–293, as amended; 42 USC 5121–5207, the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, as amended; National Security Presidential Directive – 51 and Homeland Security Presidential Directive - 20; Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12; Federal Continuity Directive 1; Executive Order (EO) 12137,The Peace Corps; EO 12472, Assignment of National Security and Emergency Preparedness Telecommunications Functions, as amended; EO 12656, Assignment of Emergency Preparedness Responsibilities; Peace Corps Manual Section (MS) 129, Office of the Chief Information Officer: Organization, Mission, and Functions; MS 130, Office of Safety and Security: Organization, Mission, and Functions; MS 132, Office of Human Resources: Organization, Mission, and Functions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are used to maintain current Peace Corps personnel locator listings, and to notify Peace Corps personnel with specific, time-sensitive information before, during, and after an event, and to account for personnel who are affected by the event.  Communication may be used for routine alerts, work-related issues, and emergency communications.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Peace Corps general routine uses A through M apply to this system.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p>None.</p>
                <p>Policies and practices for storing, retrieving, securing, retaining, and disposing of records in the system:</p>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> Records are maintained in electronic media and paper.</p>
                <p>Retrievability – Information retrieved using the following unique identifier(s):</p>
                <p>First name, last name, employment type, unique Peace Corps ID number, office name, position title, work or personal email account, and country or site in which the individual works.</p>
                <p>Safeguards:</p>
                <p>Records are centrally maintained in controlled areas within a secure facility.  Physical entry is restricted by security guards and presentation of authenticated identification badges at entry control points, and key cards for access into buildings and authorized areas.  Electronic records are maintained in a secured electronic system accessible only to authorized personnel responsible for maintaining the record system in the performance of their official duties.  Access to computer data is managed by privileged management software and governing policies.  Access is protected by an assigned user profile, user ID, password, encryption, and PIV card access on work computers.  User profiles are role-based and ensure that the individual’s role will only access authorized data.  Paper records are maintained in locked file storage areas or in specified secured areas to which only authorized personnel have access.</p>
                <p>Retention and Disposal:</p>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with the applicable NARA-approved retention schedules for temporary records.  Disposal and destruction of electronic records is done by erasing, deleting, or overwriting the data. Paper records are destroyed by secure shredding.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Associate Director for Safety and Security; the Chief Information Officer; or the Chief Human Capital Officer, Peace Corps, 1111 20th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20526.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system of records must send the written request to the Privacy Act Officer, Peace Corps, 1111 20th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20526.  Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification for verification purposes, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional identification may be required in some instances.  The individual should reasonably specify the record contents being sought. Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.  Current Peace Corps personnel may also directly access the particular system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Active Peace Corps personnel have full access to and control over their individual record and may amend information at any time, or contact the System Manager. Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system of records must send the written request to the Privacy Act Officer Peace Corps, 1111 20th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20526.  Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification for verification purposes, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other identifying documentation. Additional identification may be required in some instances.  The individual should reasonably specify the record contents being sought. All individuals requesting access must follow Peace Corps Privacy Act regulations regarding verification and identity.  Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Active Peace Corps personnel have full access to and control over their individual record and may amend information at any time, or contact the System Manager.  Any individual who wants to contest the contents of a record outside of their control should make a written request to the Privacy Act Officer at the address specified under notification procedures above.  Requests for correction or amendment must reasonably identify the specific record to be changed, the information to be contested, and corrective action sought with supporting justification.  Complete Peace Corps Privacy Act procedures are set out in 22 CFR Part 308.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The information contained in this system is obtained from and updated by the individual on whom the record is maintained.</p>
                <p>Systems exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act:</p>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pc37" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-37</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Reasonable Accommodation Requests, PC-37.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Civil Rights and Diversity, Peace Corps, 1275 First Street, NE, Washington, DC 20526.  Some documents related to requests for reasonable accommodations   may also be located in an electronic file in the Office of Human Resources at the same address.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director, Office of Civil Rights and Diversity, Peace Corps, 1275 First Street, NE, Washington, DC 20526.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Peace Corps Act, as amended (22 U.S.C. § 2503); the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended (29 U.S.C. § 791); Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, as amended (42 U.S.C. § 2000e); Civil Rights Act of 1991 42 U.S.C. § 1981; Executive Order (E.O.) 13163, Increasing the Opportunities for Individuals with Disabilities to be Employed in the Federal Government; E.O. 13164, Requiring Federal Agencies To Establish Procedures To Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation; E.O. 13548, Increasing Federal Employment of Individuals with Disabilities, and Executive Order 14043: Requiring Coronavirus Disease 2019 Vaccination for Federal Employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of this system is to document and manage the agency’s receipt, review, approval or denial decision, and implementation of an individual’s reasonable accommodation request under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended, Title VII of the Civil Rights Act, as amended, and the 1991 Civil Rights Act. The purpose is also to allow the agency to collect and maintain records on applicants for employment as well as employees with disability, medical condition or because of their religious beliefs, practice or observance who request or receive reasonable accommodations as required by the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended, and Title VII of the Civil Rights Act, as amended, and the 1991 Civil Rights Act. This system will also track and report the processing of requests for reasonable accommodation to comply with applicable law and regulations and to preserve and maintain confidentiality of the records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The categories of individuals covered by the system are Peace Corps applicants, personnel, or public participants in a Peace Corps activity who request a reasonable accommodations on the bases of a disability, medical condition or for religious reasons. This includes federal job and internship applicants, current and former federal employees, political appointees, experts, and interns; Peace Corps Volunteer applicants, Peace Corps Volunteers, and Returned Peace Corps Volunteers; covered federal employees as defined in 5 U.S.C. 2105 to be fully vaccinated against COVID-19, and third parties who represent or advocate for or on the behalf of the requesting individual, or who participate in a Peace Corps activity or program.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The categories of records in this system include the requesting individual’s reasonable accommodation request form, the individual’s supporting documentation for disability, or medical condition, medical records, medical notes or letters, the requested accommodation, information involving medical devices, impairments, disability type, and disability condition. Requests for accommodation for religious reasons may include documents related to support the request for religious accommodation including documents from third parties.</p>
                <p>The categories of records also may include documents that describe the type of accommodation, documents that approve or deny the reasonable accommodation request; documents or information about the implementation of the accommodation request, emails, notes, letter and memoranda regarding the request for accommodation.</p>
                <p>Identifying information includes the requesting individual’s first and last name, office name and location; work email address and  telephone numbers, employee position and grade; supervisor’s full name, email address, phone number, office name; a third-party advocate’s first and last name and contact information; a health care provider’s full name, work address, work phone number, fax number, work email address and signature; full name and office of personnel processing requests; the information related to the accommodation request such as medical or disability information, and religious affiliation, belief, practice, or observance for a religious accommodation request.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information sources include individuals requesting reasonable accommodations, healthcare providers or supporting professionals, advocates for the individual; and Peace Corps personnel who participate in evaluation, review, determination, and implementation of a reasonable accommodation request.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, the Peace Corps may disclose all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system without the consent of the subject individual may be disclosed if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected outside the Peace Corps as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>A. Disclosure for Law Enforcement Purposes. Information may be disclosed to the appropriate Federal, State, local, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.</p>
                <p>B. Disclosure Incident to Requesting Information. Information may be disclosed to any source from which additional information is requested (to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, or to identify the type of information requested); when necessary to obtain information relevant to a Peace Corps decision concerning retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a grant or other benefit.</p>
                <p>C. Disclosure to Requesting Agency. Information may be disclosed to a Federal, State, local, or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the requesting agency's retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a request supported by the written consent of the individual for part or all of the record if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.</p>
                <p>D. Disclosure to Office of Management and Budget. Information may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.</p>
                <p>E. Disclosure to Congressional Offices. Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p>F. Disclosure to Department of Justice. Information may be disclosed for purposes of litigation, provided that in each case the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected. Disclosure for these purposes may be made to the Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Peace Corps is authorized to appear. This disclosure may be made when: 1. The Peace Corps, or any component thereof; 2. Any employee of the Peace Corps in his or her official capacity; 3. Any employee of the Peace Corps in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the Peace Corps has agreed to represent the employee; or 4. The United States (when the Peace Corps determines that litigation is likely to affect the Peace Corps or any of its components) is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the Peace Corps is deemed by the Peace Corps to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
                <p>G. Disclosure to the National Archives. Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections.</p>
                <p>H. Disclosure to Contractors, Grantees, and Others. Information may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, consultants, or Volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Peace Corps and who have a need to have access to the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Peace Corps. When appropriate, recipients will be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974 as provided in 5 U.S.C. 552a(m).</p>
                <p>I. Disclosures for Administrative Claims, Complaints, and Appeals. Information may be disclosed to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee, but only to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding, Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to: the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Federal Labor Relations Authority, U.S. Equal Employment Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.</p>
                <p>J. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management. Information may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to that agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
                <p>K. Disclosure in Connection with Litigation. Information may be disclosed in connection with litigation or settlement discussions regarding claims by or against the Peace Corps, including public filings with a court, to the extent that disclosure of the information is relevant and necessary to the litigation or discussions and except where court orders are otherwise required under Section (b)(11) of the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(11).</p>
                <p>L. Disclosure to U.S. Ambassadors. Information from this system of records may be disclosed to a U.S. Ambassador or his or her designee in a country where the Peace Corps serves when the information is needed to perform an official responsibility, to allow the Ambassador to knowledgeably respond to official inquiries and deal with in- country situations that are within the scope of the Ambassador's responsibility.</p>
                <p>M. Disclosure to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the Peace Corps suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the Peace Corps has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach, there is a risk of harm to individuals, the Peace Corps (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Peace Corps' efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>N. Disclosure another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the Peace Corps determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>O. Disclosures to Public Health Agencies and Authorities, individuals records’ may be disclosed to federal, state, local, and Tribal health departments, other cooperating medical authorities, or other appropriate entities or organizations, in order for them to take measures to control, prevent, or treat communicable disease; and to deal more effectively with contagious diseases and conditions of public health.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records in this system of records are stored electronically on Peace Corps’ database servers, hosted at the Peace Corps data center in Ashburn, VA. Access to these servers are restricted to authorized government personnel. Paper records are stored in a locked metal file cabinet.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Reasonable Accommodation Requests records and information may be retrieved by an individual’s name, Employee ID number, assigned office, and date of request.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retired and destroyed in accordance with the Peace Corps’ published record disposition schedules that are approved by the National Archives and Records Administration. Records in this system are subject to General Records Schedule (GRS) for "Reasonable Accommodation Program Files," disposition authority: DAA-GRS-2018-0002-0001, GRS 2.3, item 010, and will be retained for three years unless a business use is identified that requires a longer retention.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Peace Corps safeguards records in this system in accordance with applicable laws, rules and policies to protect personally identifiable information against unauthorized access or disclosure. The Peace Corps has imposed strict controls to minimize such risks. Administrative safeguards include but not limited to: access to the records in this system is limited to authorized personnel who need to know the information to perform official duties, and whose roles have been authorized with such access permissions. All such individuals receive the appropriate privacy and cybersecurity training on an annual basis.</p>
                <p>The physical controls in place include the servers storing electronic data are located offsite in a locked facility with access limited to authorized personnel. The servers are maintained in accordance with a government contract that requires adherence to applicable laws, rules, and policies on protecting individual privacy.</p>
                <p>The technical controls in place include multiple firewalls, system access, encrypted data at rest, encrypted data in motion, periodic vulnerability scans to ensure security compliance, and security access logs. Security complies with applicable Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Access is restricted to specific authorized Peace Corps individuals who have internet access through work computers using a Personally Identity Verification (PIV) or an assigned RSA token for general login access. Individual users can only access records with the proper pre-approved accreditation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking access to their records should follow the procedures in 22 CFR part 308. Individuals should address written inquiries to the Privacy Officer at FOIA@peacecorps.gov. Provide a signed written request containing the name and number of this system of records notice along with the individual’s full name, current address, and email address. The requester must provide either a notarized statement or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the appropriate format:</p>
                <p>If executed outside the United States: "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)."</p>
                <p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)."</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals may request that records about them be amended or appeal an adverse decision by writing to the Peace Corps, Privacy Act Officer, Privacy Act Office at 1275 First Street, NE, Washington, DC 20526 or submitting an electronic request to FOIA@peacecorps.gov and furnish the same information as required in the "Record Access Procedures" (full name. identify the system of records, provide the relevant signed declaration). In addition, clearly and concisely state what information is being contested, the reasons for contesting it, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Record Access Procedures."</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="22">
<heading> Foreign Relations </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="III">
<heading>Peace Corps</heading>
<regulationsPart number="308">
<heading>IMPLEMENTATION OF THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>308.1 Purpose.
</p>
<p>308.2 Policy.
</p>
<p>308.3 Definitions.
</p>
<p>308.4 Disclosure of records.
</p>
<p>308.5 New uses of information.
</p>
<p>308.6 Reports regarding changes in systems.
</p>
<p>308.7 Use of social security account number in records systems. [Reserved]
</p>
<p>308.8 Rules of conduct.
</p>
<p>308.9 Records systems--management and control.
</p>
<p>308.10 Security of records systems--manual and automated.
</p>
<p>308.11 Accounting for disclosure of records.
</p>
<p>308.12 Contents of records systems.
</p>
<p>308.13 Access to records.
</p>
<p>308.14 Specific exemptions.
</p>
<p>308.15 Identification of requesters.
</p>
<p>308.16 Amendment of records and appeals with respect thereto.
</p>
<p>308.17 Denial of access and appeals with respect thereto.
</p>
<p>308.18 Fees.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b>5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b>50 FR 1844, Jan. 14, 1985, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.1 Purpose.
</b></p>
<p>The purpose of this part is to set forth the basic policies of the Peace Corps governing the maintenance of systems of records containing personal information as defined in the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a). Records included in this part are those described in the aforesaid Act and maintained by the Peace Corps and/or any component thereof.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.2 Policy.
</b></p>
<p>It is the policy of the Peace Corps to protect, preserve and defend the right of privacy of any individual as to whom the agency maintains personal information in any records system and to provide appropriate and complete access to such records including adequate opportunity to correct any errors in said records. It is further the policy of the agency to maintain its records in such a fashion that the information contained therein is and remains material and relevant to the purposes for which it is collected in order to maintain its records with fairness to the individuals who are the subject of such records.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.3 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Record</i>means any document, collection, or grouping of information about an individual maintained by the agency, including but not limited to information regarding education, financial transactions, medical history, criminal or employment history, or any other personal information which contains the name or personal identification number, symbol, photograph, or other identifying particular assigned to such individual, such as a finger or voiceprint.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>System of Records</i>means a group of any records under the control of the agency from which information is retrieved by use of the name of an individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Routine Use</i>means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p>
<p>(d) The term <i>agency</i>means the Peace Corps or any component thereof.
</p>
<p>(e) The term <i>individual</i>means any citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted to permanent residence.
</p>
<p>(f) The term <i>maintain</i>includes the maintenance, collection, use or dissemination of any record.
</p>
<p>(g) The term <i>Act</i>means the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a) as amended from time to time.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.4 Disclosure of records.
</b></p>
<p>The agency will not disclose any personal information from systems of records it maintains to any individual other than the individual to whom the record pertains, or to another agency, without the express written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains, or his or her agent or attorney, except in the following instances:
</p>
<p>(a) To officers or employees of the Peace Corps having a need for such record in the official performance of their duties.
</p>
<p>(b) When required under the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552).
</p>
<p>(c) For routine uses as published in the <i>Federal Register.</i>
</p>
<p>(d) To the Bureau of the Census for uses pursuant to title 13.
</p>
<p>(e) To an individual or agency having a proper need for such record for statistical research provided that such record is transmitted in a form which is not individually identifiable and that an appropriate written statement is obtained from the person to whom the record is transmitted stating the purpose for the request and a certification under oath that the records will be used only for statistical purposes.
</p>
<p>(f) To the National Archives of the United States as a record of historical value under rules and regulations of the Archives or to the Administrator of General Services or his designee to determine if it has such value.
</p>
<p>(g) To an agency or instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within the control of the United States for civil or criminal law enforcement activities, if the activity is authorized by law, and the head of any such agency or instrumentality has made a written request for such records specifying the particular portion desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought. Such a record may also be disclosed by the agency to the law enforcement agency on its own initiative in situations in which criminal conduct is suspected: <i>Provided,</i>That such disclosure has been established as a routine use or in situations in which the misconduct is directly related to the purpose for which the record is maintained.
</p>
<p>(h) In emergency situations upon a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of any individual provided that after such disclosure, notification of such disclosure must be promptly sent to the last known address of the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>(i) To either House of Congress or to a subcommittee or committee (joint or of either house) to the extent the subject matter falls within their jurisdiction.
</p>
<p>(j) To the Comptroller General, or any of his authorized representatives, in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office.
</p>
<p>(k) Pursuant to an order by the presiding judge of a court of competent jurisdiction. If any record is disclosed under such compulsory legal process and subsequently made public by the court which issued it, the agency must make a reasonable effort to notify the individual to whom the record pertains of such disclosure.
</p>
<p>(l) To consumer reporting agencies as defined in 31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3) in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711, and under contracts for collection services as authorized in 31 U.S.C. 3718.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.5 New uses of information.
</b></p>
<p>The agency shall publish in the <i>Federal Register</i>a notice of its intention to establish a new or revised routine use of any system of records maintained by it with an opportunity for public comments on such use. Such notice shall contain the following:
</p>
<p>(a) The name of the system of records for which the new or revised routine use is to be established.
</p>
<p>(b) The authority for maintaining the system of records.
</p>
<p>(c) The categories of records maintained in the system.
</p>
<p>(d) The purpose for which the record is to be maintained.
</p>
<p>(e) The proposed routine use(s).
</p>
<p>(f) The purpose of the routine use(s).
</p>
<p>(g) The categories of recipients of such use.

</p>
<p>In the event of any request for an addition to the routine uses of the systems which the agency maintains, such request may be sent to the following officer: Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Corps, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.6 Reports regarding changes in systems.
</b></p>
<p>The agency shall provide to Congress and the Office of Management and Budget advance notice of any proposal to establish or alter any system of records as defined herein. This report will be submitted in accord with guidelines provided by the Office of Management and Budget.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.7</b>[RESERVED] Use of social security account number in records systems. [Reserved]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.8 Rules of conduct.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The head of the agency shall assure that all persons involved in the design, development, operation or maintenance of any systems of records as defined herein are informed of all requirements necessary to protect the privacy of individuals who are the subject of such records. All employees shall be informed of all implications of the Act in this area including the criminal penalties provided under the Act, and the fact the agency may be subject to civil suit for failure to comply with the provisions of the Privacy Act and these regulations.
</p>
<p>(b) The head of the agency shall also ensure that all personnel having access to records receive adequate training in the protection of the security of personal records and that adequate and proper storage is provided for all such records with sufficient security to assure the privacy of such records.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.9 Records systems--management and control.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Director, Office of Administrative Services, shall have overall control and supervision of the security of all records keeping systems and shall be responsible for monitoring the security standards set forth in these regulations.
</p>
<p>(b) A designated official (System Manager) shall be named who shall have management responsibility for each record system maintained by the agency and who shall be responsible for providing protection and accountability for such records at all times and for insuring that such records are secured in appropriate containers wherever not in use or in the direct control of authorized personnel.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.10 Security of records systems--manual and automated.
</b></p>
<p>The head of the agency has the responsibility of maintaining adequate technical, physical, and security safeguards to prevent unauthorized disclosure or destruction of manual and automatic record systems. These security safeguards shall apply to all systems in which identifiable personal data are processed or maintained including all reports and outputs from such systems which contain identifiable personal information. Such safeguards must be sufficient to prevent negligent, accidental, or unintentional disclosure, modification or destruction of any personal records or data and must furthermore minimize the extent technicians or knowledgeable persons could improperly obtain access to modify or destroy such records or data and shall further insure against such casual entry by unskilled persons without official reasons for access to such records or data.
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Manual systems.</i>(1) Records contained in records systems as defined herein may be used, held or stored only where facilities are adequate to prevent unauthorized access by persons within or without the agency.
</p>
<p>(2) All records systems when not under the personal control of the employees authorized to use same must be stored in an appropriate metal filing cabinet. Where appropriate, such cabinet shall have a three position dial-type combination lock, and/or be equipped with a steel lock bar secured by a GSA approved changeable combination padlock or in some such other securely locked cabinet as may be approved by GSA for the storage of such records. Certain systems are not of such confidential nature that their disclosure would harm an individual who is the subject of such record. Records in this category shall be maintained in steel cabinets without the necessity of combination locks.
</p>
<p>(3) Access to and use of systems of records shall be permitted only to persons whose official duties require such access within the agency, for routine use as defined in &#167; 308.4 and in the Peace Corps’ published systems of records notices, or for such other uses as may be provided herein.
</p>
<p>(4) Other than for access within the agency to persons needing such records in the performance of their official duties or routine uses as defined herein and in the Peace Corps’ systems of records notices or such other uses as provided herein, access to records within systems of records shall be permitted only to the individual to whom the record pertains or upon his or her written request to a designated personal representative.
</p>
<p>(5) Access to areas where records systems are stored will be limited to those persons whose official duties require work in such areas and proper accounting of removal of any records from storage areas shall be maintained at all times in the form directed by the Director, Administrative Services.
</p>
<p>(6) The agency shall assure that all persons whose official duties require access to and use of records contained in records systems are adequately trained to protect the security and privacy of such records.
</p>
<p>(7) The disposal and destruction of records within records systems shall be in accord with rules promulgated by the General Services Administration.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Automated systems.</i>(1) Identifiable personal information may be processed, stored or maintained by automatic data systems only where facilities or conditions are adequate to prevent unauthorized access to such systems in any form. Whenever such data contained in punch cards, magnetic tapes or discs are not under the personal control of an authorized person such information must be stored in a metal filing cabinet having a built-in three position combination lock, a metal filing cabinet equipped with a steel lock, a metal filing cabinet equipped with a steel lock bar secured with a General Services Administration (GSA) approved combination padlock, or in adequate containers or in a secured room or in such other facility having greater safeguards than those provided for herein.
</p>
<p>(2) Access to and use of identifiable personal data associated with automated data systems shall be limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. Proper control of personal data in any form associated with automated data systems shall be maintained at all times including maintenance of accountability records showing disposition of input and output documents.
</p>
<p>(3) All persons whose official duties require access to processing and maintenance of identifiable personal data and automated systems shall be adequately trained in the security and privacy of personal data.
</p>
<p>(4) The disposal and disposition of identifiable personal data and automated systems shall be carried on by shredding, burning or in the case of tapes of discs, degaussing, in accord with any regulations now or hereafter proposed by the GSA or other appropriate authority.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.11 Accounting for disclosure of records.
</b></p>
<p>Each office maintaining a system of records shall keep a written account of routine disclosures (see paragraphs (a) through (e) of this section) for all records within such system in the form prescribed by the Director, Office of Administrative Services. Disclosure made to employees of the agency in the normal course of their official duties or pursuant to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act need not be accounted for. Such written account shall contain the following:
</p>
<p>(a) The date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure of a record to any person or to another agency.
</p>
<p>(b) The name and address of the person or agency to whom the disclosure was made.
</p>
<p>(c) Sufficient information to permit the construction of a listing of all disclosures at appropriate periodic intervals.
</p>
<p>(d) The justification or basis upon which any release was made including any written documentation required when records are released for statistical or law enforcement purposes under the provisions of subsection (b) of the Act.
</p>
<p>(e) For the purpose of this part, the system of accounting for disclosure is not a system of records under the definitions hereof and no accounting need be maintained for the disclosure of accounting of disclosures.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.12 Contents of records systems.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The agency shall maintain in any records contained in any records system hereunder only such information about an individual as is accurate, relevant, and necessary to accomplish the purpose for which the agency acquired the information as authorized by statute or executive order.
</p>
<p>(b) In situations in which the information may result in adverse determinations about such individual’s rights, benefits and privileges under any Federal program, all information placed in records systems shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be collected from the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>(c) Each form or other document which an individual is expected to complete in order to provide information for any records system shall have appended thereto, or in the body of the document:
</p>
<p>(1) An indication of the authority authorizing the solicitation of the information and whether the provision of the information is mandatory or voluntary.
</p>
<p>(2) The purpose or purposes for which the information is intended to be used.
</p>
<p>(3) Routine uses which may be made of the information and published pursuant to &#167; 308.7 of this regulation.
</p>
<p>(4) The effect on the individual, if any, of not providing all or part of the required or requested information.
</p>
<p>(d) Records maintained in any system of records used by the agency to make any determinatioin about any individual shall be maintained with such accuracy, relevancy, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to assure fairness to the individual in the making of any determination about such individual: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the agency shall not be required to update or keep current retired records.
</p>
<p>(e) Before disseminating any record about an individual to any person other than an agency as defined in 5 U.S.C. 552(e) or pursuant to the provsions of the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552), the agency shall make reasonable efforts to assure that such records are accurate, complete, timely and relevant for agency purposes.
</p>
<p>(f) Under no circumstances shall the agency maintain any record about an individual with respect to or describing how such individual exercises rights guaranteed by the first amendment of the Constitution of the United States unless expressly authorized by statute or by the individual about whom the record is maintained or unless pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized law enforcement activity.
</p>
<p>(g) In the event any record is disclosed as a result of the order of a presiding judge of a court of competent jurisdiction, the agency shall make reasonable efforts to notify the individual whose record was so disclosed after the process becomes a matter of public record.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.13 Access to records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Director, Administrative Services, shall keep a current list of systems of records maintained by the agency and published in accordance with the provisions of these regulations.
</p>
<p>(b) Individuals requesting access to any record the agency maintains about him or her in a system of records shall be provided access to such records. Such requests shall be submitted in writing by mail, or in person during regular business hours, to the System Managers identified in the specific system notices. Systems maintained at overseas and dometic field offices may be addressed to the Country Director or Regional Service Center Manager. If assistance is needed, the Director, Office of Administrative Services, will provide agency addresses.
</p>
<p>(c) Requests for records from more than one system of records shall be directed to the Director, Office of Administrative Services, Peace Crops, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p>
<p>(d) Requests for access to or copies of records should contain, at a minimum, identifying information needed to locate any given record and a brief description of the item or items of information required. If the individual wishes access to specific documents the request should identify or describe as nearly as possible such documents.
</p>
<p>(e) A record may be disclosed to a representative of the person to whom a record relates who is authorized in writing to have access to the record by the person to whom it relates.
</p>
<p>(f) A request made in person will be promptly complied with if the records sought are in the immediate custody of the Peace Corps. Mailed or personal request for documents in storage which must be complied from more than one location, or which are otherwise not immediately available, will be acknowledge within ten working days, and the records requested will be provided as promptly thereafter as possible.
</p>
<p>(g) Medical or psychological records shall be disclosed to an individual unless in the judgment of the agency, access to such records might have an adverse effect upon such individual. When such determination has been made, the agency may require that the information be disclosed only to a physician chosen by the requesting individual. Such physician shall have full authority to disclose all or any portion of such record to the requesting individual in the exercise of his or her professional judgment.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.14 Specific exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>Records or portions of records in certain record systems specified in paragraphs (a) through (c) of this section shall be exempt from disclosure: <i>Provided, however,</i>That no such exemption shall apply to the provisions of &#167; 308.12(a) (maintaining records with accuracy, completeness, etc. as reasonably necessary for agency purposes); &#167; 308.12(b) (collecting information directly from the individual to whom it pertains); &#167; 308.12(c) (informing individuals asked to supply information of the purposes for which it is collected and whether it is mandatory); &#167; 308.12(g) (notifying the subjects of records disclosed under compulsory court process); &#167; 308.16(d)(3) (informing prior recipient of corrected or disputed records); &#167; 308.16(g) (civil remedies). With the above exceptions the following material shall be exempt from disclosure to the extent indicated:
</p>
<p>(a) Material in any system of records considered classified and exempt from disclosure under provisions of section 552(b)(1) of the Freedom of Information Act. Agency systems of records now containing such material are: Legal Files--Staff, Volunteers and Applicants; Security Records Peace Corps Staff/Volunteers and ACTION staff.
</p>
<p>(1) Authority: 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(1)
</p>
<p>(2) Reasons: To protect information classified in the interest of national defense or foreign policy.
</p>
<p>(b) Investigatory material compiled for the purposes of law enforcement: <i>Provided, however,</i>That if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that he or she would otherwise be entitled to by Federal law, or for which he or she would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, such material shall be provided to such individual except to the extent necessary to protect the identity of a source who furnished information to the government under an express promise that his or her identity would be held in confidence, or prior to the effective date of the Privacy Act of 1974, under an implied promise of such confidentiality of the identity of such source. Agency systems of records containing such investigatory material are: Discrimination Complaint Files; Employee Occupational Injury and Illness Reports; Legal Files--Staff, Volunteers and Applicants; Security Records--Peace Corps Staff/Volunteers and ACTION Staff.
</p>
<p>(1) Authority: 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2)
</p>
<p>(2) Reasons: To protect the identity of sources to whom proper promises of confidentiality have been made during investigations. Without these promises, sources will often be unwilling to provide information essential in adjudicating access in a fair and impartial manner.
</p>
<p>(c) Investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility or qualification for service as an employee or volunteer or for the obtaining of a Federal contract or for access to classified information: <i>Provided, however,</i>That such material shall be disclosed to the extent possible without revealing the identity of a source who furnished information to the government under an express promise of the confidentiality of his or her identity or, prior to the effective date of the Privacy Act of 1974, under an implied promise of such confidentiality of identity. Agency systems of records containing such material are: Contractors and Consultant Files; Discrimination Complaint Files; Legal Files--Staff, Volunteers and Applicants; Personal Service Contract Records--Peace Corps Staff/Volunteers and ACTION Staff; Staff Applicant and Personnel Records; Talent Bank; Volunteer Applicant and Service Record Systems.
</p>
<p>(1) Authority: 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5)
</p>
<p>(2) Reasons: To ensure the frankness of information used to determine whether Peace Corps Volunteers applicants and Peace Corps Staff applicants are qualified for service with the agency.
</p>
<p>(d) Records in the Office of Inspector General Investigative Files and Records system of records are exempt from certain provisions to the extent provided hereinafter.
</p>
<p>(1) To the extent that the system of records pertains to the enforcement of criminal laws, the Office of Inspector General Investigative Files and Records system of records is exempt from all sections of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) except the following sections: (b) relating to conditions of disclosure; (c)(1) and (2) relating to keeping and maintaining a disclosure accounting; (e)(4)(A) through (F) relating to publishing a system notice setting the name, location, categories of individuals and records, routine uses, and policies regarding storage, retrievability, access controls, retention and disposal of the records; (e)(6), (7), (9), (10), and (11) relating to dissemination and maintenance of records and (i) relating to criminal penalties. This system of records is also exempt from the provisions of &#167; 308.11 through &#167; 308.17 to the extent that the provisions of these sections conflict with this paragraph.
</p>
<p>(i) Authority: 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2).
</p>
<p>(ii) Reasons:
</p>
<p>(A) To prevent interference with law enforcement proceedings.
</p>
<p>(B) To avoid unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, by disclosure of information about third parties, including other subjects of investigations, investigators, and witnesses.
</p>
<p>(C) To protect the identity of Federal employees who furnish a complaint or information to OIG, consistent with section 7(b) of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. App. 3.
</p>
<p>(D) To protect the confidentiality of non-Federal employee sources of information.
</p>
<p>(E) To assure access to sources of confidential information, including those contained in Federal, State, and local criminal law enforcement information systems.
</p>
<p>(F) To prevent disclosure of law enforcement techniques and procedures.
</p>
<p>(G) To avoid endangering the life or physical safety of confidential sources.
</p>
<p>(2) To the extent that there may exist within this system of records investigative files compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of subsection (j)(2) of the Privacy Act, the OIG Investigative Files and Records system of records is exempt from the following sections of the Privacy Act: (c)(3) relating to access to the disclosure accounting; (d) relating to access to records; (e)(1) relating to the type of information maintained in the records; (e)(4) (G), (H), and (I) relating to publishing the system notice information as to agency procedures for access and amendment, and information as to the categories of sources or records; and (f) relating to developing agency rules for gaining access and making corrections. <i>Provided, however,</i>That if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that they would otherwise be entitled by Federal law, or for which they would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, such material shall be provided to such individual except to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or, prior to January 1, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence. This system of records is also exempt from the provisions of &#167; 308.11 through &#167; 308.17 to the extent that the provisions of these sections conflict with this paragraph.
</p>
<p>(i) Authority: 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2)
</p>
<p>(ii) Reasons:
</p>
<p>(A) To prevent interference with law enforcement proceedings.
</p>
<p>(B) To protect investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes.
</p>
<p>(C) To avoid unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, by disclosure of information about third parties, including other subjects of investigation, law enforcement personnel, and sources of information.
</p>
<p>(D) To fulfill commitments made to protect the confidentiality of sources.
</p>
<p>(E) To protect the identity of Federal employees who furnish a complaint or information to the OIG, consistent with Section 7(b) of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. App. 3.
</p>
<p>(F) To assure access to sources of confidential information, including those contained in Federal, State, and local criminal law enforcement systems.
</p>
<p>(G) [Reserved]
</p>
<p>(H) To prevent disclosure of law enforcement techniques and procedures.
</p>
<p>(I) To avoid endangering the life or physical safety of confidential sources and law enforcement personnel.
</p>
<p>[50 FR 1844, Jan. 14, 1985, as amended at 58 FR 39657, July 26, 1993]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.15 Identification of requesters.
</b></p>
<p>The agency shall require reasonable identification of all individuals who request access to records to assure that records are not disclosed to persons not entitled to such access.
</p>
<p>(a) In the event an individual requests disclosure in person, such individual shall be required to show an identification card such as a driver’s license, etc., containing a photo and a sample signature of such individual. Such individual may also be required to sign a statement under oath as to his or her identity acknowledging that he or she is aware of the penalties for improper disclosure under the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974.
</p>
<p>(b) In the event that disclosure is requested by mail, the agency may request such information as may be necessary to reasonably assure that the individual making such request is properly identified. In certain cases, the agency may require that a mail request be notarized with an indication that the notary received an acknowledgment of identity from the individual making such request.
</p>
<p>(c) In the event an individual is unable to provide suitable documentation or identification, the agency may require a signed notarized statement asserting the identity of the individual and stipulating that the individual understands that knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another person under false pretenses is punishable by a fine of up to $5,000.
</p>
<p>(d) In the event a requester wishes to be accompanied by another person while reviewing his or her records, the agency may require a written statement authorizing discussion of his or her records in the presence of the accompanying representative or other persons.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.16 Amendment of records and appeals with respect thereto.
</b></p>
<p>(a) In the event an individual desires to request an amendment of his or her record, he or she may do so by submitting such written request to the Director, Administrative Services, Peace Corps, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20526. The Director, Administrative Services, shall provide assistance in preparing any amendment upon request and a written acknowledgment of receipt of such request within 10 working days after the receipt thereof from the individual who requested the amendment. Such acknowledgment may, if necessary, request any additional information needed to make a determination with respect to such request. If the agency decides to comply with the request within the 10 day period, no written acknowledgment is necessary: <i>Provided, however,</i>That a certification of the change shall be provided to such individual within such period.
</p>
<p>(b) Promptly after acknowledgment of the receipt of a request for an amendment the agency shall take one of the following actions:
</p>
<p>(1) Make any corrections of any portion of the record which the individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely or complete.
</p>
<p>(2) Inform the individual of its refusal to amend the record in accord with the request together with the reason for such refusal and the procedures established for requesting review of such refusal by the head of the agency or his or her designee. Such notice shall include the name and business address of the reviewing official.
</p>
<p>(3) Refer the request to the agency that has control of and maintains the record in those instances where the record requested remains the property of the controlling agency and not of the Peace Corps.
</p>
<p>(c) In reviewing a request to amend the record the agency shall assess the accuracy, relevance, timeliness and completeness of the record with due and appropriate regard for fairness to the individual about whom the record is maintained. In making such determination, the agency shall consult criteria for determining record quality published in pertinent chapters of the <i>Federal Personnel Manual</i>and to the extent possible shall accord therewith.
</p>
<p>(d) In the event the agency agrees with the individual’s request to amend such record it shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Advise the individual in writing,
</p>
<p>(2) Correct the record accordingly, and
</p>
<p>(3) Advise all previous recipients of a record which was corrected of the correction and its substance.
</p>
<p>(e) In the event the agency, after an initial review of the request to amend a record, disagrees with all or a portion of it, the agency shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Advise the individual of its refusal and the reasons therefore,
</p>
<p>(2) Inform the individual that he or she may request further review in accord with the provisions of these regulations, and
</p>
<p>(3) Specify The name and address of the person to whom the request should be directed.
</p>
<p>(f) In the event an individual requester disagrees with the initial agency determination, he or she may appeal such determination to the Director of the Peace Corps or his or her designee. Such request for review must be made within 30 days after receipt by the requester of the initial refusal to amend.
</p>
<p>(g) If after review the Director or designee refuses to amend the record as requested he or she shall advise the individual requester of such refusal and the reasons for same; of his or her right to file a concise statement in the record of the reasons for disagreeing with the decision of the agency; of the procedures for filing a statement of disagreement and of the fact that such statement so filed will be made available to anyone to whom the record is subsequently disclosed together with a brief statement of the agency summarizing its reasons for refusal, if the agency decides to place such brief statement in the record. The agency shall have the authority to limit the length of any statement to be filed, such limit to depend upon the record involved. The agency shall also inform such individual that prior recipients of the disputed record will be provided a copy of both statements of the dispute to the extent that the accounting of disclosures has been maintained and of the individual’s right to seek judicial review of the agency’s refusal to amend the record.
</p>
<p>(h) If after review the official determines that the record should be amended in accordance with the individual’s request, the agency shall proceed as provided above in the event a request is granted upon initial demand.
</p>
<p>(i) Final agency determination of an individual’s request for a review shall be concluded with 30 working days from the date of receipt of the review request: <i>Provided, however,</i>That the Director or designee may determine that fair and equitable review cannot be made within that time. If such circumstances occur, the individual shall be notified in writing of the additional time required and of the approximate date on which determination of the review is expected to be completed.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.17 Denial of access and appeals with respect thereto.
</b></p>
<p>In the event that the agency finds it necessary to deny any individual access to a record about such individual pursuant to provisions of the Privacy Act or of these regulations, a response to the original request shall be made in writing within ten working days after the date of such initial request. The denial shall specify the reasons for such refusal or denial and advise the individual of the reasons therefore, and of his or her right to an appeal within the agency and/or judicial review under the provisions of the Act.
</p>
<p>(a) In the event an individual desires to appeal any denial of access, he or she may do so in writing by addressing such appeal to the attention of the Director, Peace Corps, or designee identified in such denial. Such appeal should be addressed to Director, Peace Corps, c/o Office of Administrative Services, Room P-314, 806 Connecticut Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20526.
</p>
<p>(b) The Director, or designee, shall review a request from a denial of access and shall make a determination with respect to such appeal within 30 days after receipt thereof. Notice of such determination shall be provided to the individual making the request in writing. If such appeal is denied in whole or in part, such notice shall include notification of the right of the person making such request to have judicial review of the denial as provided in the Act.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 308.18 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>No fees shall be charged for search time or for any other time expended by the agency to produce a record. Copies of records may be charged for at the rate of 10 cents per page provided that one copy of any record shall be provided free of charge.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
