<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>
<pai>
	<agency toc="yes">
<name>National Indian Gaming Commission</name>
<abbrev>
NIGC</abbrev>

        <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
            <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
        </previousPubs>  
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-14/pdf/2021-26943.pdf</url>
            <title>NIGC Reasonable Accommodations Records.</title>
            <date year="21" month="12" day="14" />
        </previouslyPublished>



        <section id="nigc1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Indian Gaming Individuals Record System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Indian Gaming Commission, Suite 250, 1850 M St., NW, Washington, DC 20036-5803.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Key employees and primary management officials as defined under 25 CFR part 502.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Copies of applications for employment in gaming operations on Indian lands; information collected by the staff and members of the Commission; copies of reports of background investigations. Such information includes: (1) Full name, other names used, social security number(s) and birth date; (2) business and employment positions held, business and residence addresses, driver's license numbers; (3) the names and current addresses of personal references; (4) current business and residence telephone numbers; (5) a description of any previous business relationships with Indian tribes; (6) a description of any previous business relationships with the gaming industry generally; (7) the name and address of any licensing or regulatory agency with which the person has filed an application for a license or permit relating to gaming; (8) for any felony for which there is an ongoing prosecution or a conviction, the charge, the name and address of the court involved, and the date and disposition; (9) for any misdemeanor conviction or ongoing misdemeanor prosecution, the name and address of the court involved and the date and disposition; and (10) whatever other information a tribe deems relevant.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>25 U.S.C. 2710.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Used by Commission members and staff to verify suitability of key employees and primary management officials in Indian gaming operations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To disclose relevant information to Federal, State, tribal, or local law enforcement of regulatory agencies to verify information supplied by applicant key employees and primary management officials in connection with determining suitability for employment in an Indian gaming operation.
</p><p>2. To disclose relevant information to tribes that employ or may wish to employ individuals in Indian gaming operations.
</p><p>3. In the event that records in this system indicate a violation or potential violation of law, criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, the relevant records may be referred to the agency charged with responsibility for investigating or prosecuting such violation.
</p><p>4. To disclose relevant information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual.
</p><p>5. To disclose relevant information to a Federal, State, local, or tribal agency (or their agents) that is involved in a civil regulatory or enforcement action to protect the integrity of Indian gaming.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper files, machine-processable storage media, and other computer storage devices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee name, gaming operation where employed, social security number, and birth date.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Folders are maintained in locked cabinets to which only authorized personnel have access; automated records are protected by computer passwords and tape or disc library physical security.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration requirements. A records retention and disposal plan is under development. At present, the Commission contemplates disposal of the records after 10 years.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Records Manager, NIGC, Suite 250, 1850 M Street, NW, Washington, DC 20036-5803.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons wishing to inquire whether the System contains information concerning themselves may submit inquiries to the Records Manager, NIGC, at the address above. Such persons must provide proof of their identity by including a statement, signed by the individual and either notarized or witnessed by two persons (include addresses of witnesses). The statement must be that the person is who he or she claims to be. If an individual makes an inquiry in person, such person must present the Commission with a statement signed by the individual and either notarized or witnessed by two persons (include addresses of witnesses).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons wishing access to their records should contact the Records Manager, NIGC, at the address above. Such persons must provide proof of their identity by including a statement, signed by the individual and either notarized or witnessed by two persons (include addresses of witnesses). The statement must be that the person is who he or she claims to be. If an individual makes an inquiry in person, such person must present the Commission with a statement signed by the individual and either notarized or witnessed by two persons (include addresses of witnesses). Such persons must comply with the Privacy Act regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who has reviewed a record pertaining to him or her may request that the Commission amend all or any part of that record by sending a request to the Records Manager. A request must contain the name of the individual requesting the amendment, the name of the system of records where the record is maintained, a copy of the record sought to be amended or a description of that record, a statement of the material requested to be amended, and the basis for amendment, including material that substantiates the reason for the amendment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual applications for employment in Indian gaming operations; background investigation reports compiled by tribes or by contractors; persons interviewed as part of a background investigation; Federal, state, foreign, tribal, and local law enforcement and regulatory agencies; Commission staff and members; credit bureaus.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) the Commission is claiming exemptions from certain provisions of the Act for portions of its records. The exemptions and the reasons for them are described in the regulations.
	</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
        section id="nigc2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> NIGC Reasonable Accommodations Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained primarily by the NIGC Human Resource Office located at 90 K Street, NE, Suite 200, Washington, DC 20002.  Records may be located in locked cabinets and offices, on NIGC’s local area network, or in designated U.S. data centers for FedRAMP-authorized cloud service providers.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Human Resources Administrator, 90 K Street, NE, Suite 200, Washington, DC 20002.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 U.S.C. 701, 791, 794; Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42 U.S.C. 2000e; 29 CFR 1605 (Guidelines on Discrimination Because of Religion); 29 CFR 1614 (Federal Sector Equal Employment Opportunity); 29 CFR 1614 (Regulations to Implement the Equal Employment Provisions of the Americans With Disabilities Act); 5 U.S.C. 302, 1103; Executive Order 13164, Requiring Federal Agencies to Establish Procedures to Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation (July 26, 2000); and Executive Order 13548, Increasing Federal Employment of  Individuals with Disabilities (July 26, 2010).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purpose of this system of records is to allow NIGC to collect and maintain records on applicants for employment, employees, and other individuals who participate in NIGC programs or activities who request or receive reasonable accommodations or other appropriate modifications from NIGC for medical or religious reasons; to process, evaluate, and make decisions on individual requests; and to track and report the processing of such requests agency-wide to comply with applicable requirements in law and policy.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Applicants for Federal employment, Federal employees, and visitors to Federal buildings who requested and/or received reasonable accommodations or other appropriate modifications from NIGC for medical or  religious reasons. It also covers individuals or representatives (e.g., a family member or attorney) authorized to request reasonable accommodation on behalf of an applicant for employment or employee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Requester’s name;</p>
	<p>Requester’s status (applicant or current employee);</p>
	<p>Date of request;</p>
	<p>Employee’s position title, grade, series, step;</p>
	<p>Position title, grade, series, step of the position the requester is applying for;</p>
	<p>Requester’s contact information (addresses, phone numbers, and email addresses);</p>
	<p>Description of the requester’s medical condition or disability and any medical documentation provided in support of the request; Requester’s statement of a sincerely held religious belief and any additional information provided concerning that religious belief and the need for an accommodation to exercise that belief;</p>
	<p>Description of the accommodation being requested;</p>
	<p>Description of previous requests for accommodation;</p>
	<p>Whether the request was made orally or in writing;</p>
	<p>Documentation by an NIGC official concerning whether the disability is obvious, and the accommodation is obvious and uncomplicated, whether medical documentation is required to evaluate the request, whether research is necessary regarding possible accommodations, and any extenuating circumstances that prevent the NIGC official from meeting the relevant timeframe;</p>
	<p>Whether the request for reasonable accommodation was granted or denied, and if denied the reason for the denial;</p>
	<p>The amount of time taken to process the request;</p>
	<p>The sources of technical assistance consulted in trying to identify a possible reasonable accommodation;</p>
	<p>Any reports or evaluations prepared in determining whether to grant or deny the request; and</p>
	<p>Any other information collected or developed in connection with the request for a reasonable accommodation.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information is obtained from the individuals who request and/or receive a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modification from NIGC, directly or indirectly from an individual’s medical provider or another medical professional who evaluates the request, directly or indirectly from an individual’s religious or spiritual advisors or institutions, and from management officials.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed outside NIGC as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
<p>a. To the Department of Justice, including Offices of the U.S. Attorneys; another Federal agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative, or administrative body; another party in litigation before a court,  adjudicative, or administrative body; or to a court, adjudicative, or administrative body. Such disclosure is permitted only when it is relevant or necessary to the litigation or proceeding, and one of the following is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation:</p>
<p>(1) NIGC, or any component thereof;</p>
<p>(2) Any employee or former employee of NIGC in his or her official capacity;</p>
<p>(3) Any employee or former employee of NIGC in his or her capacity where the Department of Justice or NIGC has agreed to represent the employee;</p>
<p>(4) The United States, a Federal agency, or another party in litigation before a court, adjudicative, or administrative body, upon the NIGC General Counsel’s approval, pursuant to 5 CFR part 295 or otherwise.</p>
<p>b. To the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates it is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
<p>c. To a member of Congress for the record of an individual in response to an inquiry made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
<p>d. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
<p>e. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) NIGC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) NIGC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach, there is a risk of harm to individuals, NIGC (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with NIGC’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>f. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when NIGC determines that information from the system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
<p>g. To contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for NIGC when NIGC determines that it is necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to NIGC employees.</p>
<p>h. To another federal agency or commission with responsibility for labor or employment relations or other issues, including equal employment opportunity and reasonable accommodation issues, when that agency or commission has jurisdiction over reasonable accommodation.</p>
<p>i. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official who engages in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who requested a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modification.</p>
<p>j. To another Federal agency, including but not limited to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and the Office of Special counsel to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements related to reasonable accommodation.</p>
<p>k. To a Federal agency or entity authorized to procure assistive technologies and services in response to a request for reasonable accommodation.</p>
<p>l. To first aid and safety personnel if the individual’s medical condition requires emergency treatment.</p>
<p>m. To another Federal agency or oversight body charged with evaluating NIGC’s compliance with the laws, regulations, and policies governing reasonable accommodation requests.</p>
<p>n. To another Federal agency pursuant to a written agreement with NIGC to provide services (such as medical evaluations), when necessary, in support of reasonable accommodation decisions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The records in this system of records are stored electronically on NIGC’s local area network or with FedRAMPauthorized cloud service providers segregated from non-government traffic and data, with access limited to a small number of personnel. In addition, paper records are stored in locked file cabinets in access-restricted offices.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records may be retrieved by name or other unique personal identifiers.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system of records are maintained in accordance with GRS 2.3 and are destroyed three years after separation from the agency or all appeals are concluded, whichever is later, but longer retention is authorized if requested for business use.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is stored. Access to the paper and electronic records in this system of records is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals seeking notification of and access to their records in this system of records may submit a request in writing to the National Indian Gaming Commission, FOIA Office, 1849 C Street, N.W., Mail Stop # 1621 Washington, D.C., 20240, ATTN: NIGC Privacy Officer; or by emailing foia_requests@NIGC.gov. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located: 1. Full name. 2. Signature. 3. The reason why the individual believes this system contains information about him/her. 4. The address to which the information should be sent. Individuals requesting access must also comply with NIGC’s Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and access to records (25 CFR 515).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals wishing to request amendment of records about them contained in this system of records may do so by writing to the National Indian Gaming Commission, FOIA Office, 1849 C Street, N.W., Mail Stop # 1621 Washington, D.C., 20240, ATTN: NIGC Privacy Officer; or by emailing foia_request@nigc.gov. Requests for amendment of records should include the words ‘‘PRIVACY ACT AMENDMENT REQUEST’’ in capital letters at the top of the request letter or in the subject line of the email. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located:</p>
<p>1. Full name.</p>
<p>2. Signature.</p>
<p>3. Precise identification of the information to be amended.</p>
<p>Individuals requesting amendment must also comply with NIGC’s Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and access to records (25 CFR 515)The agency procedures whereby an individual can be notified at his or her request how he or she can contest the content of any record pertaining to him or her in the system.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>See "Record Access Procedures.".</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any Privacy Act exemptions</p>
<p>promulgated for the system.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="history"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

        
        <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
            <regulationsTitle number="25">
                <heading>Indians</heading>
                <regulationsChapter number="III">
                    <heading>National Indian Gaming Commission</heading>
                    <regulationsPart number="515">
                        <heading> PRIVACY ACT PROCEDURES </heading>
                        <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Sec. </p>
                    <p>515.1 Purpose and scope. </p>
                    <p>515.2 Definitions. </p>
                    <p>515.3 Request for access to records. </p>
                    <p>515.4 Responsibility for responding to requests.</p>
                        <p>515.5 Responses to requests for access to records. </p>
                        <p>515.6 Request for amendment or correction of records. </p>
                        <p>515.7 Appeals of initial agency adverse determination. </p>
                        <p>515.8 Requests for an accounting of record disclosure. </p>
                        <p>515.9 Notice of court-ordered and emergency disclosures. </p>
                        <p>515.10 Fees. </p>
                        <p>515.11 Penalties. </p>
                        <p>515.12 [Reserved] </p>
                        <p>515.13 Specific exemptions. </p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
        <p><b>Authority:</b>5 U.S.C. 552a
        </p>

        <p><b>Source:</b>82 FR 8141, Jan. 24, 2017, unless otherwise noted.
        </p>
                <xhtmlContent>
        <p>
            <b>
                &#167;  515.1
                Purpose and scope.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>This part contains the regulations the National Indian Gaming Commission (Commission) follows in implementing the Privacy Act of 1974. These regulations should be read together with the Privacy Act, which provides additional information about records maintained on individuals. The regulations in this part apply to all records contained within systems of records maintained by the Commission that are retrieved by an individual's name or personal identifier. They describe the procedures by which individuals may request access to records about themselves, request amendment or correction of those records, and request an accounting of disclosures of those records by the Commission. The Commission shall also process all Privacy Act requests for access to records under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 5 U.S.C. 552, and the Commission's FOIA regulations contained in 25 CFR part 517, which gives requesters maximum disclosure.  </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.2
                Definitions.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>For the purposes of this subpart:  </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>Individual </i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Maintain </i> means store, collect, use, or disseminate.
        </p>
        <p>
            (c)  <i>Record </i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by the Commission, including education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history, and that contains the individual's name, or identifying number, symbol, or other identifier assigned to the individual, such as social security number, finger or voice print, or photograph.
        </p>
        <p>
            (d)  <i>System of records </i> means a group of any records under the control of the Commission from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifier assigned to the individual.
        </p>
        <p>
            (e)  <i>Routine use </i> means use of a record for a purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
        </p>
        <p>
            (f)  <i>Working day </i> means a Federal workday that does not include Saturdays, Sundays, or Federal holidays.
        </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.3
                Request for access to records.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>How made and addressed. </i> Any individual may make a request to the Commission for access to records about him or herself. Such requests shall conform to the requirements of this section. The request may be made in person at 90 K Street NE, Suite 200, Washington, DC 20002 during the hours of 9 a.m. to 12 noon and 2 p.m. to 5 p.m. Monday through Friday, in writing at NIGC Attn: Privacy Act Office, 1849 C Street NW, Mail Stop # 1621, Washington, DC 20240, or via electronic mail addressed to <i>PARequests@nigc.gov.</i>
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Description of records sought. </i> Each request for access to records must describe the records sought in enough detail to enable Commission personnel to locate the system of records containing them with a reasonable amount of effort. Whenever possible, the request should describe the records sought, the time periods in which the records were compiled, any tribal gaming facility with which they were associated, and the name or identifying number of each system of records in which the records are kept.
        </p>
        <p>
            (c)  <i>Agreement to pay fees. </i> Requests shall also include a statement indicating the maximum amount of fees the requester is willing to pay to obtain the requested information. The requester must send acknowledgment to the Privacy Act Officer indicating his/her willingness to pay the fees. Absent such an acknowledgment within the specified time frame, the request will be considered incomplete, no further work shall be done, and the request will be administratively closed.
        </p>
        <p>
            (d)  <i>Verification of identity. </i> When making a request for access to records the individual seeking access must provide verification of identity. The requester must provide a full name, current address, and date and place of birth. The request must be signed and must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, which is a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury as a substitute for notarization. In order to assist in the identification and location of requested records, a request may also, at the requester's option, include a social security number.
        </p>
        <p>
            (e)  <i>Verification of guardianship. </i> When making a request as a parent or guardian of a minor or as the guardian of someone determined by a court to be incompetent, for access to records about that individual, the request must establish:
        </p>
        <p>(1) The identity of the individual who is the subject of the record by stating the name, current address, date and place of birth, and, at the requester's option, the social security number of the individual;  </p>
        <p>(2) The requester's own identity, as required in paragraph (d) of this section;  </p>
        <p>(3) That the requester is the parent or guardian of the individual and proof of such relationship by providing a birth certificate showing parentage or a court order establishing guardianship; and </p>
        <p>(4) That the requester is acting on behalf of that individual in making the request.  </p>
        <p>
            (f)  <i>Verification in the case of third party information requests. </i> Any individual who desires to have a record covered by this part disclosed to or mailed to another person may designate such person and authorize such person to act as his or her agent for that specific purpose. The authorization shall be in writing, signed by the individual whose record is requested, and notarized or witnessed as provided in paragraph (d) of this section.
        </p>
        <p>
            (g)  <i>In-person disclosures. </i> An individual to whom a record is to be disclosed in person, pursuant to this section, may have a person of his or her own choosing accompany him or her when the record is disclosed. If a requester is accompanied by another individual, the requester shall be required to authorize in writing any discussion of the records in the presence of the other person.
        </p>
                    <p>[82 FR 8141, Jan. 24, 2017, as amended at 82 FR 34403, July 25, 2017]</p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.4
                Responsibility for responding to requests.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>In general. </i> In determining which records are responsive to a request, the Commission ordinarily will include only records in its possession as of the date it begins its search for records. If any other date is used, the Privacy Act Officer shall inform the requester of that date.
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Authority to grant or deny requests. </i> The Privacy Act Officer shall make initial determinations either to grant or deny in whole or in part access to records.
        </p>
        <p>
            (c)  <i>Consultations and referrals. </i> When the Commission receives a request for a record in its possession, the Privacy Act Officer shall determine whether another agency of the Federal Government is better able to determine whether the record is exempt from disclosure under the Privacy Act. If the Privacy Act Officer determines that it is best able to process the record in response to the request, then it shall do so. If the Privacy Act Officer determines that it is not best able to process the record, then it shall either:
        </p>
        <p>(1) Respond to the request regarding that record, after consulting with the agency best able to determine whether to disclose it and with any other agency that has a substantial interest in it; or </p>
        <p>(2) Refer the responsibility for responding to the request regarding that record to the agency best able to determine whether to disclose it, or to another agency that originated the record. Ordinarily, the agency that originated a record will be presumed to be best able to determine whether to disclose it.  </p>
        <p>
            (d)  <i>Notice of referral. </i> Whenever the Privacy Act Officer refers all or any part of the responsibility for responding to a request to another agency, it ordinarily shall notify the requester of the referral and inform the requester of the name of each agency to which the request has been referred and of the part of the request that has been referred.
        </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.5
                Responses to requests for access to records.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>Acknowledgement of requests. </i> Upon receipt of a request, the Privacy Act Officer ordinarily shall, within 20 working days, send an acknowledgement letter which shall confirm the requester's agreement to pay fees under &#167;  515.9 and provide an assigned request number.
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Grants of requests for access. </i> Once the Privacy Act Officer makes a determination to grant a request for access in whole or in part, it shall notify the requester in writing. The notice shall inform the requester of any fee charged under &#167;  515.9 of this part and the Privacy Act Officer shall disclose records to the requester promptly on payment of any applicable fee. If a request is made in person, the Privacy Act Officer will disclose the records to the requester directly, in a manner not unreasonably disruptive of its operations, on payment of any applicable fee and with a written record made of the grant of the request. If a requester is accompanied by another individual, the requester shall be required to authorize in writing any discussion of the records in the presence of the other person.
        </p>
        <p>
            (c)  <i>Adverse determinations of requests for access. </i> If the Privacy Act Officer makes any adverse determination denying a request for access in any respect, it shall notify the requester of that determination in writing. The notification letter shall be signed by the official making the determination and include:
        </p>
        <p>(1) The name and title of the person responsible for the denial;  </p>
        <p>(2) A brief statement of the reason(s) for the denial, including any Privacy Act exemption(s) applied to the denial;  </p>
        <p>(3) A statement that the denial may be appealed under &#167; 515.7 and a description of the requirements of &#167; 515.7.  </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.6
                Request for amendment or correction of records.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>How made and addressed. </i> An individual may make a request for an amendment or correction to a Commission record about that individual by writing directly to the Privacy Act Officer, following the procedures in &#167; 515.3. The request should identify each particular record in question, state the amendment or correction that is sought, and state why the record is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete. The request may include any documentation that would be helpful to substantiate the reasons for the amendment sought.
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Privacy Act Officer response. </i> The Privacy Act Officer shall, not later than 10 working days after receipt of a request for an amendment or correction of a record, acknowledge receipt of the request and provide notification of whether the request is granted or denied. If the request is granted in whole or in part, the Privacy Act Officer shall describe the amendment or correction made and shall advise the requester of the right to obtain a copy of the amended or corrected record. If the request is denied in whole or in part, the Privacy Act Officer shall send a letter signed by the denying official stating:
        </p>
        <p>(1) The reason(s) for the denial; and </p>
        <p>(2) The procedure for appeal of the denial under paragraph (c) of this section.  </p>
        <p>
            (c)  <i>Appeals. </i> A requester may appeal a denial of a request for amendment or correction in the same manner as a denial of a request for access as described in &#167;  515.7. If the appeal is denied, the requester shall be advised of the right to file a Statement of Disagreement as described in paragraph (d) of this section and of the right under the Privacy Act for judicial review of the decision.
        </p>
        <p>
            (d)  <i>Statements of Disagreement. </i> If the appeal under this section is denied in whole or in part, the requester has the right to file a Statement of Disagreement that states the reason(s) for disagreeing with the Privacy Act Officer's denial of the request for amendment or correction. Statements of Disagreement must be concise, must clearly identify each part of any record that is disputed, and should be no longer than one typed page for each fact disputed. The Statement of Disagreement shall be placed in the system of records in which the disputed record is maintained and the record shall be marked to indicate a Statement of Disagreement has been filed.
        </p>
        <p>
            (e)  <i>Notification of amendment, correction, or disagreement. </i> Within 30 working days of the amendment or correction of the record, the Privacy Act Officer shall notify all persons, organizations, or agencies to which it previously disclosed the record, and if an accounting of that disclosure was made, that the record has been amended or corrected. If a Statement of Disagreement was filed, the Commission shall append a copy of it to the disputed record whenever the record is disclosed and may also append a concise statement of its reason(s) for denying the request to amend the record.
        </p>
        <p>
            (f)  <i>Records not subject to amendment. </i> Section 515.13 lists the records that are exempt from amendment or correction.
        </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.7
                Appeals of initial adverse agency determination.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>Adverse determination. </i> An initial adverse agency determination of a request may consist of: A determination to withhold any requested record in whole or in part; a determination that a requested record does not exist or cannot be located; a determination that the requested record is not a record subject to the Privacy Act; a determination that a record will not be amended; a determination to deny a request for an accounting; a determination on any disputed fee matter; and any associated denial of a request for expedited treatment under the Commission's FOIA regulations.
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Appeals. </i> If the Privacy Act Officer issues an adverse determination in response to a request, the requester may file a written notice of appeal. The notice shall be accompanied by the original request, the initial adverse determination that is being appealed, and a statement describing why the adverse determination was in error. The appeal shall be addressed to the Privacy Act Appeals Officer at the locations listed in &#167; 515.3 of this part no later than 90 calendar days after the date of the letter denying the request. Both the appeal letter and envelope should be marked Privacy Act Appeal; Any Privacy Act appeals submitted via electronic mail should state Privacy Act Appeal in the subject line.
        </p>
        <p>
            (c)  <i>Responses to appeals. </i> The decision on appeal will be made in writing within 20 working days of receipt of the notice of appeal by the Privacy Act Appeals Officer. For good cause shown, however, the Privacy Act Appeals Officer may extend the 20 day working period. If such an extension is taken, the requester shall be promptly notified of such extension and the anticipated date of decision. A decision affirming an adverse determination in whole or in part will include a brief statement of the reason(s) for the determination, including any Privacy Act exemption(s) applied. If the adverse determination is reversed or modified in whole or in part, the requester will be notified in a written decision and the request will be reprocessed in accordance with that appeal decision. The response to the appeal shall also advise of the right to institute a civil action in a federal district court for judicial review of the decision.
        </p>
        <p>
            (d)  <i>When appeal is required. </i> In order to institute a civil action in a federal district court for judicial review of an adverse determination, a requester must first appeal it under this section.
        </p>
                    <p>[82 FR 8141, Jan. 24, 2017, as amended at 82 FR 34403, July 25, 2017]</p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.8
                Requests for an accounting of record disclosure.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>How made and addressed. </i> Subject to the exceptions listed in paragraph (b) of this section, an individual may make a request for an accounting of the disclosures of any record about that individual that the Commission has made to another person, organization, or agency. The accounting contains the date, nature and purpose of each disclosure, as well as the name and address of the person, organization, or agency to which the disclosure was made. The request for an accounting should identify each particular record in question and should be made in writing to the Commission's Privacy Act Officer, following the procedures in &#167;  515.3.
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Where accountings are not required. </i> The Commission is not required to provide an accounting where they relate to:
        </p>
        <p>(1) Disclosures for which accountings are not required to be kept, such as those that are made to employees of the Commission who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties and disclosures that are made under section 552 of title 5;  </p>
        <p>(2) Disclosures made to law enforcement agencies for authorized law enforcement activities in response to written requests from those law enforcement agencies specifying the law enforcement activities for which the disclosures are sought; or </p>
        <p>(3) Disclosures made from law enforcement systems of records that have been exempted from accounting requirements.  </p>
        <p>
            (c)  <i>Appeals. </i> A requester may appeal a denial of a request for an accounting in the same manner as a denial of a request for access as described in &#167;  515.7 of this part and the same procedures will be followed.
        </p>
        <p>
            (d)  <i>Preservation of accountings. </i> All accountings made under this section will be retained for at least five years or the life of the record, whichever is longer, after the disclosure for which the accounting is made.
        </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.9
                Notice of court-ordered and emergency disclosures.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>
            (a)  <i>Court-ordered disclosures. </i> When a record pertaining to an individual is required to be disclosed by a court order, the Privacy Act Officer shall make reasonable efforts to provide notice of this to the individual. Notice shall be given within a reasonable time after the Privacy Act Officer's receipt of the order-except that in a case in which the order is not a matter of public record, the notice shall be given only after the order becomes public. This notice shall be mailed to the individual's last known address and shall contain a copy of the order and a description of the information disclosed. Notice shall not be given if disclosure is made from a criminal law enforcement system of records that has been exempted from the notice requirement.
        </p>
        <p>
            (b)  <i>Emergency disclosures. </i> Upon disclosing a record pertaining to an individual made under compelling circumstances affecting health or safety, the Privacy Act Officer shall, within a reasonable time, notify that individual of the disclosure. This notice shall be mailed to the individual's last known address and shall state the nature of the information disclosed; the person, organization, or agency to which it was disclosed; the date of disclosure; and the compelling circumstances justifying disclosure.
        </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.10
                Fees.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>The Commission shall charge fees for duplication of records under the Privacy Act in the same way in which it charges duplication fees under &#167; 517.9 of this chapter. No search or review fee may be charged for any record. Additionally, when the Privacy Act Officer makes a copy of a record as a necessary part of reviewing the record or granting access to the record, the Commission shall not charge for the cost of making that copy. Otherwise, the Commission may charge a fee sufficient to cover the cost of duplicating a record.  </p>

                    <p>[82 FR 8141, Jan. 24, 2017, as amended at 82 FR 34403, July 25, 2017] </p>
                    <p>
            <b>
                &#167;515.11
                Penalties.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>Any person who makes a false statement in connection with any request for access to a record, or an amendment thereto, under this part, is subject to the penalties prescribed in 18 U.S.C. 494 and 495.  </p>

        <p>
            <b>&#167; 515.12  [Reserved] </b>
        </p>

        <p>
            <b>
                &#167; 515.13
                Specific exemptions.
            </b>
        </p>
        <p>(a) The following systems of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1) and (f):  </p>
        <p>(1) Indian Gaming Individuals Records System.  </p>
        <p>(2) Management Contract Individuals Record System.  </p>
        <p>(b) The exemptions under paragraph (a) of this section apply only to the extent that information in these systems is subject to exemption under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). When compliance would not appear to interfere with or adversely affect the overall responsibilities of the Commission, with respect to licensing of key employees and primary management officials for employment in an Indian gaming operation or verifying the suitability of an individual who has a financial interest in, or management responsibility for a management contract, the applicable exemption may be waived by the Commission.  </p>
        <p>(c) Exemptions from the particular sections are justified for the following reasons:  </p>
        <p>(1) From 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), because making available the accounting of disclosures to an individual who is the subject of a record could reveal investigative interest. This would permit the individual to take measures to destroy evidence, intimidate potential witnesses, or flee the area to avoid the investigation.  </p>
        <p>(2) From 5 U.S.C. 552a(d), (e)(1), and (f) concerning individual access to records, when such access could compromise classified information related to national security, interfere with a pending investigation or internal inquiry, constitute an unwarranted invasion of privacy, reveal a sensitive investigative technique, or pose a potential threat to the Commission or its employees or to law enforcement personnel. Additionally, access could reveal the identity of a source who provided information under an express promise of confidentiality.  </p>
        <p>(3) From 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(2), because to require the Commission to amend information thought to be incorrect, irrelevant, or untimely, because of the nature of the information collected and the length of time it is maintained, would create an impossible administrative and investigative burden by continually forcing the Commission to resolve questions of accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness.  </p>
        <p>(4) From 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(1) because:  </p>
        <p>(i) It is not always possible to determine relevance or necessity of specific information in the early stages of an investigation.  </p>
        <p>(ii) Relevance and necessity are matters of judgment and timing in that what appears relevant and necessary when collected may be deemed unnecessary later. Only after information is assessed can its relevance and necessity be established.  </p>
        <p>(iii) In any investigation the Commission may receive information concerning violations of law under the jurisdiction of another agency. In the interest of effective law enforcement and under 25 U.S.C. 2716(b), the information could be relevant to an investigation by the Commission.  </p>
        <p>(iv) In the interviewing of individuals or obtaining evidence in other ways during an investigation, the Commission could obtain information that may or may not appear relevant at any given time; however, the information could be relevant to another investigation by the Commission.  </p>

    </xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
