<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>


<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency</name>
<abbrev>
CIGIE
</abbrev>
    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-01-27/pdf/2021-01429.pdf</url>
        <title>PRAC Data Warehouse System (PDWS)- CIGIE-5</title>
        <date year="2021" month="1" day="27" />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-02-04/pdf/2021-02338.pdf</url>
        <title>PRAC Data Warehouse System (PDWS)- CIGIE-5</title>
        <date year="2021" month="2" day="4" />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-05-17/pdf/2021-10376.pdf</url>
        <title>PRAC Accountability Data System (PADS) - CIGIE-6</title>
        <date year="2021" month="5" day="17" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-05-17/pdf/2021-10375.pdf</url>
        <title>5 CFR Part 9801, Interim Rules</title>
        <date year="2021" month="5" day="17" />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <section id="cigie1" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber> cigie1</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName"> Correspondence Tracking – CIGIE-1.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
               <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The principal location of paper records contained within the system is the headquarters of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE), 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006. Paper records within the system may also be located at CIGIE’s Inspector General Criminal Investigator Academy, Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, 384 Marana Circle, Glynco, Georgia 31524. Records maintained in electronic form are principally located in contractor-hosted data centers in the United States. Contact the System Manager identified below for additional information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Executive Director, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app (IG Act); 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information is used to track and record the incoming correspondence to determine whether the matter is appropriate for CIGIE to handle and prepare a response, whether CIGIE should refer it to another Federal agency for handling, and whether CIGIE should decline to take any action.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who submit correspondence to CIGIE, who have correspondence submitted on their behalf to CIGIE, who are the subject of correspondence to CIGIE, or who request to receive correspondence from CIGIE, as well as CIGIE employees responsible for processing, reviewing, and/or responding to such correspondence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system maintains information about correspondence that CIGIE receives from Members and Committees of Congress; Federal, state, and local agencies; private entities; and private citizens, regarding significant issues that do or may fall within CIGIE’s jurisdiction under the IG Act.  The system also contains information about responses to such correspondence, as well as referrals of the complaints/correspondence to the various Offices of Inspector General and other Federal agencies for response. The system may contain personal information relating to the sender and individuals (both public officials and private citizens) who are named in or related to the correspondence, such as names, addresses, phone numbers, and email addresses. This system does not contain all correspondence received or sent by CIGIE. For example, most routine email correspondence is not included in this system and some correspondence is maintained in other CIGIE systems of record.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information is provided by Members and Committees of Congress; Federal, State, and local agencies; private entities; and private citizens.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)), the records or information contained in this system of records may specifically be disclosed outside of CIGIE as a routine use pursuant to the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3)) as follows:</p>
                <p>A. To a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the individual. In such cases, however, the Member's right to a record is no greater than that of the individual.</p>
                <p>B. If the disclosure of certain records to the Department of Justice (DOJ) is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the DOJ. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>C. If disclosure of certain records to a court, adjudicative body before which CIGIE is authorized to appear, individual or entity designated by CIGIE or otherwise empowered to resolve disputes, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the court, adjudicative body, individual or entity, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>D. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, tribal, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.</p>
                <p>E. To officials and employees of any Federal agency to the extent the record contains information that is relevant to that agency’s decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; issuance of a security clearance; execution of a security or suitability investigation; or classification of a job.</p>
                <p>F. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>G. To contractors, grantees, consultants, volunteers, or other individuals performing or working on a contract, interagency agreement, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for CIGIE and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for CIGIE.</p>
                <p>H. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:  CIGIE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; CIGIE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CIGIE (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CIGIE’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>I. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when:  CIGIE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>J. To Federal agencies and independent certified public accounting firms that have a need for the information in order to audit the financial statements of CIGIE.</p>
                <p>K. To an organization or an individual in the public or private sector if there is reason to believe the recipient is or could become the target of a particular criminal activity or conspiracy, or to the extent the information is relevant to the protection or life or property.</p>
                <p>L. To officials, members, and employees of CIGIE who have need of the information in the performance of their duties.</p>
                <p>M. To the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) in accordance with OPM’s responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
                <p>N. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons, to the extent necessary to respond to or refer correspondence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system is maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individual on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information is retained and disposed of in accordance with the General Records Schedule or the CIGIE records schedule applicable to the record and/or as otherwise required by the Federal Records Act and implementing regulations. Destruction is by shredding or electronic deletion.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are located in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking notification and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may inquire in writing to the System Manager listed above. CIGIE has published a rule, entitled "Privacy Act Regulations," to establish its procedures relating to access, maintenance, disclosure, and amendment of records which are in a CIGIE system of records under the Privacy Act, promulgated at 5 CFR Part 9801.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="cigie2" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber> cigie2</systemNumber>
           <subsection type="systemName"> Freedom of Information Act – Privacy Act System – CIGIE-2.
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                    </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The principal location of paper records contained within the system is the headquarters of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE), 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006. Paper records within the system may also be located at CIGIE’s Inspector General Criminal Investigator Academy, Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, 384 Marana Circle, Glynco, Georgia 31524. Records maintained in electronic form are principally located in contractor-hosted data centers in the United States. Records within this system may also be located at the offices of entities performing Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 5 U.S.C. 552, and Privacy Act of 1974 (Privacy Act), 5 U.S.C. 552a, request processing on behalf of CIGIE. Contact the System Manager identified below for additional information.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Executive Director, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app (IG Act); 5 U.S.C. 301; 5 U.S.C. 552; 5 U.S.C. 552a; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>To assist CIGIE in carrying out its responsibilities under FOIA and the Privacy Act.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals who have requested access to information pursuant to FOIA or the Privacy Act; individuals who have made a request to access or correct records pertaining to themselves; persons who, on behalf of another individual, have made a request to access or correct that individual’s records; and individuals whose requests and/or records have been referred to CIGIE by other agencies.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The system maintains records received, created, or compiled in processing FOIA and Privacy Act requests or appeals, including, but not limited to, correspondence or internal memoranda related to the processing of these requests and documents relevant to administrative appeals and litigation under FOIA and the Privacy Act.  Records will also contain such data as the name of requester, address of requester, and subject of request.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information is derived from the individuals and entities making requests, the records searched in the process of responding to requests, and other agencies referring requests for access to or correction of records.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)), the records or information contained in this system of records may specifically be disclosed outside of CIGIE as a routine use pursuant to the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3)) as follows:</p>
                    <p>A. To a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the individual. In such cases, however, the Member's right to a record is no greater than that of the individual.</p>
                    <p>B. If the disclosure of certain records to the Department of Justice (DOJ) is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the DOJ. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                    <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                    <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                    <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                    <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                    <p>C. If disclosure of certain records to a court, adjudicative body before which CIGIE is authorized to appear, individual or entity designated by CIGIE or otherwise empowered to resolve disputes, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the court, adjudicative body, individual or entity, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                    <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                    <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                    <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                    <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                    <p>D. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, tribal, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.</p>
                    <p>E. To officials and employees of any Federal agency to the extent the record contains information that is relevant to that agency’s decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; issuance of a security clearance; execution of a security or suitability investigation; or classification of a job.</p>
                    <p>F. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    <p>G. To contractors, grantees, consultants, volunteers, or other individuals performing or working on a contract, interagency agreement, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for CIGIE and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for CIGIE.</p>
                    <p>H. To any appropriate Federal, state, or local agency or entity to:</p>
                    <p>1. Permit a decision as to access, amendment or correction of records to be made in consultation with or by that agency; or</p>
                    <p>2. Verify the identity of an individual or the accuracy of information submitted by an individual who has requested access to or amendment or correction of records.</p>
                    <p>I. To NARA, Office of Government Information Services (OGIS), to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities in 5 U.S.C. 552(h), to review administrative agency policies, procedures, and compliance with the FOIA, and to facilitate OGIS’s offering of mediation services to resolve disputes between persons making FOIA requests and administrative agencies.</p>
                    <p>J. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:  CIGIE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; CIGIE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CIGIE (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CIGIE’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>K. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when:  CIGIE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    <p>L. To Federal agencies and independent certified public accounting firms that have a need for the information in order to audit the financial statements of CIGIE.</p>
                    <p>M. To an organization or an individual in the public or private sector if there is reason to believe the recipient is or could become the target of a particular criminal activity or conspiracy, or to the extent the information is relevant to the protection or life or property.</p>
                    <p>N. To officials, members, and employees of CIGIE who have need of the information in the performance of their duties.</p>
                    <p>O. To the Office of Management and Budget for the purpose of obtaining its advice regarding CIGIE obligations under the Privacy Act.</p>
                    <p>P. To a submitter or subject of a record or information in order to obtain assistance to CIGIE in making a determination as to access or amendment.</p>
                    <p>Q. To the DOJ Office of Information Policy for the purpose of obtaining its advice regarding CIGIE obligations under the FOIA.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information in this system is maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individual on whom they are maintained.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The information is retained and disposed of in accordance with the General Records Schedule or the CIGIE records schedule applicable to the record and/or as otherwise required by the Federal Records Act and implementing regulations. Destruction is by shredding or electronic deletion.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Paper records are located in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals seeking notification and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may inquire in writing to the System Manager listed above. CIGIE has published a rule, entitled "Privacy Act Regulations," to establish its procedures relating to access, maintenance, disclosure, and amendment of records which are in a CIGIE system of records under the Privacy Act, promulgated at 5 CFR Part 9801.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>To the extent that copies of exempt records from other systems of records are entered into this system, CIGIE claims the same exemptions for those records that are claimed for the original primary systems of records from which they originated.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>


    <section id="cigie3" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber> cigie3</systemNumber>
                    <subsection type="systemName"> Employee-related Records System – CIGIE-3.
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                       <p>None.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The principal location of paper records contained within the system is the headquarters of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE), 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006. Paper records within the system may also be located at CIGIE’s Inspector General Criminal Investigator Academy, Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, 384 Marana Circle, Glynco, Georgia 31524. Records maintained in electronic form are principally located in contractor-hosted data centers in the United States. Contact the System Manager identified below for additional information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Executive Director, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app (IG Act); 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is primarily maintained to perform agency functions related to general management of CIGIE personnel, including, but not limited to, employee training, leave, attendance, and payments, including determinations relating to the amounts to be paid to employees, the distribution of pay according to employee directions (for allotments, to financial institutions, and for other authorized purposes), and for tax withholdings and other authorized deductions. The system is also used to facilitate communication between CIGIE employees, initiate personnel actions, counsel employees on their performance, and propose disciplinary action.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former employees of CIGIE, individuals detailed to CIGIE, and applicants for employment at CIGIE.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records includes personnel information regarding current CIGIE employees, former CIGIE employees, prospective CIGIE employees, and individuals detailed to CIGIE. Such personnel information may include: name; addresses; telephone numbers; Social Security number; duty location; position data; time, attendance, and leave information; payroll information; awards and bonus information; professional registrations; qualifications; training history; employment history; counseling; reprimands; grievances; work assignments; and injuries.</p>
                <p>The system’s records contain but are not limited to the following information about the individual’s time, attendance, and leave: the number and type of hours worked; overtime information, including compensatory or credit time earned and used; compensatory travel earned; leave requests, balances, and credits; leave charge codes; and medical records as they pertain to employee medical leave.</p>
                <p>The system’s records contain but are not limited to the following information about an individual’s payroll: marital status and number of dependents; child support enforcement court orders; information about taxes and other deductions; debts owed to CIGIE and garnishment information; salary data; retirement data; Thrift Savings Plan contribution and loan amount; and direct deposit information, including financial institution.</p>
                <p>The system does not include records covered by government-wide systems of record, including, but not limited to, applicable government-wide systems of record established by the U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM), U.S. Department of Labor (DOL), U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), General Services Administration (GSA), U.S. Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB), U.S. Office of Government Ethics, and U.S. Office of Special Counsel (OSC). Additionally, the system does not include CIGIE current and former employee records maintained by GSA and covered by GSA’s GSA/Agency-1: Employee-Related Files system of record as a result of GSA’s provision of payroll and other services to CIGIE. When records in the custody of CIGIE are covered in a record system published by another Federal agency as a government-wide record system, or by GSA/Agency-1, they are considered part of that system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The sources for the information are individuals themselves; other employees; other personnel records; Federal, State, and local agencies; private entities; and private citizens.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)), the records or information contained in this system of records may specifically be disclosed outside of CIGIE as a routine use pursuant to the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3)) as follows:</p>
                <p>A. To a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the individual. In such cases, however, the Member's right to a record is no greater than that of the individual.</p>
                <p>B. If the disclosure of certain records to the Department of Justice (DOJ) is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the DOJ. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>C. If disclosure of certain records to a court, adjudicative body before which CIGIE is authorized to appear, individual or entity designated by CIGIE or otherwise empowered to resolve disputes, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the court, adjudicative body, individual or entity, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>D. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, tribal, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.</p>
                <p>E. To officials and employees of any Federal agency to the extent the record contains information that is relevant to that agency’s decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; issuance of a security clearance; execution of a security or suitability investigation; or classification of a job.</p>
                <p>F. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>G. To contractors, grantees, consultants, volunteers, or other individuals performing or working on a contract, interagency agreement, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for CIGIE and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for CIGIE.</p>
                <p>H. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: CIGIE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; CIGIE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CIGIE (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CIGIE’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>I. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when: CIGIE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>J. To Federal agencies and independent certified public accounting firms that have a need for the information in order to audit the financial statements of CIGIE.</p>
                <p>K. To an organization or an individual in the public or private sector if there is reason to believe the recipient is or could become the target of a particular criminal activity or conspiracy, or to the extent the information is relevant to the protection or life or property.</p>
                <p>L. To officials, members, and employees of CIGIE who have need of the information in the performance of their duties.</p>
                <p>M. To the OPM in accordance with OPM’s responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
                <p>N. To the OPM, MSPB, Federal Labor Relations Authority, OSC, or EEOC when requested in the performance of their respective authorized duties.</p>
                <p>O. To an individual’s prospective or current employer to the extent necessary to determine employment eligibility.</p>
                <p>P. To an authorized appeal or grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system is maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individual on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information is retained and disposed of in accordance with the General Records Schedule or the CIGIE records schedule applicable to the record and/or as otherwise required by the Federal Records Act and implementing regulations. Destruction is by shredding or electronic deletion.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are located in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking notification and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may inquire in writing to the System Manager listed above. CIGIE has published a rule, entitled "Privacy Act Regulations," to establish its procedures relating to access, maintenance, disclosure, and amendment of records which are in a CIGIE system of records under the Privacy Act, promulgated at 5 CFR Part 9801.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>



    <section id="cigie4" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber> cigie4</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName"> Integrity Committee Management System (ICMS) – CIGIE-4.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The vast majority of the information in the system is Controlled Unclassified Information. However, there is some classified information as well.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The principal location of paper records contained within the ICMS is the headquarters of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE), 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006. Records maintained in electronic form are principally located in contractor-hosted data centers in the United States. Records within the system may also be temporarily located at a Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) location in the system location specified in the current System of Record Notice associated with The FBI Central Records System, Justice/FBI-002. Contact the System Manager identified below for additional information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Executive Director, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app (IG Act); Section 3 of the Inspector General Empowerment Act of 2016, Pub. L. 114-317, 130 Stat. 1595 (IGEA); 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>CIGIE maintains this system of records in order to carry out its responsibilities pursuant to the IG Act, as further amended by section 3 of the IGEA. Pursuant to section 11(d)(1) of the IG Act, CIGIE is statutorily directed to establish the Integrity Committee (IC), which shall receive, review, refer for investigation, or otherwise act on allegations of wrongdoing that are made against Inspectors General and certain staff members of various Offices of Inspector General (OIGs), as well as the Special Counsel and Deputy Special Counsel, and make appropriate recommendations regarding confirmed or verified allegations. Furthermore, pursuant to section 11(d)(13) of the IG Act, as further amended by the IGEA, the Chairperson of CIGIE is statutorily obligated to maintain the records of the IC. Accordingly, the records in this system are used in the course of responding to complaints made to or referred to the IC, investigating individuals suspected of wrongdoing falling within the authority of the IC, referring matters to the Department of Justice (DOJ) or the Office of Special Counsel (OSC), as appropriate, and making recommendations to the President or head of the relevant agency, as appropriate.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In connection with its investigative and other duties, the IC maintains records on the following categories of individuals:</p>
                <p>A. Individuals who relate in any manner to official IC matters, including, but not limited to, individuals who are or have been the subject, complainant, victim, witness, or close relative or associate of a subject, complainant, victim, or witness in a complaint made or referred to the IC. Such individuals include, but are not necessarily limited to, Inspectors General, the Special Counsel, the Deputy Special Counsel, and those staff members of the OIGs specified in section 11(d)(4)(B) of the IG Act, as well as other individuals identified in such complaints.</p>
                <p>B. Individuals identified in reports of investigation and other materials received from the DOJ or the OSC pursuant to section 11(d)(7)(E) of the IG Act or received from other entities that submit materials to the IC, such as Inspectors General who conduct investigations on behalf of the IC.</p>
                <p>C. Individuals identified in correspondence or records that are related to the general administration of the IC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information relating to complaints and investigations, including:</p>
                <p>A. Letters, memoranda, and other documents describing complaints or alleged criminal, civil, or administrative misconduct.</p>
                <p>B. Investigative files, which include reports of investigations and related exhibits, statements, affidavits, and records obtained during investigations.</p>
                <p>C. General administrative materials, including minutes, reports, case-tracking logs, and Congressional and other correspondence.</p>
                <p>D. Records relating to referrals and recommendations to and from external entities, including, but not limited to the DOJ, the OSC, OIGs, and others.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The subjects of investigations and inquiries; individuals and entities with which the subjects of investigations and inquiries are associated; Federal, state, local, and foreign law enforcement and non-law enforcement agencies and entities; private citizens; witnesses; complainants; and public and/or commercially available source materials.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)), the records or information contained in this system of records may specifically be disclosed outside of CIGIE as a routine use pursuant to the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3)) as follows:</p>
                <p>A. To a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the individual. In such cases, however, the Member's right to a record is no greater than that of the individual.</p>
                <p>B. If the disclosure of certain records to the DOJ is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the DOJ. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>C. If disclosure of certain records to a court, adjudicative body before which CIGIE is authorized to appear, individual or entity designated by CIGIE or otherwise empowered to resolve disputes, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness is relevant and necessary to litigation and is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected, CIGIE may disclose those records to the court, adjudicative body, individual or entity, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>D. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, tribal, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity, including, but not limited to, the DOJ or the OSC pursuant to section 11(d)(5) of the IG Act, as further amended by the IGEA.</p>
                <p>E. To officials and employees of any Federal agency to the extent the record contains information that is relevant to that agency’s decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; issuance of a security clearance; execution of a security or suitability investigation; or classification of a job.</p>
                <p>F. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>G. To contractors, grantees, consultants, volunteers, or other individuals performing or working on a contract, interagency agreement, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for CIGIE (including, but not limited to, representatives of the DOJ and the OSC reviewing complaints made to the IC pursuant to section 11(d)(5) of the IG Act, as further amended by the IGEA, the Chief of the Public Integrity Section of the Criminal Division of the DOJ, or his designee, who serves as legal advisor to the IC, and officials at the FBI involved with the maintenance of IC-related records) and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for CIGIE.</p>
                <p>H. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:  CIGIE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; CIGIE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CIGIE (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CIGIE’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>I. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when:  CIGIE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>J. To Federal agencies and independent certified public accounting firms that have a need for the information in order to audit the financial statements of CIGIE.</p>
                <p>K. To an organization or an individual in the public or private sector where there is reason to believe the recipient is or could become the target of a particular criminal activity or conspiracy, or to the extent the information is relevant to the protection or life or property.</p>
                <p>L. To officials, members, and employees of CIGIE and members of the IC who have need of the information in the performance of their duties.</p>
                <p>M. To any individual or entity when necessary to elicit information that will assist an IC investigation.</p>
                <p>N. To the President or the head of a designated Federal entity, as appropriate, for resolution after assessment and final disposition of reports by the IC to the extent required to comply with section 11(d) of the IG Act or as otherwise required by law.</p>
                <p>O. To Members of Congress and appropriate congressional committees of jurisdiction to the extent required to comply with section 11(d) of the IG Act or as otherwise required by law.</p>
                 </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system is maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individual on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information is retained and disposed of in accordance with the General Records Schedule or the CIGIE records schedule applicable to the record and/or as otherwise required by the Federal Records Act and implementing regulations. Destruction is by shredding or electronic deletion.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are located in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Part of this system is exempt from notification and access requirements pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), (k)(1), and (k)(2). To the extent that this system is not subject to exemption, it is subject to notification and access requirements. Individuals seeking notification and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may inquire in writing to the System Manager listed above. CIGIE has published a rule, entitled "Privacy Act Regulations," to establish its procedures relating to access, maintenance, disclosure, and amendment of records which are in a CIGIE system of records under the Privacy Act, promulgated at 5 CFR Part 9801.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See ‘‘Record Access Procedures’’ above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>CIGIE has exempted this system of records from the following provisions of the Privacy Act pursuant to the general authority in 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2): 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) and (c)(4); (d); (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G)-(H), (e)(5), and (e)(8); (f); and (g). Additionally, CIGIE has exempted this system from the following provisions of the Privacy Act pursuant to the general authority in 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and (k)(2): 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3); (d); (e)(1) and (e)(4)(G)-(H); and (f). See 5 CFR Part 9801.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="cigie5" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber> cigie5</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>PRAC Data Warehouse System (PDWS)- CIGIE-5.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The location of paper records contained within the PDWS is the headquarters of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE), 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006. Records maintained in electronic form are principally located in contractor-hosted data centers in the United States. Contact the System Manager identified below for additional information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Executive Director, Pandemic Response Accountability Committee, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006, (202)292-2600, cigie.information@cigie.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app (IG Act); 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; Pub. L. 116-136; Pub. L. 116-123; and Pub. L. 116-127.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To carry out the PRAC’s responsibilities to promote transparency and conduct oversight of any funds, including but not limited to loans, that are made available in any form to any non-Federal entity, not including an individual, under: Public Law 116-136; Public Law 116-123; and Public Law 116-127; or any other act primarily making appropriations for Coronavirus response and related activities(Coronavirus Funds).  The term "Coronavirus response" means the Federal Government’s response to the nationwide public health emergency declared by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, retroactive to January 27, 2020, pursuant to 42 U.S.C. 247d as a result of confirmed cases of the novel Coronavirus, COVID–19, in the United States (Coronavirus Response).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains records on individuals acting in a personal capacity who relate to PRAC efforts undertaken in support of its mission to promote transparency and conduct and support oversight of Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response to prevent and detect fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement and mitigate major risks that cut across programs and agencies. Individuals include but are not limited to those who have applied for, sought, or received Federal funds. These records are comingled with information concerning individuals in their entrepreneurial/sole-proprietor capacity; however, this information is not subject to the Privacy Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system maintains records that contribute to the transparency of Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response and effective oversight of fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement and mitigation of major risks that cut across programs and agencies related to Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response. These records may include, but are not limited to, records concerning: Coronavirus Funds and other Federal funding; the Coronavirus Response; individuals in their personal capacity or individuals who are employees or representatives of businesses, corporations, tribal governments, not-for-profit organizations, or other organizations that have applied for, sought, or received Coronavirus Funds or have been involved in any capacity in the Coronavirus Response. Such records may include, but are not limited to these individuals’ home addresses, telephone numbers, social security numbers or tax identifications numbers, company business addresses, business financial information and records, bank account information, payroll records, personal contact information, business affiliations, and employment history.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Publicly and/or commercially available data sets and other source material; Federal agencies; and individuals and entities, including states and local jurisdictions, tribal governments, businesses, corporations, and other organizations, that have applied for, sought, or received Coronavirus Funds or other Federal funds or have been involved in any capacity in the Coronavirus Response.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b), all or portions of the records or information contained in this system may specifically be disclosed outside of CIGIE as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>A. To a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the individual. In such cases, however, the Member's right to a record is no greater than that of the individual.</p>
                <p>B. If the disclosure of certain records to the Department of Justice (DOJ) is relevant and necessary to litigation, CIGIE may disclose those records to the DOJ. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>C. If disclosure of certain records to a court, adjudicative body before which CIGIE is authorized to appear, individual or entity designated by CIGIE or otherwise empowered to resolve disputes, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness is relevant and necessary to litigation, CIGIE may disclose those records to the court, adjudicative body, individual or entity, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>D. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, tribal, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.</p>
                <p>E. To officials and employees of any Federal agency to the extent the record contains information that is relevant to that agency's decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; issuance of a security clearance; execution of a security or suitability investigation; or classification of a job.</p>
                <p>F. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>G. To contractors, grantees, consultants, volunteers, or other individuals performing or working on a contract, interagency agreement, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for CIGIE and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for CIGIE.</p>
                <p>H. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: CIGIE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; CIGIE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CIGIE (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CIGIE's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>I. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when: CIGIE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p> J. To Federal agencies and independent certified public accounting firms that have a need for the information in order to audit the financial statements of CIGIE.</p>
                <p>K. To an organization or an individual in the public or private sector if there is reason to believe the recipient is or could become the target of a particular criminal activity or conspiracy, or to the extent the information is relevant to the protection or life or property.</p>
                <p>L. To officials of CIGIE, as well as CIGIE members and their employees, who have need of the information in the performance of their duties.</p>
                <p>M. To the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) in accordance with OPM's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
                <p>N. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons, to the extent necessary to respond to or refer correspondence.</p>
                <p>O. To the news media and the public, unless it is determined that release of the specific information would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                <p>P. To populate public-facing government websites to promote transparency of Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response, unless it is determined that release of the specific information would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information within this system of records is maintained in paper/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individuals on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information is retained and disposed of in accordance with the General Records Schedule and/or the CIGIE records schedule applicable to the record and/or otherwise required by the Federal Records Act and implementing regulations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are located in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Individuals seeking notification and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may inquire in writing to the System Manager listed above. CIGIE has published a rule, entitled "Privacy Act Regulations," to establish its procedures relating to access, maintenance, disclosure and amendment of records which are in a CIGIE system of records per the Privacy Act, promulgated at 5 CFR part 9801 (<i>https://www.ecfr.gov/cgi-bin/text-idx?SID=c3344b4e456f682fe915c0e982f8ce94&amp;mc=true&amp;tpl=/ecfrbrowse/Title05/5cfr9801_main_02.tpl</i>).
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Records Access Procedures" above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Records Access Procedures" above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>N/A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="cigie6" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber> cigie6</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>PRAC Accountability Data System (PADS) - CIGIE-6.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Controlled Unclassified Information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The location of paper records contained within the PADS is the headquarters of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE), 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006. Records maintained in electronic form are principally located in contractor-hosted data centers in the United States. Contact the System Manager identified below for additional information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Executive Director, Pandemic Response Accountability Committee, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006, (202)292-2600, cigie.information@cigie.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app (IG Act); 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; Pub. L. 116-136; Pub. L. 116-123; Pub. L. 116-127; and any other act primarily making appropriations for Coronavirus response and related activities.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To carry out the PRAC’s responsibilities to conduct oversight of any funds, including but not limited to loans, that are made available in any form to any non-Federal entity, not including an individual, under: Public Law 116-136; Public Law 116-123; Public Law 116-127; or any other act primarily making appropriations for Coronavirus response and related activities (Coronavirus Funds).  The term "Coronavirus response" means the Federal Government’s response to the nationwide public health emergency declared by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, retroactive to January 27, 2020, pursuant to 42 U.S.C. 247d as a result of confirmed cases of the novel Coronavirus, COVID–19, in the United States (Coronavirus Response).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains records on individuals acting in a personal capacity who relate to PRAC efforts undertaken in support of its mission to conduct and support oversight of Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response to prevent and detect fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement and mitigate major risks that cut across programs and agencies. Individuals include but are not limited to those who have applied for, sought, or received Federal funds. In addition, these individuals include:</p>
                <p>(a) Individuals who are or have been the subject of investigations or other inquiries identified by or submitted to the PRAC;</p>
                <p>(b) Individuals who are or have been witnesses, complainants, or informants in investigations or other inquiries identified by or submitted to the PRAC;</p>
                <p>(c) Individuals who are or have been potential subjects or parties to an investigation or other inquiry identified by or submitted to the PRAC;</p>
                <p>(d) Individuals who are or have been related to entities or individuals that are or have been a subject of, potential subject of, or party to an investigation or other inquiry identified by or submitted to the PRAC;</p>
                <p>(e)Individuals who have or have had increased risk factors indicating they may have been involved with possible fraud, waste, abuse, mismanagement, or improper payments related to Federal funds; and</p>
                <p>(f) Individuals who are or have been related to entities or individuals that have or have had increased risk factors indicating they may have been involved with possible fraud, waste, abuse, mismanagement, or improper payments related to Federal funds.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system maintains records that contribute to the oversight of Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response and effective oversight of fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement and mitigation of major risks that cut across programs and agencies related to Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response. These records may include, but are not limited to, records concerning: Coronavirus Funds and other Federal funding; the Coronavirus Response; individuals in their personal capacity or individuals who are employees or representatives of businesses, corporations, tribal governments, not-for-profit organizations, or other organizations that have applied for, sought, or received Coronavirus Funds or have been involved in any capacity in the Coronavirus Response. Such records may include, but are not limited to, these individuals’ home addresses, telephone numbers, social security numbers or tax identifications numbers, company business addresses, business financial information and records, bank account information, payroll records, personal contact information, business affiliations, and employment history.  The records may further include:</p>
                <p>(a) Letters, memoranda, and other documents describing complaints, derogatory information, or alleged criminal, civil, or administrative misconduct; and</p>
                <p>(b) General intelligence and relevant data, leads for the PRAC or Offices of Inspector General (or other applicable oversight and law enforcement entities), reports of investigations and related exhibits, statements and affidavits, and records obtained or generated during an investigation or other inquiry, including but not limited to risk-based analytical research.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Publicly and/or commercially available data sets and other source material; Federal agencies; and individuals and entities, including states and local jurisdictions, tribal governments, businesses, corporations, and other organizations, that have applied for, sought, or received Coronavirus Funds or other Federal funds or have been involved in any capacity in the Coronavirus Response. The subjects of investigations and other inquiries; individuals and entities with which the subjects of investigations and other inquiries are associated; Federal, state, local, and foreign law enforcement and non-law enforcement agencies and entities; private citizens; witnesses; and informants.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b), all or portions of the records or information contained in this system may specifically be disclosed outside of CIGIE as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>A. To a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the individual. In such cases, however, the Member's right to a record is no greater than that of the individual.</p>
                <p>B. If the disclosure of certain records to the Department of Justice (DOJ) is relevant and necessary to litigation, CIGIE may disclose those records to the DOJ. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>C. If disclosure of certain records to a court, adjudicative body before which CIGIE is authorized to appear, individual or entity designated by CIGIE or otherwise empowered to resolve disputes, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness is relevant and necessary to litigation, CIGIE may disclose those records to the court, adjudicative body, individual or entity, counsel or other representative, party, or potential witness. CIGIE may make such a disclosure if one of the following parties is involved in the litigation or has an interest in the litigation:</p>
                <p>1. CIGIE or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of CIGIE in his or her individual capacity when the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4. The United States, if CIGIE determines that litigation is likely to affect CIGIE or any of its components.</p>
                <p>D. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, tribal, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.</p>
                <p>E. To officials and employees of any Federal agency to the extent the record contains information that is relevant to that agency's decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; issuance of a security clearance; execution of a security or suitability investigation; or classification of a job.</p>
                <p>F. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>G. To contractors, grantees, consultants, volunteers, or other individuals performing or working on a contract, interagency agreement, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for CIGIE and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for CIGIE.</p>
                <p>H. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: CIGIE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; CIGIE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CIGIE (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CIGIE's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>I. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when: CIGIE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>J. To Federal agencies and independent certified public accounting firms that have a need for the information in order to audit the financial statements of CIGIE.</p>
                <p> K. To an organization or an individual in the public or private sector if there is reason to believe the recipient is or could become the target of a particular criminal activity or conspiracy, or to the extent the information is relevant to the protection or life or property.</p>
                <p>L. To officials of CIGIE, as well as CIGIE members and their employees, who have need of the information in the performance of their duties.</p>
                <p>M. To the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) in accordance with OPM's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
                <p>N. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons, to the extent necessary to respond to or refer correspondence.</p>
                <p>O. To the news media and the public, unless it is determined that release of the specific information would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                <p>P. To populate public-facing government websites to promote transparency and oversight of Coronavirus Funds and the Coronavirus Response, unless it is determined that release of the specific information would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                <p>Q. Disclosure may be made to (a) complainants and/or victims to the extent necessary to provide such persons with information and explanations concerning the results of the investigation or other inquiry arising from the matters about which they complained and/or with respect to which they were a victim, and (b) to an individual who has been interviewed or contacted by the PRAC pursuant to an investigation or other inquiry, to the extent that the PRAC may provide copies of that individual’s statements, testimony, or records produced.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information within this system of records is maintained in paper/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individuals on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information is retained and disposed of in accordance with the General Records Schedule and/or the CIGIE records schedule applicable to the record and/or otherwise required by the Federal Records Act and implementing regulations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are located in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.  </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Part of this system is exempt from notification and access requirements pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), (k)(1), and (k)(2). To the extent that this system is not subject to exemption, it is subject to notification and access requirements. Individuals seeking notification and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may inquire in writing to the System Manager listed above. CIGIE has published a rule, entitled "Privacy Act Regulations," to establish its procedures relating to access, maintenance, disclosure and amendment of records which are in a CIGIE system of records per the Privacy Act, promulgated at 5 CFR part 9801 (https://www.ecfr.gov/cgi-bin/text-idx?SID=c3344b4e456f682fe915c0e982f8ce94&amp;mc=true&amp;tpl=/ecfrbrowse/Title05/5cfr9801_main_02.tpl).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Records Access Procedures" above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Records Access Procedures" above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>CIGIE has exempted this system of records from the following provisions of the Privacy Act pursuant to the general authority in 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2): 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) and (c)(4); (d); (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G)-(H), (e)(5), and (e)(8); (f); and (g). Additionally, CIGIE has exempted this system from the following provisions of the Privacy Act pursuant to the general authority in 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and (k)(2): 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3); (d); (e)(1) and (e)(4)(G)-(H); and (f). See 5 CFR Part 9801.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>N/A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="5">
<heading> Administrative Personnel </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XCVIII">
<heading> Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency </heading>
<regulationsPart number="9801">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT REGULATIONS </heading>
<xhtmlContent>


<p><b>Subpart A--General Provisions</b></p>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>9801.101 Purpose and scope.</p>
<p>9801.102 CIGIE organization.</p>
<p>9801.103 Definitions.</p>
<p>9801.104 Rules for determining if an individual is the subject of a record.</p>
<p>9801.105 Employee standards of conduct.</p>
<p>9801.106 Use and collection of social security numbers.</p>
<p>9801.107 Other rights and services.</p>
<p><b>Subpart B--Access to Records and Accounting of Disclosures</b></p>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>9801.201 Requests for access.</p>
<p>9801.202 Response to requests.</p>
<p>9801.203 Granting access.</p>
<p>9801.204 Special procedures: Medical records.</p>
<p>9801.205 Appeals from denials of requests for access to records.</p>
<p>9801.206 Response to appeal of a denial of access.</p>
<p>9801.207 Fees.</p>
<p>9801.208 Requests for accounting of record disclosures.</p>
<p><b>Subpart C--Amendment of Records</b></p>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>9801.301 Requests for amendment of record.</p>
<p>9801.302 Response to requests.</p>
<p>9801.303 Appeal from adverse determination on amendment.</p>
<p>9801.304 Response to appeal of adverse determination on amendment; disagreement statements.</p>
<p>9801.305 Assistance in preparing request to amend a record or to appeal an initial adverse determination.</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b>  Section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app.; 5 U.S.C. 301, 552a; 31 U.S.C. 9701; Sec. 15010, Pub. L. No. 116-136, 134 Stat. 281.</p>
<p>Source: 81 FR 86563, Dec. 1, 2016, unless otherwise noted.</p>
<p><b>Subpart A--General Provisions</b></p>
<p><b>&#167;  9801.101 Purpose and scope. </b></p>
<p> This part contains the regulations of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE) implementing the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a.  This part sets forth the basic responsibilities of CIGIE with regard to CIGIE's compliance with the requirements of the Privacy Act and offers guidance to members of the public who wish to exercise any of the rights established by the Privacy Act with regard to records maintained by CIGIE.  These regulations should be read in conjunction with the Privacy Act, which explains in more detail individuals' rights.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.102 CIGIE organization. </b></p>
    <p>
        (a) <i>Centralized program. </i> CIGIE has a centralized Privacy Act program, with one office receiving and coordinating the processing of all Privacy Act requests to CIGIE.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) <i>Acceptance of requests and appeals.</i>  CIGIE will accept initial requests or appeals regarding CIGIE records.
    </p>
    <p>[82 FR 51333, Nov. 6, 2017]</p>
    <p><b>&#167; 9801.103 Definitions. </b></p>
<p> (a) For purposes of this part the terms<i> individual, maintain, record, routine use, and system of records</i>, shall have the meanings set forth in 5 U.S.C. 552a(a).</p>
<p> (b) <i>CIGIE</i> means the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency and includes its predecessor entities, the Executive Council on Integrity and Efficiency and the President's Council on Integrity and Efficiency.</p>
<p> (c) <i>Days</i>, unless stated as calendar days, are working days and do not include Saturdays, Sundays, or Federal holidays.</p>
<p> (d) <i>IC</i> means the CIGIE Integrity Committee established under section 11(d) of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app. (Inspector General Act).</p>
<p> (e) <i>Request for access</i> to a record means a request made under Privacy Act subsection (d)(1).</p>
<p>(f) <i>Request for amendment</i> of a record means a request made under Privacy Act subsection (d)(2).</p>
<p>(g) <i>Request for an accounting</i> means a request made under Privacy Act subsection (c)(3).</p>
<p>(h) <i>Requester</i> means an individual who makes a request for access, a request for amendment, or a request for an accounting under the Privacy Act.</p>
    <p>(i) <i>PRAC</i> means the Pandemic Response Accountability Committee established under Section 15010 of the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act, Pub. L. No. 116-136, 134 Stat. 281.
    </p>
    <p> [81 FR 86563, Dec. 1, 2016, as amended at 86 FR 26649, May 17, 2021]</p>
    <p><b>&#167; 9801.104 Rules for determining if an individual is the subject of a record. </b></p>
<p> An individual seeking to determine if a specific CIGIE system of records contains a record pertaining to the individual must follow the procedures set forth for access to records in &#167; 9801.201(a), (b)(1) and (2), (c), and (d).  A request to determine if an individual is the subject of a record will ordinarily be responded to within 10 days, except when CIGIE determines otherwise, in which case the request will be acknowledged within 10 days and the individual will be informed of the reasons for the delay and an estimated date by which a response will be issued.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.105  Employee standards of conduct. </b></p>
<p>CIGIE will inform its employees involved in the design, development, operation, or maintenance of any system of records, or in maintaining any record, of the provisions of the Privacy Act, including the Act's civil liability and criminal penalty provisions. Unless otherwise permitted by law, an employee of CIGIE shall:</p>
<p>(a) Collect from individuals only the information that is relevant and necessary to discharge the responsibilities of CIGIE;</p>
<p>(b) Collect information about an individual directly from that individual whenever practicable when the information may result in adverse determinations about an individual's rights, benefits, and privileges under Federal programs;</p>
<p>(c) Inform each individual from whom information is collected of:</p>
<p>(1) The legal authority to collect the information and whether providing it is mandatory or voluntary;</p>
<p>(2) The principal purpose for which CIGIE intends to use the information;</p>
<p>(3) The routine uses CIGIE may make of the information; and</p>
<p>(4) The effects on the individual, if any, of not providing the information;</p>
<p>(d) Maintain no system of records without public notice and notify appropriate CIGIE officials of the existence or development of any system of records that is not the subject of a current or planned public notice;</p>
<p>(e) Maintain all records that are used by CIGIE in making any determination about an individual with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to ensure fairness to the individual in the determination;</p>
<p>(f) Except as to disclosures made to an agency or made under the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552 (FOIA), make reasonable efforts, prior to disseminating any record about an individual, to ensure that the record is accurate, relevant, timely, and complete;</p>
<p>(g) Maintain no record describing how an individual exercises his or her First Amendment rights, unless it is expressly authorized by statute or by the individual about whom the record is maintained, or is pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized law enforcement activity;</p>
<p>(h) When required by the Privacy Act, maintain an accounting in the specified form of all disclosures of records by CIGIE to persons, organizations, or agencies;</p>
<p>(i) Maintain and use records with care to prevent the unauthorized or inadvertent disclosure of a record to anyone. No record contained in a CIGIE system of records shall be disclosed to another person, or to another agency outside CIGIE, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains, unless the disclosure is otherwise authorized by the Privacy Act; and</p>
<p>(j) Notify the appropriate CIGIE official of any record that contains information that the Privacy Act does not permit CIGIE to maintain.</p>
    <p>[81 FR 86563, Dec. 1, 2016, as amended at 82 FR 51333, Nov. 6, 2017]</p>
    <p><b>&#167; 9801.106  Use and collection of social security numbers. </b></p>
<p>(a) <i>No denial of right, benefit, or privilege.</i>  Individuals may not be denied any right, benefit, or privilege as a result of refusing to provide their social security numbers, unless the collection is required by Federal statute; and</p>
<p>(b) <i>Notification to individual.</i>  Individuals requested to provide their social security numbers must be informed of:</p>
<p>(1) Whether providing social security numbers is mandatory or voluntary;</p>
<p>(2) The statutory or regulatory authority that authorizes the collection of social security numbers; and</p>
<p>(3) The uses that will be made of the numbers.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.107  Other rights and services. </b></p>
<p>Nothing in this part shall be construed to entitle any person, as of right, to any service or to the disclosure of any record to which such person is not entitled under the Privacy Act.</p>
<p><b>Subpart B--Access to Records and Accounting of Disclosures</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.201  Requests for access. </b></p>
<p>(a) How addressed.  A requester seeking access to records pertaining to the requester in a CIGIE system of records should submit a written request that includes the words Privacy Act Request on both the envelope and at the top of the request letter to the Executive Director, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
<p>(b) Description of records sought. (1) A request should contain a specific reference to the CIGIE system of records from which access to the records is sought. Notices of CIGIE systems of records subject to the Privacy Act are published in the Federal Register, and copies of the notices are available on CIGIE's website at www.ignet.gov, or upon request from CIGIE's Office of General Counsel.</p>
<p>(2) If the written inquiry does not refer to a specific system of records, it must describe the records that are sought in enough detail to enable CIGIE personnel to locate the system of records containing them with a reasonable amount of effort.</p>
<p>(3) The request should state whether the requester wants a copy of the record or wants to examine the record in person.</p>
<p>(c) Verification of identity.  A requester seeking access to records pertaining to the requester must verify their identity in their request.  The request must state the requester's full name, current address, and date and place of birth.  The requester must sign the request and the signature must either be notarized or state, Under penalty of perjury, I hereby declare that I am the person named above and I understand that any falsification of this statement is punishable under the provisions of Title 18, United States Code (U.S.C.), Section 1001 by a fine of not more than $10,000 or by imprisonment of not more than five years, or both; and that requesting or obtaining any record(s) under false pretenses is punishable under the provisions of Title 5, U.S.C., Section 552a(i)(3) as a misdemeanor and by a fine of not more than $5,000.  In order to help the identification and location of requested records, the requester may optionally include their social security number.   No identification shall be required if the records are required by 5 U.S.C. 552 to be released.</p>
<p>(d) Verification of guardianship. When making a request as the parent or guardian of a minor or as the guardian of someone determined by a court to be incompetent for access to records about that individual, the requester must establish:</p>
<p>(1) The identity of the individual who is the subject of the record, by stating the name, current address, date and place of birth, and, at the requester's option, the social security number of the individual;</p>
<p>(2) The requester's identity, as required in paragraph (c) of this section;</p>
<p>(3) That the requester is the parent or guardian of that individual, which may be established by providing a copy of the individual's birth certificate showing the requester's parentage or by providing a court order establishing the requester's guardianship; and</p>
<p>(4) That the requester is acting on behalf of that individual in making the request.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.202 Response to requests. </b></p>
<p>A request for access will ordinarily be responded to within 10 days, except when CIGIE determines otherwise, in which case the request will be acknowledged within 10 days and the requester will be informed of the reasons for the delay and an estimated date by which a response will be issued.  A response to a request for access should include the following:</p>
<p>(a) A statement that there is a record or records as requested or a statement that there is not a record in the system of records;</p>
<p>(b) The method of access (if a copy of all the records requested is not provided with the response);</p>
<p>(c) The amount of any fees to be charged for copies of records under &#167; 9801.207, if applicable;</p>
<p>(d) The name and title of the official responsible for the response; and</p>
<p>(e) If the request is denied in whole or in part, or no record is found in the system, a statement of the reasons for the denial, or a statement that no record has been found, and notice of the procedures for appealing the denial or no record finding.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.203 Granting access. </b></p>
<p>(a) Means of access.  (1) The methods for allowing access to records, when such access has been granted by CIGIE, are:</p>
<p>(i) Examination in person in a designated office during the hours specified by CIGIE; or</p>
<p>(ii) Providing copies of the records.</p>
<p>(2) When a requester has not indicated whether he wants a copy of the record or wants to examine the record in person, CIGIE may choose the means of granting access.  However, the means chosen should not unduly impede the requester's right of access.  A requester may elect to receive a copy of the records after having examined them.</p>
<p> (b) Accompanying individual.  If the requester is granted in person access to examine the records, the requester may be accompanied by another individual of the requester's choice during the course of the examination of the records.  CIGIE may require the requester to submit a signed statement authorizing the accompanying individual's access to the records.</p>
<p>(c) Certified copies. CIGIE will not furnish certified copies of records. When copies are to be furnished, they may be provided as determined by CIGIE.</p>
<p>(d) Original records.  When the requester seeks to obtain original documentation, CIGIE reserves the right to limit the request to copies of the original records.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.204  Special procedures: Medical records. </b></p>
<p> In the event CIGIE receives a request pursuant to &#167; 9801.201 for access to medical records (including psychological records) whose disclosure CIGIE determines would be harmful to the individual to whom they relate, it may refuse to disclose the records directly to the requester but shall transmit them to a physician designated by the requester.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.205  Appeals from denials of requests for access to records. </b></p>
<p>(a) How addressed.  A requester may submit a written appeal of the decision by CIGIE to deny an initial request for access to records or a no record response to the Chairperson, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.  The words Privacy Act Appeal should be included on the envelope and at the top of the letter of appeal.</p>
<p>(b) Deadline and content.  The appeal must be received by CIGIE within 60 days of the date of the letter denying the access request or reflecting the no record finding and should contain a brief description of the records involved or copies of the relevant correspondence from CIGIE.  The appeal should attempt to refute the reasons given by CIGIE in support of its decision to deny the initial request for access or no record finding.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.206 Response to appeal of a denial of access. </b></p>
<p>(a) Access granted.  If the Chairperson or the Chairperson's designee determines that access to the records should be granted, the response will state how access will be provided if the records are not included with the response.</p>
<p>(b) Denial affirmed.  Any decision that either partially or fully affirms the initial decision to deny access or no record finding shall inform the requester of the right to seek judicial review of the decision in accordance with the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(g)).</p>
<p>(c) When appeal is required. If a requester wishes to seek review by a court of any adverse determination or denial of a request, the requester must first appeal it under &#167; 9801.205.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.207 Fees. </b></p>
<p> (a) No fees for most services.  Services for which fees will not be charged:</p>
<p>(1) The search and review time expended by CIGIE to produce a record;</p>
<p>(2) The first copy of the records provided; and</p>
<p>(3) CIGIE making the records available to be personally reviewed by the requester.</p>
<p>(b) Fees for additional copies.  When a requester requests additional copies of records, CIGIE will assess the requester a fee of $.20 per page.  CIGIE will bill requester in arrears for such fees, except as follows:</p>
<p>(1) If the total fee for additional copies amounts to more than $25.00, the requester will be notified of the fee amount.  Except as specified in paragraph (b)(2) of this section, upon requester's written agreement to pay the assessed fees, CIGIE will provide the additional copies without prepayment of such fees (i.e., payment will be accepted in arrears).</p>
<p>(2) An advance payment before additional copies of the records are made will be required if:</p>
<p>(i) CIGIE determines that the total fee to be assessed under this section exceeds $250.00.  When such a determination is made, the requester will be notified of the determination and will be required to submit an advance payment of an amount up to the total fee.  The amount of the advanced payment will be at the sole discretion of CIGIE and will be based, in part, on whether requester has a history of prompt payment of Privacy Act fees.  If the required advanced payment is an amount less than the total fee, requester will be required to submit a written agreement to pay any fees not paid in advance; or</p>
<p>(ii) The requester has previously failed to pay a previously assessed Privacy Act fee in a timely fashion (i.e., within 30 days of the date of the billing).  In such cases, the requester will be required to pay the full amount outstanding plus any applicable interest as provided by paragraph (c) of this section and to make an advance payment of the full amount of the determined fee before CIGIE begins to process a new request for additional copies.</p>
<p>(c) Interest charges. For additional copies provided to requester that result in fees assessed, CIGIE will begin levying interest charges on an unpaid balance starting on the 31st day following the day on which the billing was sent.  Interest will be assessed at the rate prescribed under 31 U.S.C. 3717 and will accrue from the date of the billing.</p>
<p>(d) Payment address. Payment of fees should be made by either a personal check, bank draft or a money order that is payable to the Department of the Treasury of the United States and mailed or delivered to:  Privacy Officer, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.208   Requests for accounting of record disclosures. </b></p>
<p>(a) How made and addressed. Except where accountings of disclosures are not required to be kept (as stated in paragraph (b) of this section), a requester may request an accounting of any disclosure that has been made by CIGIE to another person, organization, or agency of any record about the requester.  This accounting contains the date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure, as well as the name and address of the person, organization, or agency to which the disclosure was made.  A requester seeking an accounting of record disclosures must follow the procedures set forth for access to records in &#167; 9801.201(a), (b)(1) and (2), (c), and (d).</p>
<p>(b) Where accountings are not required. CIGIE is not required to provide accountings to requesters where they relate to:</p>
<p>(1) Disclosures for which accountings are not required to be kept, including disclosures that are made to officers and employees of CIGIE and disclosures that are made under the FOIA.  For purposes of this part, officers and employees of CIGIE includes, in part, CIGIE's membership, as addressed in section 11 of the Inspector General Act, when such members are acting in their capacity as CIGIE members;</p>
<p>(2) Disclosures made to law enforcement agencies for authorized law enforcement activities in response to written requests from those law enforcement agencies specifying the law enforcement activities for which the disclosures are sought; or</p>
<p>(3) Disclosures made from law enforcement systems of records that have been exempted from accounting requirements.</p>
<p><b>Subpart C--Amendment of Records</b></p>
<p><b>&#167;  9801.301 Requests for amendment of record. </b></p>
<p>(a) How addressed.  A requester seeking to amend a record or records pertaining to requester in a CIGIE system of records should submit a written request that includes the words Privacy Act Amendment Request on both the envelope and at the top of the request letter to the Executive Director, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.  Records not subject to the Privacy Act will not be amended in accordance with these provisions.</p>
<p>(b) Contents of request. A request to amend a record in a CIGIE system of records must include:</p>
<p>(1) The name of the system of records and a brief description of the record proposed for amendment.  In the event the request to amend the record is the result of the requester having gained access to the record in accordance with the provisions concerning access to records as set forth in subpart B of this part, copies of previous correspondence between the requester and CIGIE will serve in lieu of a separate description of the record.</p>
<p>(2) The exact portion of the record the requester seeks to have amended should be indicated clearly. If possible, proposed alternative language should be set forth, or, at a minimum, the reasons why the requester believes the record is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete should be set forth with enough particularity to permit CIGIE to not only understand the requester's basis for the request, but also to make an appropriate amendment to the record.</p>
<p>(c) Burden of proof.  The requester has the burden of proof when seeking the amendment of a record.  The requester must furnish sufficient facts to persuade the appropriate system manager of the inaccuracy, irrelevance, untimeliness, or incompleteness of the record.</p>
<p>(d) Identification requirement. When the requester's identity has been previously verified pursuant to &#167; 9801.201, further verification of identity is not required as long as the communication does not suggest a need for verification.  If the requester's identity has not been previously verified, the appropriate system manager may require identification validation as described in &#167; 9801.201.</p>
    <p>[81 FR 86563, Dec. 1, 2016, as amended at 82 FR 51333, Nov. 6, 2017]</p>
    <p><b>&#167;  9801.302  Response to requests. </b></p>
<p>(a) Time limit for acknowledging a request for amendment. To the extent possible, CIGIE will acknowledge receipt of a request to amend a record or records within 10 working days.</p>
<p>(b) Determination on an amendment request. The decision of CIGIE in response to a request for amendment of a record in a system of records may grant in whole or deny any part of the request to amend the record.</p>
<p>(1) If CIGIE grants the request, the appropriate system manager will amend the record(s) and provide a copy of the amended record(s) to the requester.  To the extent an accounting of disclosure has been maintained, the system manager shall advise all previous recipients of the record that an amendment has been made and give the substance of the amendment.  Where practicable, the system manager shall send a copy of the amended record to previous recipients.</p>
<p>(2) If CIGIE denies the request in whole or in part, the reasons for the denial will be stated in the response letter. In addition, the response letter will state:</p>
<p>(i) The name and address of the official with whom an appeal of the denial may be lodged; and</p>
<p>(ii) A description of any other procedures which may be required of the requester in order to process the appeal.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.303 Appeal from adverse determination on amendment. </b></p>
<p>(a) How addressed.  A requester may submit a written appeal of the decision by CIGIE to deny an initial request to amend a record in a CIGIE system of records to the Chairperson, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.  The words �Privacy Act Appeal� should be included on the envelope and at the top of the letter of appeal.</p>
<p>(b) Deadline and content.  The appeal must be received by CIGIE within 60 days of the date of the letter denying the request and should contain a brief description of the record(s) involved or copies of the correspondence from CIGIE and the reasons why the requester believes that the disputed information should be amended.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.304  Response to appeal of adverse determination on amendment; disagreement statements. </b></p>
<p>(a) Response timing.  The Chairperson should make a final determination in writing not later than 30 days from the date the appeal was received.  The 30-day period may be extended for good cause.  Notice of the extension and the reasons therefor will be sent to the requester within the 30-day period.</p>
<p>(b) Amendment granted.  If the Chairperson determines that the record(s) should be amended in accordance with the requester's request, the Chairperson will take the necessary steps to advise the requester and to direct the appropriate system manager:</p>
<p>(1) To amend the record(s); and</p>
<p>(2) To notify previous recipients of the record(s) for which there is an accounting of disclosure that the record(s) have been amended.</p>
<p>(c) Denial affirmed.  If the appeal decision does not grant in full the request for amendment, the decision letter will notify the requester that the requester may:</p>
<p>(1) Obtain judicial review of the decision in accordance with the terms of the Privacy Act at 5 U.S.C. 552a(g); and</p>
<p>(2) File a statement setting forth their reasons for disagreeing with the decision.</p>
<p>(d) Requester's disagreement statement.  A requester's disagreement statement must be concise. CIGIE has the authority to determine the conciseness of the statement, taking into account the scope of the disagreement and the complexity of the issues.</p>
<p>(e) Provision of requester's disagreement statement.  In any disclosure of information about which an individual has filed a proper statement of disagreement, CIGIE will clearly note any disputed portion(s) of the record(s) and will provide a copy of the statement to persons or other agencies to whom the disputed record or records has been disclosed and for whom an accounting of disclosure has been maintained.  A concise statement of the reasons for not making the amendments requested may also be provided.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9801.305 Assistance in preparing request to amend a record or to appeal an initial adverse determination. </b></p>
<p> Requesters may seek assistance in preparing a request to amend a record or an appeal of an initial adverse determination, or to learn further of the provisions for judicial review, by contacting CIGIE's Privacy Officer by email at privacy@cigie.gov or by mail at Privacy Officer, Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, 1717 H Street, NW, Suite 825, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
    <p>
        <b> Subpart D—Exemptions</b>
    </p>
    <p>Source: 82 FR 51334, Nov. 6, 2017, unless otherwise noted.</p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167; 9801.401 Exemptions. </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) <i>General policy. </i> Systems of records maintained by CIGIE are authorized to be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act under the general and specific exemptions set forth in the Privacy Act. In utilizing these exemptions, CIGIE is exempting only those portions of systems that are necessary for the proper functioning of CIGIE and that are consistent with the Privacy Act. Where compliance would not appear to interfere with or adversely affect the law enforcement process, and/or where it may be appropriate to permit individuals to contest the accuracy of the information collected, e.g., public source materials, the applicable exemption may be waived, either partially or totally, by CIGIE, at the sole discretion of CIGIE, as appropriate.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) <i>Specific system of records exempted under (j)(2), (k)(1), and (k)(2)</i>.  The system of records maintained in connection with CIGIE’s Integrity Committee, the Integrity Committee Management System (CIGIE-04), is subject to general exemption under 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and the specific exemptions under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and (2). These exemptions apply only to the extent that information in this system is subject to exemption pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2), (k)(1) and (k)(2). Where compliance would not appear to interfere with or adversely affect the law enforcement process, and/or where it may be appropriate to permit individuals to contest the accuracy of the information collected, e.g., public source materials, the applicable exemption may be waived, either partially or totally, by CIGIE, at the sole discretion of CIGIE, as appropriate.
    </p>
    <p>
        (1) Pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), CIGIE-04 is exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act: 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) and (c)(4); (d); (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G)-(H), (e)(5), and (e)(8); (f); and (g).
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) Pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and (2), CIGIE-04 is exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act: 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3); (d); (e)(1) and (e)(4)(G)-(H); and (f).
    </p>
    <p>
        (3) Exemptions from the particular subsections are justified for the following reasons:
    </p>
    <p>
        (i) From subsection (c)(3) because release of disclosure accounting could alert the subjects of an investigation of an actual or potential criminal, civil, or regulatory violation to the existence of the investigation and the fact that they are subjects of the investigation, and reveal investigative interest by not only CIGIE, through the IC, but also by external agencies such as the Public Integrity Section of the Department of Justice. Because release of such information to the subjects of an investigation would provide them with significant information concerning the nature of the investigation, release could result in the destruction of documentary evidence, improper influencing of witnesses, and other activities that could impede or compromise the investigation.  In addition, accounting for each disclosure could result in the release of properly classified information which would compromise the national defense or disrupt foreign policy.
    </p>
    <p>
        (ii) From subsection (c)(4) because this system is exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d) pursuant to subsections (j) and (k) of the Privacy Act.
    </p>
    <p>
        (iii) From the access and amendment provisions of subsection (d) because access to the records contained in this system of records could inform the subjects of an investigation of an actual or potential criminal, civil, or regulatory violation of the existence of that investigation and of the nature and scope of the information and evidence obtained as to their activities. Such awareness by the subjects could prevent the successful completion of an investigation and/or lead to the improper influencing of witnesses, the destruction of evidence, or fabricated testimony. In addition, granting access to such information could disclose security-sensitive or confidential business information or information that would constitute an unwarranted invasion of the personal privacy of third parties. Finally, access to the records could result in the release of classified information which would compromise the national defense or disrupt foreign policy. Amendment of the records would interfere with ongoing investigations and law enforcement activities and impose an impossible administrative burden by requiring investigations to be continuously reinvestigated.
    </p>
    <p>
        (iv) From subsection (e)(1) because the application of this provision could impair investigations and interfere with the law enforcement responsibilities of CIGIE through the IC for the following reasons:
    </p>
    <p>
        (A) It is not possible to detect relevance or necessity of specific information in the early stages of a civil, criminal, or other law enforcement investigation, case, or matter, including investigations in which use is made of classified information. Relevance and necessity are questions of judgment and timing, and it is only after the information is evaluated that the relevance and necessity of such information can be established.
    </p>
    <p>
        (B) During the course of any investigation, CIGIE, through the IC, may obtain information concerning actual or potential violations of laws other than those within the scope of its jurisdiction. In the interest of effective law enforcement, CIGIE should retain this information, as it may aid in establishing patterns of criminal activity and can provide valuable leads for Federal and other law enforcement agencies.
    </p>
    <p>
        (C) In interviewing individuals or obtaining other forms of evidence during an investigation, information may be supplied to an investigator that relates to matters incidental to the primary purpose of the investigation but which may relate also to matters under the investigative jurisdiction of another agency. Such information cannot readily be segregated.
    </p>
    <p>
        (v) From subsection (e)(2) because, in some instances, the application of this provision would present a serious impediment to law enforcement for the following reasons:
    </p>
    <p>
        (A) The subjects of an investigation would be placed on notice as to the existence of an investigation and would therefore be able to avoid detection or apprehension, to improperly influence witnesses, to destroy evidence, or to fabricate testimony.
    </p>
    <p>
        (B) In certain circumstances the subjects of an investigation cannot be required to provide information to investigators, and information relating to their illegal acts, violations of rules of conduct, or any other misconduct must be obtained from other sources.
    </p>
    <p>
        (C) In any investigation it is necessary to obtain evidence from a variety of sources other than the subjects of the investigation.
    </p>
    <p>
        (vi) From subsection (e)(3) because the application of this provision would provide the subjects of an investigation with substantial information which could impede or compromise the investigation.
    </p>
    <p>
        (vii) From subsection (e)(4)(G)-(I) because this system of records is exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d).
    </p>
    <p>
        (viii) From subsection (e)(5) because the application of this provision may prevent the collection of any data not shown to be accurate, relevant, timely, and complete at the moment it is collected. In the collection of information for law enforcement purposes, it is impossible to determine in advance what information is accurate, relevant, timely, and complete. Material which may seem unrelated, irrelevant, or incomplete when collected may take on added meaning or significance as an investigation progresses. The restrictions of this provision could interfere with the preparation of a complete investigative report, and thereby impede effective law enforcement.
    </p>
    <p>
        (ix) From subsection (e)(8) because the application of this provision could prematurely reveal an ongoing criminal investigation to the subjects of an investigation and could reveal investigative techniques, procedures, or evidence.
    </p>
    <p>
        (x) From subsection (f) because CIGIE's rules are inapplicable to those portions of the system that are exempt and would place the burden on CIGIE of either confirming or denying the existence of a record pertaining to a requesting individual, which might in itself provide an answer to that individual relating to an ongoing investigation. The conduct of a successful investigation leading to the indictment of a criminal offender precludes the applicability of established agency rules relating to verification of record, disclosure of the record to that individual, and record amendment procedures for this record system.
    </p>
    <p> (xi) From subsection (g) to the extent that this system is exempt from the access and amendment provisions of subsection (d) pursuant to subsections (j)(2), (k)(1), and (k)(2) of the Privacy Act. </p>
    <p>
        (c) <i>Specific system of records exempted under (j)(2), (k)(1), and (k)(2).</i>  The system of records maintained in connection with PRAC Accountability Data System (CIGIE-6), is subject to general exemption under 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and the specific exemptions under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and (2). These exemptions apply only to the extent that information in this system is subject to exemption pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2), (k)(1) and (k)(2). Where compliance would not appear to interfere with or adversely affect the law enforcement process, and/or where it may be appropriate to permit individuals to contest the accuracy of the information collected, e.g., public source materials, the applicable exemption may be waived, either partially or totally, by CIGIE, at the sole discretion of CIGIE, as appropriate.
    </p>
    <p>(1) Pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), CIGIE-6 is exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act: 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) and (c)(4); (d); (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G)-(H), (e)(5), and (e)(8); (f); and (g).</p>
    <p>(2) Pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and (2), CIGIE-6 is exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act: 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3); (d); (e)(1) and (e)(4)(G)-(H); and (f).</p>
    <p> (3) Exemptions from the particular subsections are justified for the following reasons:</p>
    <p> (i) From subsection (c)(3) because release of disclosure accounting could alert the subjects of an investigation of an actual or potential criminal, civil, or regulatory violation to the existence of the investigation and the fact that they are subjects of the investigation, and reveal investigative interest by not only CIGIE, through the PRAC, but also by external agencies such as Federal Offices of Inspector General. Because release of such information to the subjects of an investigation would provide them with significant information concerning the nature of the investigation, release could result in the destruction of documentary evidence, improper influencing of witnesses, and other activities that could impede or compromise the investigation.  In addition, accounting for each disclosure could result in the release of properly classified information which would compromise the national defense or disrupt foreign policy.</p>
    <p>(ii) From subsection (c)(4) because this system is exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d) pursuant to subsections (j) and (k) of the Privacy Act.</p>
    <p>(iii) From the access and amendment provisions of subsection (d) because access to the records contained in this system of records could inform the subjects of an investigation of an actual or potential criminal, civil, or regulatory violation of the existence of that investigation and of the nature and scope of the information and evidence obtained as to their activities. Such awareness by the subjects could prevent the successful completion of an investigation and/or lead to the improper influencing of witnesses, the destruction of evidence, or fabricated testimony. In addition, granting access to such information could disclose security-sensitive or confidential business information or information that would constitute an unwarranted invasion of the personal privacy of third parties. Finally, access to the records could result in the release of classified information which would compromise the national defense or disrupt foreign policy. Amendment of the records would interfere with ongoing investigations and law enforcement activities and impose an impossible administrative burden by requiring investigations to be continuously reinvestigated.</p>
    <p>(iv) From subsection (e)(1) because the application of this provision could impair investigations and interfere with the law enforcement responsibilities of CIGIE through the PRAC for the following reasons:</p>
    <p>(A) It is not possible to detect relevance or necessity of specific information in the early stages of a civil, criminal, or other law enforcement investigation, case, or matter, including investigations in which use is made of classified information. Relevance and necessity are questions of judgment and timing, and it is only after the information is evaluated that the relevance and necessity of such information can be established.</p>
    <p>(B) During the course of any investigation, CIGIE, through the PRAC may obtain information concerning actual or potential violations of laws other than those within the scope of its jurisdiction. In the interest of effective law enforcement, the PRAC should retain this information, as it may aid in establishing patterns of criminal activity and can provide valuable leads for Federal and other law enforcement agencies.</p>
    <p>(C) In interviewing individuals or obtaining other forms of evidence during an investigation, information may be supplied to an investigator that relates to matters incidental to the primary purpose of the investigation but which may relate also to matters under the investigative jurisdiction of another agency. Such information cannot readily be segregated.</p>
    <p>(v) From subsection (e)(2) because, in some instances, the application of this provision would present a serious impediment to law enforcement for the following reasons:</p>
    <p>(A) The subjects of an investigation would be placed on notice as to the existence of an investigation and would therefore be able to avoid detection or apprehension, to improperly influence witnesses, to destroy evidence, or to fabricate testimony.</p>
    <p>(B) In certain circumstances the subjects of an investigation cannot be required to provide information to investigators, and information relating to their illegal acts, violations of rules of conduct, or any other misconduct must be obtained from other sources.</p>
    <p>(C) In any investigation it is necessary to obtain evidence from a variety of sources other than the subjects of the investigation.</p>
    <p>(vi) From subsection (e)(3) because the application of this provision would provide the subjects of an investigation with substantial information which could impede or compromise the investigation.</p>
    <p>(vii) From subsection (e)(4)(G)-(I) because this system of records is exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d).</p>
    <p>(viii) From subsection (e)(5) because the application of this provision may prevent the collection of any data not shown to be accurate, relevant, timely, and complete at the moment it is collected. In the collection of information for law enforcement purposes, it is impossible to determine in advance what information is accurate, relevant, timely, and complete. Material which may seem unrelated, irrelevant, or incomplete when collected may take on added meaning or significance as an investigation progresses. The restrictions of this provision could interfere with the preparation of a complete investigative report, and thereby impede effective law enforcement.</p>
    <p>(ix) From subsection (e)(8) because the application of this provision could prematurely reveal an ongoing criminal investigation to the subjects of an investigation and could reveal investigative techniques, procedures, or evidence.</p>
    <p>(x) From subsection (f) because CIGIE's rules are inapplicable to those portions of the system that are exempt and would place the burden on CIGIE of either confirming or denying the existence of a record pertaining to a requesting individual, which might in itself provide an answer to that individual relating to an ongoing investigation. The conduct of a successful investigation leading to the indictment of a criminal offender precludes the applicability of established agency rules relating to verification of record, disclosure of the record to that individual, and record amendment procedures for this record system.</p>
    <p>(xi) From subsection (g) to the extent that this system is exempt from the access and amendment provisions of subsection (d) pursuant to subsections (j)(2), (k)(1), and (k)(2) of the Privacy Act.</p>
    <p>[81 FR 86563, Dec. 1, 2016, as amended at 86 FR 26649, May 17, 2021]</p>


</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
