<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes"> 
<name>Central Intelligence Agency</name>
<abbrev>
CIA

</abbrev>

       

<routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Statement of General Routine Uses</p>
<p>The following routine uses apply to, and are incorporated by reference into, each system of records maintained by the CIA:
</p><p>1. In the event that a system of records maintained by the Central Intelligence Agency to carry out its functions indicates, or relates to, a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency whether federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation, or charged with the responsibility to take appropriate administrative action, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a federal, state or local agency maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a Central Intelligence Agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance or special access, or the performance of the Agency's acquisition functions</p>
<p>3. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a federal, state, or local agency, or other appropriate entities, or individuals, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance or special access, the reporting or an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the entity's decision on the matter</p>
<p>4. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate or administrative tribunal, including disclosures to opposing parties or their counsel or other representatives in the course of settlement negotiations, and disclosures made pursuant to statutes or regulations governing the conduct of such proceedings</p>
<p>5. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget in connection with the review of private relief legislation, as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19, at any stage of the legislative coordination and clearance process as set forth in the Circular</p>
<p>6. A record from a system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to NARA (GSA) in records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906</p>
<p>7. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a federal, state, or local agency, other appropriate entities or individuals, or, through established liaison channels, to selected foreign governments, provided such disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the purpose for which the record was collected and is undertaken to enable the Central Intelligence Agency to carry out its responsibilities under the National Security Act of 1947, as amended, the CIA Act of 1949, as amended, Executive Order 12333 or any successor order, national security directives applicable to the Agency and classified implementing procedures approved by the Attorney General promulgated pursuant to such Orders and directives, as well as statutes, Executive orders and directives of general applicability. This routine use is not intended to supplant the other routine uses published by the Central Intelligence Agency</p></xhtmlContent></routineUses>
<section id="cia1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Financial Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former CIA staff and contract employees, and military and civilian personnel detailed to CIA; and personal services independent contractors, industrial contractors, commercial vendors, and consultants to the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains financial accounts and records concerning CIA expenditures. This includes: records relating to financial transactions associated with commercial vendors and contracts; official travel orders, records of funds advanced and transportation furnished, copies of travel claims and accountings, visas, and passports; records concerning claims submitted for financial review, including all financial documentation accumulated in the collection and settlement of amounts due the agency from employees and former employees; records tracking general accounting data, including the status of funds advanced to individuals for official purposes and the procurement of materials and services; records on certifying officers, contracting officers, cash custodians and credit card holders, including authorizing letters and signature cards; and records for the processing of personal property claims and related activity.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act (50 U.S.C. 2001 et seq.).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide accounting data to track items such as budget and expenses to allow the CIA to acquire goods and services and provide an accounting infrastructure; travel services; and financial management expertise for fiscal resource utilization and control; and determine whether the commitment and expenditure of CIA funds is authorized, approved, and certified by officials to whom such authority has been delegated.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by utomated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities used in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured area within the CIA accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Financial Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals to whom records in this system pertain, and other CIA employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cia2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Training Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees, other federal employees, CIA personal services independent contractors and industrial contractors to CIA who have completed internal and CIA-sponsored external training courses or programs; and instructors and potential instructors for the CIA off-campus education program.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Transcripts of CIA-sponsored training; student and instructor biographic data; course information; and names of CIA employees responsible for approving CIA-sponsored training.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; manage training activities for individuals assigned to the CIA; process requests for internal and external training for CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, industrial contractors and military and civilian personnel detailed to CIA; update and provide reference for CIA employee training records; and facilitate the process for selecting instructors for the CIA off-campus education program.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name and employee number. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Training and Development Office, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; students and instructors in CIA internal and CIA-sponsored external training; and training facilities and other educational institutions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Language Program Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>CIA staff and contract employees, and other individuals who have participated in CIA-managed or CIA-sponsored language training and testing.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographic data; test scores; training reports from instructors; training requests from sponsoring office(s); and attendance reports.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide information concerning language proficiency of CIA and non-CIA personnel who have taken internal or CIA-sponsored external language training or testing; monitor student performance; and conduct research and compile statistics on a variety of matters related to language learning and testing.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or social security number. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Training and Development Office, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Students and instructors in CIA internal or CIA-sponsored external language training courses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>


</section>
<section id="cia4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">CIA Declassification Center (CDC) External Liaison Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to CONFIDENTIAL.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals at U.S. government agencies who serve as points of contact for dealings with the CDC External Referral &amp;Liaison Branch.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographic information including name, social security number, position, title/rank, and expertise; locator information including telephone numbers, fax numbers, and addresses (primary, e-mail and pouch); and information related to security clearances and access approvals, including clearances held, current status of clearances, and period of certification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and maintain a current list of points of contact at U.S. government agencies on EO 12958 declassification issues.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in secure file servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, social security number, and agency. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated search based on capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access is restricted to individuals who are certified on an access control list. Additional software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with records control schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, External Referral &amp;Liaison Branch/CIA Declassification Center, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.1-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals covered by this system, and points of contact provided by U.S. government agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Center for the Study of Intelligence (CSI) Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors to CIA, and current and former employees detailed to the CIA who have participated in an "oral history"  program.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names, biographic data and the content of information provided by individuals who have participated in CSI's "oral history"  program, or worked with CSI.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and record experiences of current and former CIA associates for use in CSI projects.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Center for the Study of Intelligence, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals covered by this system; and CIA records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>


</section>
<section id="cia6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Manuscript Review Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former CIA employees; other authors obligated to submit writings or oral presentations for pre-publication review; and individuals otherwise involved in pre-publication review matters with CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Manuscripts and other writings submitted for pre-publication review; Publication Review Board meeting minutes, official memoranda, bibliographic files and related documents; and Publication Review Board Reference Center documentation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825); Executive Order 12968 (60 FR 40245); Snepp v. United States, 444 U.S. 507 (1980).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; to enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; as references for manuscripts, meeting minutes, official memoranda, bibliographic files and related documents which have been submitted for review in compliance with applicable regulations; and to facilitate review of new manuscript submissions of proposed publications or speeches authored or given by present or former employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chair, Publications Review Board, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former CIA employees and other obligated authors; Publication Review Boards members and staff; and other CIA personnel involved in the publications review process.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Security Access Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>CIA employees and other individuals authorized to access CIA buildings and facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal identification information; building and entrance information; entry or exit data and codes; and credential information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; verify individuals' authorization to access CIA buildings and facilities; create a record of individuals' access to CIA buildings and facilities; facilitate the issuance and retrieval of visitor and temporary badges; and provide statistical data on building and facility access patterns for resource planning purposes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Security, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>CIA badge system; after-hours building and facility logs; visitor-no-escort badge record cards; and permits and identification sources.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Security Operations Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals, including CIA employees, who have contacted or been referred to the CIA's Security Operations Center; individuals, including CIA employees, who have been responsible for or suspected of security incidents, or have witnessed, reported, or investigated security incidents involving CIA information, and/or CIA-controlled property or facilities; individuals who have had restrictions imposed upon their entrance to CIA-controlled property or facilities; and individuals involved in traffic violations on CIA-controlled property or facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal identification and event information that includes: biographic information, including name, social security number, and CIA identification information; information on security-related incidents occurring on CIA-controlled property or facilities, including date and place of incidents, subject matter or incident description, arrests and violation information, including court disposition and vehicular information where appropriate.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; track events, individuals, and groups of individuals that may pose a threat to the CIA; assist CIA security officials in identifying present and future threats to CIA-controlled property or facilities and CIA personnel; track traffic violations, security incidents, and access control issues; serve as a statistical and management reporting tool; and facilitate court cases or other legal proceedings.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Reports regarding accidents and traffic violations may be provided to the individuals involved and their insurance companies to facilitate the resolution of claims. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name or other personal identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Security, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals covered by this system of records; members of the general public; CIA employees; and employees of other federal agencies and state and local governments.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Industrial Security Clearance Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Industrial contractors and commercial vendors; and persons in the private sector associated with the CIA who hold industrial security clearances.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographic data, including name, address, position, and social security number; and security clearance information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 10450 (5 U.S.C. 7311 note); Executive Order 12958 (78 FR 19825); and Executive Order 12968 (60 FR 40245).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; document security clearance(s) held by industrial contractors, commercial vendors, and persons in the private sector associated with the CIA; and provide a reference to answer inquiries on security clearances.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used to certify clearances of individuals covered by the system. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By individual or company name, and social security number. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Procurement Executive, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who hold or have held security clearances and the organizations with which they are employed or otherwise associated; and certification of clearance from the Center for CIA Security.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Parking Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to CONFIDENTIAL.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA employees and any other individuals requiring parking permits at CIA-controlled facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Name, office location, grade, badge number, vehicle license number, personal identifying information and relevant medical information of individuals covered in this system.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and document the allocation and control of parking spaces at CIA-controlled facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, and vehicle license number. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief of Global Support, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA employees and other individuals requiring parking permits at CIA-controlled facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Accountable Property Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees; personal services independent contractors; industrial contractors; military and civilian personnel detailed to CIA; and other individuals who possess CIA accountable property.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Name, signature and office location of individuals covered by this system; and description of accountable property charged to individuals covered by this system.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; document accountability for CIA nonexpendable property; and track, inventory, audit, and report on accountable property.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief of Global Support, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals concerned with accountable property, and accountable property officers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Vehicle Operator Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, or industrial contractors who have licenses to drive buses, trucks, and other specialty vehicles as part of their official CIA employment duties.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic data on employees; medical qualification forms; driver test data; registers of permits issued; and accident report records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; document CIA staff and contract employees who are qualified to drive buses, trucks, and other specialty vehicles in the course of their CIA employment duties; and issue official U.S. Government driver's licenses and renewals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name or driver's permit number. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities used in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Transportation Support, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, and industrial contractors; and federal, state and local law enforcement agencies as their records relate to competency testing and accident reporting.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Component Human Resources Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former CIA staff and contract employees; military and civilian personnel detailed or assigned to the CIA; applicants for employment with the CIA; current and former employees of industrial contractors; and current and former independent contractors.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Memoranda, correspondence and other documents, including personnel soft files and supervisors' working files maintained by Agency offices and components, concerning individuals covered by this system on matters involving: performance appraisals; travel, financial, retirement and claims information; time and attendance, including leave information; performance, conduct, and suitability; education, certification, training, and testing; special qualifications or restrictions; dependency and residence; emergency notifications; medical information, including disabilities and job-related injuries; biographic data; skills assessment data; locator information; cables and dispatches of administrative and operational significance; employee grievances, including equal employment opportunity complaints; employee evaluation panel files; and employee awards.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act (50 U.S.C. 2001 et seq.).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are created, maintained and used by human resource management officials, supervisory personnel, and other authorized personnel at all levels of the organization on a need-to-know basis. These records, including supervisors' working files, EEO and grievance files, and suitability files, are used to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; supplement official personnel folders ("soft files" ); facilitate and expedite processing or procedural requirements related to employee transactions; provide reference to monitor, record, and perform personnel management functions including employee counseling, employee evaluation, assignment, promotion, authorization of training, awards and leave; and provide management with statistical reporting.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in a secured area located in premises controlled by the head of the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located in premises controlled by the head of the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, CIA employee number, or other personal identifiers. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<table>
    <tr>
        <th scope="col">Component:</th>
        <th scope="col">Manager:</th>
    </tr>
<tr><td>Office of the Executive Director</td> <td>Executive Director</td></tr>
<tr><td>Directorate of Intelligence</td> <td>DI Information Management Officer</td></tr>
<tr><td>Directorate of Operations</td> <td>Chief, DO Human Resources Staff</td></tr>
<tr><td>Directorate of Science &amp;Technology</td> <td>Chief, DS&amp;T Administrative Resources</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of the Chief Financial Officer </td><td>Chief Financial Officer</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of the Chief Information Officer</td><td>Chief Information Officer</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of Global Support </td><td>Chief of Global Support</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of Human Resources</td> <td>Chief Human Resources Officer</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of Security </td><td>Director of Security</td></tr>
<tr><td>National Intelligence Council</td> <td>Chairman, National Intelligence Council</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of Congressional Affairs </td><td>Director of Congressional Affairs</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of the DDCI for Community Management</td><td>Executive Director for IC Affairs</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of General Counsel </td><td>General Counsel</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of Inspector General </td><td>Inspector General</td></tr>
<tr><td>Office of Public Affairs </td><td>Director of Public Affairs</td></tr>
<tr><td>Additional DCI Area Components:</td><td>DCI Information Management Officer</td></tr></table>
<p>Address: Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals covered by the system; educational institutions and private organizations; CIA employees; and other federal agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Information Release Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who make information release requests to CIA under provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), Privacy Act (PA), and Executive Order 12958 (EO); individuals who make special search requests and other related individuals; and individuals who are the subject of FOIA/PA/EO and special search requests and other related individuals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>FOIA/PA/EO requests and processing files including correspondence and supporting documents; documents responsive to FOIA/PA/EO and special search requests; duplicate files maintained by Directorate Information Review Officers (IROs) and component focal points; weekly reports of FOIA/PA/EO case activity and status; and indices related to special searches.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825); the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552); the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a); the President John F. Kennedy Assassination Records Collection Act of 1992 (44 U.S.C. 2107 note); the Nazi War Crimes Disclosure Act (5 U.S.C. 552 note); the Japanese Imperial Government Records Disclosure Act (5 U.S.C. 552 note).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; support the review, redaction, and release of CIA records pursuant to federal statutes and Executive Orders; formulate responses to FOIA/PA/EO and special search requests; provide reference in processing cases under administrative appeal and civil litigation; provide documentation for referral to other federal agencies for their review pursuant to Executive Order 12958, and the third agency rule; and generate external reports as required by federal statutes and internal reports for use by CIA officials.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, case number, and full text search. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief of Information Management Services, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who make FOIA/PA/EO and special search requests, and related individuals; and CIA components that provide information in response to FOIA/PA/EO and special search requests.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Guest Speaker Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals under consideration for guest speaker engagements, training courses and other presentations; such individuals may include members of the academic and business world as well as present and former senior CIA and other government officials.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic data including academic credentials; publicly available information, including publications authored by the potential speaker; correspondence; and administrative records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; to enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and for curriculum development and selection of speakers for training courses and special presentations. Biographic data may be used as part of the official file for personal services contracts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief Information Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; CIA employees; academic institutions and private organizations; libraries and commercial databases; and federal agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Clinical and Psychiatric Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees and their dependents; military and civilian employees detailed to CIA and their dependents; retired or separated CIA employees and their dependents; and physicians who provide services to any of the categories of individuals listed above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Physical examinations; laboratory data; X-rays; private physician reports; reports of on-the-job injuries and illnesses; results of psychiatric screening and testing; reports of psychiatric interviews; records of immunizations; records on individuals covered by this system receiving Agency counseling; other medical material relating to environmental health, safety training, and preventative medicine; and biographic information on physicians covered by this system of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; to enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; to maintain a complete and accurate medical record of all CIA employees, their dependents, military and civilian employees detailed to CIA, and retired or separated employees; to respond to requirements relating to safety and environmental issues and to CIA safety and environmental compliance training; to evaluate suitability for assignment, travel, fitness-for-duty, health maintenance and in reviewing applications for medical disability retirement; to track the safety and health status of CIA employees, components, sites, and operations; and to refer individuals for specialty medical assistance.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the Office of Personnel Management in the case of an employee who applies for medical disability, and to the Department of Labor in the case of an employee who applies for Worker's Compensation benefits. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, chart number, or other identifying information. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Medical Services Office, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals supply their medical history; physicians supply their biographic information; and additional sources may include routine medical processing and reports from private physicians or medical facilities when written permission is granted by the individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>


</section>
<section id="cia17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Applicant Clinical and Psychiatric Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Applicants for employment with CIA.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Physical examinations and related medical material; laboratory data; results of psychiatric screening and testing; and reports of psychiatric interviews.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; to enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; to maintain a complete and accurate medical file on all individuals applying for CIA employment; to evaluate the medical suitability of applicants; to serve as a basis for the Employee Clinical and Psychiatric Record once an applicant is hired by the CIA; and to generate statistical reports on applicants.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, chart number, or other identifying information. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Medical Services Office, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Applicants who supply their medical history; additional sources may include routine medical processing and reports from private physicians or medical facilities when written permission is granted by the applicant.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-18</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Psychological Testing Data Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Applicants for employment with the CIA; CIA staff or contract employees and their dependents; military and civilian personnel detailed to the CIA; and retired or separated CIA staff or contract employees and their dependents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Psychological testing records and assessment reports.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; to enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; to track individual test results which aid CIA management and advisory personnel, who have a need-to-know, in decision making; to produce research reports of aggregate data for appropriate officials and components of the CIA; and to examine the relationship between test scores and other variables of interest such as job performance.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, or other identifying information. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Medical Services Office, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who have completed a variety of psychological tests and interview sessions with CIA medical officers; and individuals involved in the assessment of test data.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>


</section>
<section id="cia19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Agency Human Resources Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former CIA staff and contract employees; military and civilian personnel detailed to the CIA; personal services independent contractors; applicants in process for CIA employment; candidates for CIA awards; participants, and beneficiaries designated by deceased CIA employees who were participants, in the CIA's authorized retirement systems and retirement savings programs; and certain OSS veterans.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic data including records on education, military service data, insurance, medical and retirement status and locator information on individuals covered by this system; employment information including records on applicant tracking, job matching, seasonal and cooperative employment programs, and information on those separating from CIA employment; personnel information including records on employment history, leave, time and attendance, fitness and performance appraisal reports, awards, travel, training, job injury, worker's compensation records and security clearance information; CIA personnel information including records on position and job title information, qualifications and skills assessments, authorized personnel staffing data, levels, and patterns; financial information relating to payroll and authorized retirement and retirement savings accounts, including authorized or required payroll deductions or contributions for federal, state and local taxes, other tax documentation, and retirement, insurance and leave entitlements; banking instructions for dissemination of salary paychecks; contracts relating to contract employees and independent contractors; and financial disclosure forms submitted pursuant to the Ethics in Government Act.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act (50 U.S.C. 2001 et seq.).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> To serve as the central human resources management system for the CIA. Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; perform centralized personnel functions such as employment, separation of employment, payroll, position and personnel staffing, and general employee transactions; support the general administration of systems dependent on personnel data such as insurance, medical and health care, and retirement and retirement savings; compute salary, attendance, leave, benefits and entitlements for payroll and its dependent systems including insurance, medical and health care, and authorized retirement and retirement savings systems; track applicant and employee biographic and demographic data for use in employee location tracking, and statistical reports; compile statistical reports for CIA management on strength, distribution and utilization of staffing, average grades and salaries, minorities, projected retirements, profiles of CIA skills and qualifications, comparative rates on promotions, separations, new employees, reasons for separations; provide information and statistics for heads of Career Services to assist them in administering their career development and evaluation programs, including promotion rates and headroom, performance appraisal report ratings, qualifications, changes in their Career Services; assess staffing patterns, grade and salary data for office heads required for staffing and budget projections; provide information and statistics for components responsible for administering recruitment, hospitalization, insurance, and authorized retirement and retirement savings programs; and provide records of employee transactions to responsible CIA officials and to the employees themselves.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Information from this system concerning CIA retirees is routinely disseminated to the Office of Personnel Management. Information concerning work-related injuries of CIA employees is routinely provided to the Department of Labor in connection with Worker's Compensation claims. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses," which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, CIA employee number, or other personal identifiers. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief Human Resources Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; educational institutions; physicians and medical practitioners; CIA employees; and other federal agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>


</section>
<section id="cia20" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-20</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Official Personnel Files.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former CIA staff and contract employees; and military and civilian personnel detailed to the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Personal and employment history statements; employment contracts; personnel actions; performance appraisal reports; awards and commendations; biographic profiles and data; retirement status and exit processing information; training and travel records; correspondence; and photographs.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act (50 U.S.C. 2001 et seq.).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by human resource management personnel and other authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; administer routine personnel transactions including: personnel assignments; performance evaluations; promotions; adverse actions; counseling; retirement determinations of qualifications; separations; medical or insurance claims; and statistical reports; decide on the rights, benefits, entitlements and utilization of CIA employees; provide a data source for production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies related to human resource management issues; support resource metrics; locate specific individuals for personnel research or other personnel management functions; and verify employment.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Information from this system of records may be transmitted to another U.S. Government agency relative to employment considerations by that agency, and to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) relative to OPM's administration of retirement benefits for individuals covered by this system. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses," which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in secured area(s) within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located with the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other personal identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief Human Resources Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; educational institutions and private organizations; physicians and medical practitioners; CIA employees; and other federal agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>


</section>
<section id="cia21" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-21</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Applicant Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Applicants for employment with the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records concerning the applicant, including: biographic data; medical and employment history statements; educational transcripts; and personal references, and records relating to employment processing, including: interview reports; test results; correspondence; review comments; and general processing records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are used by CIA human resources management officials and other authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; to enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; to review an applicant's qualifications; for security background investigations; for suitability determinations; for medical screening; and to determine whether employment with the CIA will be offered.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other personal identifiers. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Recruitment Center, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA applicants; applicant references; educational institutions and private organizations; physicians and medical practitioners; CIA employees; and other federal agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former applicants for CIA employment; CIA staff and contract employees; personal services independent contractors and industrial contractors; military and civilian personnel detailed to the CIA; individuals of security interest to CIA; persons of, or contemplated for, substantive affiliation with, or service to, the CIA; persons on whom the CIA has conducted or is conducting an investigation; and federal, civilian, and military personnel with whom the CIA conducts liaison.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic data (including name, sex, date and place of birth, social security number, and completed security questionnaires); authorizations for the release of financial, travel, employment, housing, educational, and other information; summaries or reports of information obtained from other CIA records such as personnel, medical, or counterintelligence records; financial disclosure forms submitted by CIA personnel; travel data on individuals covered by this system; correspondence pertaining to an individual's suitability for CIA assignment or affiliation, and the individual's security eligibility for access to classified information, projects, or facilities; investigative reports, investigative information, and data pertaining to actual or purported compromises of classified or otherwise protected information; appraisals that summarize investigative results and provide the decision or rationale for determining whether an individual should receive access to classified information, projects, or facilities, or is suitable for CIA affiliation or assignment; documentation of, or relating to, interim or final actions relating to issues of security, discipline, or the grant, denial, suspension, or revocation of a CIA security clearance, access approval, or security approval; and secrecy agreements executed by individuals covered by this system.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 10450 (5 U.S.C. 7311 note); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825); and Executive Order 12968 (60 FR 40245).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; to document personnel security and suitability decisions; assist with security eligibility determinations and employment or assignment suitability decisions in accordance with applicable statutes, Executive Orders, Director of Central Intelligence Directives, CIA regulations, and other applicable law; record information regarding security eligibility determinations and employment or assignment suitability decisions concerning individuals who are under consideration for affiliation or continued affiliation with the CIA, or access or continued access to classified or otherwise protected CIA information, projects, or facilities; verify individual security clearances or access approvals; and record information relevant to investigations into possible violations of CIA rules and regulations, including the possible loss or compromise of classified or protected CIA information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used to provide information, including biographic information and records of security breaches, to other federal agencies involved in national security matters in the following circumstances: to respond to national agency checks; to certify security clearances and access approvals; and to provide information relevant to espionage investigations. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are safeguarded by combination lock security containers, or are stored within a vaulted area. Access is restricted to individuals who are certified on an "Access List."  The Access List is validated at least annually and circulated to responsible Agency officials so that they can ensure that records are accessed only for official purposes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director of Security, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system of records; personal and business references provided by the individual or developed during the course of an investigation; educational institutions and private organizations; federal, state, and local government entities; public sources such as newspapers and periodicals, consumer reporting agencies, financial, travel, educational, employment-related, and other commercial sources; and classified and unclassified reporting on investigations and investigative materials.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia23" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-23</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Intelligence Community Security Clearance and Access Approval Repository.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> U.S. government employees, military personnel, personal services independent contractors and industrial contractors to U.S government programs who possess security clearances and security access approvals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic data (including name, date and place of birth, social security number, and employer); and information relating to security clearances and security access approvals, including clearances and access approvals held, current status of clearances and access approvals, and date of background investigation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 10450 (5 U.S.C. 7311 note); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825); and Executive Order 12968 (60 FR 40245).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and to verify individual security clearances or security access approvals throughout the Intelligence Community in order to control access to classified and compartmented materials.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are provided to Intelligence Community agencies and relevant government contractors to certify individuals' security clearances and access approvals. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas controlled by the head of the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located in premises controlled by the head of the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name or social security number. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records and servers are stored within a vaulted area. Access is restricted to individuals with appropriate clearances and a "need to know,"  as certified by an Access Control List.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director of Security, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system of records; U.S. government agencies; and current and former employers of individuals covered by this system of records, including both government and private sector organizations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia24" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-24</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Polygraph Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former applicants for CIA employment; CIA staff and contract employees; personal services independent contractors and industrial contractors; military and civilian personnel detailed to the CIA; individuals of security interest to CIA; persons of, or contemplated for, substantive affiliation with, or service to, the CIA; and persons on whom the CIA has conducted or is conducting an investigation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Polygraph reports; polygraph charts; polygraph tapes; and notes from polygraph interviews or activities related to polygraph interviews.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 10450 (5 U.S.C. 7311 note); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825); Executive Order 12968 (60 FR 40245).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; document polygraph results; assist with security eligibility determinations and employment or assignment suitability decisions in accordance with applicable statutes, Executive Orders, Director of Central Intelligence Directives, CIA regulations, and other applicable law; and to assist with investigations into possible violations of CIA rules and regulations, including the possible loss or compromise of classified or protected CIA information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director of Security, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia25" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-25</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of the Director Action Center Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who send correspondence to, or receive correspondence from, the Office of the Director; and individuals who are the subject of correspondence to or from the Office of the Director.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Correspondence and documents addressed to, received by, or originated in the Office of the Director concerning: matters of policy, operations, and security within the purview of the head of the CIA; Congressional inquiries; and inquiries from the members of the general public.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; document the activities and policy decisions of the head of the CIA; and serve as reference material for business areas within the purview of the Office of the Director.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Correspondence contained in this system of records may be provided to U.S. Government agencies, other than the CIA, when it is determined that such other agencies can more appropriately handle the matters addressed in the correspondence. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, DAC, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> U.S. Government records; publicly available information from the media, libraries, and commercial databases; and Executive branch and Congressional officials and staff members, and members of the general public who send correspondence to, or receive correspondence from, the Office of the Director of Central Intelligence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia26" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of General Counsel Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, employees of industrial contractors, military and civilian personnel detailed or assigned to the CIA; applicants for employment with the CIA; current and former employees and contractors of U.S. Government agencies; individuals in contact with the CIA, including individuals whose inquiries concerning the CIA or the Intelligence Community (IC) are forwarded to the Office of General Counsel for response; attorneys in private practice who hold CIA security clearances or access approvals; individuals in government, academia, the business community, or other elements of the private sector with expertise on matters of interest to the Office of General Counsel; and individuals who may be involved in matters which implicate the CIA's and/or the IC's legal authorities, responsibilities, and obligations, including but not limited to administrative claimants, grievants, parties in litigation, witnesses, targets or potential targets of investigations or intelligence collection, and individuals who are interviewed by, or provide information to the CIA or the IC.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Legal documents, including but not limited to pleadings, subpoenas, motions, affidavits, declarations, briefs, litigation reports, and legal opinions; biographic information for private attorneys, including Social Security Number, date and place of birth, education, law firm (if any), office addresses, fax and telephone numbers, bar memberships, legal specialties and/or areas of practice, names of CIA-affiliated clients, and date and type of security clearance and/or access approval pending or granted; crimes reports filed with the U.S. Department of Justice or other appropriate law enforcement agencies concerning individuals covered by this system of records; public and confidential Financial Disclosure Reports required by the Office of Government Ethics; internal CIA documents and cables concerning individuals covered by this system of records; and correspondence with members of the public, members of the U.S. Congress, Congressional staff, and federal, state, local, international and foreign agencies, courts and administrative tribunals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide legal advice and representation to the Central Intelligence Agency and the Director of Central Intelligence; provide factual information necessary for the preparation of legal documents, including pleadings, subpoenas, motions, affidavits, declarations, briefs, legal opinions, litigation reports prepared for the Department of Justice, and reports to law enforcement agencies; provide a historical record of all private attorneys who have received security clearances and/or access approvals to receive and discuss U.S. Government information necessary to their representation of CIA-affiliated clients, and record the nature, scope and duration of private attorneys' legal representations of CIA-affiliated clients; and maintain a record of federal, state, local, international or foreign litigation, administrative claims, and other legal matters in which CIA is a party or has an interest.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name or other personal identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> General Counsel, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; publicly available information; CIA records; and federal, state and local government agencies and courts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia27" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-27</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of Equal Employment Opportunity (OEEO) Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, industrial contractors, and military and civilian personnel detailed to the CIA; and applicants for employment with the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Documents relating to EEO complaints, including: Data collected by an EEO Investigator which bears on charges of discrimination brought by a complainant; sworn affidavits from the complainant, the alleged discriminating officer(s), and other individuals as appropriate; other documents or statistical evidence considered pertinent to the case which assists the CIA in making a decision; requests made by individuals or offices for reasonable accommodations, and the products or services provided in response to such requests; and information regarding individuals who apply for retirement on the basis of medical disabilities, and other individuals with medical disabilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 11478, as amended by Executive Order 13097 (63 FR 30097) and Executive Order 13152 (65 FR 26115); Equal Employment Opportunity Act of 1972 (42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.); Age Discrimination in Employment Act (29 U.S.C. 633a); the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended (29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; process EEO complaints; provide information for review by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; provide information for federal court review; track requests and provide reasonable accommodations through the provision of products and services to individuals who make requests for such accommodations; and track applications for retirement on the basis of medical disabilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director, Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; applicants for employment with the CIA; individuals who provide information during the investigation of EEO complaints; and medical and psychiatric personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia28" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-28</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Congressional Liaison Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former members of the U.S. Congress and Congressional staff; individuals whose inquiries relating to CIA matters are forwarded by members of the U.S. Congress or Congressional staff to CIA for response, and CIA employees wishing to contact members of Congress or Congressional staff on official matters.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Correspondence and other documents between CIA's Office of Congressional Affairs, members of Congress, Congressional staff, constituents, and other CIA offices and/or U.S. Government entities regarding inquiries made by constituents or others and sent to the CIA for response; and memoranda, correspondence, position papers and other documents used to support CIA's liaison with members of Congress, staff, and their offices and committees, including memoranda documenting substantive briefings and debriefings, as well as reports provided to the CIA by Congressional personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; document constituent or other inquiries forwarded by members of Congress and staff to the CIA and CIA's responses to those inquiries; coordinate and prepare memoranda and position papers reflecting CIA's views on proposed legislation; facilitate Congressional briefings by maintaining a record of CIA's positions on issues of interest to particular members of Congress and staff; and provide guidance to employees on Congressional matters.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records from this system may be disclosed to Congress. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director of Congressional Affairs, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Current and former members of the U.S. Congress and their staffs; CIA employees; individuals whose inquiries relating to CIA matters are forwarded by members or staff of the U.S. Congress to the CIA for response.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia29" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-29</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Public Affairs Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Members of the general public who have written to the CIA to inquire about CIA activities; CIA personnel who have reported media contacts; and media representatives.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Media coverage, including newspaper and magazine articles, which mentions the CIA; correspondence between media representatives and the Office of Public Affairs; memoranda of conversations between the Office of Public Affairs and media representatives; correspondence from the general public regarding CIA, and CIA responses; internal CIA memoranda concerning the subject matter of this records system; and names of CIA personnel who have reported contacts with media representatives.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide a record of significant media coverage of the CIA; provide a record of contact with media representatives by the Office of Public Affairs; maintain a record of correspondence between members of the general public who raise questions about CIA activities; and maintain a record of CIA personnel media contacts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director of Public Affairs, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Publicly available information from the media, libraries and commercial databases; CIA records concerning CIA activities and the subject matter of media contacts; and individuals covered by this system of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia30" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-30</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Inspector General Research Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA personnel; and other individuals whose names appear in documents assembled primarily from other CIA records systems by the Inspector General in relation to Executive branch commission and Congressional committee reviews conducted between 1972 and 1976 concerning Agency activities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA documents that are pertinent to Executive branch commission and Congressional committee reviews of CIA activities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and for reference use in connection with Executive branch and Congressional committee reviews of CIA activities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Inspector General, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA employees; CIA records; and records of Executive branch commissions and Congressional committees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cia31" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-31</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Inspector General Investigation and Interview Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, industrial contractors, persons with other contractual relationships, or other relationships with the CIA, persons who are interviewed by or provide information to the Office of the Inspector General, persons involved with or knowledgeable about matters being investigated by the Office of Inspector General, and persons who have filed grievances with the Office of Inspector General or CIA components.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Reports of interviews, signed statements, correspondence, reports of investigations, forms, cables, internal CIA memoranda, prior criminal records of individuals covered by the system, and other materials relating to employee grievances and other matters of interest to or inspected by the Office of Inspector General.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and maintain a detailed record of the investigative activities of the CIA Office of Inspector General, including investigations of grievances, allegations of misconduct by CIA personnel; and to provide information to CIA management regarding personnel matters and to assist in the evaluation of current and proposed programs, policies and activities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> a. Records in this system are used and disclosed as necessary by members of the Office of Inspector General in the investigation of matters of interest or concern to the head of the CIA, Inspector General, and senior Agency officials, including grievances and allegations of misconduct by Agency employees, and to provide information to Agency management regarding personnel matters, and for evaluating current and proposed programs, policies and activities, selected assignments, and requests for awards or promotions</p>
<p>b. Records in this system that indicate a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program, or by rule, regulation or order pursuant thereto, or that indicate a violation or potential violation of a contractual obligation, may be disclosed to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local, foreign, or international, charged with the responsibility for investigating or prosecuting such violation, enforcing or implementing such statute, rule, regulation, or order, or with enforcing such contract</p>
<p>c. Records in the system may be disclosed to a federal, state, local, foreign, or international agency, or to an individual or organization, when necessary to elicit information relevant to an Office of Inspector General investigation, inquiry, decision, or recommendation</p>
<p>d. Records in the system may be disclosed to a federal, state, local, foreign, or international agency when requested in connection with the assignment, hiring, or retention of an individual, the issuance or revocation of a security clearance, letting of a contract, or any authorized inquiry or investigation to the extent that the information is relevant to the requesting agency's decision on the matter</p>
<p>e. Records in the system may be disclosed to any federal agency when documents, witness statements, or other information obtained from that agency are used in compiling the system record, or when the record is relevant to the official responsibilities of that agency</p>
<p>f. Unclassified records in the system, or unclassified portions thereof, including information identifying individuals covered by the system, may be disclosed to the public when the matter under investigation has become public knowledge or the Inspector General determines that such disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of the Inspector General process, or is necessary to demonstrate the accountability of CIA employees, officers, or individuals covered by the system, unless it is determined that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy</p>
<p>g. Records in the system pertaining to an employee grievance may be disclosed to any party to that grievance except for records that disclose the identity of a non-party who requested confidentiality and provided a statement during the grievance process</p>
<p>h. Records in the system may be disclosed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, including disclosures in the course of settlement negotiations, or pursuant to statutes or regulations governing the conduct of such proceedings</p>
<p>i. Records in the system may be disclosed to representatives of the Department of Justice or of any other agency that is responsible for representing Agency interests in connection with judicial, administrative or other proceedings. Records may also be disclosed to the Department of Justice to the extent necessary to obtain its advice on any matter relevant to an Office of Inspector General investigation</p>
<p>j. Records in the system may be disclosed to the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence and the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, or other congressional committees, or the staffs thereof, in connection with their oversight and legislative functions</p>
<p>k. Records in the system may be disclosed to the President's Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board, and the Intelligence Oversight Board, and any successor organizations, when requested by those entities, or when the Inspector General determines that disclosure will assist in the performance of their oversight functions</p>
<p>Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper records are stored in secured areas within CIA facilities. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices, and by automated means utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Inspector General, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA records; CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, industrial contractors, and military and civilian detailees to CIA; federal, state, and local officials; foreign governments; private citizens, including U.S. citizens and foreign nationals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia32" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-32</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of the Deputy Director of Central Intelligence (DDCI) for Community Management Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who visit, contact, have employment, contractual, or other relationships with, or otherwise participate in the activities of, the Office of the DDCI for Community Management or the Intelligence Community; individuals who are of foreign intelligence, counterintelligence, or security interest to the Intelligence Community, including individuals identified as being involved in activities related to intelligence matters; and individuals in government, academia, the business community, or other elements of the private sector with expertise on matters of intelligence interest to the Office of the DDCI for Community Management, or other elements of the Intelligence Community.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system include: information relating to the management and oversight of intelligence requirements, analysis, reporting and operations, including acquisitions; biographic and other information about individuals of intelligence interest; information on individuals and events of interest to the Intelligence Community; information identifying source documents and their recipients; and biographic and other information, including security clearances, access approvals, and employment and training records, about individuals who visit, contact, have employment, contractual or other relationships with, or otherwise participate in, the activities of the Office of the DDCI for Community Management
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the Director of Central Intelligence to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide classified and unclassified information to the Director of Central Intelligence, CIA and other appropriate Intelligence Community and U.S. Government officers, employees, detailees, or contractors for the conduct of authorized activities; and assist the Director of Central Intelligence with his Intelligence Community responsibilities, including resources management, program assessment and evaluation, policy formulation, and collection requirements management, and the protection of intelligence sources and methods.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records from this system of records may be disclosed to U.S. Government organizations, personnel and contractors: in order to facilitate security, employment, or contractual decisions; and as necessary for the protection of intelligence sources and methods, intelligence oversight and management, and in support of intelligence operations, analysis and reporting. Additionally, records from this system are used to prepare periodic statistical reports for U.S. Government officials related to the control and dissemination of classified information. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in a secured area located in premises controlled by the Director of Central Intelligence (DCI). Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located in premises controlled by the DCI.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Executive Director for Intelligence Community Affairs, Office of the DDCI for Community Management, c/o Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; U.S. Government officers, employees, agencies, organizations and contractors; publicly available information from the media, libraries and commercial databases; unclassified reporting; classified intelligence reporting and source documents; investigative reports; and correspondence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia33" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-33</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Intelligence Council (NIC) Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who have employment, detailee, liaison, or contractual relationships with the National Intelligence Council (NIC) or Intelligence Community agencies, including personal services independent contractors and industrial contractors; individuals in academia and the private sector with expertise on matters of intelligence interest to the NIC; and individuals who are of foreign intelligence, counterintelligence, or security interest to the NIC, including individuals identified as being involved in activities related to intelligence matters.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system include administrative and contact information; documents relating to intelligence requirements, analysis, reporting and operations; National Intelligence Council operational records; biographic information about individuals of intelligence interest; publicly-available information on individuals and events of interest to the NIC; other policy and operational data based on foreign intelligence, counterintelligence and security reporting.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the Director of Central Intelligence to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide classified and unclassified information within the CIA and to appropriate Intelligence Community and U.S. Government officials for the conduct of authorized activities; and assist the Director of Central Intelligence and the Intelligence Community by evaluating the adequacy of intelligence support to U.S. policymakers and other senior intelligence consumers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records from this system of records may be disclosed to other U.S. Government organizations in order to facilitate any security, employment, or contractual decisions. Records also may be disclosed to other U.S. Government organizations as necessary for the protection of intelligence sources and methods and in support of intelligence operations, analysis and reporting. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in a secured area located in premises controlled by the Director of Central Intelligence (DCI). Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located in premises controlled by the DCI.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chairman, National Intelligence Council, c/o Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals covered by this system; U.S. Government employees, agencies and organizations; publicly-available information from the media, libraries and commercial databases; classified reporting and intelligence source documents; and correspondence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia34" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-34</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Arms Control Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who have employment, detailee, liaison, or contractual relationships with the Center for Weapons Intelligence, Nonproliferation and Arms Control (WINPAC), including personal services independent contractors and industrial contractors; individuals who visit, contact, or otherwise participate in the activities of WINPAC.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system include administrative, biographic and contact information; publicly available information on events of interest to the arms control community; classified reporting on events of interest to the arms control community; documents identifying classified source documents and their recipients.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941); Executive Order 12958 (76 FR 19825).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity, enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and provide classified and unclassified information to appropriate CIA and Intelligence Community officials for the conduct of authorized activities, including support to the negotiation and assessment of arms control agreements.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records from this system of records may be disclosed to other U.S. Government organizations in order to facilitate any security, employment, or contractual decisions by those organizations. Records also may be disclosed to other U.S. Government organizations as necessary for the protection of intelligence sources and methods and in support of intelligence operations, analysis and reporting. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within premises controlled by the head of the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers within premises controlled by the head of the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in a secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director, WINPAC, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who are the subject of records in this system; U.S. Government employees, agencies and organizations; publicly available information obtained from the media, libraries and commercial databases; unclassified and classified reporting and intelligence source documents; and correspondence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia35" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-35</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Directorate of Science &amp;Technology (DS&amp;T) Private Sector Contact Information.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals in the private sector who work or have worked on CIA personal services or industrial contracts; individuals about which there is publicly-available information identifying a scientific, technical or related expertise of interest to CIA; and CIA staff and contract employees, and other individuals affiliated with CIA who work on CIA projects with private sector experts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic information, including areas of expertise.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide reference information; and facilitate communication by CIA with private sector experts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director, DS&amp;T Administrative Resources Center, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who are the subject of records in the system; and publicly available information obtained from the media, libraries and commercial databases.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia36" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-36</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Alumni Communications Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Former CIA employees who voluntarily contact the Alumni Communications Port to offer comments, insights or suggestions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic data (including name, contact information such as address or phone number, and Social Security Number or CIA identifier); and correspondence and memoranda regarding the content of conversations with former employees and any resulting actions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; verify the identities of individuals contacting the Port; continue communications with individuals who contact the Port; and record a summary of the conversations and any resulting actions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in a secured area within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director, DS&amp;T Investment Program Office, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who voluntarily contact the Alumni Communications Port; and CIA employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia37" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-37</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Directorate of Operations Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals who are of foreign intelligence or foreign counterintelligence interest to the CIA, either because of their actual, apparent, or potential association with foreign intelligence or foreign counterintelligence activities, or because they are of actual or potential use to the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Documents recording the operational activities of the Directorate of Operations (DO) of the Central Intelligence Agency.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity, enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities, and maintain a record of the operational activities of the Directorate of Operations of the Central Intelligence Agency.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records from this system of records may be provided to selected federal agencies, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation, military departments and, through established liaison channels, to selected foreign government agencies, as necessary for the conduct of foreign intelligence and counterintelligence operations by the CIA and other U.S. Government entities authorized to conduct such operations. Information on additional routine uses is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, DO Information Management Staff, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Foreign intelligence and counterintelligence sources; U.S. Government agencies; CIA predecessor organizations; publicly available information; and state and local agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia38" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-38</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Academic and Business Contact Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Members of the academic community, members of scientific and other professional organizations, U.S. Government officials, employees of private sector organizations, and other individuals who have expertise in, or access to information on, subjects of intelligence interest; and individuals who have served as, or are considered potential advisers, consultants, or personal services independent contractors to the CIA on matters of intelligence interest.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Biographic information including names, contact information, professional credentials and areas of interest and expertise of individuals covered under this system of records; history of CIA association, if any, of individuals covered under this system.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity, enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities, and maintain a record of persons inside and outside the U.S. Government of current or potential utility as advisors or consultants to the CIA in performing its mission to produce intelligence analyses on matters of national security concern.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand searches based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Directorate of Intelligence Information Management Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification procedures section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who are the subject of records in this system; U.S. Government employees; publicly available information obtained from the media, libraries and commercial databases.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia39" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-39</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Customer Relations Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former intelligence customers including U.S. policymakers, U.S. Government personnel, and other authorized recipients of CIA intelligence products.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographic information including names, addresses, contact information, security clearances and access approvals, and subjects of intelligence interest to individuals covered by this system of records; documents containing comments and feedback from individuals covered by this system of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry out their lawful and authorized responsibilities; maintain dissemination lists for CIA finished intelligence products, in order to ensure proper dissemination of classified and unclassified products; maintain a record of disseminations; maintain a list of topics of interest to particular intelligence customers; and document customer feedback on particular products.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand searches based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Directorate of Intelligence Information Management Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who are the subjects of records in this system; CIA personnel; other U.S. Government personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia40" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-40</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Research System Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence interest to the CIA, including individuals associated with international terrorism, international organized crime, or international narcotics trafficking activities; and individuals who have written on the general topic of intelligence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Classified intelligence reporting, including reports from other U.S. Government agencies and foreign government information; and publicly available information from the media, libraries and commercial databases.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity; enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry our their lawful and authorized responsibilities; provide a repository of classified and unclassified information on topics of foreign intelligence and counterintelligence interest to the CIA; assist the CIA's Directorate of Intelligence to fulfill its mission of providing timely, accurate, and objective intelligence analysis on the full range of national security threats and foreign policy issues facing the United States; and provide a reference file for publicly available publications pertaining to intelligence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other CIA identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand searches based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Directorate of Intelligence Information Management Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, and industrial contractors; U.S. Government agencies; publicly available information from the media, libraries and commercial databases; and foreign intelligence and counterintelligence sources.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cia41" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-41</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Intelligence Analysis Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> The classification of records in this system can range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence interest to the CIA, including individuals associated with international terrorism, international organized crime, or international narcotics trafficking activities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Intelligence reports and other information that supports the analytic mission of the CIA's Directorate of Intelligence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403 et seq.); the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403a et seq.); Executive Order 12333 (46 FR 59941).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p> Records in this system are used by authorized personnel to: Ensure process integrity, enable the CIA and the head of the CIA to carry our their lawful and authorized responsibilities; and assist the CIA's Directorate of Intelligence to fulfill its mission of providing timely, accurate, and objective intelligence analysis on the full range of national security threats and foreign policy issues facing the United States, including key foreign countries, regional conflicts, and issues that transcend national boundaries such as terrorism, weapons proliferation, and narcotics trafficking.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> This information is set forth in the "CIA Statement of General Routine Uses,"  which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p> Paper and other hard-copy records are stored in secured areas within the CIA. Electronic records are stored in secure file-servers located within the CIA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name, social security number, or other identifier. Information may be retrieved from this system of records by automated or hand searches based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, all searches of this system of records will be performed in CIA offices by CIA personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Records are stored in secured areas accessed only by authorized persons. Software access controls are also in place.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> All records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Directorate of Intelligence Information Management Officer, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Individuals seeking to learn if this system of records contains information about them should direct their inquiries to: Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC 20505. Identification requirements are specified in the CIA rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.13). Individuals must comply with these rules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. Regulations for access to individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning the access to records are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.11-45).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals to correct or amend records should be addressed as indicated in the notification section above. CIA's regulations regarding requests for amendments to, or disputing the contents of individual records or for appealing an initial determination by CIA concerning these matters are published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (32 CFR 1901.21-23, 32 CFR 1901.42).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> CIA staff and contract employees, personal services independent contractors, and industrial contractors; U.S. Government agencies; publicly available information from the media, libraries and commercial databases; and foreign intelligence and counterintelligence sources.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p> Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted from certain provisions of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1), (k), and (d)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
	<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="32">
<heading> National Defense </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XIX">
<heading> Central Intelligence Agency </heading>
<regulationsPart number="1901">
<heading> PUBLIC RIGHTS UNDER THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>General
</b></p>
<p>Sec. 
</p>
<p>1901.01 Authority and purpose. 
</p>
<p>1901.02 Definitions. 
</p>
<p>1901.03 Contact for general information and requests. 
</p>
<p>1901.04 Suggestions and complaints. </p>
<p><b>Filing of Privacy Act Requests 
</b></p>
<p>1901.11 Preliminary information. 
</p>
<p>1901.12 Requirements as to form. 
</p>
<p>1901.13 Requirements as to identification of requester. 
</p>
<p>1901.14 Fees. </p>
<p><b>Action on Privacy Act Requests
</b></p>
<p>1901.21 Processing requests for access to or amendment of records. 
</p>
<p>1901.22 Action and determination(s) by originator(s) or any interested party. 
</p>
<p>1901.23 Notification of decision and right of appeal. </p>
<p><b>Additional Administrative Matters 
</b></p>
<p>1901.31 Special procedures for medical and psychological records. 
</p>
<p>1901.32 Requests for expedited processing. 
</p>
<p>1901.33 Allocation of resources; agreed extensions of time. </p>
<p><b>Action on Privacy Act Administrative Appeals 
</b></p>
<p>1901.41 Establishment of appeals structure. 
</p>
<p>1901.42 Right of appeal and appeal procedures. 
</p>
<p>1901.43 Determination(s) by Deputy Director(s). 
</p>
<p>1901.44 Action by appeals authority. 
</p>
<p>1901.45 Notification of decision and right of judicial review. </p>
<p><b>Prohibitions 
</b></p>
<p>1901.51 Limitations on disclosure. 
</p>
<p>1901.52 Criminal penalties. </p>
<p><b>Exemptions 
</b></p>
<p>1901.61 Purpose and authority. 
</p>
<p>1901.62 General exemptions. 
</p>
<p>1901.63 Specific exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> National Security Act of 1947, as amended; Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended; Privacy Act, as amended; and Executive Order 12958 (or successor Orders). 
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 62 FR 32488, June 16, 1997, unless otherwise noted.</p>
<p><b>General 
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.01 
 Authority and purpose. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Authority.</i> This part is issued under the authority of and in order to implement the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a); sec. 102 of the National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403); and sec. 6 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403g). 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Purpose in general.</i> This part prescribes procedures for a requester, as defined herein: 
</p>
<p>(1) To request notification of whether the Central Intelligence Agency maintains a record concerning them in any non-exempt portion of a system of records or any non-exempt system of records; 
</p>
<p>(2) To request a copy of all non-exempt records or portions of records; 
</p>
<p>(3) To request that any such record be amended or augmented; and 
</p>
<p>(4) To file an administrative appeal to any initial adverse determination to deny access to or amend a record. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Other purposes.</i> This part also sets forth detailed limitations on how and to whom the Agency may disclose personal information and gives notice that certain actions by officers or employees of the United States Government or members of the public could constitute criminal offenses. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.02 
 Definitions. 
</b></p>
<p>For purposes of this part, the following terms have the meanings indicated: 
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Agency</i> or <i>CIA</i> means the United States Central Intelligence Agency acting through the CIA Information and Privacy Coordinator; 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Days</i> means calendar days when the Agency is operating and specifically excludes Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays. Three (3) days may be added to any time limit imposed on a requester by this part if responding by U.S. domestic mail; ten (10) days may be added if responding by international mail; 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Control</i> means ownership or the authority of the CIA pursuant to federal statute or privilege to regulate official or public access to records; 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Coordinator</i> means the CIA Information and Privacy Coordinator who serves as the Agency manager of the information review and release program instituted under the Privacy Act; 
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Federal agency</i> means any executive department, military department, or other establishment or entity included in the definition of agency in 5 U.S.C. 552(f); 
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Interested party</i> means any official in the executive, military, congressional, or judicial branches of government, United States or foreign, or U.S. Government contractor who, in the sole discretion of the CIA, has a subject matter or physical interest in the documents or information at issue; 
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Maintain</i> means maintain, collect, use, or disseminate; 
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Originator</i> means the U.S. Government official who originated the document at issue or successor in office or such official who has been delegated release or declassification authority pursuant to law; 
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Privacy Act</i> or <i>PA</i> means the statute as codified at 5 U.S.C. 552a; 
</p>
<p>(j) <i>Record</i> means an item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by the Central Intelligence Agency in a system of records; 
</p>
<p>(k) <i>Requester</i> or <i>individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence who is a living being and to whom a record might pertain; 
</p>
<p>(l) <i>Responsive record</i> means those documents (records) which the Agency has determined to be within the scope of a Privacy Act request; 
</p>
<p>(m) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which the record is maintained; 
</p>
<p>(n) <i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of the Central Intelligence Agency from which records are retrieved by the name of an individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to that individual. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.03 
 Contact for general information and requests. 
</b></p>
<p>For general information on this part, to inquire about the Privacy Act program at CIA, or to file a Privacy Act request, please direct your communication in writing to the Information and Privacy Coordinator, Central Intelligence Agency, Washington, DC. 20505. Requests with the required identification statement pursuant to 32 CFR 1901.13 must be filed in original form by mail. Subsequent communications and any inquiries will be accepted by mail or facsimile at (703) 613-3007 or by telephone at (703) 613-1287. Collect calls cannot be accepted. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.04 
 Suggestions and complaints. 
</b></p>
<p>The Agency welcomes suggestions or complaints with regard to its administration of the Privacy Act. Many requesters will receive pre-paid, customer satisfaction survey cards. Letters of suggestion or complaint should identify the specific purpose and the issues for consideration. The Agency will respond to all substantive communications and take such actions as determined feasible and appropriate.</p> 
<p><b>Filing of Privacy Act Requests 
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.11 
 Preliminary information. 
</b></p>
<p>Members of the public shall address all communications to the contact specified at &#167; 1901.03 and clearly delineate the communication as a request under the Privacy Act and this regulation. Requests and administrative appeals on requests, referrals, and coordinations received from members of the public who owe outstanding fees for information services at this or other federal agencies will not be accepted and action on existing requests and appeals will be terminated in such circumstances. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.12 
 Requirements as to form. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> No particular form is required. All requests must contain the identification information required at &#167; 1901.13. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>For access.</i> For requests seeking access, a requester should, to the extent possible, describe the nature of the record sought and the record system(s) in which it is thought to be included. Requesters may find assistance from information described in the Privacy Act Issuances Compilation which is published biannually by the <i>Federal Register.</i> In lieu of this, a requester may simply describe why and under what circumstances it is believed that this Agency maintains responsive records; the Agency will undertake the appropriate searches. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>For amendment.</i> For requests seeking amendment, a requester should identify the particular record or portion subject to the request, state a justification for such amendment, and provide the desired amending language. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.13 
 Requirements as to identification of requester. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> Individuals seeking access to or amendment of records concerning themselves shall provide their full (legal) name, address, date and place of birth, and current citizenship status together with a statement that such information is true under penalty of perjury or a notarized statement swearing to or affirming identity. If the Agency determines that this information is not sufficient, the Agency may request additional or clarifying information. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Requirement for aliens.</i> Only aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence (PRAs) may file a request pursuant to the Privacy Act and this part. Such individuals shall provide, in addition to the information required under paragraph (a) of this section, their Alien Registration Number and the date that status was acquired. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Requirement for representatives.</i> The parent or guardian of a minor individual, the guardian of an individual under judicial disability, or an attorney retained to represent an individual shall provide, in addition to establishing the identity of the minor or individual represented as required in paragraph (a) or (b) of this section, evidence of such representation by submission of a certified copy of the minor?s birth certificate, court order, or representational agreement which establishes the relationship and the requester?s identity. 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Procedure otherwise.</i> If a requester or representative fails to provide the information in paragraph (a), (b), or (c) of this section within forty-five (45) days of the date of our request, the Agency will deem the request closed. This action, of course, would not prevent an individual from refiling his or her Privacy Act request at a subsequent date with the required information. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.14 
 Fees. 
</b></p>
<p>No fees will be charged for any action under the authority of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a, irrespective of the fact that a request is or may be processed under the authority of both the Privacy Act and the Freedom of Information Act. </p> 
<p><b>Action on Privacy Act Requests 
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.21 
 Processing requests for access to or amendment of records. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> Requests meeting the requirements of 32 CFR 1901.11 through 1901.13 shall be processed under both the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552, and the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a, and the applicable regulations, unless the requester demands otherwise in writing. Such requests will be processed under both Acts regardless of whether the requester cites one Act in the request, both, or neither. This action is taken in order to ensure the maximum possible disclosure to the requester. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Receipt, recording and tasking.</i> Upon receipt of a request meeting the requirements of &#167;&#167; 1901.11 through 1901.13, the Agency shall within ten (10) days record each request, acknowledge receipt to the requester, and thereafter effect the necessary taskings to the components reasonably believed to hold responsive records. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Effect of certain exemptions.</i> In processing a request, the Agency shall decline to confirm or deny the existence or nonexistence of any responsive records whenever the fact of their existence or nonexistence is itself classified under Executive Order 12958 or revealing of intelligence sources and methods protected pursuant to section 103(c)(5) of the National Security Act of 1947. In such circumstances, the Agency, in the form of a final written response, shall so inform the requester and advise of his or her right to an administrative appeal. 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Time for response.</i> Although the Privacy Act does not mandate a time for response, our joint treatment of requests under both the Privacy Act and the FOIA means that the Agency should provide a response within the FOIA statutory guideline of ten (10) days on initial requests and twenty (20) days on administrative appeals. However, the current volume of requests require that the Agency often seek additional time from a requester pursuant to 32 CFR 1901.33. In such event, the Agency will inform the requester in writing and further advise of his or her right to file an administrative appeal. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.22 
 Action and determination(s) by originator(s) or any interested party. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Initial action for access.</i> CIA components tasked pursuant to a Privacy Act access request shall search all relevant record systems within their cognizance. They shall: 
</p>
<p>(1) Determine whether responsive records exist; 
</p>
<p>(2) Determine whether access must be denied in whole or part and on what legal basis under both Acts in each such case; 
</p>
<p>(3) Approve the disclosure of records for which they are the originator; and 
</p>
<p>(4) Forward to the Coordinator all records approved for release or necessary for coordination with or referral to another originator or interested party as well as the specific determinations with respect to denials (if any). 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Initial action for amendment.</i> CIA components tasked pursuant to a Privacy Act amendment request shall review the official records alleged to be inaccurate and the proposed amendment submitted by the requester. If they determine that the Agency?s records are not accurate, relevant, timely or complete, they shall promptly: 
</p>
<p>(1) Make the amendment as requested; 
</p>
<p>(2) Write to all other identified persons or agencies to whom the record has been disclosed (if an accounting of the disclosure was made) and inform of the amendment; and 
</p>
<p>(3) Inform the Coordinator of such decisions. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Action otherwise on amendment request.</i> If the CIA component records manager declines to make the requested amendment or declines to make the requested amendment but agrees to augment the official records, that manager shall promptly: 
</p>
<p>(1) Set forth the reasons for refusal; and 
</p>
<p>(2) Inform the Coordinator of such decision and the reasons therefore. 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Referrals and coordinations.</i> As applicable and within ten (10) days of receipt by the Coordinator, any CIA records containing information originated by other CIA components shall be forwarded to those entities for action in accordance with paragraphs (a), (b), or (c) of this section and return. Records originated by other federal agencies or CIA records containing other federal agency information shall be forwarded to such agencies within ten (10) days of our completion of initial action in the case for action under their regulations and direct response to the requester (for other agency records) or return to the CIA (for CIA records). 
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Effect of certain exemptions.</i> This section shall not be construed to allow access to systems of records exempted by the Director of Central Intelligence pursuant to subsections (j) and (k) of the Privacy Act or where those exemptions require that the CIA can neither confirm nor deny the existence or nonexistence of responsive records. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.23 
 Notification of decision and right of appeal. 
</b></p>
<p>Within ten (10) days of receipt of responses to all initial taskings and subsequent coordinations (if any), and dispatch of referrals (if any), the Agency will provide disclosable records to the requester. If a determination has been made not to provide access to requested records (in light of specific exemptions) or that no records are found, the Agency shall so inform the requester, identify the denying official, and advise of the right to administrative appeal.</p> 
<p><b>Additional Administrative Matters 
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.31 
 Special procedures for medical and psychological records. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> When a request for access or amendment involves medical or psychological records and when the originator determines that such records are not exempt from disclosure, the Agency will, after consultation with the Director of Medical Services, determine: 
</p>
<p>(1) Which records may be sent directly to the requester and 
</p>
<p>(2) Which records should not be sent directly to the requester because of possible medical or psychological harm to the requester or another person. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Procedure for records to be sent to physician.</i> In the event that the Agency determines, in accordance with paragraph (a)(2) of this section, that records should not be sent directly to the requester, the Agency will notify the requester in writing and advise that the records at issue can be made available only to a physician of the requester?s designation. Upon receipt of such designation, verification of the identity of the physician, and agreement by the physician: 
</p>
<p>(1) To review the documents with the requesting individual, 
</p>
<p>(2) To explain the meaning of the documents, and 
</p>
<p>(3) To offer counseling designed to temper any adverse reaction, the Agency will forward such records to the designated physician. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Procedure if physician option not available.</i> If within sixty (60) days of the paragraph (a)(2) of this section, the requester has failed to respond or designate a physician, or the physician fails to agree to the release conditions, the Agency will hold the documents in abeyance and advise the requester that this action may be construed as a technical denial. The Agency will also advise the requester of the responsible official and of his or her rights to administrative appeal and thereafter judicial review. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.32 
 Requests for expedited processing. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) All requests will be handled in the order received on a strictly "first-in, first-out"  basis. Exceptions to this rule will only be made in circumstances that the Agency deems to be exceptional. In making this determination, the Agency shall consider and must decide in the affirmative on all of the following factors: 
</p>
<p>(1) That there is a genuine need for the records; and 
</p>
<p>(2) That the personal need is exceptional; and 
</p>
<p>(3) That there are no alternative forums for the records sought; and 
</p>
<p>(4) That it is reasonably believed that substantive records relevant to the stated needs may exist and be deemed releasable. 
</p>
<p>(b) In sum, requests shall be considered for expedited processing only when health, humanitarian, or due process considerations involving possible deprivation of life or liberty create circumstances of exceptional urgency and extraordinary need. In accordance with established judicial precedent, requests more properly the scope of requests under the Federal Rules of Civil or Criminal Procedure (or equivalent state rules) will not be granted expedited processing under this or related (e.g., Freedom of Information Act) provisions unless expressly ordered by a federal court of competent jurisdiction. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.33 
 Allocation of resources; agreed extensions of time. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> Agency components shall devote such personnel and other resources to the responsibilities imposed by the Privacy Act as may be appropriate and reasonable considering: 
</p>
<p>(1) The totality of resources available to the component, 
</p>
<p>(2) The business demands imposed on the component by the Director of Central Intelligence or otherwise by law, 
</p>
<p>(3) The information review and release demands imposed by the Congress or other governmental authority, and 
</p>
<p>(4) The rights of all members of the public under the various information review and disclosure laws. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Discharge of Privacy Act responsibilities.</i> Components shall exercise due diligence in their responsibilities under the Privacy Act and must allocate a reasonable level of resources to requests under the Act in a strictly "first-in, first-out"  basis and utilizing two or more processing queues to ensure that smaller as well as larger (i.e., project) cases receive equitable attention. The Information and Privacy Coordinator is responsible for management of the Agency-wide program defined by this Part and for establishing priorities for cases consistent with established law. The Director, Information Management through the Agency Release Panel shall provide policy and resource direction as necessary and shall make determinations on administrative appeals. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Requests for extension of time.</i> While the Privacy Act does not specify time requirements, our joint treatment of requests under the FOIA means that when the Agency is unable to meet the statutory time requirements of the FOIA, the Agency may request additional time from a requester. In such instances the Agency will inform a requester of his or her right to decline our request and proceed with an administrative appeal or judicial review as appropriate. </p>
<p><b>Action on Privacy Act Administrative Appeals 
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.41 
 Establishment of appeals structure. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> Two administrative entities have been established by the Director of Central Intelligence to facilitate the processing of administrative appeals under the Freedom of Information Act. Their membership, authority, and rules of procedure are as follows. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Historical Records Policy Board ("HRPB"  or "Board" ).</i> This Board, the successor to the CIA Information Review Committee, acts as the senior corporate board in the CIA on all matters of information review and release. 
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Membership.</i> The HRPB is composed of the Executive Director, who serves as its Chair, the Deputy Director for Administration, the Deputy Director for Intelligence, the Deputy Director for Operations, the Deputy Director for Science and Technology, the General Counsel, the Director of Congressional Affairs, the Director of the Public Affairs Staff, the Director, Center for the Study of Intelligence, and the Associate Deputy Director for Administration/Information Services, or their designees. 
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Authorities and activities.</i> The HRPB, by majority vote, may delegate to one or more of its members the authority to act on any appeal or other matter or authorize the Chair to delegate such authority, as long as such delegation is not to the same individual or body who made the initial denial. The Executive Secretary of the HRPB is the Director, Information Management. The Chair may request interested parties to participate when special equities or expertise are involved. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Agency Release Panel ("ARP"  or "Panel" ).</i> The HRPB, pursuant to its delegation of authority, has established a subordinate Agency Release Panel. 
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Membership.</i> The ARP is composed of the Director, Information Management, who serves as its Chair; the Information Review Officers from the Directorates of Administration, Intelligence, Operations, Science and Technology, and the Director of Central Intelligence Area; the CIA Information and Privacy Coordinator; the Chief, Historical Review Group; the Chair, Publications Review Board; the Chief, Records Declassification Program; and representatives from the Office of General Counsel, the Office of Congressional Affairs, and the Public Affairs Staff. 
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Authorities and activities.</i> The Panel shall meet on a regular schedule and may take action when a simple majority of the total membership is present. The Panel shall advise and assist the HRPB on all information release issues, monitor the adequacy and timeliness of Agency releases, set component search and review priorities, review adequacy of resources available to and planning for all Agency release programs, and perform such other functions as deemed necessary by the Board. The Information and Privacy Coordinator also serves as Executive Secretary of the Panel. The Chair may request interested parties to participate when special equities or expertise are involved. The Panel, functioning as a committee of the whole or through individual members, will make final Agency decisions from appeals of initial adverse decisions under the Freedom of Information Act and such other information release decisions made under 32 CFR parts 1901, 1907, and 1908. Issues shall be decided by a majority of members present; in all cases of a divided vote, any member of the ARP then present may refer such matter to the HRPB by written memorandum to the Executive Secretary of the HRPB. Matters decided by the Panel or Board will be deemed a final decision by the Agency. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.42
 Right of appeal and appeal procedures. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Right of Appeal.</i> A right of administrative appeal exists whenever access to any requested record or any portion thereof is denied, no records are located in response to a request, or a request for amendment is denied. The Agency will apprise all requesters in writing of their right to appeal such decisions to the CIA Agency Release Panel through the Coordinator. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Requirements as to time and form.</i> Appeals of decisions must be received by the Coordinator within forty-five (45) days of the date of the Agency?s initial decision. The Agency may, for good cause and as a matter of administrative discretion, permit an additional thirty (30) days for the submission of an appeal. All appeals to the Panel shall be in writing and addressed as specified in 32 CFR 1901.03. All appeals must identify the documents or portions of documents at issue with specificity, provide the desired amending language (if applicable), and may present such information, data, and argument in support as the requester may desire. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Exceptions.</i> No appeal shall be accepted if the requester has outstanding fees for information services at this or another federal agency. In addition, no appeal shall be accepted if the information in question has been the subject of an administrative review within the previous two (2) years or is the subject of pending litigation in the federal courts. 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Receipt, recording, and tasking.</i> The Agency shall promptly record each administrative appeal, acknowledge receipt to the requester in writing, and thereafter effect the necessary taskings to the Deputy Director(s) in charge of the directorate(s) which originated or has an interest in the record(s) subject to the appeal. As used herein, the term Deputy Director includes an equivalent senior official within the DCI-area as well as a designee known as the Information Review Officer for a directorate or area. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.43
 Determination(s) by Deputy Director(s). 
</b></p>
<p>Each Deputy Director in charge of a directorate which originated or has an interest in any of the records subject to the appeal, or designee, is a required party to any appeal; other interested parties may become involved through the request of the Coordinator when it is determined that some or all of the information is also within their official cognizance. These parties shall respond in writing to the Coordinator with a finding as to the exempt or non-exempt status of the information including citations to the applicable exemption and/or their agreement or disagreement as to the requested amendment and the reasons therefore. Each response shall be provided expeditiously on a "first-in, first-out"  basis taking into account the business requirements of the parties and consistent with the information rights of members of the general public under the various information review and release laws. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.44
 Action by appeals authority. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Preparation of docket.</i> The Coordinator, acting as the Executive Secretary of the Agency Release Panel, shall place administrative appeals of Privacy Act requests ready for adjudication on the agenda at the next occurring meeting of that Panel. The Executive Secretary shall provide a summation memorandum for consideration of the members; the complete record of the request consisting of the request, the document(s) (sanitized and full text) at issue, and the findings of the concerned Deputy Director(s) or designee(s). 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Decision by the Agency Release Panel.</i> The Agency Release Panel shall meet and decide requests sitting as a committee of the whole. Decisions are by majority vote of those present at a meeting and shall be based on the written record and their deliberations; no personal appearances shall be permitted without the express permission of the Panel. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Decision by the Historical Records Policy Board.</i> In any cases of divided vote by the ARP, any member of that body is authorized to refer the request to the CIA Historical Records Policy Board which acts as the senior corporate board for the Agency. The record compiled (the request, the memoranda filed by the originator and interested parties, and the previous decision(s)) as well as any memorandum of law or policy the referent desires to be considered, shall be certified by the Executive Secretary of the Agency Release Panel and shall constitute the official record of the proceedings and must be included in any subsequent filings. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.45 
 Notification of decision and right of judicial review. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> The Executive Secretary of the Agency Release Panel shall promptly prepare and communicate the decision of the Panel or Board to the requester. With respect to any decision to deny information or deny amendment, that correspondence shall state the reasons for the decision, identify the officer responsible, and include a notice of the right to judicial review. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>For amendment requests.</i> With further respect to any decision to deny an amendment, that correspondence shall also inform the requester of the right to submit within forty-five (45) days a statement of his or her choice which shall be included in the official records of the CIA. In such cases, the applicable record system manager shall clearly note any portion of the official record which is disputed, append the requester?s statement, and provide copies of the statement to previous recipients (if any are known) and to any future recipients when and if the disputed information is disseminated in accordance with a routine use. </p>
<p><b>Prohibitions 
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.51
 Limitations on disclosure. 
</b></p>
<p>No record which is within a system of records shall be disclosed by any means of communication to any individual or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains, unless disclosure of the record would be: 
</p>
<p>(a) To those officers and employees of this Agency which maintains the record who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties; 
</p>
<p>(b) Required under the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552; 
</p>
<p>(c) For a routine use as defined in &#167; 1901.02(m), as contained in the Privacy Act Issuances Compilation which is published biennially in the <i>Federal Register,</i> and as described in &#167;&#167; (a)(7) and (e)(4)(D) of the Act; 
</p>
<p>(d) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity pursuant to the provisions of U.S.C. Title 13; 
</p>
<p>(e) To a recipient who has provided the Agency with advance adequate written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable; 
</p>
<p>(f) To the National Archives and Records Administration as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the United States Government, or for evaluation by the Archivist of the United States or designee to determine whether the record has such value; 
</p>
<p>(g) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity if the activity is authorized by law, and if the head of that agency or instrumentality has made a written request to the CIA specifying the particular information desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought; 
</p>
<p>(h) To a person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual if upon such disclosure notification is transmitted to the last known address of such individual; 
</p>
<p>(i) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee; 
</p>
<p>(j) To the Comptroller General or any of his authorized representatives in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office; or 
</p>
<p>(k) To any agency, government instrumentality, or other person or entity pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction of the United States or constituent states. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.52
 Criminal penalties. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Unauthorized disclosure.</i> Criminal penalties may be imposed against any officer or employee of the CIA who, by virtue of employment, has possession of or access to Agency records which contain information identifiable with an individual, the disclosure of which is prohibited by the Privacy Act or by these rules, and who, knowing that disclosure of the specific material is so prohibited, willfully discloses the material in any manner to any person or agency not entitled to receive same. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Unauthorized maintenance.</i> Criminal penalties may be imposed against any officer or employee of the CIA who willfully maintains a system of records without meeting the requirements of section (e)(4) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C.552a. The Coordinator and the Inspector General are authorized independently to conduct such surveys and inspect such records as necessary from time to time to ensure that these requirements are met. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Unauthorized requests.</i> Criminal penalties may be imposed upon any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual from the CIA under false pretenses.</p>
<p><b>Exemptions 
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.61 
 Purpose and authority. 
</b></p>
<p><i>Purpose of exemptions.</i> This Part sets forth those systems of records or portions of systems of records which the Director of Central Intelligence has determined to exempt from the procedures established by this regulation and from certain provisions of the Privacy Act: 
</p>
<p>(a) The purpose of the following specified general exemption of polygraph records is to prevent access and review of records which intimately reveal CIA operational methods. The purpose of the general exemption from the provisions of sections (c)(3) and (e)(3) (A)-(D) of the Privacy Act is to avoid disclosures that may adversely affect ongoing operational relationships with other intelligence and related organizations and thus reveal or jeopardize intelligence sources and methods or risk exposure of intelligence sources and methods in the processing of covert employment applications. 
</p>
<p>(b) The purpose of the general exemption from sections (d), (e)(4)(G), (f)(1), and (g) of the Privacy Act is to protect only those portions of systems of records which if revealed would risk exposure of intelligence sources and methods or hamper the ability of the CIA to effectively use information received from other agencies or foreign governments. 
</p>
<p>(c) It should be noted that by subjecting information which would consist of, reveal, or pertain to intelligence sources and methods to separate determinations by the Director of Central Intelligence under the provision entitled <i>"General exemptions," </i> 32 CFR 1901.62 regarding access and notice, an intent is established to apply the exemption from access and notice only in those cases where notice in itself would constitute a revelation of intelligence sources and methods; in all cases where only access to information would reveal such source or method, notice will be given upon request. 
</p>
<p>(d) The purpose of the general exemption for records that consist of, pertain to, or would otherwise reveal the identities of employees who provide information to the Office of the Inspector General is to implement section 17 of the CIA Act of 1949, as amended, 50 U.S.C. 403q(e)(3), and to ensure that no action constituting a reprisal or threat of reprisal is taken because an employee has cooperated with the Office of Inspector General. 
</p>
<p>(e) The purpose of the specific exemptions provided for under section (k) of the Privacy Act is to exempt only those portions of systems of records which would consist of, reveal, or pertain to that information which is enumerated in that section of the Act. 
</p>
<p>(f) In each case, the Director of Central Intelligence currently or then in office has determined that the enumerated classes of information should be exempt in order to comply with dealing with the proper classification of national defense or foreign policy information; protect the identification of persons who provide information to the CIA Inspector General; protect the privacy of other persons who supplied information under an implied or express grant of confidentiality in the case of law enforcement or employment and security suitability investigations (or promotion material in the case of the armed services); protect information used in connection with protective services under 18 U.S.C. 3056; protect the efficacy of testing materials; and protect information which is required by statute to be maintained and used solely as statistical records. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.62 
 General exemptions. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) Pursuant to authority granted in section (j) of the Privacy Act, the Director of Central Intelligence has determined to exempt from all sections of the Act--except sections 552a(b); (c) (1) and (2); (e) (1), (4) (A)-(F), (5), (6), (7), (9), (10), and (11); and (i)--the following systems of records or portions of records in a system of record: 
</p>
<p>(1) Polygraph records. 
</p>
<p>(2) [Reserved]
</p>
<p>(b) Pursuant to authority granted in section (j) of the Privacy Act, the Director of Central Intelligence has determined to exempt from sections (c)(3) and (e)(3) (A)-(D) of the Act all systems of records maintained by this Agency. 
</p>
<p>(c) Pursuant to authority granted in section (j) of the Privacy Act, the Director of Central Intelligence has determined to exempt from notification under sections (e)(4)(G) and (f)(1) those portions of each and all systems of records which have been exempted from individual access under section (j) in those cases where the Coordinator determines after advice by the responsible components that confirmation of the existence of a record may jeopardize intelligence sources and methods. In such cases the Agency must neither confirm nor deny the existence of the record and will advise a requester that there is no record which is available pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974. 
</p>
<p>(d) Pursuant to authority granted in section (j) of the Privacy Act, the Director of Central Intelligence has determined to exempt from access by individuals under section (d) of the Act those portions and only those portions of all systems of records maintained by the CIA that: 
</p>
<p>(1) Consist of, pertain to, or would otherwise reveal intelligence sources and methods; 
</p>
<p>(2) Consist of documents or information provided by any foreign government entity, international organization, or, any United States federal, state, or other public agency or authority; and 
</p>
<p>(3) Consist of information which would reveal the identification of persons who provide information to the CIA Inspector General. 
</p>
<p>(e) Pursuant to authority granted in section (j) of the Privacy Act, the Director of Central Intelligence has determined to exempt from judicial review under section (g) of the Act all determinations to deny access under section (d) of the Act and all decisions to deny notice under sections (e)(4)(G) and (f)(1) of the Act pursuant to determination made under paragraph (c) of this section when it has been determined by an appropriate official of the CIA that such access would disclose information which would: 
</p>
<p>(1) Consist of, pertain to, or otherwise reveal intelligence sources and methods; 
</p>
<p>(2) Consist of documents or information provided by any foreign government entity, international organization, or, any United States federal, state, or other public agency or authority; and 
</p>
<p>(3) Consist of information which would reveal the identification of persons who provide information to the CIA Inspector General. 
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1901.63 
 Specific exemptions. 
</b></p>
<p>Pursuant to authority granted in section (k) of the Privacy Act, the Director of Central Intelligence has determined to exempt from section (d) of the Privacy Act those portions and only those portions of all systems of records maintained by the CIA that would consist of, pertain to, or otherwise reveal information that is: 
</p>
<p>(a) Classified pursuant to Executive Order 12958 (or successor or prior Order) and thus subject to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(1) and 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1); 
</p>
<p>(b) Investigatory in nature and compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of section (j)(2) of the Act; provided however, that if an individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit to which they are otherwise eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, then such material shall be provided to that individual except to the extent that the disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished the information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality; 
</p>
<p>(c) Maintained in connection with providing protective services to the President of the United States or other individuals pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 3056; 
</p>
<p>(d) Required by statute to be maintained and used solely as statistical records; 
</p>
<p>(e) Investigatory in nature and compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for federal civilian employment, military service, federal contracts, or access to classified information, but only to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality; 
</p>
<p>(f) Testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the federal service the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process; or 
</p>
<p>(g) Evaluation material used to determine potential for promotion in the armed services, but only to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality. 
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>

