<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Broadcasting Board of Governors</name>
<abbrev>

BBG
</abbrev>

    
    
<routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
	<p><b>Editorial Note:</b> The Broadcasting Board of Governors supersedes the Board for International Broadcasting per the International Broadcasting Act of 1994, Title III of Public Law 103-236.</p>
<p><b>Statement of General Routine Uses Applicable to All BBG System of Records Files</b></p>
<p>The following routine uses apply to and are incorporated by reference into each system of records (BBG-1 through BBG-19) set forth in this Notice:
</p><p><i>1. Disclosure for Law Enforcement Purposes</i></p>
<p>Information may be disclosed to the appropriate Federal, State, local, tribal or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, reviewing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, license or order, if the information is relevant to a potential violation or civil or criminal law or regulation within the apparent jurisdiction of the entity.
</p><p><i>2. Disclosure Incident to Requesting Information</i></p>
<p>Information may be disclosed to any source from which additional information is requested ( to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose of the request, and to identify the type of information requested), when necessary to obtain information related to an agency decision concerning retention of the individual, or other personnel action (except hiring), retention or issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, subcontract, cooperative agreement, grant, or other financial arrangement, or other benefit.
</p><p><i>3. Disclosure to Requesting Agency
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to a Federal, State, local, foreign, tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention or granting of a security clearance, the letting or retention of a contract, subcontract, cooperative agreement, grant or other financial arrangement, or the issuance or retention of a license or other benefit. The other agency or organization may then make a request supported by the written consent of the individual if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the agency has a good faith belief that the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.
</p><p><i>4. Disclosure to the Office of Management and Budget
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.
</p><p><i>5. Disclosure to Congressional Offices
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.
</p><p><i>6. Disclosure to the Department of Justice or for Litigation or Other Proceedings
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to the Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Agency is authorized or required to appear. Such disclosures may occur in circumstances in which the Agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the Agency or any of its components, and the Agency is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation, the Department of Justice or the Agency is deemed to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, and the use of the records is compatible with the purpose for which the records or information were collected. Information may also be disclosed in connection with litigation or settlement discussions regarding claims by or against the Agency, including public filing with a court, arbitrator, mediator, administrative body or other deciding or mediating official or body, as relevant and necessary to the discussions or proceedings, and except where court orders are otherwise required under section (b)(11) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(11).
</p><p><i>7. Disclosure for Hiring or Retention of Employee
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed from this system of records to a Federal, State or local agency in response to a request by the agency in connection with the hiring, retention or investigation of an employee, issuance of a security clearance, letting of a grant or contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that such information is deemed relevant to the requesting agency's decision.
</p><p><i>8. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to the Agency's responsibility or authority for oversight or evaluation of Federal personnel management.
</p><p><i>9. Disclosure to the National Archives or Federal Records Management Centers
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to the National Archives or Federal Records Management Centers as necessary for purposes of records management or records management inspections.
</p><p><i>10. Disclosure for Administrative Claims, Complaints, Appeals
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal opportunity employment investigator or official, arbitrator, mediator, opposing counsel or representative, or other person properly engaged in investigation, settlement, litigation or decision regarding an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee, but only to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p><i>11. Disclosure to Contractors, Grantees and Others
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, grant, cooperative agreement, job, service, or other activity for the Agency and who have a need to have access to the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Agency. Where appropriate, the Agency may require such individuals or entities to comply with the Privacy Act, as provided in 5 U.S.C. 552a(m).
</p><p><i>12. Disclosure to Federal Agencies for Purposes of Audit
</i></p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed to authorized employees of a Federal agency for purposes of audit or program review. Examples of such agencies include, but are not limited to, Offices of Inspector General, General Accounting Office, Department of the Treasury, and Office of Management and Budget.
</p><p><i>13. Disclosure to Department of State
</i></p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the Department of State and its posts abroad for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency, or for purposes related to the responsibilities of the Department of State in conducting foreign policy or protecting United States citizens, such as the assignment of employees to positions abroad, the reporting of accidents abroad, evacuation of employees and dependents, and other purposes for which officers and employees of the Department of State have a need for the records in the performance of their official duties.
</p><p><i>14. Disclosure to International or Foreign Agencies or Entities
</i></p><p>A record in this system of records may be disclosed to a foreign government or international agency when necessary to facilitate the conduct of U.S. relations with that government or agency through the issuance of such documents as visas, country clearances, identification cards, drivers' licenses, diplomatic lists, licenses to import or export personal effects, and other official documents and permits routinely required in connection with the official service or travel abroad of the individual and her or his dependents.
</p><p><i>15. Disclosure Under Foreign Assistance Act
</i></p><p>A record in this system of records may be disclosed to Federal agencies with which the Agency has entered into an agreement to provide services to assist the Agency in carrying out its functions under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended. Such disclosures would be for transmitting information between organizational units of the Agency, for providing to the original employing agency information concerning the services of its employee while under the supervision of the Agency, including performance evaluations, reports of conduct, awards and commendations, and information normally obtained in the course of personnel administration and employee supervision, or for providing other information directly related to the purpose of the inter-agency agreement as set forth therein, and necessary and relevant to its implementation.
</p><p><i>16. Disclosure Pursuant to FOIA
</i></p><p>A record in this system of records may be disclosed to the Department of Justice to determine whether disclosure thereof is required by the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552). A record in this system of records may be disclosed when the information is subject to exemption under the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552), but the Agency, in its discretion, determines not to assert the exemption.
</p><p><i>17. Disclosure to State and Local Tax Authorities
</i></p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed to state and local tax authorities with which the Secretary of the Treasury has entered into agreements and only to those state and local taxing authorities for which the employee is subject to tax (whether or not tax is withheld).</p></xhtmlContent></routineUses>


<section id="bbg1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Broadcasting Board of Governors Staff Files--BBG.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>
Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), Rm. 3360, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who submit or receive official correspondence from the BBG or Board Staff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondence to and from the Board and Board Staff, BBG reports, Board biographical files, Broadcasting Entities (e.g., Voice of America (VOA), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Office of Cuba Broadcasting (OCB), Radio Free Asia (RFA), and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty (RFE/RL)).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Records Act of 1950, as amended; 44 U.S.C. 3101-3167; Records Disposal Act of 1943, as amended; 44 U.S.C. 3301-3314.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain a record of correspondence to and from the BBG Board, both with individuals and institutions outside the Agency and to the BBG Broadcasting entities, reports provided to Congress either by request or on an informational basis, and biographical information on Board members for BBG and public use. Records are used and accessed by Board members and Board staff. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Information is retained in document form in file folders and in computers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Manually retrieved by category and name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Authorized users: access to files is limited to only authorized BBG employees having a substantiated need for the information.
</p><p>2. Physical safeguards: all files are protected by office personnel during regular duty hours and during non-duty hours by security doors that can only be accessed by BBG staff employees. Computer information is protected by the use of passwords restricted to authorized users. Files are contained in secure building that can be accessed only by persons showing proper identification credentials.
</p><p>3. Procedural safeguards: access to records is limited to staff members on a need to know basis, to employees performing their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained until no longer useful or relevant and then retired or destroyed in accordance with BBG policy and procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>BBG Executive Director, Broadcasting Board of Governors, Room 3360, 330 Independence Ave., SW, Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW, Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting contents and appealing determinations by the individual concerned appear at 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographical and ethics information furnished voluntarily by subject individuals, unsolicited correspondence, requests and inquiries from U.S. Government officials and members of the general public to the BBG and BBG staff.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="bbg2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of the General Counsel Litigation Files.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Broadcasting Board of Governors, Office of the General Counsel, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW, Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Some documents within the system may be classified or confidential.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have filed grievances, inquiries or discrimination complaints; employees separated or considered for separation for cause; officers selected out; individuals taking legal actions against the BBG or its employees; tort claimants and accident victims; employees and related persons for whom legislative action is sought; personal property loss claimants; employees and applicants raising legal or administrative issues concerning rights or benefits; individuals whose salaries have been garnished; individuals whose official personnel files have been subpoenaed in connection with divorce, custody or other litigation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Investigatory reports; litigation reports; pre-hearing and pre-trial material; evidence for discovery and submission to hearing officers and courts; pleadings; briefs; transcripts; decisions and other related documents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Federal Records Act, as amended, 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To represent the BBG in claims and other legal actions; to issue legal opinions or determinations regarding BBG action and perform all of the BBG's legal representation and advocacy functions</p><p>Information is made available on a need-to-know basis to personnel of the BBG as may be required in the performance of their official duties. The principal users of this information outside of the BBG are the Department of Justice, Department of State, including Office of Inspector General, Office of Personnel Management, Foreign Service Grievance Board, and the Employee Management Relations Committee</p><p>Records contained in these files may be released to agencies outside the BBG who have statutory, regulatory, or other lawful authority to collect, maintain or use such information. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records in file folders, electronic data on computer storage media.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By the name of the individual and the nature of the legal action.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Maintained in locked file cabinets and in offices in office suites to which only authorized BBG personnel have access. Computer files are maintained on networked BBG computers that are accessible only through the use of passwords.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retained until such time as they are no longer useful, current, or for a period of time until it can be assured that all legal proceedings and matters are final and concluded.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the General Counsel, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW, Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW, Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting the contents of records subject to the Privacy Act, and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information provided by the individual and/or their attorneys or representatives, and by employees of the BBG; information produced in the processing of a claim, grievance, legal action or issue.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552(a)(k)(2) and (k)(5), all investigatory material in the record which meets the criteria of these subsections is exempted from the notice, access and contest requirements (under 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d)(e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I) and (f) of the BBG regulations) in order for the BBG's legal staff to properly perform its functions. See also 22 CFR 505.15. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Freedom of Information and Privacy Act Files--BBG/GC/FP.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)/Privacy Act (PA) Officer, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Suite 3349, Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Some documents may be classified Confidential and Secret.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have requested documents/records or other information maintained and in the possession of the BBG (pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act) or maintained by the BBG in a System of Records about themselves (pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Official, unofficial or personal information maintained and in possession of the BBG through reports, memoranda, correspondence, etc.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552 (Freedom of Information Act) and 5 U.S.C. 552a (Privacy Act).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For processing of requests received pursuant to the FOIA and the Privacy Act. Information is made available on a need to know basis to personnel of the BBG as may be required in the performance of their official duties</p><p>Information in these records is not normally available to individuals or agencies outside the BBG, but records may be released to other government agencies who have statutory or other lawful authority to maintain or view such information</p><p>Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records in file folders, and electronic storage on computers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name of individual or personal identifier.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in secure office area with access only to BBG employees, and in bar locked cabinets and in combination locked storage. Computer and data base records are maintained on secure BBG computers with access only to authorized individuals with the appropriate password information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retired and destroyed in accordance with record disposition schedules for BBG.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Suite 3349, Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contract; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting/amending record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Compiled as a result of requests under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) and the Privacy Act.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within the system of records may be exempted under 5 U.S.C. 552 (k)(1)-(2), (k)(4)-(6)</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of Legal Counsel Ethics Files (Financial Disclosure Reports).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the General Counsel, BBG, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Suite 3349, Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None for the system. However, some documents within the system may be classified as confidential or otherwise protected or immunized from disclosure.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Experts or consultants, employees, paid at the Executive Schedule level; employees classified at GS-13, or the Foreign Service Equivalent, or higher, who are in positions of responsibility for a government decision or taking a government action with regard to: Contracting or procurement; administering or monitoring grants or subsidies; regulating or auditing private or other non-Federal enterprise; or required to report employment or financial interests in order to determine potential conflicts of interest or to ensure that BBG decision making is not performed by individuals with an ethical conflict.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Statements of personal and family financial and share holdings and other interests in business enterprises; copies of blind trusts and other agreements pertaining to such interests; correspondence regarding potential or actual conflicts of interest, or regarding investigation, insulation or control of individuals to prevent or eliminate potential conflicts of interest; opinions of counsel, including recommendations of waivers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 11222; 5 U.S.C. 7301; 18 U.S.C. 208; Ethics in Government Act of 1948, as amended.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Review by the Ethics Officer and staff for possible conflicts of interest. Provide necessary reference information should allegations of conflicts arise. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p><p>On a need-to-know basis, sharing of ethics information among BBG components or employees in their official capacities for the purpose of investigating or addressing allegations of conduct that is related to addressing ethics issues.
</p><p>Information in Confidential Financial Disclosure Reports is not normally available to individuals or agencies outside of the BBG, but records may be released to other government agencies who have statutory or other lawful authority to maintain such information. Information in Public Financial Disclosure Reports is generally subject to public disclosure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records in file folders and electronic data base and computer entries.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Alphabetically by name and by BBG element or geographic area.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Maintained in secure office area with access only to BBG employees, and in bar locked cabinets and in combination locked storage. Computer and data base records are maintained on secure BBG computers with access only to authorized individuals with the appropriate password information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Disposed of six years after employee leaves a position for which a report or ethics information is or has been required.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting/amending record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From the individual who filed the required ethics form or from any individual who provided information pursuant to a complaint or legal request for examination of ethics or conflict of interest issues.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within the system of records may be exempted from disclosure pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552 (k)(1)-(2), (k)(4)-(6).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="bbg5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">IBB Director's Executive Secretariat Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Director's Office, Executive Secretariat, International Broadcasting Bureau, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Some documents may be classified confidential or secret.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Members of the White House Staff, Members of Congress and their staffs, heads of other executive agencies of the Federal Government and members of the general public.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondence addressed to the IBB Director, as well as the BBG, and copies of responses to requests for reports, information and/or assistance of various kinds prepared by the Director or designated representative.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Records Act of 1950, as amended, 44 U.S.C. 3101-3167; Records Disposal Act of 1943, as amended, 44 U.S.C. 3301-3314.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Reference files to provide oversight of the flow of requests of the Director for reports on programming effectiveness of BBG broadcasts; to provide information and/or assistance of various kinds; and to provide and monitor responses to such requests.
</p><p>Information is made available on a need-to-know basis to personnel of the BBG as may be required in the performance of their official duties.
</p><p>The information may also be released to other government agencies who have statutory or other lawful authority to maintain or use such information.
</p><p>Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are stored on computer maintained by and located within the Secretariat, and maintained as paper records in file folders in the Secretariat.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are cross-indexed by individual name, organization, subject file and by computer reference number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are accessible only to authorized employees of the Director's staff with appropriate password information. Paper records are kept in locked file cabinets that are contained in a secure area. All records are contained in secure building that is accessible only to individuals with appropriate identification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained indefinitely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Supervisory Staff Analyst, Executive Secretariat, BBG, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access, contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Unsolicited correspondence from U.S. Government Officials and members of the general public addressed to the Director concerning VOA, Worldnet, RFE/RL, RFA, or Office of Cuba Broadcasting.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained in this system of records may be exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552(a)(k)(1)-(2), (k)(4)-(6); See 22 CFR 505.15.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/A--Office of Administration Travel Card Program Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>
Office of Administration, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>IBB/BBG employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records and information pertaining to IBB/BBG employees who participate in the Government Travel Charge Card Program.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel and Transportation Reform Act of 1998, Public Law 105-264, dated October 19, 1998, 112 STAT. 2350; 5 U.S.C. 5707; 40 U.S.C. 486, Sec. 2.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Used by the staff of the Office of Administration to prepare various reports. The information may be released to other government agencies that have Statutory or other lawful authority to maintain, examine or compile such information</p><p>Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records maintained in file folders and lists maintained in computers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name of employee.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in file cabinets in office space that is restricted to authorized BBG employees. Computer records are maintained in systems accessible only by authorized users with appropriate password information. All records are contained in a secure building with access limited to individuals with appropriate identification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>To date, these records have no disposal authority.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Administrative Operations Division, IBB, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting contents and appealing determinations by the individual concerned appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information obtained from individuals in the context of applications for approval of travel credit card. Delinquent and Misuse report.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/A--Office of Administration (Employee Parking).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administration, International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>IBB/BBG employees assigned to BBG controlled parking spaces; employees waiting for assignment of vacated parking spaces.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Regulations regarding the use of Federally-controlled parking spaces at 41 CFR Part 101.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Assignment of parking space to BBG executives; to assure fairness in the assignment of parking spaces to employees and to give priority to certain individuals, e.g. the handicapped and individuals in car pools.
</p><p>Information is made available to authorized BBG personnel as may be required in the performance of their official duties.
</p><p>The information may also be released to other government agencies who have statutory or other lawful authority to maintain, examine or compile such information.
</p><p>Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records maintained in file folders and lists maintained in computers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name of employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in file cabinets in office space that is restricted to authorized BBG employees. Computer records are maintained in systems accessible only by authorized users with appropriate password information. All records are contained in a secure building with access limited to individuals with appropriate identification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are destroyed within 18 months of time when employee relinquishes the assigned parking space or is separated from the BBG.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Administration, IBB, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting contents and appealing determinations by the individual concerned appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous, or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information obtained from individuals in the context of application for and administration of BBG parking spaces, and responses generated to this information by various BBG personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/A--Office of Administration (Office Travel Records).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administration, IBB, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Past and present BBG employees and private citizens who have traveled under BBG auspices or as a result of BBG travel orders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel documents and correspondence relating to shipment and storage of personal effects and property; records of active passports and visa requests from foreign embassies; records of temporary duty travel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Supplemental Appropriation Act of 1995, Public Law 663, section 1331 (31 U.S.C. 200); Section 367, the Revised Statutes, as amended; Anti-Deficiency Act (31 U.S.C. 665).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Used by the staff of the Office of Administration to provide reimbursement for travel services provided to BBG travelers and the packing, storing, or shipment of their household effects and automobiles; to obtain passports and visas for BBG employees and other BBG travelers; and to prepare various reports on BBG travel activities. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p><p>Information in these records is not normally available to individuals or agencies outside the BBG, but records may be released to other government agencies that have lawful authority to maintain, collect, view or compile such information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records maintained in file folders in storage files, loose leaf binders, and cards. Electronic records maintained in computers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Alphabetically by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Passports and related material and all classified material are kept in bar-locked cabinets. Other records are kept in unlocked files that are under surveillance and supervision of authorized employees during the working day, and by security guards after official working hour. Computer records are maintained in areas controlled by authorized BBG employees and are accessible by authorized individuals using password information. All records are within a secure building that is accessible only to individuals with appropriate identification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Temporary duty travel authorizations are maintained for four years and then sent to the Federal records center. Records of personal property are maintained for six years. Passport records are kept for ten years for employees and five years for non-employee travelers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Administrative Operations Division, IBB, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type ="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel request forms initiated by various BBG components. Information regarding personal items obtained from the traveler and from transportation carriers. Passport information received from the Department of State's Passport Office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="bbg9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/CON--Office of Contracts (Vendor Data-Base File Extracts). </subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Contracts (M/CON), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 "C"  Street, SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Actual and prospective BBG contractors or grantees; individuals with whom the BBG contracts for talent, including Purchase Order Vendors (POV) and individuals retained for Expert Consultant Services.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information on individuals as either past, current, or potential future vendor(s) to the BBG is contained in and can be extracted as electronic or paper records from M/CON's computer data base files. Such records may contain an individual's name, business/Internet address(s) and type, telephone/facsimile numbers, security clearances, college/higher education diplomas and degrees, specialized Government training, awards, and personal data from previous contracts, product/service code, and/or North America Industry and Classification System (NAICS) code.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Acquisition Regulation (45 CFR 14.205-1(c) and 53.21(e)).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To prepare BBG Solicitation Mailing Lists for competitive procurements; to determine potential contractor responsibility information such as financial status, annual billing amounts, technical experience, past performance, relevant experience, and other contractor qualification information. Information in the system of records is made available on a need to know basis to BBG personnel as required in the performance of their official duties. Information may be released to other Government agencies who have lawful authority to maintain, view or compile such information. The principal user of this information outside the BBG is the General Services Administration.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Information is initially entered into M/CON's computer system from either Requisition or Contract forms or from the former Standard Form 129 (Solicitation Mailing List Application). Once the data is entered into the computer system, the SF-129 paper documents copies are then destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By the name of the individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Authorized Users: Contracting personnel and other authorized BBG personnel.
</p><p>2. Physical Safeguards: Access to computer records is limited via password only to authorized personnel; all records are contained within a secure building with access only to individuals with appropriate identification.
</p><p>3. Procedural Safeguards: All authorized users of the information stored in these systems protect the information from public view and unauthorized personnel. Data stored in computers are accessed through the use of passwords available only to authorized personnel.
</p><p>4. Implementation Guidelines: BBG Manual of Operations and Administration (MOA) III 500; Records Management Handbook (Domestic) Section 560-565.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>A routine update of information is conducted approximately every five (5) years. Outdated information is disposed of internally.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Senior Procurement Executive, Office of Contracts (M/CON), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 "C"  Street SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, must submit a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, 330 Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individual requests shall contain the name and address of the System Manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name that would be the vendor name used in the contract;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contract; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by individuals, companies, and other organizations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/CON--Office of Contracts (Acquisition and Procurement Workforce Information System).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Contracts (M/CON), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 "C"  Street SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>BBG employees involved with acquisition and procurement activities, including but not limited to warranted Contracting Officers, Contracting Specialists, Purchasing Agents, Procurement Analysts, and Authorized Representatives of the Contracting Officer (AR/CO).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records containing information regarding an individual's capacity or ability to serve or be involved with BBG procurement activities, including but not limited to Name, Office Symbol, Position Title, Series and Grade, Service Computation Date, Supervisory Designation, Functional Description of Present Position, Education, Training, Procurement Experience, Professional Organizations, Honors, Awards, Career Objectives.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Authority for this system is derived from the Federal Records Act, 44 U.S.C. 3101, and Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR), Subpart 1-6 (Career Development, Contracting Authority, and Responsibilities).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Identification of employees who have met standards of experience, education, and training for appointment as warranted Contracting Officers and Authorized Representatives of Contracting Officers (AR/CO). Additional purposes are to comply with applicable FAR requirements, and procurement education and training requirements of the Clinger-Cohen Act (Pub. L. 104-106) and the Office of Federal Procurement Policy (OFPP) Letters 92-03 and 97-01 pertaining to mandatory training requirements for the career development of Federal acquisition and procurement workforce personnel. Information is also used to analyze overall BBG procurement system performance regarding such areas as functional workforce structure and size, and system-wide and individual training needs. Information is available for performance of official duties. Information may be released to other Government agencies who have lawful authority to maintain, view or compile such information. Also, see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Information is maintained in paper form in files and in Office of Contracts computer storage.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by BBG employee's name, office, job series and grade.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Authorized Users: Office of Contracts personnel and BBG employees with express authorization.
</p><p>2. Physical safeguards: Files are kept in binders and in desktop PCs in the Policy and Procedures Staff offices in the Office of Contracts. During non-duty hours the binders and PC is kept in a locked office. Computer records are maintained in office space that is controlled by BBG employees and in computers in which only authorized users may access via passwords. All records are contained within a secure building with access only to individuals with appropriate identification.
</p><p>3. Procedural safeguards: All users of the personal information in connection with the performance of their official duties protect information from public view and from unauthorized personnel entering the office space where the records are kept. Access to records is strictly limited to Office of Contracts (M/CON) personnel.
</p><p>4. Implementation guidelines: BBG Manual of Operations and Administration (MOA) III-500; Records Management Handbook (Domestic) Sections 560-565.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files will be retained as long as the individual remains an employee of the BBG and is assigned to an Office of Contracts (M/CON) Headquarters or Field Procurement Activity procurement position (i.e., Contracting Officer, Purchasing Agent) or the employee is designated as an Authorized Representative of the Contracting Officer (AR/CO) for the term of the specific contract to which the AR/CO designation is applicable. Records will be destroyed within a reasonable time upon the employee's separation from the BBG, revocation or expiration of the employee's contracting warrant or AR/CO designation, or completion of the contract to which the AR/CO designation is applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Senior Procurement Executive, Office of Contracts (M/CON), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 "C"  Street SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, must submit a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, 330 Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individual requests shall contain the name and address of the System Manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name that would be the vendor name used in the contract;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contract; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by individuals, companies, and other organizations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="bbg11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/CON--Office of Contracts--(Suspension and Debarment Information System).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Contracts (M/CON), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 "C"  Street SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Some documents may be classified at the "Confidential"  level of security classification, and they may also be considered as "Procurement Sensitive"  information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have been suspended, proposed for debarment, or debarred from Federal procurement, non-procurement, and assistance programs, and individuals who have been the subject of agency review, audit or inquiry to determine whether they should be debarred and/or suspended from Federal procurement/non-procurement and assistance programs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records include information on individuals and firms excluded, suspended, or considered for exclusion or suspension or other lawful disqualification from Federal acquisition (including procurement and non-procurement programs) or assistance programs as a result of suspension or debarment proceedings initiated by BBG or pursuant to information forwarded to or received by the BBG from another agency pursuant to lawful function or from the GSA's List of Parties Excluded from Federal Procurement or nonprocurement Programs. Such information includes, but is not limited to, names and addresses, and other identifying information such as Social Security numbers or taxpayer identification numbers, of individuals covered by the system of records. Such information also includes evidence obtained in support of: criminal, civil or administrative action and closure, interim decisions, compliance agreements, audits, and final determinations. Examples of evidence contained in files include correspondence, inspection reports, memoranda of interviews, contracts and cooperative and assistance agreements, judgment, plea and conviction documents, and corporate information. Computer generated records may include data regarding categories and status of cases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, 41 U.S.C. 251 et seq., Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act., 41 U.S.C. 401 et seq.; Executive Order 12549 (Feb. 18, 1986) and Executive Order 12689 (Aug. 16, 1989); Federal Acquisition Regulation 9.404; and 22 CFR 513.500 and 513.505.
</p><p>Purpose:
</p><p>To assist the BBG in assembling information on, conducting, and documenting debarment and suspension proceedings to ensure that Federal contracts, cooperative agreements and Federal assistance, loans, and benefits are awarded to responsible business entities and individuals.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be disclosed to the General Services Administration (GSA) to compile and maintain the "List of Parties Excluded from Federal Procurement or Nonprocurement Programs"  in accordance with FAR 9.404 and 22 CFR 513.500 and 513.505; to organizations or individuals suspended, proposed for debarment or debarred in BBG proceedings; to the legal representatives of such organizations; and to the legal representatives of individuals suspended, proposed for debarment or debarred in BBG proceedings; to a Federal, State or local agency, financial institution, or other entity to verify an individual's eligibility for engaging in a covered transaction, including covered, primary and lower-tier covered transactions as defined at 22 CFR 513.110; to Federal, State or local agencies, in response to requests or subpoenas, or for the purpose(s) of (a) assisting them in administering Federal acquisition, loan and benefit programs or regulatory programs or monies; (b) assisting them in discharging their duties to ensure that Federal contracts and assistance, loans, benefits programs and monies are awarded to responsible individuals and organizations; or (c) ensuring that Federal, State or local regulatory responsibilities are met; to the public, upon request, and to publishers of computerized legal research systems, but such disclosures shall be limited to interim or final decisions and settlement agreements. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>File-folders, computer data-bases and other electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name of the individual or firm and by file number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password protected computer system. Paper records are maintained by authorized individuals in locked file cabinets and in secure locked offices. All records are maintained in secure, access-controlled areas. All records are contained within a secure building with access only to individuals with appropriate identification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Investigative and advocacy files are maintained until such time after all litigation or appeal ceases and no further activity is likely to occur. Audit files are retained throughout the term of any compliance agreement or settlement, or until such time as all litigation activity is final and ceases. The official administrative record is retained in the office until six months after the period of debarment or exclusion expires, or until all provisions of any compliance agreement or settlement agreement have been completely fulfilled. The official administrative record is then transferred to the Federal Records Center (FRC) for storage. Files relating to cases closed without action are also transferred to the FRC within one year after the decision to close the matter.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Senior Procurement Executive, Office of Contracts (M/CON), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 "C"  Street SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, must make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, 330 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests must contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear at 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>BBG and other Federal officials, State and local government officials, private parties, business and other entities who may have information relevant to an inquiry, and individuals who have been suspended, proposed for debarment, or debarred, and their legal representatives.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted by 5 U.S.C. 552(a)(k)(2); (k)(4); and (k)(5).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/P--Office of Personnel.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Personnel, International Broadcasting Bureau, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Some documents are classified Confidential.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>BBG employees and overseas American employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records and information pertaining to the recruitment, testing and appointment of employees. Records include application forms; fiscal documents related to expenses; documents regarding post appointment; changes in employee skills, qualifications and experience; copies of SF-50 forms and payroll change slips.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Law 80-402, the United States Information and Exchange Act of 1948, as amended ( 22 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.); the U.S. International Broadcasting Act of 1994, as amended (22 U.S.C. 6201, et seq.); and the Foreign Affairs Consolidation Act of 1998 (Pub. L. 105-277).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Official Personnel Files contains long-term records necessary or relevant to documenting employee status and service, as required by the United States Office of Personnel Management's (OPM's) instructions and designated in OPM's Guide to Personnel Record Keeping.
</p><p>Information is made available as required by BBG personnel in performance of their official duties. The principal users of this information outside the BBG are personnel officers in other government agencies as a result of a transfer, detail or hiring processes relating to the individual to whom the records pertain, and investigators performing official functions. The information may also be released to other government agencies who have a statutory or other lawful authority to maintain such information.
</p><p>Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Documents are maintained in Standard Form 66 for all Official Personnel Files (OPFs), additional information is contained in computer data base.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>OPFs are manually retrieved by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>OPFs are maintained in a security approved locked storage room and in computers accessed by individuals only with appropriate password information.
</p><p>Access to OPFs is limited to authorized BBG employees and other authorized individuals, such as security or EEO investigators, with a substantiated official need for access to the information to perform their duties. Computer files are maintained in secure office area with access to authorized individuals with appropriate password information. All files are stored in a secure building with access only to individuals with appropriate identification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are maintained as long as employee remains at BBG. Records of former employees are transferred to their destination agency or to the Federal Records Center, as appropriate.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Operations and Benefits Division, Office of Personnel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, International Broadcasting Bureau, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access, contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear at 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is retrieved from employee application forms; from employees' supervisors (documentation relating to employees' experience, training, evaluation, performance, review, and recommendation for promotion, etc.; and from organizational personnel and fiscal elements (e.g. SF-50--Notification of Personnel Actions, payroll change slips, etc.).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted by 5 U.S.C. 552(a)(k)(1); (k)(2); (k)(4); (k)(5); and (k)(6).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">OWSDS – Office of Workforce Support and Development System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p> None. </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Office of Workforce Support and Development, Broadcasting Board of Governors, International Broadcasting Bureau, 330 C St., SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>BBG employees and contractor personnel receiving Agency-provided training.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Employee and contractor personnel training registration data, applications, biographic data, educational backgrounds, training records, training program outlines, evaluations of training courses.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948, as amended (22 U.S.C. 1431, et seq.); the U.S. International Broadcasting Act of 1994, as amended (22 U.S.C. 6201, et seq.); and the Foreign Affairs Consolidation Act of 1998 (Pub. L. 105-277).</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Background material used to determine eligibility for training; justification for training reports and record-keeping; evaluation and selection of lecturers and contractors to provide training; preparation of reports to Congress and other Government agencies on training provided and training costs, as well as projected training needs and costs.</p>

<p>Information is made available on a need-to-know basis to personnel of the BBG as may be required in the performance of their official duties. The principal users of this information outside the BBG are personnel officers in other Government agencies as a result of transfer, detail, or reassignment of the individual to whom the record pertains, other agencies considering employees for detail or transfer, and investigators performing their job functions.</p>

<p>The information may also be released to other Government agencies that have statutory or other lawful authority to maintain such information. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage:</p><p> Paper records stored in file folders and file cabinets. Computer records stored on computer drives.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Manually retrieved by name, by computer generated lists of training statistics, or by training course title or description.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to files is limited only to authorized BBG employees having an official use or need for the information. All files are maintained in locked file cabinets during non-duty hours and are protected by office personnel when being used during duty hours. All files are contained within a secure building with access only to individuals with appropriate identification. All users of personal information in connection with the performance of their jobs protect information from public view and from unauthorized personnel entering an unsupervised office or workspace.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Training records maintained until employee is separated, until records are no longer needed, or otherwise as directed by the General Records Schedule. Budget records and cost statistics are kept for three to five years or otherwise as directed by the General Records Schedule.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, Office of Workforce Support and Development, Broadcasting Board of Governors, International Broadcasting Bureau, 330 C St., SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:</p>
<p>A. Full legal name;</p>
<p>B. Date of Birth;</p>
<p>C. Social Security Number;</p>
<p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and</p>
<p>E. Signature.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The employee; training applications and records; training officers and other individuals involved in personnel management; supervisors; contracting officer representatives; trainee evaluations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>
                Certain records contained within this system of records may be exempted by 5 U.S. C. 552a(k)(2); (k)(4); (k)(5); and (k)(6).
            </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/SEC--Office of Security (Personnel Security and Integrity Records).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Security, Broadcasting Board of Governors, International Broadcasting Bureau, 330 C St., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Retired records stored at Washington National Records Center, 4205 Suitland Road, Suitland, MD 20409.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Most records are unclassified, but the system may include records that are confidential and secret.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All persons currently or formerly employed by BBG in the United States; all persons currently or formerly employed by BBG in other countries; some foreign nationals currently or formerly employed outside the United States; some contractors or individuals whose services are utilized by BBG; former applicants to BBG; some prospective spouses of BBG employees; persons who have significant relationship with persons whose services were utilized or considered for utilization by the BBG; some persons who were significantly involved in non-security related administrative inquiries conducted by the M/SEC; some persons of counterintelligence interest whose names appeared in the press or are contained in documents furnished by other agencies of the United States. </p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Application and security forms provided by subjects; reports of investigation and background check, including those conducted by the Office of Security and other Government agencies; Personnel Security Worksheet Records evaluating investigative material; security clearance and security approval forms; intra-office, intra-Agency and inter-agency correspondence relating to investigations; security and suitability determinations and administrative matters; correspondence to and from Federal and non-Federal law enforcement and counterintelligence agencies; correspondence to and from State and local law enforcement jurisdictions, credit bureaus, private employers, schools, businesses, and individuals relating to investigative inquiries; records regarding briefings, interviews and de-briefings; security certifications to other agencies, contact reports, and security violations; photographs and finger print cards; Cross Reference Sheets and Records of Release of Information; records from Security Identification Card System. Not all files contain all of the above-listed elements.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The authority of the Office of Security to collect and maintain security data is derived from the following: Executive Order 10450 of April 27, 1953, as amended; Executive Order 10865 of January 17, 1961, as amended; Executive Order 12968 of August 2, 1995; and Title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To collect, record and maintain information deemed necessary to make security and suitability determinations regarding applicants for employment with and employees of the IBB and BBG; to make security determinations regarding the advisability of employee assignments; to make security assessments regarding the advisability of contracts and other financial arrangements such as cooperative agreements, and positions with IBB and BBG; to make security determinations regarding the advisability of certain promotions, as required by regulation; to make determinations regarding employees' receipt of special clearances as required by regulation; to make determinations whether certain non-citizen employees of IBB or BBG abroad should be granted security approval; to disclose information to the Office of Inspector General, U.S. Attorneys' Offices, and other Federal, State and local law enforcement entities as necessary for these offices to carry out their investigative and law enforcement functions; to provide information to officials within IBB and BBG components and management elements as necessary to assist in the performance of their official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Data may be disclosed to Foreign Service Board of Examiners as necessary to determine qualifications and suitability of applicants; data may be disclosed to the Department of State as necessary to determine whether an applicant or employee should be granted or maintain medical clearance; data may be disclosed to other Government agencies as necessary for those agencies to determine whether employees should be granted special clearances required in connection with IBB or BBG duties; data may be disclosed in advising duly authorized security officers or other agencies of significant security information related to a BBG or IBB employee or applicant. Data may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel or to the Office of Personnel Management that significant security or suitability information was developed or obtained regarding an applicant or employee. IBB/BBG investigative material having counterintelligence or national security significance may be disclosed to other U.S. Government agencies with responsibilities in these areas. Records may be used by the Director of the Office of Security or his/her lawful agent in correspondence and contacts with officials of other Government agencies when, in the judgment of the Director, it becomes necessary to inform other Government agencies of information uncovered or available to the Office of Security.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records kept in file folders; computer data stored on computers and electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Authorized Users: Employees of the Records Management Unit and employees of the Office of Security.
</p><p>Physical Safeguards: Files and computers are maintained in a secure area which, during working hours, is staffed by authorized users. Room is locked and alarmed during non-duty hours. Files in possession of other authorized users are kept in approved safe or locked cabinets when not in use and during non-duty hours. Computer records are maintained on secure computers with strict password access. Entire building is secured during non-duty hours, with security guards on duty.
</p><p>Procedural/Technical Safeguards: Records Management Unit personnel furnish files to other authorized users in exchange for properly executed "Chargeout Record"  form. Record Management Unit is provided properly executed "Recharge"  form if file is passed from one authorized user to another. All personnel having routine access to records have top secret security clearances</p><p>Citation of Implementing Guidelines: Executive Order 12958, and the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files pertaining to employees, contractors, and other whose relationship with IBB and BBG required a security clearance or certification may be transferred to the Washington National Records Center after the individual leaves the BBG or after the relationship with the BBG ceases. Records may be destroyed upon notification of death or not later than five years after separation or transfer of employee or termination of contract, whichever is applicable. Files pertaining to unsuccessful applicants may be transferred to Washington National Records Center 120 days after non-selection, and destroyed ten years after date of last action; index and cross-index cards may be destroyed as files are destroyed. All destruction of documents pursuant to appropriate security controls.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Security, BBG, 330 C Street, SW., Washington, DC 20237.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear at 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographic, personal history and other relevant information furnished by the subject individual on application and security forms or furnished by the subject during personal interviews or contained in reports of investigation conducted by the Office of Security, the Office of Personnel Management, Department of State, Office of Inspector General, Federal Bureau of Investigation, Department of Homeland Security and other Federal, State and local Government agencies or entities. Biographical, personal history and other relevant information obtained from credit bureaus, current and former employers, supervisors, co-workers, schools, teachers, rental and real estate agencies, landlords, neighbors, references, and acquaintances. Biographical, personal history and other relevant information, which may or may not be in the form of a photograph obtained from birth certificates, medical records and professional organization and society records. Counterintelligence and security reports that are furnished by other Federal agencies; various public records and indices such as those produced by Congressional committees, other elements and employees of BBG, employees of other Government agencies, non-government entities, and members of the public who may furnish information to the Office of Security in the interests of national security, the integrity or preservation of the federal service, good citizenship or desire to assist others, whistleblower activity, or concern regarding potentially unlawful, unethical, or improper activities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1), (k)(2), and (k)(5); 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), 552a(d), 552a(e)(1), (e)(4)(H)-(I), and (f). See 22 CFR 505.15.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="bbg15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">OCB--Office of Cuba Broadcasting.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Director's Office, Office of Cuba Broadcasting, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 4201 NW 77th Avenue, Miami, Florida 33166.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees and interns.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Leave slips and statements, performance appraisals, position descriptions, manager's notes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Records Act of 1950, as amended, 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To track employee information for use by managers</p><p>Storage:</p><p>Stored in file folders and on computers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Retrieved by name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>In secure areas and cabinets that are only accessible by managers. Computer information is maintained on secure computers with access limited by password.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Maintained until employee is separated from the BBG. Records of former employees are transferred to their destination agency or to the Federal Records Center, as appropriate.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director's Office, Office of Cuba Broadcasting, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 4201 NW 77th Avenue, Miami, Florida 33166.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear at 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous, or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by individuals and managers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of Civil Rights Complaint Files--OCR.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Civil Rights, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 301 4th Street, SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any employee with BBG who has a belief he/she has been discriminated against in some manner, or an individual who believes he/she has been retaliated against for a past filing of a discrimination complaint, and who has consulted with an Office of Civil Rights Counselor of the BBG or a member of OCR staff about the alleged discrimination.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>42 U.S.C. 200e-16; 29 U.S.C. 633a; 29 U.S.C. 206(d).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To record statements and actions taken regarding employees' and employment applicants' claims of discrimination. Principal users of this information outside the BBG are the Department of Justice, the Merit Systems Protection Board, and the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. The information contained in this system may also be released to other government agencies having statutory or other lawful authority to maintain, compile, view or receive such information.
</p><p>Information is made available on a need to know basis to BBG personnel as required for the performance of their official duties. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage::</p><p>Partially automated system. Most information is stored in paper folders, with additional information stored on computers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access is limited to OCR staff and contract EEO investigators. Records are stored in cabinets with bar locks and on computers protected with passwords known only to authorized OCR officials. Files are not removed from OCR offices, complainant and/or the complainant's representative are provided with copies of file materials, and copies may also be provided to other government agencies in accordance with the exercise of these agencies' statutory, regulatory or other official authorized functions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Civil Rights, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 310 4th Street, SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW, Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear at 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous, or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal interviews, affidavits, statements, BBG Personnel and Employment records, transcripts of hearings and litigation proceedings, correspondence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">OCR--Office of Civil Rights General Files (General Files).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Civil Rights, Broadcasting Board of governors (BBG), 301 4th St, SW., Washington, DC 20237
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Some documents may be classified Confidential.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees of the BBG, applicants for positions in the BBG, organizations and institutes of higher education applying for grants from the BBG, recruitment contacts, prominent individuals who may be appropriate contacts for promotion panels, speakers, electronic media experts, and other individuals with whom the office is in contact, such as contractors and consultants.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Copies of applications, resumes, correspondence and bibliographical information regarding the individuals covered by the system, including memoranda to the files of employees covered by the system who seek counseling. General administrative files, including those dealing with travel, budget training and personnel matters. Various affirmative action plans, correspondence with BBG officials and others, such as correspondence with other agencies and individuals requesting information. Chron files and historical files outlining a variety of actions taken by the office and others in the area of EEO and Civil Rights. Computer generated lists of employees, and statistical studies of various parts of the BBG. Medical records of applicants and employees with disabling conditions and compliance records containing information about the EEO status of BBG grantee organizations and action taken on their applications.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>29 CFR Parts 1613 et seq.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To enable the office to carry out activities designed to recruit, hire, train, promote, assign and otherwise provide equal employment opportunity to employees of and applicants for employment in the BBG Compliance Review files containing information about grant applicant's implementation of Titles VI, VII, and IX of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, as amended, the Rehabilitation Act of 1974, as amended, and the Age Discrimination in Employment Act, as amended; to enable the office to monitor and implement Federal regulations as stipulated in these statutes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system is made available on a need-to-know basis to Personnel Officers of the BBG as may be required in the performance of their duties. It may also be provided to Congressional Committees, individual Members of Congress, the White House, the Department of Justice, the Office of Personnel Management, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and to other government entities that have statutory or other lawful authority to maintain such information. Compliance Review information may also be released to grant applicants on request. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>The system is partially automated. Some information is also maintained on discs, and some in paper folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name and types of activities, i.e., affirmative action plans, travel, training, etc.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Authorized users: OCR staff members and contract EEO investigators who are authorized to have access to the system of records in the performance of their duties.</p><p>2. Physical safeguards: Bar-locked safes, files contained in secure building requiring appropriate identification to enter.</p><p>3. Procedural safeguards: Separate maintenance of tables linking codes, data encryption, security software providing restricted commands programs, employee training, procedures for recording and reporting security violations, computer log-on codes. Contract investigator has security clearance and is supervised by an OCR staff member.</p><p>4. Implementation guidelines: BBG Manual of Operations and Administration (MOA) V-A (Domestic) Section 560-565.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Civil Rights, Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 301 4th Street, SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting contents and appealing determinations by the individual concerned appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondence, memos of conversations, BBG records of personnel actions, published biographical sources.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-18</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">OCR--Office of Civil Rights (Minority Groups).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Civil Rights, Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 301 4th St, SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of BBG and some applicants for employment in BBG.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are categorized by name, race, sex, national origin, age, grade or wage level. Handicap or lack thereof and may contain medical records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>29 CFR 1613.301; 29 CFR 1613.302.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To compile statistical records of women, minorities, and individuals with disabling conditions who are considered for employment, hired, promoted, assigned, training, awarded, disciplined, and/or separated or who resign from the BBG, to measure EEO progress and to identify problems.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is made available on a need-to-know basis to personnel of the BBG as may be required in the performance of their official duties, including implementing affirmative action plans and in processing complaints of discrimination. Information is not normally available to individuals or agencies outside the BBG, but records may be released to other government agencies having a statutory or other lawful authority to maintain such information. The principal users of this information outside of BBG are the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Office of Personnel Management, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and Congress. Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper and computer records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, race, sex, age, handicap, national origin, agency location, date of entry or separation, date of last promotion, grade or wage level.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Authorized users: Members of the OCR staff and certain authorized members of the Office of Personnel, Policy and Services staff.</p><p>2. Physical safeguards: Bar-locked safes, security guard patrol (off-duty hours); access to building limited to individuals with appropriate identification.</p><p>3. Procedural safeguards: Computer passwords; Separate maintenance of tables linking codes, data encryption, security software providing restricted commands programs, employee training, procedures for recording and reporting security violations. Contractors are supervised by employees with a security clearance.</p><p>4. Implementation guidelines: BBG Manual of Operations and Administration (MOA) V-A (Domestic) Section 560-565. The source of security standards is 29 CFR 1613.301 et seq.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Civil Rights, Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 301 4th Street, SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver's license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document. Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting contents and appealing determinations by the individual concerned appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From the employee or applicant concerned, BBG personnel data, visual inspection of the employee or application.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Not applicable.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="bbg19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">P/K--Office of External Affairs (Clearance Files for Speaking, Teaching and Writing, and Approval Files for Outside Employment).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Office of External Affairs, Room 3131, 330 Independence Ave, SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees of the IBB, the Voice of America, the Office of Cuba Broadcasting (Radio and Television Marti), WORLDNET Television, Office of engineering and Technical Operations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
  <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondence addressed to the Director of the Office of External Affairs requesting clearance for outside speaking, teaching, or writing, or requesting approval for outside employment. Correspondence from office, language service, and division directors to the Director of the Office of External Affairs regarding employees' requests for clearance or approval. Correspondence from the Office of External Affairs to and from the BBG Office of the General Counsel and Ethics Officer. Responses to IBB and BBG employees on clearance or approval from the Director of the Office of External Affairs.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Records Act of 1950, as amended, 44 U.S.C. 3101-3167, Records Disposal Act of 1943, as amended, 44 U.S.C. 3301-3314.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are routinely used by the Director of the Office of External Affairs or his/her delegate to determine record of current or previous requests for clearance and/or approval and the disposition of those requests. Files may be used by representatives of the Labor Relations offices in the course of investigations. Also see General Routine Uses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper and computer records are stored in a locked office within the Office of External Affairs.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept in hard copy or computer chronologically by year of the request. A small number of files are kept by individual identifier.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>General access to files is permitted only to administrative staffs and other top management officials having a need-to-know such information in the normal performance of their duties. Computer records are protected by password access for authorized users. All records are located within secure building with access restricted to individuals showing appropriate identification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are retained in the Office of External Affairs, and are used periodically for reference purposes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of External Affairs, International Broadcasting Bureau (IBB), Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to: FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, BBG, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20237. Individuals' requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>A. Full legal name;
</p><p>B. Date of Birth;
</p><p>C. Social Security Number;
</p><p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and
</p><p>E. Signature.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the General Counsel, 330 Independence Ave, SW., Suite 3349, Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The rules for access and for contesting contents and appealing determinations by the individual concerning appeal are found in CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is received from employees seeking advance clearance for outside speaking, teaching or writing on matters of official concern, or approval for outside employment; from supervisors of such employees; from the Office of the General Counsel; from the IBB Designated Ethics Officer, and from the Director of the Office of External Affairs in making the determination on requests for clearance and/or approval.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="bbg20" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-20</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">M/SEC-Office of Security (Personal Identity Verification (PIV) System).</subsection>

<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20237.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who require regular, ongoing access to BBG facilities, information technology systems, or information classified in the interest of national security, including applicants for employment or contracts, federal employees, contractors, and individuals formerly in any of these positions. The system also includes individuals accused of security violations or found in violation. The system also includes individuals authorized to perform or use services provided in agency facilities (<i>e.g.,</i> Fitness Center, Cafeteria, or <i>etc.</i>)
</p><p>The system does not apply to occasional visitors or short-term guests to whom BBG will issue temporary identification and credentials.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records maintained on individuals issued credentials by BBG include the following data fields: Full name; Social Security number; date of birth; signature; image (photograph); fingerprints; hair color; eye color; height; weight; organization/office of assignment; company name; telephone number; copy of background investigation form; PIV card issue and expiration dates; personal identification number (PIN); results of background investigation; PIV request form; PIV security sponsor approval signature; PIV card serial number; copies of documents used to verify identification or information derived from those documents such as document title, document issuing authority, document number, document expiration date, document other information); computer system user name; user access and permission rights, authentication certificates; and digital signature information</p><p>Records maintained on card holders entering BBG facilities or using BBG systems include: Name, PIV Card serial number; date, time, and location of entry and exit; company name; contain in the record but not on the PIV card and expiration date; digital signature information; computer networks/applications/data accessed.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301; Federal Information Security Act (Pub. L. 104-106, sec. 5113); Electronic Government Act (Pub. L. 104-347, sec. 203); the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995 (44 U.S.C. 3501); and the Government Paperwork Elimination Act (Pub. L. 105-277, 44 U.S.C. 3504); Homeland Security Presidential Directive (HSPD) 12, Policy for a Common Identification Standard for Federal Employees and Contractors, August 27, 2004; Federal Property and Administrative Act of 1949, as amended.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose">xhtmlContent><xhtmlContent><p><i>The primary purposes of the system are:</i> (a) To ensure the safety and security of BBG facilities, systems, or information, and our occupants and users; (b) To verify that all persons entering federal facilities, using federal information resources, or accessing classified information are authorized to do so; (c) To track and control PIV cards issued to persons entering and exiting the facilities, using systems, or accessing classified information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) the Statement of General Routine Uses Applicable to All BBG System of Records Files, and:
</p><p>&#149; <i>To a court or adjudicative body in a proceeding when:</i> (a) The agency or any component thereof; (b) any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; (c) any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where agency or the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or (d) the United States Government, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and by careful review, the agency determines that the records are both relevant and necessary to the litigation and the use of such records is therefore deemed by the agency to be for a purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which the agency collected the records</p><p>&#149; Except as noted on Forms SF 85, 85-P, and 86, when a record on its face, or in conjunction with other records, indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, disclosure may be made to the appropriate public authority, whether Federal, foreign, State, local, or tribal, or otherwise, responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, if the information disclosed is relevant to any enforcement, regulatory, investigative or prosecutorial responsibility of the receiving entity</p><p>&#149; To a Federal State, or local agency, or other appropriate entities or individuals, or through established liaison channels to selected foreign governments, in order to enable an intelligence agency to carry out its responsibilities under the National Security Act of 1947 as amended, the CIA Act of 1949 as amended, Executive Order 12333 or any successor order, applicable national security directives, or classified implementing procedures approved by the Attorney General and promulgated pursuant to such statutes, orders or directives</p><p>&#149; To notify another federal agency when, or verify whether, a PIV card is no longer valid.</p>
<p>DISCLOSURE TO CONSUMER REPORTING AGENCIES:
</p><p>Privacy Act information may be reported to consumer reporting agencies pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in electronic media or in paper files in a secured Federal facility and a lockable storage area.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by name, Social Security number, other ID number, PIV card serial number, image (photograph), and fingerprint.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are kept in a controlled area, which uses electronic high security lock that is armed with motion detector. The motion detector is connected to a guard station that is manned on a constant basis. The controlled area is equipped with locked cabinets within a Security File Room. Access to paper records is restricted to individuals whose role requires use of the records. The computer servers in which records are stored are located in facilities that are secured by alarm systems and off-master key access. The computer servers themselves are password-protected. Access by individuals working at guard stations is password-protected; each person granted access to the system at guard stations must be individually authorized to use the system. A Privacy Act Warning Notice appears on the monitor screen when records containing information on individuals are first displayed. Data exchanged between the servers and the client PCs at the guard stations and badging office is encrypted. Backup tapes are stored in a locked and controlled room in a secure, off-site location</p><p>An audit trail is maintained and reviewed periodically to identify unauthorized access. Persons given roles in the PIV process must complete training specific to their roles to ensure they are knowledgeable about how to protect personally identifiable information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to GRS 18, Item 22a records used to initiate background investigations; register and enroll individuals; manage the PIV card lifecycle; and, verify, authenticate and revoke PIV cardholder access to Federal resources are destroyed upon notification of death or not later than 5 years after separation or transfer of employee or no later than 5 years after contract relationship expires, whichever is applicable</p><p>Pursuant to GRS 11, Item PIV cards are destroyed three months after they are returned to the issuing office. Pursuant to GRS 11, Item 4a identification credentials are destroyed by cross-cut shredding no later than 90 days after deactivation</p><p>Pursuant to GRS 18, Item 17 registers or logs used to record names of outside contractors, service personnel, visitors, employees admitted to areas, and reports on automobiles and passengers for areas under maximum security are destroyed five years after final entry or five years after date of document, as appropriate</p><p>Other documents pursuant to GRS 18, Item 17b are destroyed two years after final entry or two years after date of document, as appropriate.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Michael Lawrence, Director of Security (DAA/SAO), International Broadcasting Bureau, 330 C Street, SW., Room 4117, Washington, DC 20237, (202) 382-7779, <i>mtlawren@bbg.gov.</i></p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking notification of and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may submit a request in writing to the BBG FOIA Office, whose contact information can be found at <i>http://www.bbg.gov/reports/foia</i>/. If an individual believes more than one component maintains Privacy Act records concerning him or her, the individual may submit the request to the Chief FOIA Officer, Broadcasting Board of Governors, 330 Independence Avenue, SW., Room 3349, Washington, DC 20237</p><p>When seeking records about yourself from this system of records or any other Agency system of records your request must conform with the Privacy Act regulations set forth in 6 CFR part 5. You must first verify your identity, meaning that you must provide your full name, current address and date and place of birth. You must sign your request, and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty or perjury as a substitute for notarization. While no specific form is required, you may obtain forms for this purpose from the BBG FOIA Office at the address above or by calling 202-203-4550</p><p>In addition to the requirements above, in your request you should:
</p><p>--Provide an explanation of why you believe the Agency would have information about you;
</p><p>--Identify which component(s) of the Agency you believe may have the information about you;
</p><p>--Specify when you believe the records would have been created;
</p><p>--Provide any other information that will help the FOIA staff determine which BBG component agency may have responsive records;
</p><p>--If your request is seeking records pertaining to another living individual, you must include a statement from that individual certifying his/her agreement for you to access his/her records</p><p>Without this bulleted information the component(s) will not be able to conduct an effective search, and your request may be denied due to lack of specificity or lack of compliance with applicable regulations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>
See "Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See "Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee, contractor, or applicant; sponsoring agency; former sponsoring agency; other federal agencies; contract employer; former employer.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="bbg21" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-21</systemNumber><subsection type="systemName">Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG) Financial and Acquisition Management System.

</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>BBG Financial and Acquisition Management System records and files are maintained in the Phoenix Data Center (PDC), with records also stored at the Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), 330 Independence Avenue, SW, Washington, DC 20237.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>BBG vendors/contractors, grant recipients, employees, interns, students, consultants, experts, and others.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p><i>Business related information</i> </p>
<p>These records contain information about vendors/contractors and grant recipients, and may include the following elements:  names including name of company, titles, points of contact information, telephone numbers, fax numbers, addresses, email addresses, vendor or record numbers (system unique identifiers), Tax Identification Numbers (TIN), Social Security Numbers (SSN), Dun &amp; Bradstreet (D&amp;B) Data Universal Numbering System (DUNS) and DUNS Plus 4 numbers, Commercial and Government Entity (CAGE) codes, or contract, agreement, and debarment information.</p>

<p>Information related to employees, interns, students, consultants, experts, and others </p>
<p>These records contain information about BBG employees, interns, students, consultants, experts, and others that are in connection with BBG activities.  The records may include the following elements:  names, titles, points of contact, telephone numbers, fax numbers, addresses, email addresses, record numbers (system unique identifiers), TINs, SSNs, and travel information. </p>

<p><i>Financial related information</i> </p>
<p>May be associated with the categories of records listed above that are within this system and may include the following elements:  financial institution names, lockbox numbers, routing transit numbers, account numbers, account types, debts (e.g., unpaid bills/invoices, overpayments, etc.), and remittance addresses.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>31 U.S.C. 3501, et seq., 31 U.S.C. 7701(c), 41 CFR parts 300-304, 2 CFR 25.215, and Federal Acquisition Regulation, 48 CFR.  Where the employee identification number is the social security number, collection of this information is authorized by Executive Order 9397 as amended by Executive Order 13478.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Serves as the BBG’s core financial and acquisitions management system that integrates program, budgetary, financial, travel, and procurement information.  Records are collected to ensure that agency financial and procurement activities are in conformance with laws, existing rules and regulations, good business practices, and for the maintenance of information at the proper account and/or organizational level for agency operations.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>

<p><i>Disclosure in response to a compromise of information</i></p>
<p>To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the BBG has determined that, as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the BBG or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the BBG’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.  Also see Statement of General Routine Uses.</p>

<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:  </p>
<p>Disclosures may be made from this system to consumer reporting agencies in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12) and 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p> Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in electronic and paper format.  Electronic records are stored in secure computerized databases and/or on computer disc.  Paper records and records on computer disc are stored in locked rooms and/or file cabinets.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrievable by the following, including but not limited to, record and system unique identifiers, DUNS and/or DUNS Plus 4 numbers, CAGE codes, TINs (including SSN), names, titles, addresses, or by any of the elements listed above within the categories of records within this system.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are safeguarded in a secured environment.  Buildings where records are stored have security cameras and 24-hour security guard service.  The records are maintained in limited access areas during duty hours and in locked file cabinets and/or locked offices or file rooms at all other times.  Access is limited to those personnel who require access to the records in the performance of their agency duties.  Access to electronic records is controlled through the use of access codes and/or information technology security.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>These records will be maintained in accordance with the General Records Schedule.  After which, they will be retired or destroyed in accordance with and as approved by the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA).</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Chief Financial Officer</p>
<p>Office of the Chief Financial Officer</p>
<p>Broadcasting Board of Governors</p>
<p>330 Independence Avenue, SW</p>
<p>Washington, DC 20237</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who want to know whether this system of records contains information about them, or who want access to their records, or who want to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to:  FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG), Suite 3349, 330 Independence Ave., SW, Washington, DC 20237.  Individuals’ requests should contain the name and address of the system manager (listed above) and the following information to enable their records to be located and identified:</p>

<p>A. Full legal name;</p>
<p>B. Date of Birth;</p>
<p>C. Social Security Number;</p>
<p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and</p>
<p>E. Signature.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above).  Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide adequate identification, such as driver’s license, employee identification card, and/or other identifying document.  Additional identification procedures may be required in some instances.  To request a file other than your own, you must have a notarized, signed statement giving you express permission to access the file from the individual to whom the file pertains.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The BBG’s rules for access and for contesting contents and appealing determinations by the individual concerned appear at 22 CFR part 505.  The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous or untimely.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>From individuals (e.g., vendors/contractors, employees, etc.) that are covered within this system as described within the categories of records listed above, and through agency personnel who obtain the information through agency duties.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="bbg22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Time and Attendance and Leave Records System.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Time and attendance reports, leave records, and service history files are located at 330 Independence Avenue SW, Washington, DC  20237, as well a FedRAMP-certified secure government cloud facility in Reston, Virginia.</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Past and present BBG employees in the Civil Service and the Foreign Service, excluding Foreign Service Nationals and Personal Services Contractors.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>These records include time and attendance and leave records, including number and type of hours worked (e.g., regular, overtime, night differential, or Sunday differential), compensatory time earned and used, credit hours earned and used under alternative work schedules, leave requests, and leave balances.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>5 U.S.C. 301; 5 U.S.C. Chapter 53; 5 U.S.C. Chapter 55; 5 U.S.C. Chapter 61; 5 U.S.C. Chapter 63; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purpose of this system is to track time worked and leave for pay administration, leave administration, reporting, and compliance functions.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>

<p>The primary uses of the records are to manage the BBG’s fiscal operations for payroll, time and attendance, leave, insurance, tax, retirement, qualifications, and benefits functions. In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), all or a portion of the records contained in this system of records may be disclosed outside BBG as a routine use as follows:</p>

<p>(1) A record from this system may be disclosed to Federal entities that provide payroll processing services to BBG. These services may include the issuance of salary payments to employees and distribution of wages and the distribution of allotments and deductions to financial and other institutions, many of which are through electronic funds transfer.</p>

<p>(2) A record from this system may be disclosed to other Federal entities, including the Department of Treasury and the Office of Personnel Management, for purposes of: processing payroll payments; collecting withheld taxes; managing personnel; processing benefits; establishing and maintaining records related to payroll, retirement, and benefits; processing worker’s compensation claims; conducting personnel research; and producing statistics or analytical studies and reports. </p>

<p>(3) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (a) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the BBG has determined that, as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the BBG or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the BBG’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>

<p>(4) A record from this system may be also be disclosed in accordance with the Statement of General Routine Uses Applicable to All BBG Systems of Records, originally published at 69 FR 46478, Aug. 3, 2004.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in electronic and paper format.  Electronic records are stored in secure computerized databases.  Paper records are stored in locked rooms and/or file cabinets.  </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>These records may be retrieved by identifiers including, but not limited to, individual’s name, social security number or employee number, and date of birth, or organizational code.  </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Access to records is limited to authorized BBG employees having an official use or need for the information. All records are stored within secure buildings with access granted only to individuals with appropriate identification. All paper records are maintained in locked offices and/or file cabinets during non-duty hours and are protected by office personnel when being used during duty hours. All users of personal information in connection with the performance of their jobs protect information from public view and from unauthorized personnel entering an unsupervised office.</p>

<p>Technical security measures within the electronic time and attendance system include: restrictions on computer access to authorized individuals; required use of strong, frequently changed passwords; use of encryption for certain data types and transfers; and regular review of security procedures and best practices to enhance security. Physical measures include restrictions on building access to authorized individuals and maintenance of records in lockable offices and filing cabinets. Only specifically authorized individuals may access the electronic time and attendance computer system, and unique User IDs and passwords are required.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Agency time and attendance records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 2.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Payroll Manager, Office of the Chief Financial Officer and Director, Office of Human Resources, BBG - Broadcasting Board of Governors, International Broadcasting Bureau, 330 Independence Avenue SW, Washington, DC 20237.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>A. Full legal name;</p>
<p>B. Date of Birth;</p>
<p>C. Social Security Number or employee identification number;</p>
<p>D. Last employing organization (include duty station location) and the approximate dates of employment or contact; and</p>
<p>E. Signature.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should follow the Notification Procedures (listed above). Individuals requesting access will also be required to provide identification, such as a driver's license, employee identification card, or other appropriate identifying document. A notarized signature is required if the request is made by written correspondence. To request a record other than your own, you must have a signed and notarized statement from the individual to whom the record pertains granting you express permission to access their record.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The BBG's rules for access and for contesting record contents and appealing determinations appear in 22 CFR Part 505. The right to contest records is limited to information that is incomplete, irrelevant, erroneous, or untimely.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The individual about whom the record is maintained, supervisors, timekeepers, and official personnel records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>



    <section id=" BGFRS-38" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/ BGFRS-38</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Transportation Subsidy Records </p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</p>
                <p>20th Street and Constitution Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20551.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Craig Delaney, Sr. Manager, Accounting,  Division of Financial Management, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, 20th Street and Constitution Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20551, (202) 452-2041, or craig.j.delaney@frb.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Sections 10 and 11 of the Federal Reserve Act (12 USC 244 and 248).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are collected and maintained by the Board in order to administer the Board’s transportation subsidy program.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Past and present employees who apply for a transportation subsidy.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Applications submitted by employees for transportation subsidies, which may include name, employee ID number, home address, current commuting pattern and estimated commuting cost, and other information related to carrying out activities under the transportation subsidy program.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information is provided by the employee to whom the record pertains.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>General routine uses A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, and J apply to this system. These general routine uses are located at https://www.federalreserve.gov/files/SORN-page-general-routine-uses-of-board-systems-of-records.pdf and are published in the Federal Register at 83 FR 43872 at 43873-74 (August 28, 2018).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on a secure server with access limited to staff with a need to know.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records can be retrieved by employee name or ID number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Transportation subsidy records are destroyed two years after the employee revalidates their participation or no longer participates in the program.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system has the ability to track individual user actions within the system. The audit and accountability controls are based on NIST and Board standards, which, in turn, are based on applicable laws and regulations. The controls assist in detecting security violations and performance or other issues in the system. Access to the system is restricted to authorized users who require access for official business purposes. Users are classified into different roles and common access and usage rights are established for each role. User roles are used to delineate between the different types of access requirements such that users are restricted to data that is required in the performance of their duties. Periodic assessments and reviews are conducted to determine whether users still require access, have the appropriate role, and whether there have been any unauthorized changes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Privacy Act allows individuals the right to access records maintained about them in a Board system of records. Your request for access must: (1) contain a statement that the request is made pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974; (2) provide either the name of the Board system of records expected to contain the record requested or a concise description of the system of records; (3) provide the information necessary to verify your identity; and (4) provide any other information that may assist in the rapid identification of the record you seek.</p>
                <p>Current or former Board employees may make a request for access by contacting the Board office that maintains the record. The Board handles all Privacy Act requests as both a Privacy Act request and as a Freedom of Information Act request. The Board does not charge fees to a requestor seeking to access or amend his/her Privacy Act records.</p>
                <p>You may submit your Privacy Act request to the—</p>
                <p>Secretary of the Board</p>
                <p>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</p>
                <p>20th Street and Constitution Avenue NW</p>
                <p>Washington, DC 20551</p>
                <p>You may also submit your Privacy Act request electronically through the Board’s FOIA "Electronic Request Form" located here: https://www.federalreserve.gov/secure/forms/efoiaform.aspx.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Privacy Act allows individuals to seek amendment of information that is erroneous, irrelevant, untimely, or incomplete and is maintained in a system of records that pertains to them. To request an amendment to your record, you should clearly mark the request as a "Privacy Act Amendment Request." You have the burden of proof for demonstrating the appropriateness of the requested amendment and you must provide relevant and convincing evidence in support of your request.</p>
                <p>Your request for amendment must: (1) provide the name of the specific Board system of records containing the record you seek to amend; (2) identify the specific portion of the record you seek to amend; (3) describe the nature of and reasons for each requested amendment; (4) explain why you believe the record is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete; and (5) unless you have already done so in a related Privacy Act request for access or amendment, provide the necessary information to verify your identity.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as "Access procedures" above. You may also follow this procedure in order to request an accounting of previous disclosures of records pertaining to you as provided for by 5 U.S.C. 552a(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This SORN was previously published in the Federal Register at 73 FR 54595 at 54977 (September 22, 2008). The SORN was amended to incorporate two new routine uses required by OMB at 83 FR 43872 (August 28, 2018).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>




    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">

<regulationsTitle number="22">
<heading> Foreign Relations </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="V">
<heading>Broadcasting Board of Governors </heading>
<regulationsPart number="505">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT REGULATION </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec. 
</p>
<p>505.1 Purpose and scope. 
</p>
<p>505.2 Definitions. 
</p>
<p>505.3 Procedures for requests. 
</p>
<p>505.4 Requirements and identification for making requests. 
</p>
<p>505.5 Disclosure of information. 
</p>
<p>505.6 Medical records. 
</p>
<p>505.7 Correction or amendment of record. 
</p>
<p>505.8 Agency review of requests for changes. 
</p>
<p>505.9 Review of adverse agency determination. 
</p>
<p>505.10 Disclosure to third parties. 
</p>
<p>505.11 Fees. 
</p>
<p>505.12 Civil remedies and criminal penalties. 
</p>
<p>505.13 General exemptions (Subsection (j)). 
</p>
<p>505.14 Specific exemptions (Subsection (k)). 
</p>
<p>505.15 Exempt systems of records used.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Pub. L. 93-579, 88 Stat. 1897; 5 U.S.C. 552a. 
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 67 FR 8875, Feb. 27, 2002, unless otherwise noted.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.1 
 Purpose and scope. 
</b></p>
<p>The Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG) will protect individuals? privacy from misuses of their records, and grant individuals access to records concerning them which are maintained by the Agency?s domestic and overseas offices, consistent with the provisions of Public Law 93-579, 88 Stat. 1897; 5 U.S.C. 552a, the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended. The Agency has also established procedures to permit individuals to amend incorrect records, to limit the disclosure of personal information to third parties, and to limit the number of sources of personal information. The Agency has also established internal rules restricting requirements of individuals to provide social security account numbers. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.2 
 Definitions. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Access Appeal Committee (AAC).</i> The body established by and responsible to the Broadcasting Board for reviewing appeals made by individuals to amend records held by the Agency. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Agency, BBG, our, we</i> or <i>us.</i> The BBG, its offices, divisions, branches and its worldwide operations. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Amend.</i> To make a correction to or expunge any portion of a record about an individual which that individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely or complete. 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Individual</i> or <i>you.</i> A citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence. 
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Maintain.</i> Collect, use, store, disseminate or any combination of these record keeping functions; exercise of control over and hence responsibility and accountability for systems of records. 
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Record.</i> Any information maintained by the Agency about an individual that can be reproduced, including finger or voice prints and photographs, and which is retrieved by that particular individual?s name or personal identifier, such as a social security number. 
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Routine use.</i> With respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose, which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected. The common ordinary purposes for which records are used and all of the proper and necessary uses even if any such uses occur infrequently. 
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Statistical record.</i> A record in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual, except as provided in 12 U.S.C.8. 
</p>
<p>(i) <i>System of records.</i> A group of records under the maintenance and control of the Agency from which information is retrieved by the name or personal identifier of the individual. 
</p>
<p>(j) <i>Personnel record.</i> Any information about an individual that is maintained in a system of records by the Agency that is needed for personnel management or processes such as staffing, employee development, retirement, grievances and appeals. 
</p>
<p>(k) <i>Worldwide Operations.</i> Any of the foreign service establishments of the Agency. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.3 
 Procedures for requests. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) The agency will consider all written requests received from an individual for records pertaining to herself/himself as a request made under the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552a) whether or not the individual specifically cites the Privacy Act when making the request. 
</p>
<p>(b) All requests under the Privacy Act should be directed to the FOIA/Privacy Act Office, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Avenue, SW, Washington, DC 20237, which will coordinate the search of all systems of records specified in the request. Requests should state name, date of birth, and social security number. 
</p>
<p>(c) Requests directed to any of the Agency?s worldwide establishments which involve routine unclassified, administrative and personnel records available only at those establishments may be released to the individual by the establishment if it determines that such a release is authorized by the Privacy Act. All other requests shall be submitted by the establishment to the FOIA/Privacy Act Office, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Avenue, SW, Washington, DC 20237, and the individual shall be so notified of this section in writing, when possible. 
</p>
<p>(d) In those instances where an individual requests records pertaining to herself/himself, as well as records pertaining to another individual, group or some other category of the Agency?s records, only that portion of the request which pertains to records concerning the individual will be treated as a Privacy Act request. The remaining portions of such a request will be processed as a Freedom of Information Act request and sent to the office noted in paragraph (b) of this section. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.4 
 Requirements and identification for making requests. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) When you seek access to Agency records, you may present your written request, fax it to (202) 260-4394 or mail it to the FOIA/Privacy Act Office, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Avenue, SW, Washington, DC 20237. The FOIA/Privacy Act Office may be visited between the hours of 9 a.m. and 3 p.m., Monday through Friday, except for legal holidays. 
</p>
<p>(b) When you seek access to Agency records, you will be requested to present identification. You must state your full name, date of birth and social security number. You must also include your present mailing address and zip code, and if possible, a telephone number. 
</p>
<p>(c) When signing a statement confirming your identity, you should understand that knowingly and willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another person under false pretenses is punishable by a fine of up to $5,000. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.5 
 Disclosure of information. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) In order to locate the system of records that you believe may contain information about you, you should first obtain a copy of the Agency?s Notice of Systems of Records. By identifying a particular record system and by furnishing all the identifying information requested by that record system, it would enable us to more easily locate those records which pertain to you. At a minimum, any request should include the information specified in Sec. 505.4(b). 
</p>
<p>(b) In certain circumstances, it may be necessary for us to request additional information from you to ensure that the retrieved record does, in fact, pertain to you. 
</p>
<p>(c) All requests for information on whether or not the Agency?s systems of records contain information about you will be acknowledged within 20 working days of receipt of that request. The requested records will be provided as soon as possible thereafter. 
</p>
<p>(d) If the Agency determines that the substance of the requested record is exceptionally sensitive, we will require you to furnish a signed, notarized statement that you are in fact the person named in the file before granting access to the records. 
</p>
<p>(e) Original records will not be furnished subject to and in accordance with fees established in &#167; 505.11. 
</p>
<p>(f) Denial of access to records: 
</p>
<p>(1) The requirements of this section do not entitle you access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding. 
</p>
<p>(2) Under the Privacy Act, we are not required to permit access to records if the information is not retrievable by your name or other personal identifier; those requests will be processed as Freedom of Information Act requests. 
</p>
<p>(3) We may deny you access to a record, or portion thereof, if following a review it is determined that the record or portion falls within a system of records that is exempt from disclosure according to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j) and 552a(k). See &#167;&#167; 505.13 and 505.14 for a listing of general and specific exemptions. 
</p>
<p>(4) The decision to deny access to a record or a portion of the record is made by the Agency?s Privacy Act Officer. The denial letter will advise you of your right to appeal the denial (See &#167; 505.9 on Access Appeal Committee?s review). 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.6 
 Medical records. 
</b></p>
<p>If, in the judgment of the Agency, the release of medical information to you could have an adverse effect, the Agency will arrange an acceptable alternative to granting access of such records directly to you. This normally involves the release of the information to a doctor named by you. However, this special procedure provision does not in any way limit your absolute right to receive a complete copy of your medical record. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.7 
 Correction or amendment of record. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) You have the right to request that we amend a record pertaining to you which you believe is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete. At the time we grant access to a record, we will furnish guidelines for you to request amendment to the record. 
</p>
<p>(b) Requests for amendments to records must be in writing and mailed or delivered to the FOIA/Privacy Act Officer, FOIA/Privacy Act Office, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Avenue, SW, Washington, DC 20237, who will coordinate the review of the request to amend the record with the appropriate office(s). Such requests must contain, at a minimum, identifying information needed to locate the record, a brief description of the item or items of information to be amended, and the reason for the requested change. The requester should submit as much documentation, arguments or other data as seems warranted to support the request for amendment. 
</p>
<p>(c) We will review all requests for amendments to records within 20 working days of receipt of the request and either make the changes or inform you of our refusal to do so and the reasons. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.8 
 Agency review of requests for changes. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) In reviewing a record in response to a request to amend or correct a file, we will incorporate the criteria of accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness of the record in the review. 
</p>
<p>(b) If we agree with you to amend your records, we will: 
</p>
<p>(1) Advise you in writing; 
</p>
<p>(2) Correct the record accordingly; 
</p>
<p>(3) And, to the extent that an accounting of disclosure was maintained, advise all previous recipients of the record of the corrections. 
</p>
<p>(c) If we disagree with all or any portion of your request to amend a record, we will: 
</p>
<p>(1) Advise you of the reasons for the determination; and 
</p>
<p>(2) Inform you of your right to further review (see Sec. 505.9). 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.9
 Review of adverse agency determination. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) When we determine to deny a request to amend a record, or portion of the record, you may request further review by the Agency?s Access Appeal Committee. The written request for review should be mailed to the Chairperson, Access Appeal Committee, FOIA/Privacy Act Office, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20237. The letter should include any documentation, information or statement, which substantiates your request for review. 
</p>
<p>(b) The Agency?s Access Appeal Committee will review the Agency?s initial denial to amend the record and your documentation supporting amendment, within 30 working days. If additional time is required, you will be notified in writing of the reasons for the delay and the approximate date when the review is expected to be completed. Upon completion of the review, the Chairperson will notify you of the results. 
</p>
<p>(c) If the Committee upholds the Agency?s denial to amend the record, the Chairperson will advise you of: 
</p>
<p>(1) The reasons for our refusal to amend the record; 
</p>
<p>(2) Your right and the procedure to add to the file a concise statement supporting your disagreement with the decision of the Agency; and 
</p>
<p>(3) Your right to seek judicial review of the Agency?s refusal to amend the file. 
</p>
<p>(d) When you file a statement disagreeing with our refusal to amend a record, we will clearly annotate the record so that the fact that the record is disputed is apparent to anyone who may subsequently have access to, use of, or reason to disclose the file. If information is disclosed regarding the area of dispute, we will provide a copy of your statement in the disclosure. Any statement, which may be included by the Agency regarding the dispute, will be limited to the reasons given to you for not amending the record. Copies of our statement shall be treated as part of your record, but will not be subject to amendment by you under these regulations. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.10
 Disclosure to third parties. 
</b></p>
<p>We will not disclose any information about you to any person or another agency without your prior consent, except as provided for in the following paragraphs: 
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Medical records.</i> May be disclosed to a doctor or other medical practitioner, named by you, as prescribed in Sec. 505.6. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Accompanying individual.</i> When you are accompanied by any other person, we will require that you sign a statement granting consent to the disclosure of the contents of your record to that person. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Designees.</i> If a person requests another person?s file, he or she must present a signed statement from the person of record that authorizes and consents to the release of the file to the designated individual. 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Guardians.</i> Parents or legal guardians) of dependent minors or of an individual who has been declared by a court to be incompetent due to physical, mental or age incapacity, may act for and on behalf of the individual on whom the Agency maintains records. 
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Other disclosures.</i> A record may be disclosed without a request by or written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains if such disclosure conditions are authorized in accordance, with 5 U.S.C. 552a(b). These conditions are: 
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Disclosure within the Agency.</i> This condition is based upon a ?need-to-know? concept, which recognizes that Agency personnel may require access to discharge their duties. 
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Disclosure to the public.</i> No consent by an individual is necessary if the record is required to be released under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 5 U.S.C. 552. The record may be exempt, however, under one of the nine exemptions of the FOIA. 
</p>
<p>(3) <i>Disclosure for a routine use.</i> No consent by an individual is necessary if the condition is necessary for a ?routine use? as defined in Sec. 505.2(g). Information may also be released to other government agencies, that have statutory or other lawful authority to maintain such information. 
</p>
<p>(4) <i>Disclosure to the Bureau of the Census.</i> For purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity. Title 13 U.S.C. Section 8 limits the uses of these records and also makes them immune from compulsory disclosure. 
</p>
<p>(5) <i>Disclosure for statistical research and reporting.</i> The Agency will provide the statistical information requested only after all names and personal identifiers have been deleted from the records. 
</p>
<p>(6) <i>Disclosure to the National Archives.</i> For the preservation of records of historical value, according to 44 U.S.C. 2103. 
</p>
<p>(7) <i>Disclosure for law enforcement purposes.</i> Upon receipt of a written request by another Federal agency or a state or local government describing the law enforcement purpose for which a record is required, and specifying the particular record. Blanket requests for all records pertaining to an individual are not permitted under the Privacy Act. 
</p>
<p>(8) <i>Disclosure under emergency circumstances.</i> For the safety or health of an individual (e.g., medical records on a patient undergoing emergency treatment). 
</p>
<p>(9) <i>Disclosure to the Congress.</i> For matters within the jurisdiction of any House or Senate committee or subcommittee, and/or joint committee or subcommittee, but only when requested in writing from the Chairman of the committee or subcommittee. 
</p>
<p>(10) <i>Disclosure to the General Accounting Office (GAO).</i> For matters within the jurisdiction of the duties of the GAO?s Comptroller General. 
</p>
<p>(11) <i>Disclosure according to court order.</i> According to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction. This does not include a subpoena for records requested by counsel and issued by a clerk of court. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.11
 Fees. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) The first copy of any Agency record about you will be provided free of charge. A fee of $0.15 per page will be charged for any additional copies requested by you. 
</p>
<p>(b) Checks or money orders should be made payable to the United States Treasurer and mailed to the FOIA/Privacy Act Office, Office of the General Counsel, Broadcasting Board of Governors, Suite 3349, 330 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20237. The Agency will not accept cash. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.12
 Civil remedies and criminal penalties. 
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Grounds for court action.</i> You will have a remedy in the Federal District Court under the following circumstances: 
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Denial of access.</i> You may challenge our decision to deny you access to records to which you consider yourself entitled. 
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Refusal to amend a record.</i> Under the conditions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(g), you may seek judicial review of the Agency?s refusal to amend a record. 
</p>
<p>(3) <i>Failure to maintain a record accurately.</i> You may bring suit against the Agency for any alleged intentional and willful failure to maintain a record accurately, if it can be shown that you were subjected to an adverse action resulting in the denial of aright, benefit, entitlement or employment you could reasonably have been expected to be granted if the record had not been deficient. 
</p>
<p>(4) <i>Other failures to comply with the Act.</i> You may bring an action for any alleged failure by the Agency to comply with the requirements of the Act or failure to comply with any rule published by the Agency to implement the Act provided it can be shown that: 
</p>
<p>(i) The action was intentional or willful; 
</p>
<p>(ii) The Agency?s action adversely affected you; and 
</p>
<p>(iii) The adverse action was caused by the Agency?s actions. 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Jurisdiction and time limits.</i> (1) Action may be brought in the district court for the jurisdiction in which you reside or have a place of residence or business, or in which the Agency records are situated, or in the District of Columbia. 
</p>
<p>(2) The statute of limitations is two years from the date upon which the cause of action arises, except for cases in which the Agency has materially and willfully misrepresented any information requested to be disclosed and when such misrepresentation is material to the liability of the Agency. In such cases the statute of limitations is two years from the date of discovery of the misrepresentation by you. 
</p>
<p>(3) A suit may not be brought on the basis of injury, which may have occurred as a result of the Agency?s disclosure of a record prior to September 27, 1975. 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Criminal penalties</i>--(1) <i>Unauthorized disclosure.</i> It is a criminal violation of the provisions of the Act for any officer or employee of the Agency to knowingly and willfully disclose a record in any manner to any person or agency not entitled to receive it, for failure to meet the conditions of disclosure listed in S U.S.C. 552a(b), or without the written consent or at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains. Any officer or employee of the Agency found guilty of such misconduct shall be fined not more than $5,000. 
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Failure to publish a public notice.</i> It is a criminal violation of the Act to willfully maintain a system of records and not publish the prescribed public notice. Any officer or employee of the Agency found guilty of such misconduct shall be fined not more than $5,000. 
</p>
<p>(3) <i>Obtaining records under false pretenses.</i> The Act makes it a criminal offense to knowingly and willfully request or gain access to a record about an individual under false pretenses. Any person found guilty of such an offense may be fined not more than $5,000. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.13
 General exemptions (Subsection (j)). 
</b></p>
<p>(a) General exemptions are available for systems of records which are maintained by the Central Intelligence Agency (Subsection (j)(1)), or maintained by an agency which performs as its principal function any activity pertaining to the enforcement of the criminal laws (Subsection (j)(2)). 
</p>
<p>(b) The Act does not permit general one exemption of records compiled primarily for a non-criminal purpose, even though there are some quasi-criminal aspects to the investigation and even though the records are in a system of records to which the general exemption applies. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.14
 Specific exemptions (Subsection (k)). 
</b></p>
<p>The specific exemptions focus more on the nature of the records in the system of records than on the agency. The following categories of records may be exempt from disclosure: 
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Subsection (k)(1).</i> Records which are specifically authorized under criteria established under an Executive Order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy, and which are in fact properly classified according to such Executive Order; 
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Subsection (k)(2).</i> Investigatory records compiled for law enforcement purposes (other than material within the scope of subsection (j)(2) as discussed in &#167; 505.13(a)). If any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit for which she/he would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, the material shall be provided to the individual, unless disclosure of the material would reveal the identity of a source who has been pledged confidentiality; 
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Subsection (k)(3).</i> Records maintained in connection with protection of the President and other VIPs accorded special protection by statute; 
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Subsection (k)(4).</i> Records required by statute to be maintained and used solely as statistical records. 
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Subsection (k)(5).</i> Records compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment, military service, Federal contracts, or access to classified information, but only if disclosure of the material would reveal the identity of a confidential source that furnished information to the Government. 
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Subsection (k)(6).</i> Testing or examination records used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the Federal service when the disclosure of such would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process. 
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Subsection (k)(7).</i> Evaluation records used to determine potential for promotion in the armed services, but only if disclosure would reveal the identity of a confidential source. 

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 505.15
 Exempt systems of records used. 
</b></p>
<p>The BBG is authorized to use exemptions (k)(1), (k)(2), (k)(4), (k)(5) and (k)(6).

</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
