<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
    <agency toc="yes">
        <name> National Commission on Military, National, and Public Service </name>
        <abbrev>NCMNPS</abbrev>

      

        <section id=" NCMNPS-2" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>-2 </systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">
                NCMNPS-2, Employee Administrative Records
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> None of the information in the system is classified.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Records are maintained at the National Commission on Military, National, and Public Service’s office in Arlington, VA. The mailing address for the Commission is 2530 Crystal Drive, Suite 1000, Box No. 63, Arlington, VA 22202.  The Department of Defense’s Washington Headquarter Services (WHS) provides some human resource services under an interagency memorandum of understanding.  Records held by WHS are handled consistent with their system of records.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Director of Operations, National Commission on Military, National, and Public Service, 2530 Crystal Drive, Suite 1000, Box No. 63, Arlington, VA 22202.  The Director of Operations can be contacted at 703-571-3742 or info@inspire2serve.gov.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>5 U.S.C. 5501 et seq., 5525 et seq., 5701 et seq., and 6301 et seq.; Executive Order 9397, as amended by Executive Order 13478; the Ethics in Government Act of 1978; 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; Pub. L. 114-328, sections 551-557.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The information in the system is being collected to enable the Commission to manage and administer human capital functions, including personnel actions, payroll, time and attendance, leave, insurance, tax, retirement and other benefits, and employee claims for loss or damage to personal property; to prepare related reports to other federal agencies; to prepare travel arrangements for Commission employees; and to apply the federal ethics regulations to the Commission and its employees.  The information will also be used for administrative purposes to ensure quality control, performance, and improving management processes.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals covered by this system are current and former Commission employees, volunteers, detailees, applicants, and interns who work at the Commission (collectively, "employees") and their named dependents, beneficiaries, and/or emergency contacts.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records in this system may contain identifiable information about individuals including, without limitation: (1) Identification and contact information, including name, address, email address, phone number and other contact information; (2) employee emergency contact information, including name, phone number, relationship to employee or emergency contact; (3) Social Security number (SSN), employee ID number, organization code, pay rate, salary, grade, length of service, and other related pay and leave records including payroll data; (4) biographic and demographic data, including date of birth and marital or domestic partnership status; (5) employment-related information such as performance reports, training, professional licenses, certification, and memberships information, employee claims for loss or damage to personal property, and other information related to employment by the Commission; (6) benefits data, such as health, life, travel, and disability insurance information; (7) retirement benefits information and flexible spending account information; (8) travel-related information, including information related to reimbursement for official travel; and (9) information compiled in connection with annual ethics filings and related regulatory requirements.</p>
                    <p>General personnel and administrative records contained in this system are covered under the government-wide systems of records notice published by the Office of Personnel Management (OPM/GOVT-1). This system complements OPM/GOVT-1 and this notice incorporates by reference but does not repeat all of the information contained in OPM/GOVT-1.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information in this system is obtained from current and former Commission employees; their named dependents, beneficiaries and/or emergency contacts; individuals who have applied for a position or have been extended offers of employment by the Commission; and from individuals and entities associated with federal employee benefits, retirement, human resource functions, accounting, and payroll systems administration.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In addition to those disclosures permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed by the Commission as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                    <p>A. To the Department of Justice (DOJ), including Offices of the U.S. Attorneys, or other federal agencies conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative, or administrative body, when it is relevant or necessary to the litigation and one of the following is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation:</p>
                    <p>    1. the Commission;</p>
                    <p>    2. Any employee or former employee of the Commission in his or her official capacity;</p>
                    <p>    3. Any employee or former employee of the Commission in his or her individual capacity when DOJ or the Commission has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                    <p>    4. The U.S. Government or any agency thereof.</p>
                    <p>    B. To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                    <p>    C. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) or General Services Administration pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. §§ 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    <p>    D. To an agency or organization for the purpose of performing audit or oversight operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                    <p>    E. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) the Commission suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the Commission has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the Commission (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Commission's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>    F. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the Commission determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    <p>    G. To contractors and their agents, experts, consultants, and others performing or working on a contract, service, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the Commission, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to the Commission officers and employees.</p>
                    <p>    H. To an appropriate federal, state, tribal, territorial, local, international, or foreign law enforcement agency or other appropriate authority charged with investigating or prosecuting a violation or enforcing or implementing a law, rule, regulation, or order, when a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law, which includes criminal, civil, or regulatory violations and such disclosure is proper and consistent with the official duties of the person making the disclosure.</p>
                    <p>    I. To designated officers and employees of federal, state, tribal, territorial, local, or international agencies in connection with the hiring or continued employment of an individual, the conduct of a suitability or security investigation of an individual, the grant, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance, or the certification of security clearances, to the extent that the Commission determines the information is relevant and necessary to the hiring agency's decision.</p>
                    <p>    J. To a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal in the course of presenting evidence, including disclosures to opposing counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations or in connection with criminal law proceedings.</p>
                    <p>    K. To the other federal agencies who provide payroll personnel processing services under a cross-servicing agreement for purposes relating to the conversion of the Commission employee payroll and personnel processing services; the issuance of paychecks to employees and distribution of wages; and the distribution of allotments and deductions to financial and other institutions, some through electronic funds transfer.</p>
                    <p>    L. To federal, state, tribal, territorial, or local agencies for use in locating individuals and verifying their income sources to enforce child support orders, to establish and modify orders of support, and for enforcement of related court orders.</p>
                    <p>    M. To provide wage and separation information to another federal agency as required by law for payroll purposes.</p>
                    <p>    N. To the Office of Personnel Management, the Merit System Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in the performance of their authorized duties.</p>
                    <p>    O. To the Department of Labor in connection with a claim filed by an employee for compensation due to a job-connected injury or illness.</p>
                    <p>    P. To the Department of the Treasury to issue checks.</p>
                    <p>    Q. To State offices of unemployment compensation with survivor annuity or health benefits claims or records reconciliations.</p>
                    <p>    R. To Federal Employee's Group Life Insurance or Health Benefits carriers in connection with survivor annuity or health benefits claims or records reconciliations.</p>
                    <p>    S. To the Internal Revenue Service and State and local tax authorities for which an employee is or was subject to tax regardless of whether tax is or was withheld in accordance with Treasury Fiscal Requirements, as required.</p>
                    <p>    T. To any source from which additional information is requested by the Commission relevant to a Commission determination concerning an individual's pay, leave, or travel expenses, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and to identify the type of information requested.</p>
                    <p>    U. To the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.</p>
                    <p>    V. To the Social Security Administration and the Department of the Treasury to disclose pay data on an annual basis.</p>
                    <p>    W. To the Department of Health and Human Services for the purpose of providing information on new hires and quarterly wages as required under the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996.</p>
                    <p>    X. To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Chief Privacy Officer in consultation with counsel, when there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information or when disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of the Commission or is necessary to demonstrate the accountability of the Commission’s officers, employees, or individuals covered by the system, except to the extent it is determined that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The Commission stores records in this system electronically or on paper in secure facilities in a locked drawer behind a locked door.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Only authorized personnel can access or retrieve information.  Records may be retrieved by a variety of fields, including, without limitation, the individual’s name, SSN, address, account number, transaction number, phone number, date of birth, or by some combination thereof.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The Commission will maintain electronic and paper records under the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedules 1.1, 2.1-2.8.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records in this system are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies, including automated systems security and access policies. Access to records in this system is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals seeking notification and access to any record contained in this system of records, or seeking to contest its content, may submit a request in writing to the Chief Privacy Officer at the address provided for the System Manager, above.  When seeking records about yourself from this system of records your request must comply with the Commission’s Privacy Act regulations and must include sufficient information to permit us to identify potentially responsive records. In addition, you must sign your request, and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. § 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury as a substitute for notarization. If your request is seeking records pertaining to another living individual, you must include a statement from that individual certifying his/her consent to your access to his/her records. Without this information, we may not be able to conduct an effective search, and your request may be denied due to lack of specificity or lack of compliance with applicable regulations.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See "Record Access Procedures" above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See "Record Access Procedures" above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> No previous Federal Register notices for this system of records exist. </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>


        <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
            <regulationsTitle number="1">
                <heading> General Provisions</heading>
                <regulationsChapter number="IV">
                    <heading> Miscellaneous Agencies</heading>
                    <regulationsPart number="426">
                        <heading> NATIONAL COMMISSION ON MILITARY, NATIONAL, AND PUBLIC SERVICE</heading>
                        <p>
                            <b>
                                Subpart A—Implementation of the Privacy Act of 1974
                           </b> </p>


    <p>Sec. </p>
    <p>
        426.101 Purpose and scope.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.102 Definitions.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.103 Inquiries about systems of records or implementation of the Privacy Act.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.104 Procedures for accessing records pertaining to an individual.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.105 Identification required when requesting access to records pertaining to an individual.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.106 Procedures for amending or correcting an individual’s record.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.107 Procedures for appealing a refusal to amend or correct a record.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.108 Fees charged to locate, review, or copy records.
    </p>
    <p>
        426.109 Procedures for maintaining accounts of disclosures.
    </p>

    <p>Authority:  U.S.C. 552a(f). </p>
    <p>
        Source: 83 FR 19409, May 2, 2018, unless otherwise noted.
    </p>
    <p>

        <b>Subpart A—Implementation of the Privacy Act of 1974</b>
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>  &#167; 426.101 Purpose and scope.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        The regulations in this part set forth the Commission’s procedures under the Privacy Act, as required by 5 U.S.C. 552a(f), with respect to systems of records maintained by the Commission. The rules in this part apply to all records maintained by the Commission that are retrieved by an individual's name or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual. These regulations establish procedures by which an individual may exercise the rights granted by the Privacy Act to determine whether a Commission system of records contains a record pertaining to him or her; to gain access to such records; and to request correction or amendment of such records. These rules should be read together with the Privacy Act, which provides additional information about records maintained on individuals.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167; 426.102 Definitions. </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        The definitions in subsection (a) of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(a)) apply to this part. In addition, as used in this part:
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>Business day </i>means a calendar day, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays.
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>Chair </i>means the Chair of the Commission, or his or her designee;
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>Commission </i>means the National Commission on Military, National, and Public Service;
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>Commission system</i> means a system of records maintained by the Commission;
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>General Counsel </i>means the General Counsel of the Commission, or his or her designee.
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>Privacy Act </i>or <i>Act </i>means the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552a);
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>You, your, </i>or other references to the reader of the regulations in this part are meant to apply to the individual to whom a record pertains.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>
            &#167;426.103 Inquiries about systems of records or implementation of the Privacy Act.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        Inquiries about the Commission’s systems of records or implementation of the Privacy Act should be sent to the following address: National Commission on Military, National, and Public Service, Office of the General Counsel, 2530 Crystal Drive, Suite 1000, Box No. 63, Arlington, VA 22202.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>
            &#167;426.104 Procedures for accessing records pertaining to an individual.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        The following procedures apply to records that are contained in a Commission system:
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) You may request to be notified if a system of records that you name contains records pertaining to you, and to review any such records, by writing to the Office of the General Counsel (see § 426.103). You also may call the Office of the General Counsel at 703-571-3742 on business days, between the hours of 9 a.m. and 5 p.m., to schedule an appointment to make such a request in person. A request for records should be presented in writing and should identify specifically the Commission system(s) involved. Your request to access records pertaining to you will be treated as a request under both the Privacy Act, as implemented by this part, and the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552), as implemented by subpart B of this part.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) Access to the records, or to any other information pertaining to you that is contained in the system, shall be provided if the identification requirements of § 426.105 are satisfied and the records are determined otherwise to be releasable under the Privacy Act and these regulations. The Commission shall provide you an opportunity to have a copy made of any such records about you. Only one copy of each requested record will be supplied, based on the fee schedule in § 426.108.
    </p>
    <p>
        (c) The Commission will comply promptly with requests made in person at scheduled appointments, if the requirements of this section are met and the records sought are immediately available. The Commission will acknowledge, within 10 business days, mailed requests or personal requests for records that are not immediately available, and the information requested will be provided promptly thereafter.
    </p>
    <p>
        (d) If you make your request in person at a scheduled appointment, you may, upon your request, be accompanied by a person of your choice to review your records. The Commission may require that you furnish a written statement authorizing discussion of your records in the accompanying person's presence. A record may be disclosed to a representative chosen by you upon your proper written consent.
    </p>
    <p>
        (e) Medical or psychological records pertaining to you shall be disclosed to you unless, in the judgment of the Commission, access to such records might have an adverse effect upon you. When such a determination has been made, the Commission may refuse to disclose such information directly to you. The Commission will, however, disclose this information to you through a licensed physician designated by you in writing.
    </p>
    <p>
        (f) If you are unsatisfied with an adverse determination on your request to access records pertaining to you, you may appeal that determination using the procedures set forth in § 426.107(a).
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167;26.105 Identification required when requesting access to records pertaining to an individual. </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        The Commission will require reasonable identification of all individuals who request access to records in a Commission system to ensure that records are disclosed to the proper person.
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) The amount of personal identification required will of necessity vary with the sensitivity of the record involved. In general, if you request disclosure in person, you will be required to show an identification card, such as a driver's license, containing your photograph and sample signature. However, with regard to records in Commission systems that contain particularly sensitive and/or detailed personal information, the Commission reserves the right to require additional means of identification as are appropriate under the circumstances. These means include, but are not limited to, requiring you to sign a statement under oath as to your identity, acknowledging that you are aware of the criminal penalties for requesting or obtaining records under false pretenses or falsifying information (see 5 U.S.C. 552a(i)(3); 18 U.S.C. 1001).
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) If you request disclosure by mail, the Commission will request such information as may be necessary to ensure that you are properly identified and for a response to be sent. Authorized means to achieve this goal include, but are not limited to, requiring that a mail request include a signed, notarized statement asserting your identity or a statement signed under oath as described in subsection (a) of this section.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167; 426.106 Procedures for amending or correcting an individual’s record. </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) You are entitled to request amendments to or corrections of records pertaining to you that you believe are not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete, pursuant to the provisions of the Privacy Act, including 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(2). Such a request should be made in writing and addressed to the Office of the General Counsel (see &#167;  426.103).
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) Your request for amendments or corrections should specify the following:
    </p>
    <p>
        (1) The particular record that you are seeking to amend or correct;
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) The Commission system from which the record was retrieved;
    </p>
    <p>
        (3) The precise correction or amendment you desire, preferably in the form of an edited copy of the record reflecting the desired modification; and
    </p>
    <p>
        (4) Your reasons for requesting amendment or correction of the record.
    </p>
    <p>
        (c) The Commission will acknowledge a request for amendment or correction of a record within 10 business days of its receipt, unless the request can be processed and the individual informed of the General Counsel's decision on the request within that 10-day period.
    </p>
    <p>
        (d) If after receiving and investigating your request, the General Counsel agrees that the record is not accurate, timely, or complete, based on a preponderance of the evidence, then the record will be corrected or amended promptly. The record will be deleted without regard to its accuracy, if the record is not relevant or necessary to accomplish the Commission’s function for which the record was provided or is maintained. In either case, you will be informed in writing of the amendment, correction, or deletion. In addition, if accounting was made of prior disclosures of the record, all previous recipients of the record will be informed of the corrective action taken.
    </p>
    <p>
        (e) If after receiving and investigating your request, the General Counsel does not agree that the record should be amended or corrected, you will be informed promptly in writing of the refusal to amend or correct the record and the reason for this decision. You also will be informed that you may appeal this refusal in accordance with &#167; 426.107.
    </p>
    <p>
        (f) Requests to amend or correct a record governed by the regulations of another agency will be forwarded to such agency for processing, and you will be informed in writing of this referral.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167;26.107 Procedures for appealing a refusal to amend or correct a record. </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) You may appeal a refusal to amend or correct a record to the Chair of the Commission. Such appeal must be made in writing within 30 business days of your receipt of the initial refusal to amend or correct your record. Your appeal should be sent to the Office of the General Counsel (see &#167;  426.103), should indicate that it is an appeal, and should include the basis for the appeal.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) The Chair will review your request to amend or correct the record, the General Counsel's refusal, and any other pertinent material relating to the appeal. No hearing will be held.
    </p>
    <p>
        (c) The Chair shall render his or her decision on your appeal within 30 business days of its receipt by the Commission, unless the Chair, for good cause shown, extends the 30-day period. Should the Chair extend the appeal period, you will be informed in writing of the extension and the circumstances of the delay.
    </p>
    <p>
        (d) If the Chair determines that the record that is the subject of the appeal should be amended or corrected, the record will be so modified, and you will be informed in writing of the amendment or correction. Where an accounting was made of prior disclosures of the record, all previous recipients of the record will be informed of the corrective action taken.
    </p>
    <p>
        (e) If your appeal is denied, you will be informed in writing of the following:
    </p>
    <p>
        (1) The denial and the reasons for the denial;
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) That you may submit to the Commission a concise statement setting forth the reasons for your disagreement as to the disputed record. Under the procedures set forth in paragraph (f) of this section, your statement will be disclosed whenever the disputed record is disclosed; and
    </p>
    <p>
        (3) That you may seek judicial review of the Chair’s determination under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1).
    </p>
    <p>
        (f) Whenever you submit a statement of disagreement to the Commission in accordance with paragraph (e)(2) of this section, the record will be annotated to indicate that it is disputed. In any subsequent disclosure, a copy of your statement of disagreement will be disclosed with the record. If the Commission deems it appropriate, a concise statement of the Chair’s reasons for denying your appeal also may be disclosed with the record. While you will have access to this statement of the Chair’s reasons for denying your appeal, such statement will not be subject to correction or amendment. Where an accounting was made of prior disclosures of the record, all previous recipients of the record will be provided a copy of your statement of disagreement, as well as any statement of the Chair's reasons for denying your appeal deemed appropriate.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167;426.108 Fees charged to locate, review, or copy records. </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) The Commission will charge no fees for search time or for any other time expended by the Commission to review a record. However, the Commission may charge fees where you request that a copy be made of a record to which you have been granted access. Where a copy of the record must be made in order to provide access to the record (e.g., computer printout where no screen reading is available), the copy will be made available to you without cost.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) Copies of records made by photocopy or similar process will be charged to you at the rate of $0.12 per page. Where records are not susceptible to photocopying (e.g., punch cards, magnetic tapes, or oversize materials), you will be charged actual cost as determined on a case-by-case basis. Copying fees will not be charged if the cost of collecting a fee would be equal to or greater than the fee itself. Copying fees for contemporaneous requests by the same individual shall be aggregated to determine the total fee.
    </p>
    <p>
        (c) Special and additional services provided at your request, such as certification or authentication, postal insurance, and special mailing arrangement costs, will be charged to you at the market rate.
    </p>
    <p>
        (d) You may request that a copying fee not be charged or, alternatively, be reduced, by submitting a written petition to the Commission’s General Counsel (see &#167;  426.103) asserting that you are indigent. If the General Counsel determines, based on the petition, that you are indigent and that the Commission’s resources permit a waiver of all or part of the fee, the General Counsel may, in his or her discretion, waive or reduce the copying fee.
    </p>
    <p>
        (e) All fees shall be paid before any copying request is undertaken.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167; 426.109 Procedures for maintaining accounts of disclosures. </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) The Office of the General Counsel shall maintain a log containing the date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure of a record to any person or to another agency. Such accounting also shall contain the name and address of the person or agency to whom each disclosure was made. This log need not include disclosures made to the Commission’s employees in the course of their official duties, or pursuant to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552).
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) The Commission will retain the accounting of each disclosure for at least five years after the disclosure or for the life of the record that was disclosed.
    </p>
    <p>
        (c) The Commission will make the accounting of disclosures of a record pertaining to you available to you at your request. Such a request should be made in accordance with the procedures set forth in § 426.104. This paragraph (c) does not apply to disclosures made for law enforcement purposes under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(7).
    </p>


</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
