<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</name>
<abbrev>TSF</abbrev>
    
    

<section id="TSF1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Payroll Records--Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> General Services Administration, Region 3 Office; copies
heldby the Foundation.(GSA holds records for the Foundation under contract.)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Past and present Foundation employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Varied payroll records, including, among other
documents, time and attendance cards; payment vouchers; comprehensive listing of employees; health benefits records; requests for deductions;
tax forms; W-2 forms; overtime requests; leave data; retirement records. Records are used by Foundation and GSA employees to
maintain adequate payroll information for Foundation employees, and otherwise by Foundation and GSA employees who have a need for the
record in the performance of their duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> 31 U.S.C., generally.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> See appendix. Records also are disclosed to GAO for
audits; to the Internal
Revenue Service for investigations; and to private attorneys, pursuant to a power of attorney. Records are
also
disclosed by providing
a copy of an employee's Federal Treasury Form W-2, "Wage and Tax Statement" to the State, city, or other local
jurisdiction which
is authorized to tax the employee's compensation. The record will be provided in accordance with a withholding
agreement between the
State, city, or other local jurisdiction and the Department of the Treasury pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 5516, 5517,
and
5520 or in the absence
thereof, in response to a written request for an appropriate official of the taxing jurisdiction to the
Executive
Secretary, Harry S.
Truman Scholarship Foundation, 712 Jackson Place, NW, Washington, DC 20006. In the latter case, the request
must
include a copy of the
applicable statute or ordinance authorizing the taxation of compensation and the solicitation of the Social
Security number, and should
indicate whether the authority of the jurisdiction to tax the employee is based on place of residence, place
of
employment, or both.
</p><p>Pursuant to a withholding agreement between a city and the Department of the Treasury (5 U.S.C. 5520),
copies of executed city
tax withholding certificates shall be furnished the city in response to a written request from an appropriate
city official to the
Executive Secretary, Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation, 712 Jackson Place, NW, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p> Paper and microfilm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> Social Security Number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Stored in guarded building; released only to authorized
personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Disposition of records, shall be in accordance with
the
HB GSA Records
Maintenance and Disposition System (OAD P 1820.2).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Executive Secretary, Harry S. Truman Scholarship
Foundation,
712 Jackson Place, NW,
Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained in
45
CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained
in
45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations
contained
in 45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> The subject individual; the Foundation.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>

<section id="TSF2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> General Financial Records Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> General Services Administration, Central Office; copies
held
by the Foundation.
(GSA holds records for the Foundation under contract.)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Employees of the Foundation and members of its
Board
of Trustees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> SF-1038, Application and account for advance of
funds;
Vendor register
and vendor payment tape. Information is used by accounting technicians to maintain adequate financial
information
and by other officers
and employees of GSA and the Foundation who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> 31 U.S.C., generally; also, the Foundation's
authorizing legislation, Pub.
L. 93-642 (20 U.S.C. 2001).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> See appendix: Records also are released to GAO for
audits; to the IRS for
investigation; and to private attorneys, pursuant to power of attorney.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p> Paper and tape.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> Manual and automated by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Stored in guarded building; released only to authorized
personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Disposition of records shall be in accordance with
the
HB GAS Records
Maintenance and Disposition System (OAD P 1820.2).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Executive Secretary, Harry S. Truman Scholarship
Foundation,
712 Jackson Place, NW,
Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained in
45
CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained
in
45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations
contained
in 45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> The subject individual; the Foundation.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="TSF3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> General Informational Files--Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation, 712 Jackson Place,
NW, Washington, DC
20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Foundation employees and members of its Board of
Trustees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> General personnel information, including, among other
data, copies of training
and travel records, applications, suggestions, position descriptions, request for and notification of
personnel
action, employee
performance ratings and promotion appraisals, time and attendance records, security clearances, titles, date
of
birth, grade, salary
employment history, home address, age, marital status, Social Security Number, home telephone number, resumes,
general correspondence,
and letters of recommendation. System also contains copies of official Civil Service Commission and Foundation
personnel forms.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> 5 U.S.C., generally; also, the Foundation's
authorizing legislation, Pub.
L. 93-642 (20 U.S.C. 2001).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> See appendix. Completion of agency forms for
requests
for personnel actions,
security clearances, training authorizations, travel authorizations, time and attendance records, reports,
etc.
Also used for issuing
passes, motor pool ID, etc. Information is used "in house" for personnel evaluation and management.
Information
is disclosed to persons
outside the agency for verifying employment/salary, preparing letters of reference at the request of the
employee, making travel and
training arrangements, and furnishing copies of performance appraisals to other government agencies when
employees have applied for
jobs elsewhere.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p> <p> Paper files.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> Manual by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Stored in guarded building, released only to authorized
personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Disposition of records, shall be in accordance with
the
HB GSA Records
Maintenance and Disposition System (OAD P 1820.2).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Executive Secretary, Harry S. Truman Scholarship
Foundation,
712 Jackson Place, NW,
Washington, DC 20006
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained in
45
CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained
in
45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations
contained
in 45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> Official personnel records, GSA Personnel and
Finance
Offices, Supervisors,
letters of reference or recommendation furnished by agency officials or persons from private industry,
educational information supplied
by colleges and universities, the subject individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="TSF4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Applicant's Records--Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation, 712 Jackson Place,
NW, Washington, DC
20006, and Educational Testing Service, Princeton, N.J.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p> Persons nominated by colleges and universities in
the United States, for
consideration as potential Truman Scholars.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Documents and certifications to assist Foundation
staff
in evaluating a
person's application for a Truman Scholarship, including, among other documents, a listing of leadership
positions held in high school
and college; and of public service activities; letters of recommendation; test results, personal essay on the
applicant's interest in
entering public service; a statement of intent to enter the public service; certifications as to U.S.
citizenship
and academic
standings; test scores.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The Foundation's authorizing legislation, Pub. L.
93-642 (20 U.S.C.
2001).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> See appendix. Records also are released to experts
and
consultants hired by
the Foundation or its administrative agent, Educational Testing Service, for evaluation and recommendation
with
respect to applicants'
qualifications for a Truman Scholarship.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p> <p> Paper.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> Manual and automated by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Stored in a guarded building; released only to authorized
personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Foundation retains records only of those chosen as
finalists in competition
(Truman Scholars and alternates); all others are destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Executive Secretary, Harry S. Truman Scholarship
Foundation,
712 Jackson Place, NW,
Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained in
45
CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations contained
in
45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Refer to Foundation access regulations
contained
in 45 CFR part 1800.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> The subject individual; the nominating
institution;
reference supplied by
the subject individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<appendix id="Appendix" toc="yes">

<title>HARRY S. TRUMAN SCHOLARSHIP FOUNDATION</title>
<xhtmlContent><p>In the event that a system of records maintained by this agency to carry out its functions
indicates a
violation or potential
violation of law, whether, civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or
particular program
statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of
records
may be referred, as a
routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local or foreign, charged with the
responsibility
of investigating or
prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order
issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a "routine use" to a Federal, State or local
agency maintaining civil,
criminal or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses,
if
necessary to obtain
information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of any employee, the issuance of
a
security clearance,
the letting of a contract or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit.
</p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request,
in
connection with the
hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of
an
employee, the letting
of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent
that
the information is
relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision in the matter.
</p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed to an authorized appeal grievance examiner,
formal
complaints examiner,
equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other duly authorized official engaged in
investigation
or settlement of a
grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to
the United States Civil
Service Commission in accordance with the agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal
personnel management.
</p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed to officers and employees of a Federal agency for
purposes of audit.
</p><p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to a Member of Congress or to a
congressional staff
member in response to an inquiry of the congressional office made at the request of the individual about whom
the
record is maintained.</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>
  <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
  <regulationsTitle number="45">
  <heading>Public Welfare</heading>
  <regulationsChapter number="XVIII">
  <heading>Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</heading>
  <regulationsPart number="1800">
  <heading>PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
  <xhtmlContent>
  <p>Sec.
  </p><p>1800.1 Purpose and scope.
  </p>

  <p>1800.2 Definitions.
      </p><p>1800.3 Procedures for requests for access to individual records in a record system.
      </p><p>1800.4 Times, places, and requirements for the identification of the individual making a request.
      </p>



    <p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.1
     Purpose and scope.
    </b></p><p>The purposes of these regulations are to:
    </p><p>(a) Establish a procedure by which an individual can determine if the Harry S. Truman Scholarship
    Foundation (hereafter known as the Foundation) maintains a system of records which includes a record
    pertaining to the individual; and
    </p>

<p>(b) Establish a procedure by which an individual can gain access to a record pertaining to him or
    her
    for the purpose of review, amendment and/or correction.

    </p>



<p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.2
   Definitions.
  </b></p><p>For the purpose of these regulations--
  </p><p>(a) The term <i>individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted
  for permanent residence;</p>
  <p>(b) The term <i>maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use or disseminate;</p>
  <p>(c) The term <i>record</i> means any item, collection or grouping of information about an individual
  that is maintained by the Foundation, including, but not limited to, his or her employment history, payroll
  information, and financial transactions and that contains his or her name, or the identifying number,
  symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as social security number;</p>
 
 
 
 
 
 
  <p>(d) The term <i>system of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of the
   Foundation from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number,
   symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual; and</p>



   <p>(e) The term <i>routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such
   record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.</p>

 
 
 
   <p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.3
    Procedures for requests for access to individual records in a record system.
   </b></p><p>An individual shall submit a request to the Deputy Executive Secretary of the Foundation to
   determine if a system of records named by the individual contains a record pertaining to the individual. The
   individual shall submit a request to the Deputy Executive Secretary of the Foundation which states the
   individual's desire to review his or her record.</p>

 
 





<p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.4
   Times, places, and requirements for the identification of the individual making a request.
  </b></p><p>An individual making a request to the Deputy Executive Secretary of the Foundation pursuant to
  &#167; 1800.3 shall present the request at the Foundation offices, 712 Jackson Place, NW., Washington,
  DC 20006, on any business day between the hours of 9 a.m. and 5 p.m. The individual submitting the request
  should present himself or herself at the Foundation's offices with a form of identification which will
  permit the Foundation to verify that the individual is the same individual as contained in the record
  requested.

  </p><p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.5
   Access to requested information to the individual.
  </b></p><p>Upon verification of identity the Foundation shall disclose to the individual the information
  contained in the record which pertains to that individual.

  </p><p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.6
   Request for correction or amendment to the record.
  </b></p><p>The individual should submit a request to the Deputy Executive Secretary of the Foundation which
  states the individual's desire to correct or to amend his or her record. This request is to be made in
  accord with the provisions of &#167; 1800.4.

  </p><p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.7
   Agency review of request for correction or amendment of the record.
  </b></p><p>Within ten working days of the receipt of the request to correct or to amend the record, the
  Deputy Executive Secretary of the Foundation will acknowledge in writing such receipt and promptly either--
  </p><p>(a) Make any correction or amendment of any portion thereof which the individual believes is not
  accurate, relevant, timely, or complete; or
  </p><p>(b) Inform the individual of his or her refusal to correct or to amend the record in accordance with
  the request, the reason for the refusal, and the procedures established by the Foundation for the individual
  to request a review of that refusal.

  </p><p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.8
   Appeal of an initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment of the record.
  </b></p><p>An individual who disagrees with the refusal of the Deputy Executive Secretary of the Foundation
  to correct or to amend his or her record may submit a request for a review of such refusal to the Executive
  Secretary, Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation, 712 Jackson Place, NW., Washington, DC 20006. The
  Executive Secretary will, not later than thirty working days from the date on which the individual requests
  such review, complete such review and make a final determination unless, for good cause shown, the Executive
  Secretary extends such thirty day period. If, after his or her review, the Executive Secretary also refuses
  to correct or to amend the record in accordance with the request, the individual may file with the
  Foundation a concise statement setting forth the reasons for his or her disagreement with the refusal of the
  Foundation and may seek judicial review of the Executive Secretary's determination under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1)
  (A).

  </p><p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.9
   Disclosure of record to a person other than the individual to whom the record pertains.
  </b></p><p>The Foundation will not disclose a record to any individual other than to the individual to whom
  the record pertains without receiving the prior written consent of the individual to whom the record
  pertains, unless the disclosure has been listed as a "routine use" in the Foundation's notices of its
  systems of records.

  </p>

<p><b>&#167;&#160;1800.10
   Fees.
  </b></p><p>If an individual requests copies of his or her record, he or she shall be charged ten cents per
  page, excluding the cost of any search for review of the record, in advance of receipt of the pages.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
