<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Consumer Product Safety Commission</name>
<abbrev>

CPSC
</abbrev>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-20/pdf/2021-27438.pdf</url>
        <title>CPSC-23, Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) Disability/ Accommodation Files.</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="20" />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-20/pdf/2021-27440.pdf</url>
        <title>Consumer Ombudsman Inquiry Database, CPSC-2021.</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="20" />
    </previouslyPublished>



    <section id="cpsc2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Advisory Committee Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Directorate for Health Sciences, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking, nominated for, or selected for membership on CPSC Advisory Committees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records of applicants contain an individual's name, address, personal history and qualifications, any correspondence with the individual, and any Commission memoranda relating to the selection of the individual. Records of members additionally contain information about the member's financial compensation and Commission documents relating to the individual's service as a member.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>15 U.S.C. 2077 and 15 U.S.C 1275.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used to select candidates for filling vacancies on Advisory Committees and to administer the operation of the committees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Disclosure may be made to a congressional office, from the record of an individual, in response to an inquiry from the congressional office, made at the request of that individual. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in hard copy.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by name of committee and then by name of applicant or member.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in file cabinets in a secured area.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files maintained by the Secretariat to the board, committee, or conference are maintained permanently. They are transferred to the Federal Records Center when they are five years old or upon permission of board, committee, or conference. Members' records are destroyed two years after termination of membership, or sooner, if no longer needed.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Health Sciences Project Manager, Directorate for Health Sciences, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by applicants, nominees for, and members of advisory committees, the National Academy of Science, and by Commission staff.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Claims.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the General Counsel, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>CPSC employees sustaining personal property damage or loss incident to service; CPSC employees involved in situations where personal injury or property damage to others results from wrongful or negligent acts or omissions of employee acting within scope of employment; claimants sustaining injury or property damage due to activities of CPSC or its employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records contain claims for money damages, accident and investigative reports, and correspondence and other documents concerning claims or potential claims.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>31 U.S.C. 3721; 28 U.S.C. 1346(b), 2672.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>(a) For processing claims and litigation under the Federal Tort Claims Act or the Military Personnel and Civilian Employee's Claims Act; (b) for preparation of reports.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
<p>2. Information from a record in this system of records may be disclosed to a person or entity having a legal interest in the claim.</p>
<p>3. Information may be disclosed to federal, state, or local law authorities, court authorities, administrative authorities, for use in connection with civil, criminal, administrative, and regulatory proceedings and actions relating to the claim.</p>
<p>4. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in hard copy.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by name of individual claimant.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a file cabinet in a secured area. Access to such area is limited to persons whose official duties require such access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained permanently.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>General Counsel, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by: (1) The individual to whom the record pertains; (2) CPSC and/or its employees; (3) affidavits, statements, or testimony of witnesses; (4) official documents relating to the claim; (5) correspondence from organizations or persons involved.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Hotline Database.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Systems Integration Incorporated, 8201 Corporate Drive, Suite 300, Landover, MD 20785.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons who contact the Consumer Product Safety Commission to report a consumer product associated injury, illness, death, incident, or perceived hazard associated with consumer products and other persons identified by the reporting persons as victims of consumer product associated incidents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information about accidents, injuries, illnesses, deaths, and suspected safety hazards associated with consumer products. The records contain free-form narratives, and a variety of fields dedicated to specific data about different types of products or incidents. Records contain personal information, such as the name, address, and telephone number of the person submitting the information, and in some cases, the name of the victim, if different.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Section 5 of the Consumer Product Safety Act, 15 U.S.C. 2054.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To collect data on hazards, defects, injuries, illnesses, and deaths associated with consumer products; to respond to inquiries from the public; to record personal information to permit further interaction with persons submitting data or persons named by those who submit data; to further public safety by helping determine the cause of injuries and deaths associated with consumer products.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Records are disclosed to contractor personnel who operate the Consumer Product Safety Commission's Hotline and who enter data into the database.</p>
<p>2. Copies of records are mailed to callers for their verification of the information provided.</p>
<p>3. Copies of records may be sent to sources of consumer products identified in the records (e.g., manufacturers, distributors, or retailers) and may be distributed to others, but any personal identifying information is deleted before such disclosure, unless permission to disclose such personal identifying information has been explicitly granted, in writing, by the person in question.</p>
<p>4. Copies of records may be sent to other governmental agencies having apparent jurisdiction over the products or hazards disclosed in a record.</p>
<p>5. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The contractor shall maintain records in a computer database management system on a local and wide-area network. Paper copies of individual computer records are made by the Hotline staff and are stored by month and by the name of the person who contacted the Hotline. Other paper copies are made available to Commission staff but are not stored by name or other individual identifier.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by a variety of fields, including the name of the person who submitted the information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to the computer records requires the use of two passwords: One to access the agency's computer network and another to access the database. Access is limited to those with a particular need to know the information--select Commission employees and the contractor employees who operate the Hotline.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained indefinitely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Hotline Contract Officer, Office of Communications, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records is initially supplied by persons who contact the Commission. The Commission may solicit additional or verifying information from those persons or from other persons who were identified as victims.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>


<subsection type="systemName">Enforcement and Investigation Files
.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Compliance and Field Operations, Office of Import Surveillance and Inspection, and Office of the General Counsel, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who are the authors or recipients of, or mentioned in, documents received by, or generated by, the Consumer Product Safety Commission in preparation for, or the conduct of, potential or actual administrative or judicial enforcement actions, and individuals mentioned in such documents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Memoranda, correspondence, test reports, injury reports, notes, and any other documents relating to the preparation for, or conduct of, potential or actual administrative or judicial enforcement actions. The materials may contain personal information as well as purely legal and technical information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>15 U.S.C. 1194, 1195, 1196, 1264, 1265, 2069, 2070.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These files are used by Commission attorneys, compliance officers, and supporting technical staff investigating product hazards and enforcing the Commission's statutory authority.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. These records may be cited and quoted in the course of enforcement negotiations, and in pleadings filed with an adjudicative body and served on opposing counsel.</p>
<p>2. They may be disclosed to the Department of Justice in connection with the conduct of litigation.</p>
<p>3. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in file folders or computer files or both.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records may be filed by and retrievable by name of the document's author or addressee or by other indicia. Computer records are indexed by, and retrievable by the names and other indicia of authors and addressees, and may permit retrieval by names elsewhere in documents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are kept in secure areas. Computer records are protected by passwords available only to staff with a need to know.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept indefinitely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>General Counsel; Director, Office of Compliance and Field Operations; and Director, Office of Import Surveillance and Inspection, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>These records come from organizations and individuals under investigation; from Commission attorneys, compliance officers, investigators, and supporting technical staff; and from other sources of information relevant to an investigation or adjudication.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>All portions of this system of records which fall within 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) (investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes) are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (mandatory accounting of disclosures); 5 U.S.C. 552a(d), (access by individuals to records that pertain to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(1), (requirement to maintain only such information as is relevant and necessary to accomplish an authorized agency purpose); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(G), (mandatory procedures to notify individuals of the existence of records pertaining to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(H), (mandatory procedures to notify individuals how they can obtain access to and contest records pertaining to them); and 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(I), (mandatory disclosure of record source categories); as well as the Commission's regulations in 16 CFR Part 1014 which implement these statutory provisions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>


<subsection type="systemName">General Counsel Tracking System.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the General Counsel, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Attorneys working in the Office of the General Counsel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Descriptions and dates of assignments; comments; starting and completion dates; due dates; names of attorneys to whom assignments are given; names of divisions within the Office of the General Counsel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>44 U.S.C. 3101; 15 U.S.C. 2051 et seq.; 16 CFR 1000.14.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To manage the workflow in the Office of the General Counsel; to assure timely completion of assignments; to respond to queries from other units of the Consumer Product Safety Commission; to assist in evaluating attorney performance.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained by a computer database management system. Hard copy printouts of selected groups of records are made from time to time.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by any field, including attorney name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to the records, and to fields within the records, is controlled by passwords. Records are accessible by all Office of the General Counsel staff, but not by others. Only supervisory staff may create records, assign or extend due dates, or enter completion dates.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept indefinitely.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>General Counsel, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Office, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records is supplied by the attorneys themselves and by supervisors.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>


</section>
<section id="cpsc10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Procurement System.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Division of Procurement Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals, non-incorporated, who sell goods or services to the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Contracts, proposals, purchase orders, correspondence and other documents related to specific procurements from individuals functioning as business entities. These records may include social security number (when used as business tax ID), home address, and home telephone number when these contact points are used for business purposes. Documents related to procurements from corporations, partnerships, or other such business entities are not included in this system of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>15 U.S.C. 2076.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records support all facets of the Commission's procurement activities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To the U.S. Department of Justice when related to litigation or anticipated litigation.</p>
<p>2. To the appropriate Federal, State, or local investigation or enforcement agency when there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of statute or regulation in connection with procurement.</p>
<p>3. To a Congressional office in response to an inquiry made at the request of the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
<p>4. To the U.S. Government Accountability Office in the event of a procurement protest involving the individual.</p>
<p>5. To the Office of Financial Management in an effort to properly process payment of invoices.</p>
<p>6. To the Office of the Secretariat, Freedom of Information Officer, to properly process incoming FOIA requests in accordance with the Freedom of Information Act.</p>
<p>7. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) the CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p><i>Disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12).</i> Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), disclosures may be made to a consumer reporting agency as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in file folders. Extracts of these records, including tax ID number, address, and phone number, are also kept in a computer database.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved from the computer database by business name used by an individual or contract number. Paper records are retrieved by contract number, which may be retrieved by first searching for the contractor name in the computer database.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are stored in locked cabinets in a secure area. Computer records are accessible only through the use of login and password, which are issued to those with a need to know.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are kept indefinitely. Paper records are destroyed 6 years and 3 months after final payment.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Division of Procurement Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal information in these records is normally obtained from the person to whom the records pertain.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Physical Security Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Facilities Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees, contractors, and others who have received uniquely coded tokens (key cards, key fobs, etc.) to gain access to various parts of Commission facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records which show the time a token has been used; the identity of the token and, therefore, of the person to whom it is assigned; the location at which it has been used; and the access privileges of the person to whom it is assigned.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records may be used to investigate breaches of security, theft, vandalism, other property losses, criminal offenses, and employee misconduct.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records may be disclosed:
</p><p>1. To a law enforcement agency when the Commission becomes aware of an indication of a violation of civil or criminal law or regulation to which these records may be pertinent.</p>
<p>2. To the Department of Justice, a court or other tribunal (including an adjudicative or administrative body), or other third-party before such tribunal when the Commission determines that the use of these records by the entity is relevant and necessary to litigation involving the Commission or a Commission employee or former employee.</p>
<p>3. To an employee, an employee's attorney or other representative designated by the employee, when the Commission questions the employee's conduct based at least in part on information from this system of records.</p>
<p>4. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>These records are stored in a central computer managed by a security services contractor. Printouts are stored in locked file cabinets.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records can be retrieved by time period, location(s), and the unique identifier of a person's token, or a combination of these.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are kept in a secure computer facility and can be retrieved only by the Commission's Physical Security Manager or designee upon request of a senior Commission official or a law enforcement officer. Printouts are stored in locked file cabinets.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are kept one year from the date of creation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Physical Security Manager, Office of Facilities Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are automatically generated when a token is passed through or across an electronic reading device.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Employee Outside Activity Notices.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the General Counsel, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Commission employees engaged in outside employment activities or outside activities such as consulting, practicing law, or teaching.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system of records contains information concerning the employee's position, nature of outside activity, relation of official duties to activity, and method of compensation for outside activity.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 12674; 5 CFR part 2635, subpart H; and 5 CFR part 8101.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records is used by the Ethics Counselor in making a determination as to whether an employee's outside activity constitutes a real or apparent conflict of interest with the employee's government duties and responsibilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained on hard copy.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are filed by employee name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in locked file cabinets.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records such as determinations regarding attendance at widely-attended gatherings which appropriate agency ethics officials determine are related to the routine, non-precedential application of settled legal standards to common factual situations and are not interpretations of the conflict of interest statutes, 18 U.S.C. 202-209, and other ethics statutes the violation of which may result in criminal penalties or civil fines are destroyed when 3 years old or when superseded or obsolete, whichever is later. All other records are destroyed when 6 years old or when superseded or obsolete, whichever is later.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Designated Agency Ethics Official (General Counsel), Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The information in these records is furnished by the employees to whom it pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Personnel, Payroll, Financial Management, Retirement, Attendance and Leave Records. Note: The personnel system complements OPM/GOV-1, the Government wide system for general personnel records maintained by the Office of Personnel Management. This notice incorporates by reference but does not repeat all of the information contained in OPM/GOVT-1.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), Director, Office of Human Resources Management, Director, Division of Financial Services, and
</p><p>The office to which the employee is assigned, and all offices which prepare and provide input documents and information for data processing and administrative actions. Automated personnel records are also maintained in the Federal Personnel Payroll System (FPPS) managed by the National Business Center in Denver, Colorado.</p>
<p>Automated financial management data for the Commission's financial management system is maintained in Delphi, an Oracle based financial management system hosted and supported by Enterprise Service Center, ESC, a shared provider located in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma.</p>
<p>4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of CPSC (employees), volunteers within CPSC, and contractors performing for CPSC.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records consist of payroll, financial records, retirement, attendance and leave records, personnel security records, safety records, contractor payment records, and personnel records including award information. In addition, the system contains data necessary to update the Central Personnel Data File at the Office of Personnel Management, to process personnel actions, to perform detailed accounting distributions, to automatically provide for such tasks as mailing checks and bonds, and to prepare and mail tax returns and reports. Records include, but are not limited to the following categories of records:
</p><p>1. Employee identification and status data such as name, social security number, date of birth, sex, work schedule, type of appointment, education, veteran's preference, military service.</p>
<p>2. Relevant data such as service computation date for leave, date probationary period began, and date of performance rating.</p>
<p>3. Position and pay data such as pay plan, occupational series, grade, step, salary, merit pay, organization location, length of service.</p>
<p>4. Employment data such as position description, special employment program, and target occupational series and grade.</p>
<p>5. Payroll data such as time; attendance; leave; federal, state, and local tax; allotments; savings bonds; and other pay allowances and deductions.</p>
<p>6. Personnel security data such as security clearance level and basis with dates.</p>
<p>7. Financial data pertaining to travel, financial obligation documents, support documentation to payment schedules and collection transactions.</p>
<p>8. Information on debts and debtors owed to the government as a result of overpayment, refund owed, or a debt referred for collection to another agency. This includes employees and former employees who have a liability to the Commission.</p>
<p>9. Information, including address and social security number, on individual vendors to the Commission. This includes employees who receive reimbursements for expenses incurred. Supporting documentation on action made to contractors are part of the payment schedule maintained in hard copy form and filed onsite at ESC for a minimum of one year from the time the action is taken. ESC provides full accounting services for CPSC.</p>
<p>10. Emergency contact information including name, address, phone number.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. Part III, is the authority for the overall system. Specific authority for use of Social Security numbers is contained in Executive Order 9397, 26 CFR 31.6011(b)(2), and 26 CFR 31.6109-1. The authority for the personnel security clearance and statistical records is contained in Executive Order 19450, April 27, 1953, as amended; Executive Order 12065, June 28, 1978; 31 U.S.C. 686; and 40 U.S.C. 318(a) through (d). The legal authority for the FPPS and Quicktime applications is defined in the Office of Management and Budget Circular A-127.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The primary uses of the records are for fiscal operations for payroll, attendance, leave, insurance, tax, retirement, business payments, budget, and cost accounting programs, and to prepare related reports to other federal agencies including the Department of the Treasury and the Office of Personnel Management.</p>
<p>This system supports the day to day operating requirements associated with personnel and finance oriented program areas from hiring employees and paying employees and vendors to calculating estimated retirement annuities. Payroll-related outputs include a comprehensive payroll; detailed accounting distribution of costs; leave data summary reports; an employee's statement of earnings, deductions and leave every payday for each employee; State, city, and local unemployment compensation reports; federal, state, and local tax reports; W-2 wage and tax statements; and reports of withholdings and contributions. Personnel-related reports include automated personnel actions as well as organization rosters, retention registers, retirement calculations, reports of the federal civilian employment, employee master record printouts, length of service lists, and listings of within-grade increases. These records are used to provide data for agency reports and internal workforce statistics and information regarding such matters as average grade, veteran and handicap employment, retention-standing, within-grade due dates, occupational groupings, geographic employment and others related to the operation of the personnel office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Routine uses of records maintained in the system include:
</p><p>1. Providing data to the Office of Personnel Management's Central Personnel Data File (CPDF).</p>
<p>2. Providing a copy of an employee's Department of the Treasury Form W-2, Wage and Tax Statement, to the State, city, or other local jurisdiction which is authorized to tax the employee's compensation. The record will be provided in accordance with a withholding agreement between the State, city, or other local jurisdiction and the Department of the Treasury pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 5516, 5517, and 5520.</p>
<p>3. Pursuant to a withholding agreement between a city and the Department of the Treasury (5 U.S.C. 5520), copies of executed tax withholding certificates shall be furnished to the city in response to a written request from an appropriate city official to the Assistant Administrator for Plans, Programs, and Financial Management, General Services Administration (B), Washington, DC 20405.</p>
<p>4. To the extent necessary, records are available to Commission and outside government agencies to monitor and document grievance proceedings, and adverse actions; and to provide reference to other agencies and persons for employees seeking employment elsewhere.</p>
<p>5. Some records or data elements in this system of records may also be in the Office of Personnel Management's government-wide system OPM/GOVT-1 and are subject to that system's routine uses.</p>
<p>6. To disclose, in response to a request for discovery or for appearance of a witness, information that is relevant to the subject matter involved in a pending judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
<p>7. The names, social security numbers, home addresses, dates of birth, quarterly earnings, employer identifying information, and State of hire of employees may be disclosed to the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services for the purpose of locating individuals to establish paternity, establishing and modifying orders of child support, identifying sources of income, and for other child support enforcement actions as required by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act (Welfare Reform law, Pub. L. 104-193).</p>
<p>8. To the U.S. Department of Justice when related to litigation or anticipated litigation.</p>
<p>9. To the General Accounting Office in the event of a procurement protest involving an individual.</p>
<p>10. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>Disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12). Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), disclosures may be made to a consumer reporting agency as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored on paper in file folders and on computer based media.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are filed by document number. Computer records are retrievable by any data element or combination of data elements.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are stored in lockable metal cabinets or in secured rooms. Password system protects access to the computerized records. Information is released only to authorized officials on a need-to know basis.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Accountable officers' records are sent to the Federal Records Center one year after the end of the fiscal year to which they pertain and kept for 6 years and 3 months. Accountable officers' records include all records concerned with accounting for and availability of, and status of public funds, General Records Schedule 6. Payroll-related records follow General Records Schedule 2 and Personnel records follow General Records Schedule 1.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>For payroll and financial-related records:



</p><p>Director, Division of Financial Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p><p>For personnel-related records:
</p><p>Director, Office of Human Resources Management, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The individuals themselves, other employees, supervisors, other agencies' management officials, non-federal sources such as private firms, and data from the systems of records OPM/GOVT-1 and EEOC/GOVT-1.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Employee Relations Files.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources Management, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4430 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system of records contains information or documents relating to: (1) Disciplinary actions, complaints, grievances, potential adverse actions, and proposals, decisions, or determinations made by management relative to the foregoing; The records consist of the notices to the individuals, records of resolutions of complaints, materials placed into the record to support the decision or determination, affidavits or statements and (2) retirement records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 1302, 3301, 4308, 5115, 5338, 7151, 7301, 7701, 8347; Executive Orders 9830, 10987, 11222, 11478.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information in the records may be used as a data source for management information for production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the records are collected and maintained, or for related personnel management functions or manpower studies; may also be utilized to respond to general requests for statistical information (without personal identification of individuals) under the Freedom of Information Act or to locate specific individuals for personnel research or other personnel management functions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an appeal, complaint or grievance.</p>
<p>2. To provide information to the public on the decision of an appeal, complaint, or grievance required by the Freedom of Information Act.</p>
<p>3. To respond to a court subpoena and/or refer to a district court in connection with a civil suit.</p>
<p>4. To adjudicate or resolve an appeal, complaint, or grievance.</p>
<p>5. To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>6. To request information from a federal, state or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement or other pertinent information, such as licenses, if necessary to obtain relevant information to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit.</p>
<p>7. To provide information or disclose to a federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, or issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision of that matter.</p>
<p>8. Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
<p>9. To disclose, in response to a request for discovery or for appearance of a witness, information that is relevant to the subject matter involved in a pending judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
<p>10. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>These records are maintained in file folders and computer based media.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are indexed by the names of the individuals on whom they are maintained.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in a combination lock metal file cabinet and access is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) For documents relating to disciplinary actions, complaints, grievances, and potential adverse actions, destroy no sooner than 7 years after case is closed. (2) For retirement records, transfer the records to the Office of Personnel Management after the employee retires, and retains copies for two years.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Deputy Director, Office of Human Resources Management, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records is furnished by: (1) Individual to whom the record pertains; (2) Agency officials; (3) Affidavits or statements from employee; (4) Testimonies of witnesses; (5) Official documents relating to appeal, grievance, or complaints; (6) Correspondence from specific organizations or persons.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Commissioned Officers' Personal Data File.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>A complete record on every commissioned officer is maintained in the Office of Compliance and Field Operations to which the commissioned officer is assigned</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>State employees commissioned as officers of CPSC</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The database system contains documents related to the commissioning of the individual and personal data including name, social security number, date of birth, educational background, employment history, medical information, home address and phone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Section 29(a)(2), Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2078(a)(2)); E.O. 10450, sections 8(c), 9(a), 9(b); E.O. 10561.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Used by agency officials for purposes of review in connection with issuance, distribution, use and return of official Commission credentials to commissioned state and local officials.</p>
<p>2. To provide statistical reports to Congress, agencies and the public on characteristics of the Commissioned officer program.</p>
<p>3. As a data source for management information for production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the records are collected and maintained, or for related personnel management functions or manpower studies; may also be utilized to respond to general requests for statistical information without personal identification of individuals under the Freedom of Information Act or to locate specific individuals for personnel research or other personal management functions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To provide information to a federal or state agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, or other benefit by the requesting agency.</p>
<p>2. To request information from a federal, state, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement or other pertinent information if necessary to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning the commissioning or recommissioning of an individual.</p>
<p>3. Disclosure to a congressional office in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
<p>4. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p><i>Disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12).</i> Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), disclosures may be made to a consumer reporting agency as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in a centralized database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by state and by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or metal file cabinets in secured rooms with access limited to those whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with Commission records management policies and procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Compliance and Field Operations, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records comes either from the individual to whom it pertains or from agency officials, CPSC supervisors, or state officials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc20" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>20</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security File.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources Management, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees of the Consumer Product Safety Commission and applicants for employment with the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Results of name checks, inquiries, and investigations furnished by the Office of Personnel Management or other approved government investigative agency, to determine suitability for employment with, or continued employment by, the Consumer Product Safety Commission. Information in records may include date and place of birth, citizenship, marital status, military status, and social security status. These records contain investigative information regarding an individual's character, conduct, and behavior in the community where he or she lives or lived; arrests and convictions for any violations of law; information from present and former supervisors, co-workers, associates, educators; credit and National Agency checks; and other information developed from the above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 10450; 5 U.S.C. 301.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The records in this system of records are used by the Director, Office of Human Resources and the Personnel Security Officer to determine whether the employment of an applicant, or retention of a current employee, is in the interest of the Commission and to determine whether to grant an employee or contractor access to non-public information or restricted areas.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To request from a federal, state, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information, data relevant to a Commission decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance to an employee, or other administrative action concerning an employee.</p>
<p>2. To the Office of Personnel Management in their role as an investigating agency, and in their role as the agency responsible for conducting a continuing assessment of agency compliance with federal personnel security and suitability program requirements.</p>
<p>3. To the Office of Personnel Management for use in other personnel matters.</p>
<p>4. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in file folders and on computer based media.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a safe-type combination lock file cabinet in the custody of the Office of Human Resources Management. Access is limited to the Personnel Security Officer, the Deputy Director, Office of Human Resources Management.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at the Consumer Product Safety Commission for at least two years from the date of any final decision placed in the record.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Deputy Director, Office of Human Resources Management, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification. The Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer will forward the request to the agency which conducted the investigation, which will make the final determination.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Personnel Management reports and reports from other federal agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
    <section id="cpsc23" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-23</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName"> Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) Disability/ Accommodation Files.</subsection>
        <subsection type="SECURITYCLASSIFICATION">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <P>None.</P>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="SYSTEMLOCATION">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Equal Employment Opportunity and Minority Enterprise, U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
                <subsection type="systemManager">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Director, Office of Equal Employment Opportunity and Minority Enterprise, U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Executive Order 14043, Requiring Coronavirus Disease 2019 Vaccination for Federal Employees (Sept. 9, 2021), Executive Order 13991, Protecting the Federal Workforce and Requiring Mask-Wearing (Jan. 20, 2021), Executive Order 12196, Occupational Safety and Health Program for Federal Employees (Feb. 26, 1980), Executive Order 11478 (Aug. 8, 1969), 5 U.S.C. chapters 11 and 79, the Rehabilitation Act, 29 U.S.C. 794, the Americans with Disabilities Act, 42 U.S.C. 12101, Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42 U.S.C. 2000e, and CPSC’s Directive on Equal Employment Opportunity and Procedures for Filing Complaints of Discrimination.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="purpose">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>The purposes of this system are: (1) to allow CPSC to collect and maintain records on prospective, current, and former employees with disabilities or sincerely held religious beliefs, practices, or observances who requested or received reasonable accommodation by CPSC; (2) to track and report the processing of requests for reasonable accommodation at CPSC to comply with applicable law and regulations; and (3) to maintain the confidentiality of medical or religious information submitted by or on behalf of applicants or employees requesting reasonable accommodation.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Individuals, classes of individuals, or representatives designated to act on behalf of CPSC employees, former employees, or applicants for employment who have 1) consulted with an Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) counselor and/or 2) who have filed a formal complaint alleging discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, sex (including gender identity and pregnancy), national origin, disability, age, genetic information, sexual orientation, parental status and/or any basis covered by Executive Order 11478, because of a determination, decision, action, or non-action administered against them by a departmental official, as well as individuals alleging reprisal for having previously participated in EEO activity and/or 3) who have filed a request for a medical or religious reasonable accommodation.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Correspondence and supporting documentation submitted to the Commission to request reasonable accommodations. Records contain information such as name, address, city, state, telephone number and other pertinent information related to the individual’s request for reasonable accommodation.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Information in these records is furnished by: (1) individual to whom the record pertains; (2) CPSC officials; (3) affidavits or statements from employee; (4) testimonies of witnesses; (5) official documents relating to appeals, grievances, or complaints; (6) correspondence from specific organizations or persons.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), and:</p>
                        1.	<p>To physicians or other medical professionals to provide them with or obtain from them the necessary medical documentation and/or certification for reasonable accommodation.</p>
                        2.	<p>To another federal agency or commission with responsibility for labor or employment relations or other issues, including equal employment opportunity and reasonable accommodation issues, when that agency or commission has jurisdiction over reasonable accommodation issues.</p>
                        3.	<p>To the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Department of Labor (DOL), Office of Personnel Management (OPM), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), or Office of Special Counsel (OSC) to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements related to reasonable accommodations.</p>
                        4.	<p>To appropriate third-parties contracted by the Agency to facilitate mediation or other dispute resolution procedures or programs.</p>
                        5.	<p>To the Department of Defense (DOD) for purposes of procuring assistive technologies and services through the Computer/Electronic Accommodation Program in response to a request for reasonable accommodation.</p>
                        6.	<p>To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records, (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CPSC (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                        7.	<p>To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when CPSC determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records will be maintained in hard copy in file folders or on computer disk/drive.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retrievability">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records will be indexed and retrieved by name.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a CPSC records disposition schedule approved by NARA. Records existing on paper are destroyed beyond recognition.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="safeguards">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records are maintained in locked/password protected files in a secured environment; access is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>CPSC’s access and amendment regulations are found at 16 C.F.R. Part 1014. Inquiries should be sent to CPSC’s Chief FOIA Officer, Office of the General Counsel, Division of the Secretariat, U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Same as notification.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Same as notification.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>
                            None.
                        </p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="history">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>CPSC – 23, Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) Disability/Accommodation files (last published at 77 FR 29596 (May 18, 2012)).</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
            </section>

            <section id="cpsc24" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-24</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Respirator Program Medical Reports.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Facilities Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>CPSC employees whose jobs may require them to wear respirators.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Medical reports indicating (a) approval or disapproval for an employee's use of respirators; (b) allowable level of exertion and any medical conditions relevant to the use of respirators; and (c) recommended interval until next medical evaluation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>29 CFR 1910.134(b)(10).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used to keep track of employees who are authorized to work in hazardous environments requiring the use of respirators and to schedule repeat medical examinations for those employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in hard copy.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name of employee.



</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a combination lock safe-type filing cabinet.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained until termination of employment with CPSC.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Facilities Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is provided by the medical facility performing the medical evaluations. The evaluation is based in part on information provided by the employee to the medical facility.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc25" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-25</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">FOIA Express System of Records (FOIAXpress).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who request information from the Consumer Product Safety Commission pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondence and email requests for information submitted to the Commission which may contain personal information about individuals, e.g., name, address, city, state, telephone number, fax and email address and other pertinent information related to processing and responding to their FOIA and/or Privacy Act request.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552 and 5 U.S.C. 552a.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used by Commission staff responding to the request for information so that requests can be tracked and responded to accurately and in a timely manner.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. These records are used to record the requesting individual's address so a response can be forwarded.</p>
<p>2. These records are used to record the specific information that the individual is seeking so that the information we provide is responsive to the request.</p>
<p>3. Staff will search the records to determine which requests have been filled and which are still pending.</p>
<p>4. CPSC will use these records to prepare an annual report of FOIA activities at the end of each fiscal year and submit the report to the Attorney General, through the Department of Justice, Office of Information and Privacy.</p>
<p>5. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records will be entered into a database tracking system and given a request number. All information will be stored electronically and paper requests will eventually be destroyed.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records will mainly be retrieved using the FOIA request number, however, records may also be retrieved by searching on a requester's first and last names, category (consumer, student, attorney, etc.), job title, address, city, state, zip code, a company name or entry date and closed date.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are protected by passwords available only to staff with a need to know.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records will be stored electronically for 2 to 6 years, contingent upon the National Archives Records Administration (NARA's General Records Schedule 14).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Alberta E. Mills, FOIA Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal information in these records is obtained from the individual requesting the information under FOIA or Privacy Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc26" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Learning Management System.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Information Technology, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>CPSC employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information concerning training courses that an employee takes during the year. The employee enters a training request by entering their social security number, date of birth, course title, vendor name, course location and other OPM specific data fields that pertain to the collection of training records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. Chapter 41--Training; 5 CFR part 410.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used by Commission to respond to Office of Personnel Management's requirements that all federal agencies submit training reports on a monthly basis. The reports must include employee social security number and date of birth.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. These records are used by CPSC to record training information for all employees.</p>
<p>2. CPSC will use these records to submit monthly training reports to OPM.</p>
<p>3. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records will be entered into a database tracking system and stored electronically.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records will mainly be retrieved using the employee's last name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are protected by passwords available only to staff with a need to know.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Training records will be stored electronically for five years.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Human Resources, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Personal information in these records is obtained from the individual requesting training.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc27" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-27</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Requests for Information.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Communications, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814,
</p><p>Hotline managed by Systems Integration Incorporated, 8201 Corporate Drive, Suite 300, Landover, MD 20785.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons who contact the Consumer Product Safety Commission to request information and publications.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records contain personal information such as the name, address, email, and telephone number of the person submitting the request for information. Requests can be received through CPSC's toll free hotline, internet Web site, and through correspondence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Section 5 of the Consumer Product Safety Act, 15 U.S.C. 2054.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record personal information so that information and publications may be mailed or otherwise provided.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Records are disclosed to contractor personnel who operate the Consumer Product Safety Commission's Hotline and who enter data into the database.</p>
<p>2. Records may be used by CPSC staff and contract staff to respond to the request for information.</p>
<p>3. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The contractor maintains Hotline records in a computer database management system on a local and wide area network.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by a variety of fields, including the name of the person who submitted the request for information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to the Hotline computer records requires the use of two passwords: One to access the agency's computer network and another to access the database. Access is limited to those with a particular need to know the information -- select Commission employees and the contractor employees who operate the Hotline.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained indefinitely. Paper records are kept for 10 years and then transferred to a Federal Records Center.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Hotline Contract Officer, Office of Communications, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records is initially supplied by persons who contact the Commission.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="cpsc28" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-28</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Emergency Contact Information Systems for the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814, and field offices throughout the United States.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees, former employees, and other individuals having business with the Commission who have provided emergency contact information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in the records may include home phone numbers, cellular phone numbers, pager numbers, numbers where individuals can be reached while on travel or otherwise away from the office, home addresses, electronic mail addresses, driver's license information, and phone numbers of family members or other contacts, and other contact information provided by individuals covered by this system of records to the Commission.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain contact information on employees and other individuals in case of emergencies involving an employee or the Commission, or when necessary for official purposes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the conditions of disclosure under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), Commission staff may provide these records to any Federal, State, local or other public authorities for the purpose of coordinating and reviewing agency continuity of operations plans or emergency contingency plans developed for responding to security threats, weather related emergencies or other critical situations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in electronic form, on paper, plastic laminated cards, lists on shared computer drives, or lists maintained on telephones or other devices issued by the Commission.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is retrieved by name of the individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are safeguarded by restricted computer passwords, Secure Zip software, and/or locked in file cabinets. Access to the records is restricted to those who require the records in the performance of official duties related to the purposes for which the system is maintained.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Periodic purging and disposal of those records concerning individuals no longer members, employees or contractors of the Commission. Otherwise, records are retained and disposed of in accordance with the appropriate National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>The system managers for emergency notification files are the Directors for the individual offices maintaining the records 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, Maryland 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Request for access must be in writing and should be addressed to the Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals desiring to contest or amend information maintained in the system should direct their request to the Privacy Act Officer listed above, stating clearly and concisely what information is being contested, the reasons for contesting it, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in emergency notification files is obtained from CPSC employees and contractors whose names appear on emergency contact lists and forms</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc29" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-29</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Request Tracking System for Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) and Privacy Act (PA) requests.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Secretariat, Freedom of Information Office and National Injury Information Clearinghouse Office, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, Maryland 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have requested CSPC records pursuant to the Freedom of Information and/or Privacy Acts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records describe incoming FOIA requests, request identification number, contact/affiliation information for individuals requesting records, action taken, description of records released or denied, fees charged/waived, and final outcome of request.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552 and 15, U.S.C. 2055.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The system is maintained for the purpose of processing records requests under FOIA and to prepare related reports.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under FOIA and the PA, the records maintained in the system may also be used for the following:
</p><p>1. Used by the CPSC Clearinghouse staff to assure that each request is processed and receives an appropriate response and to compile data for required annual reports on activities under the FOIA.</p>
<p>2. As a data source for management information and analytical studies in support of the function for which the records are collected and maintained or for related personnel management functions or manpower studies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records in file folders. An index is maintained in a computer database.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By the request identification number, name of requester, type of requester, product code.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secure, access-controlled file room and lockable file cabinets.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in accordance with CPSC Records Control Schedules as applicable to the General Records Schedule, published by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director and Lead Technical Information Specialist, Office of the National Injury Information Clearinghouse, and Freedom of Information Officer, Office of the Secretariat Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, Maryland, 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to this or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of the record, should write to the Freedom of Information Officer, Office of the Secretariat, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Request for access to records in this system may be made by writing to the Freedom of Information Officer at CPSC, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for correction or amendment must be submitted in writing to the address indicated above (see "Record Access Procedures" above). Request must adequately describe the corrective action sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Incoming Freedom of Information Act requests.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc30" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-30</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">CPSC Transit Subsidy Benefit Program.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Facilities Services, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4430 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>CPSC employees who are applicants and recipients of fare subsidies issued by the Department of Transportation (DOT).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee applications for fare subsidies. Applications include name, address, date of birth, last four digits of social security number, smart trip card serial number, work email address, effective date of program participation, value of fare media provided, and effective date of termination.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 12191 and Public Law 103-172
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Fare subsidy management.
 </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Used as part of a program designed to ensure eligibility for, and prevent misuse of funds. Disclosures may be made from this system to consumer reporting agencies (collecting on behalf of the United States Government) as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1982 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)). Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Hard copy records are stored in locking file cabinets and electronic records are stored on computers in a document library on the agency's internal document management site, which is available only to staff with a need to know.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are filed alphabetically and retrievable by employee name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are kept in locked cabinets in a secure area. Computer records are protected on document management sites available only to staff whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Electronic and hard copies of applications are retained for three years and then destroyed in accordance with General Records Schedule Number 9, Item 7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Information Technology, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications submitted by individuals for fare subsidies; notifications from DOT; and periodic certifications and reports regarding fare subsidies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc31" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-31</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Contests, Challenges, and Awards Programs.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Communications, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Members of the public, including individuals who are minors and/or the parents or guardians of minors, and companies and organizations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Information in the records may include the individuals’ names, telephone numbers, e-mail addresses, ages, grade levels in school, street addresses, company names, organization’s names, posters, videos, products, or other submissions made by individuals for contests, challenges or awards.  For contests where minors are the entrants, CPSC may collect the above-listed information for the parents or guardians of the contest entrants.  Contest entrants who win prizes from CPSC are required to provide their social security numbers so that monetary payments can be processed by the U.S. government and the value of any prize can be reported to the U.S. government.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>15 U.S.C. 205(9b), OMB Memorandum on the Use of Challenges and Prizes to Promote Open Government, M-10-11, March 8, 2010 </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>CPSC hosts contests, challenges, and award programs to educate the public, including adults and children, about product safety to prevent injuries and deaths associated with product hazards, and to identify and honor people and organizations that have made significant contributions to consumer product safety.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained for the contest, challenge, or award program for purposes of evaluating contest submissions, contacting winners and finalists, awarding prizes and reporting prize awards as may be required by law. Categories of users include CPSC employees, contractors, and websites hosting challenges for CPSC. </p>
<p>Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist with the CPSC’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Once the contest or challenge is completed, CPSC’s Office of the Secretariat maintains for two years hard or electronic copies of posters, videos, information/photos about products that may contain contact information for the contest, challenge, or award program participants. After that time, the copies are destroyed.  </p>
<p>Storage:</p><p>Posters, videos, or other submissions for contests, challenges, or awards may be stored by CPSC for use by the agency, for use in agency displays, or for disclosure in response to requests under the Freedom of Information Act.  Posters, videos, or other submissions are stored in locked file cabinets in the Office of the Secretariat or in secure electronic format.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Contest submissions (including posters and videos) become the property of CPSC, according to the agency’s published contest rules and are not returned to the submitter.  Access to the submissions may be requested to the Office of the Secretariat under the Freedom of Information Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Posters, videos, or other submissions are kept by CPSC’s Office of the Secretariat in locked file cabinets or in securer electronic format.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Posters, videos, or other submissions are disposed of after two years by CPSC’s Office of the Secretariat.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Office of Communications, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD  20814.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Same as notification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Same as notification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The information is provided by the contest, challenge, or award program participant, the participant’s parent or guardian, or the participant’s company.  

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc32" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-32</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Correspondence Tracking System (CTS).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Offices of the Secretariat and Small Business Ombudsman, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 430 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>The categories of individuals in the CTS include members of Congress, the President of the United States, the Vice President of the United States, members of the public at large, the business community subject to Commission regulations and standards, and CPSC employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Members of the public at large: individual's name, home address, home telephone number(s), personal cell phone number(s), and other miscellaneous information that an individual may include in his/her complaint, comments, or questions to the CPSC.</p>
<p>2. Members of the business community: individual's name, home address, home telephone number(s), personal cell phone number(s), and other miscellaneous information that an individual may include in his/her complaint, comment, or question to the CPSC.</p>
<p>3. CPSC employees: individual's name, work telephone number, and other miscellaneous information that a Commission employee may include in a response to members of Congress, the President and/or Vice President, members of the public at large, and/or the business community.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301 and 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The CPSC uses the Correspondence Tracking System (CTS) to store, track, and manage correspondence to and from members of Congress, the President of the United States, the Vice President of the United States, members of the public at large, the business community, and CPSC employees. This correspondence may include attachments that could contain PII from individuals (members of the public and business community at large) who contacted the Commission concerning various product safety issues affecting them, e.g., telephone number and address, etc.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To the U.S. Department of Justice when related to litigation or anticipated litigation.</p>
<p>2. To the appropriate Federal, State, or local investigation or enforcement agency when there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of a statute or regulation in connection with procurement.</p>
<p>3. To a Congressional office in response to an inquiry made at the request of the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
<p>4. To the U.S. Government Accountability Office in the event of a procurement protest involving the individual.</p>
<p>5. To the Office of Financial Management in an effort to properly process payment of invoices.</p>
<p>6. To the Office of the Secretariat, Freedom of Information Officer, to properly process incoming FOIA requests in accordance with the Freedom of Information Act.</p>
<p>7. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) the CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) CPSC has determined that as a result of suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The information in the CTS includes paper documents, records, and files that are stored in file cabinets, and electronic records, files, and data that are stored in the Commission's computer network databases.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records may be filed by and retrievable by name of the document's author or addressee or by other indicia. Computer records are indexed by, and retrievable by the names and other indicia of authors and addressees, and may permit retrieval by names elsewhere in documents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to the electronic files, which are housed in the Commission's computer network databases, is restricted to authorized supervisors and staff and to the Information Technology (IT) staff who maintain the Commission's computer network. Other CPSC employees and contractors may be granted access on a "need-to-know" basis. The CPSC computer network databases are protected by security protocols, which include controlled access, passwords, and other security features. Information resident on the database servers are backed-up routinely onto a hard disk array and computer based media. Back-up tapes are stored on-site and at a secured, off-site location. Hard copy records are maintained in secured file cabinets.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>There is no established record retention schedule for this system. Records will be kept indefinitely until a records schedule is established.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of the Secretariat, and Small Business Ombudsman, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The sources for the information in the CTS are submitted by members of Congress, the President of the United States, the Vice President of the United States, members of the public at large, the business community subject to Commission regulations and standards, and CPSC employees. This information may include complaints, comments, or questions related to product safety issues under CPSC jurisdiction.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="cpsc33" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-33</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">International Trade Data System Risk Assessment Methodology System (ITDS/RAM).</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>The system contains names, social security numbers, and addresses associated with individuals and businesses importing materials into the United States. Information on individuals is stored only when they register as the entity in the transaction; usually, this is a business entity with an associated Importer Number and business addresses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Members of the Consumer Products Trading Community: Usually business name and address. For individuals and small businesses where an individual provides personal information, their name and address is maintained.</p>
<p>2. Importation transactions as reported by U.S. Customs and Border Protection (U.S. CBP) for all product areas under jurisdiction at entry summary filing and for product areas of specific concern for hazard monitoring and enforcement programs at entry filing (Cargo).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Sec. 222 P.L. 110-314, 15 U.S.C. 2066(a).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The U.S. CPSC uses the ITDS/RAM to monitor and request examination for shipments that are potentially in violation of safety standards enforced by the Commission or potentially defective as a part of a product group that has been designated by the Commission as having properties that are hazardous. Personally Identifiable Information (PII) could be used for monitoring and requesting exams, but only between government agencies (CPSC and U.S. CBP).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To the U.S. Department of Justice when related to litigation or anticipated litigation. To the appropriate Federal enforcement agency/agencies when there is an indication of a potential violation of a statute or regulation or a predetermined hazard in connection with an importation.</p>
<p>2. Disclosure may be made to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the CPSC suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the CPSC has determined that as a result of suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by CPSC or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the CPSC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The information in the ITDS/RAM includes electronic records, files, and data that are stored in the Commission's computer network databases.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are indexed by, and retrievable by, names and addresses, and may permit retrieval by names elsewhere in documents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to electronic files, which are housed in the Commission's computer network databases, is restricted to authorized supervisors and staff and to designated Information Technology (IT) staff who maintain the Commission's computer network. CPSC project contractors may be granted access with appropriate clearance and only in support of the performance of the system. The CPSC computer network databases are protected by security protocols, which include controlled access, passwords, and other security features. Information resident on the database servers is backed-up routinely onto a hard disk array and computer based media. Back-up tapes are stored on-site and at a secured, off-site location. Hard copy records are maintained in secured file cabinets.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>There is no established record retention schedule for this system. Records will be kept indefinitely until a records schedule is established and approved and then in accordance with the applicable schedule.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Import Surveillance and Inspection, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is provided and updated on a periodic basis by U.S. CBP.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="cpsc34" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-34</systemNumber> 
<subsection type="systemName">Mailing and Other Lists.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Individuals covered by the new system of records include individuals who have indicated an interest in receiving CPSC materials or who are participants or contacts in connection with matters under consideration at CPSC, and other individuals who may be contacts, resources, or leads for various CPSC subject matter areas or programs.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p> The records in the new system may include some or all of the following information:  name; title; company, organization or affiliation; address; telephone number; e-mail or internet address.  This system includes mailing lists, contact lists, address lists, and information developed from business cards, sign-in sheets or rosters compiled at meetings.  This system excludes mailing or contact lists or similar records collected or maintained under other CPSC systems of records.  For example, addresses or other contact information for individuals who import materials into the United States are covered by CPSC-33 (International Trade Data System Risk Assessment Methodology System (ITDS/RAM)).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p> 44 U.S.C. 3101; CPSC Directives Order No. 0730.1 (Revised 2/06).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system of records is used to assist in the dissemination of CPSC information and documents to individuals, organizations, businesses, and other contacts in accordance with applicable legal constraints, and to maintain lists of business or other contacts for future reference, in furtherance of the CPSC"s mission to protect the public against unreasonable risks of injury associated with the use of consumer products.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed to authorized entities, as is determined to be relevant and necessary, outside CPSC as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3), as follows:</p>
<p>1. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration for use in records management inspections.</p>
<p>2. Contractors, agents, or other authorized individuals performing work on a contract, service, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity on behalf of CPSC or Federal Government and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p> Records are maintained in electronic format and paper form.  Electronic records are stored in computerized databases.  Other records are maintained in locked file cabinets or in agency office space whose access is limited to those with authorization.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Information about individuals maintained in mailing lists and other information covered by this system of records may be retrieved by the individual"s name, an employer or institutional or organizational affiliation name, the individual or organization category on mailing list, the city or zip code, or by any other personal identifiers.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Access to electronic records is restricted to authorized personnel who have been issued non-transferrable access codes and passwords.  Other records are maintained in locked file cabinets or in agency office space whose access is limited to those with authorization.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p> CPSC personnel revise the lists as necessary.  The records can be destroyed when deemed no longer useful.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Secretary, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Individuals wishing to determine whether this system of records contains information about them may inquire in writing in accordance with the instructions appearing at 16 CFR part 1014.  The request will be made to Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretariat, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Same as notification.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Same as notification.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p> These records contain information developed from publicly available information, information obtained from the relevant individual, information from business cards, sign-in sheets or rosters compiled at meetings, or from other sources.  Information in this system of records may also be obtained from other CPSC records systems.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p> None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="cpsc2021" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-2021</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName"> Consumer Ombudsman Inquiry Database.</subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Not Classified.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD 20814.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Consumer Ombudsman, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD, 20814, 301-504-8120, consumerombudsman@cpsc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S. Code § 301</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The CPSC uses this system to store, track, and manage inquiries received by the Consumer Ombudsman from members of the public at large. These inquiries may include PII from individuals who contacted the Commission concerning product safety issues affecting them, e.g., telephone number and address.  </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Members of the public-at-large, who have contacted the Commission with a product safety concern or question.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Members of the public-at-large: individual’s name, home address, home telephone number(s), personal cell phone number(s), electronic email address, and other miscellaneous information that an individual may include in a comment or questions to the CPSC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records can be submitted by direct phone call, electronic mail, Information Center referral, staff referral, or website input.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Staff uses the information in the system to reply to consumer inquiries through electronic mail, telephone, or postal mail.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The information in this system includes paper documents, records, and files that are stored in cabinets, and electronic records, files, and data that are stored in the Commission’s computer network databases.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records can be filed and retrieved by the name of the inquirer or by other indicia. Computer records are indexed by, and retrievable by, date of submission, names, and other indicia.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The agency's Office of the General Counsel, Division of the Secretariat and the National Archives and Records Administration will determine a records schedule for this system, which will be an agency-specific records schedule with retention periods determined with a set period, along with an option to retain for longer periods, if necessary, for business use.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The CPSC computer network databases are protected by security protocols, which include controlled access, passwords, and other security features. Paper documents will be secured in a locked office. The agency IT staff limits access to the system by putting users into predefined user roles with specific permissions for each role that dictates what abilities each user has on the system. Once a user is logged into the system, the software records when each visit occurred and logs every page and action performed on each site with the user's corresponding IP address. Only staff having an IT duty will be given permission in their user roles to access the system.  IT staff have documented controls governing access to the system, which require manager approval.  However, each accessing event does not require manager approval.  Once a user has been assigned a role that allows access, then the individual can access the system, as needed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Consumer Ombudsman, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD, 20814, 301-504-8120, consumerombudsman@cpsc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Consumer Ombudsman, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD, 20814, 301-504-8120, consumerombudsman@cpsc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Consumer Ombudsman, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, MD, 20814, 301-504-8120, consumerombudsman@cpsc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>N/A – This is a new SORN for a new system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <appendix id="app1" toc="yes">
<title> Appendix I Regional Office Addresses</title>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Central Regional Center, 230 S. Dearborn Street, Room 2944, Chicago, Illinois 60604-1601.
</p><p>Eastern Regional Center, 6 World Trade Center, Room 350, New York, New York 10048-0206.
</p><p>Western Regional Center, 600 Harrison Street, Room 245, San Francisco, California 94107-1370.
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>

<appendix id="app2" toc="yes">
<title>Appendix II Pertinent Record Systems of Other Agencies </title>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Other Federal agencies maintain government-wide systems of records which may contain information about CPSC employees. Some of these records may be physically located at CPSC. These systems include:
</p><p>1. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-1, General Personnel Records (includes official personnel folders).
</p><p>2. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-2, Employee Performance File System Records.
</p><p>3. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-3, Records of Adverse Actions, Performance Based Reduction in Grade and Removal Actions, and Termination of Probationers.
</p><p>4. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-5, Recruiting, Examining, and Placement Records.
</p><p>5. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-6, Personnel Research and Test Validation Records.
</p><p>6. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-7, Applicant Race, Sex, National Origin, and Disability Status Records.
</p><p>7. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-9, File on Position Classification Appeals, Job Grading Appeals, and Retained Grade or Pay Appeals.
</p><p>8. Office of Personnel Management, OPM/GOVT-10, Employee Medical File System Records.
</p><p>9. Office of Government Ethics, OGE/GOVT-1, Executive Branch Public Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Ethics Program Records (includes financial interest disclosure forms of CPSC employees subject to the Ethics in Government Act).
</p><p>10. Office of Government Ethics, OGE/GOVT-2, Confidential Statements of Employment and Financial Interests.
</p><p>11. Office of Special Counsel, OSC/GOVT-1, Complaint, Litigation and Political Activity Files.
</p><p>12. Federal Emergency Management Agency, FEMA/GOVT-1, Uniform Identification System for Federal Employees Performing Essential Duties During Emergencies.
</p><p>13. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, EEOC/GOVT-1, Equal Employment Opportunity in the Federal Government Complaint and Appeal Records.
</p><p>14. Merit System protection Board, MSPB/GOVT-1, Appeal and Case Records.</p>
<p>15. General Services Administration, GSA/GOVT-3, Travel Charge Card Program.
</p><p>16. General Services Administration, GSA/GOVT-4, Contracted Travel Services Program.
</p><p>17. Department of Labor, DOL/GOVT-1, Office of Workers Compensation Programs, Federal Employees Compensation Act Files.
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>

	 

<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="16">
<heading> Commercial Practices </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="II">
<heading> Consumer Product Safety Commission </heading>
<regulationsPart number="1014">
<heading> POLICIES AND PROCEDURES IMPLEMENTING THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>1014.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>1014.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>1014.3 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records.
</p>
<p>1014.4 Requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</p>
<p>1014.5 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</p>
<p>1014.6 Request for correction or amendment to a record.
</p>
<p>1014.7 Agency review of request for correction or amendment of a record.
</p>
<p>1014.8 Appeal of initial denial of access, correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>1014.9 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</p>
<p>1014.10 Fees.
</p>
<p>1014.11 Penalties.
</p>
<p>1014.12 Specific exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 40 FR 53381, Nov. 18, 1975, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.1 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>This part sets forth the regulations of the Consumer Product Safety Commission implementing the Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579). The purpose of these regulations is to inform the public about records maintained by the Commission which contain personal information about individuals, and to inform those individuals how they may seek access to and correct records concerning themselves. These regulations do not apply to requests for information made pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act (except where such disclosures would constitute an invasion of privacy of an individual).
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.2 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>As used in this part:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Individual</i> means a person who is a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Privacy Act</i> means the Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579).
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Record</i> means any item of personal information relating to an individual, such as educational, employment, financial or medical information.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>System of records</i> or <i>records systems</i> means a group of records maintained by the Commission from which information may be retrieved by the name of an individual or some other individual identifier.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Maintain</i> includes the collection, use, storage, and dissemination of information.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.3 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual may request the Commission to inform him or her whether a particular record system named by the individual contains a record pertaining to him or her. The request may be made by mail or in person during business hours (8:30 a.m. to 5 p.m.) to the Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretary, Consumer Product Safety Commission, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, Maryland (mailing address: Consumer Product Safety Commission, Washington, DC 20207).
</p>
<p>(b) An individual who believes that the Commission maintains a record pertaining to him or her but who cannot determine which record system may contain the record, may request assistance by mail or in person at the Office of the Secretary during business hours.
</p>
<p>(c) A Commission officer or employee or former employee who desires to review or obtain a copy of a personnel record pertaining to him or her may make a request by mail or in person at the Office of Human Resources Management, Room 523, 4330 East West Highway, Bethesda, Maryland (mailing address: Consumer Product Safety Commission, Washington, DC 20207).
</p>
<p>(d) Each individual requesting the disclosure of a record or a copy of a record shall furnish the following information to the extent known with the request to the Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Officer or to the Division of Personnel?s Processing Unit, as applicable:
</p>
<p>(1) A description of the record sought;
</p>
<p>(2) The approximate date of the record;
</p>
<p>(3) The name or other description of the record system containing the record;
</p>
<p>(4) Proof as required in &#167; 1014.4 that he or she is the individual to whom the requested record relates; and
</p>
<p>(5) Any other information required by the notice describing the record system.
</p>
<p>(e) An individual personally inspecting his or her records may be accompanied by other persons of his or her own choosing. The individual shall sign a written statement authorizing disclosure of the record in the other person?s presence.
</p>
<p>(f) Any individual who desires to have a record concerning himself or herself disclosed to or mailed to another person may authorize that person to act as his or her agent for that specific purpose. The authorization shall be in writing, signed by the individual, and shall be notarized. An agent requesting the review or copy of another?s record shall submit with the request the authorization and proof of his or her identify as required by &#167; 1014.4(c).
</p>
<p>(g) The parent of any minor individual or the legal guardian of any individual who has been declared by a court of competent jurisdiction to be incompetent, due to physical or mental incapacity or age, may act on behalf of that individual in any matter covered by this part. A parent or guardian who desires to act on behalf of such individual shall present suitable evidence of parentage or guardianship, by birth certificate, certified copy of a court order, or similar documents, and proof of the individual?s identity in a form that complies with &#167; 1014.4(c).
</p>
<p>(h) An individual may request an accounting of all disclosures made to other persons or agencies of his or her record, except those disclosures made to law enforcement agencies pursuant to section (b)(7) of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(7)). A request for accounting, whenever made, shall be treated as a request for disclosure of records.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 53381, Nov. 18, 1975, as amended at 53 FR 52404, Dec. 28, 1988; 62 FR 46667, Sept. 4, 1997]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.4 Requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</b></p>
<p>The following proof of identity is required for requests for records made pursuant to &#167; 1014.3:
</p>
<p>(a) An individual seeking a record about himself or herself in person may establish his or her identity by the presentation of a single document bearing a photograph (such as a passport or driver?s license) or by a presentation of two items of identification which do not bear a photograph but do bear both a name and address. An individual who cannot provide documentation of his or her identity may provide a written statement affirming his or her identity and the fact that he or she understands the penalties for making false statements (18 U.S.C. 1001 and 5 U.S.C. 552a(i)(3)).
</p>
<p>(b) An individual seeking a record by mail shall include a statement signed by the individual and properly notarized, that he or she appeared before a notary public and submitted proof of identity acceptable to the notary public.
</p>
<p>(c) Requests made by an agent, parent, or guardian shall, in addition to establishing the identity of the minor or other person he or she represents as required by paragraphs (a) and (b), establish his or her agency, parentage, or guardianship by documentation.
</p>
<p>(d) In any case in which the Commission determines that the proof of identity is not adequate, it may request the individual to submit additional proof of identity.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.5 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Upon submission of proof of identity, the Office of the Secretary or the Director of Resource Utilization, as applicable, shall promptly forward the request to the system manager who will promptly allow the individual to see and/or have a copy of the requested record or send a copy of the record to the individual by mail, as requested by the individual. If the individual asks to see the record, the record should be made available for review and/or copying at the location where the record is maintained, in the Office of the Secretary, or the Director of Resource Utilization, or at the nearest Area Office.
</p>
<p>(b) If the system manager should determine, for any reason, that the requested records are exempt from the right of access, a notice of denial shall be sent to the requester stating the reasons for denial, and the requester?s right to appeal the denial in accordance with the procedures set forth in &#167; 1014.8 of these regulations.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.6 Request for correction or amendment to a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual who has reviewed a record pertaining to himself or herself may request the Executive Director to correct or amend all or any part of the record.
</p>
<p>(b) Each request for a correction or amendment of a record shall be in writing and shall contain the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) The name of the individual requesting the correction or amendment;
</p>
<p>(2) The name or other description of the system of records in which the record sought to be amended is maintained;
</p>
<p>(3) The location of that record in the system of records to the extent that it is known;
</p>
<p>(4) A copy of the record sought to be amended or a description of that record;
</p>
<p>(5) A statement of the material in the record that should be corrected or amended;
</p>
<p>(6) A statement of the specific wording of the correction or amendment sought; and
</p>
<p>(7) A statement of the basis for the requested correction or amendment including any material that the individual can furnish to substantiate the reasons for the amendment sought.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 53381, Nov. 18, 1975, as amended at 42 FR 22878, May 5, 1977]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.7 Agency review of request for correction or amendment of a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Not later than 10 working days after the receipt of the request for the correction or amendment of a record under &#167; 1014.6, the responsible Commission official shall acknowledge receipt of the request and inform the individual whether further information is required before the correction or amendment can be considered.
</p>
<p>(b) The responsible Commission official will promptly review the request and either make the requested correction or amendment or notify the individual of his or her refusal to do so, including in the notification the reasons for the refusal, and the appeal procedures provided by &#167; 1014.8.
</p>
<p>(c) The responsible Commission official will make each requested correction or amendment to a record if that correction or amendment will correct anything within the record that is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete. A copy of each corrected or amended record shall be furnished to the individual who requested the action. If an accounting of disclosure has been kept, all previous recipients of the record shall be notified of the correction and its substance.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.8 Appeal of initial denial of access, correction or amendment.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual whose request for access, correction or amendment to a record is denied, in whole or in part, may appeal that decision within 30 working days to the Chairman, Consumer Product Safety Commission, Washington, D.C. 20207.
</p>
<p>(b) The appeal shall be in writing and shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Name the individual making the appeal;
</p>
<p>(2) Identify the record to which access is sought or which is sought to be corrected or amended;
</p>
<p>(3) Name or describe the record system in which the record is contained;
</p>
<p>(4) Contain a short statement describing the correction of amendment sought;
</p>
<p>(5) State the name and location of the Commission official who initially denied the correction or amendment; and
</p>
<p>(6) State the date of the initial denial.
</p>
<p>(c) Not later than 30 working days after the date on which the appeal is received, the Chairman shall complete a review of the appeal and make a final decision thereon. However, for good cause shown, the Chairman of the Commission may extend the 30-day period. If the Chairman so extends the period, he or she shall promptly notify the individual requesting the review that the extension has been made.
</p>
<p>(d) If after review of an appeal request, the Chairman also refuses to amend the record or grant access to the record in accordance with the request, he or she shall send a written notice to the requester containing the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) The decision and the reasons for the decision;
</p>
<p>(2) The right of the requester to institute a civil action in a Federal District Court for judicial review of the decision; and
</p>
<p>(3) The right of the requester to file with the Chairman a concise statement setting forth the reasons for his or her disagreement with the denial of the correction or amendment. A copy of the statement of disagreement shall be filed with the record in issue, and the record in issue shall be so marked as to indicate that there is a disagreement. The system manager shall make the statement of disagreement available to prior recipients of the disputed record to the extent that an accounting of disclosures was maintained, and to any person to whom the record is later disclosed, together with a brief statement, if deemed appropriate, of the reasons for denying the requested correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 53381, Nov. 18, 1975, as amended at 42 FR 22878, May 5, 1977]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.9 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any person or agency (other than an officer or employee of the Commission who has a need for individual records in the performance of his or her duty) seeking disclosure of personal records of another individual which are contained in a system of records shall submit a request in accordance with the Commission?s Procedures for Disclosure of Production of Information under the Freedom of Information Act (16 CFR part 1015, subpart A).
</p>
<p>(b) The determination of whether or not the requested disclosure is proper will be made in accordance with the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552) and the Commission?s policies and procedures issued thereunder (16 CFR part 1015).
</p>
<p>[41 FR 30324, July 23, 1976]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.10 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>The Commission shall not charge an individual for the costs of making a search for a record, the costs of reviewing or copying a record, or the cost of correcting or amending a record.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.11 Penalties.
</b></p>
<p>Any person who makes a false statement in connection with any request for a record, or an amendment thereto, under this part, is subject to the penalties prescribed in 18 U.S.C. 494, 495, and 1001; and 5 U.S.C. 552a(i)(3).
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1014.12 Specific exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Injury information.</i> (1) The Bureau of Epidemiology maintains a file of Accident Reports (In-Depth Investigations) which are conducted on a sample of product related injuries reported to the Commission by selected hospital emergency rooms, by consumers through the Commission?s "Hot-Line"  telephone service and through written consumer complaints and by other means such as newspaper reports. The purpose of this record system is to compile accident statistics for analyzing the incidence and severity of product related injuries.
</p>
<p>(2) Inasmuch as the maintenance of the record system listed in paragraph (a)(1) of this section is authorized by section 5 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2054) and the data are used solely as statistical records, the system is exempted from the requirements of the Privacy Act relating to making available the accounting of disclosures, correction or amendment of the record and the application of these rules to the system of records. Specifically, the system is exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3); (d) (2) and (3); (e)(1); (e)(4) (G), (H) and (I); and (f). However, Accident Reports made by Commission employees are disclosable in accordance with paragraph (a)(3) of this section.
</p>
<p>(3) Section 25(c) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2074(c)) provides that accident or investigation reports made by an officer or employee of the Commission shall be made available to the public in a manner which will not identify any injured person or any person treating him or her, without the consent of the person identified. Consequently, an accident or investigation report which identifies individuals is available to the injured party or the person treating him or her but would not be available for disclosure to a third party without the consent of the injured party or person treating him or her.
</p>
<p>(4) Since accident or investigation reports are compiled only for statistical purposes and are not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an individual, they are exempted from the requirement to correct or amend a record as provided by subsection (d)(2) of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a (d)(2)). Exceptions from this paragraph, insofar as they relate to amendments or additions, may be allowed by the Executive Director.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Inspector General Investigative Files--CPSC-6.</i> All portions of this system of records which fall within 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) (investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes) and 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5) (investigatory materials solely compiled for suitability determinations) are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) (mandatory accounting of disclosures); 5 U.S.C. 552a(d) (access by individuals to records that pertain to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(1) (requirement to maintain only such information as is relevant and necessary to accomplish an authorized agency purpose); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(G) (mandatory procedures to notify individuals of the existence of records pertaining to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(H) (mandatory procedures to notify individuals how they can obtain access to and contest records pertaining to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(I) (mandatory disclosure of records source categories); and the Commission?s regulations in 16 CFR part 1014 which implement these statutory provisions.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Enforcement and Litigation Files--CPSC-7.</i> All portions of this system of records that fall within 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) (investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes) are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) (mandatory accounting of disclosures); 5 U.S.C. 552a(d) (access by individuals to records that pertain to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(1) (requirement to maintain only such information as is relevant and necessary to accomplish an authorized agency purpose); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(G) (mandatory procedures to notify individuals of the existence of records pertaining to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(H) (mandatory procedures to notify individuals how they can obtain access to and contest records pertaining to them); 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4)(I) (mandatory disclosure of records source categories); and the Commission?s regulations in 16 CFR part 1014 that implement these statutory provisions.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
