<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>



<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico</name>
<abbrev>
IBWC/US
    
    
    
</abbrev>
<section id="sec1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Attendance, Leave, and Payroll Records of Employees.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 229, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, Social Security Number and employee number, grade, step, and salary; organization (code), retirement or FICA data as applicable; Federal, State and local tax deductions, as appropriate; Internal Revenue Service tax lien data; savings bond and charitable deductions; regular and optional government life insurance deduction(s), health insurance deduction and plan or code; cash award data; jury duty data; military leave data; pay differentials; union dues deductions; allotments, by type and amount; financial institution code and employee account number; leave status and leave data of all types (including annual, compensatory, jury duty, maternity, military, retirement disability, sick, transferred, and without pay); time and attendance records, including number of regular, overtime, holiday, Sunday, and other hours worked; pay period number and ending date; cost-of-living allowances; mailing address; co-owner and/or beneficiary of bonds, marital status and number of dependents; and "Notification of Personnel Action". The individual records listed herein are included only as pertinent or applicable to the individual employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950; and 31 U.S.C. 665.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Transmittal of data to United States Treasury to effect issuance of paychecks to employees and distribution of pay according to employee directions for savings bonds, allotments, financial institutions, and other authorized purposes.
</p><p>Reporting: Tax withholding to Internal Revenue Service and appropriate State and local authorities; FICA deductions to the Social Security Administration; dues deductions to labor unions; withholdings for health insurance to the insurance carriers and the United States Civil Service Commission; charity contribution deductions to agents of charitable institutions; annual W-2 statements to taxing authorities and the individual.
</p><p>(1). To the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services Federal Parent Locator System (FPLS) and Federal Tax Offset System for use in locating individuals and identifying their income sources to establish paternity, establish and modify orders of support and for enforcement action.
</p><p>(2). To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Social Security Administration for verifying social security numbers in connection with the operation of the FPLS by the Office of Child Support Enforcement;
</p><p>(3). To Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Department of Treasury for purposes of administering the Earned Income Tax Credit Program (Section 32, Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and verifying a claim with respect to employment in a tax return.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Manual and machine-readable copy.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name and/or employee number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Physical, technical, and administrative security is maintained, with all storage equipment and/or rooms locked when not in use. Admittance when open is restricted to authorized personnel only. All payroll personnel and computer operators and programmers are instructed and cautioned on the confidentiality of the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Cut off at the end of a calendar year; retained for 3 years or until after General Accounting Office audit, whichever is earlier; and then destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Request from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individuals concerned appear in the Section's rules and published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individuals, supervisors, timekeepers, official personnel records, and Internal Revenue Service.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Accounts Receivable.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 229, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons owing money to the United States Section, including employees, former employees, business firms, general public, and institutions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names and addresses; amounts owed and services performed, overpayment or other accounting therefor; invoice numbers, if any; and United States Treasury certificates of deposit numbers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950; and 31 U.S.C. 665.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For billing purposes to obtain funds due the Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Manual and machine-readable copy.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name and invoice number, as appropriate.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained until payment is received and account audited, then disposed of in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Financial Services, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79002.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individual; Procurement Section; and accounting records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Confidential Statements of Employment and Financial Interests.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 229, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees paid at a level of the Executive Schedule in subchapter II of 5 U.S.C. 53, and Section employees who are required by Executive Order 11222 to file such statements, including former employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Statements of personal and family holdings and other interests in business enterprises; listing of creditors, outside employment and opinion of reviewing official; and any confirmation material.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 11222.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To comply with United States Civil Service Commission Regulations (Federal Personnel Manual Chapter 735) records from an effective system of review for disclosing conflicts or apparent conflicts of interest on the part of employees, records from this system may be forwarded to the United States Civil Service Commission when requested. Information may not be disclosed from a statement other than to designated employees who have an official need, except as the Chairman of the United States Civil Service Commission, or the Commissioner of the Section, may determine for a good cause shown.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in sealed envelopes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by name alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in a locked box in a combination safe-metal file cabinet in a secured room, with access limited under very controlled conditions to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are disposed of 2 years after separation of the employee, in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees on whom records are required to be maintained:
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Individual Identification Cards.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Key employees of the two Sections of the International Boundary and Water Commission, whose duties necessitate travel across the border between the two countries in conduct of the Sections' business affairs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names, titles, nationalities, places of birth, physical descriptions (color of hair, eyes, and height, etc.), and photographs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>1944 Water Treaty; 5 U.S.C. 301, and 44 U.S.C. 3101.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For the identification of key employees of the two Sections of the International Boundary and Water Commission, whose duties necessitate travel across the border between the two countries in conduct of the Sections' business affairs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Index card records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by name-alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in metal card-file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained for 6 years after cancellation, and then destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals to whom identification cards pertain.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Certificates of Medical Examination.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Medical certificates (SF-78* or equivalent) and any other medical records of examinations used to determine and employee's fitness for the job, and may include employee's name, date of birth, and Social Security Number. (* Parts D, E, and F of SF-78 are not considered a medical record, and are filed in the Official Personnel Folder.)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 3301, 3302; and Executive Order 10577.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To determine medical eligibility for appointment, and for changes in assignment within the Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by name alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets in secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Upon employee's transfer to another agency or separation from Federal service, the sealed envelope with medical records attached on the right side of the Official Personnel Folder will be forwarded to National Personnel Records Center (Civilian), 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63118, within thirty (30) days after separation from Federal service, or to the agency to which the employee is transferring within thirty (30) days from such transfer. In the case of disability retirements, medical information is obtained and forwarded to the United States Civil Service Commission's Medical fficer in the El Paso, Texas area.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above. Information may be released upon receipt of a subpoena, or to a nonfederal entity or person, upon written authorization from employee, and the extent of the information will be in accordance with United States Civil Service Commission Regulations (Federal Personnel Manual Chapter 339).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access to records for contesting contends and appealing initial determinations by the indivisual concerned, as published in the Section's rules in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291), are in accordance with United States Civil Service Commission Regulations (Federal Personnel Manual Chapter 339).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual's physician or Section's designated physician covering individuals to whom the records pertain.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject system from Pub. L. 93-579, 552a, Sec. 3.(k)(6), unless approvd for release by the Regional Medical Officer of the United States Civil Service Commission. Information will be given to the employee if determined by the Regional Medical Officer that the material is not considered detrimental to the employee's well-being. Medical information may also be released to a licensed physician designated in writing for that purpose by the individual to whom the information pertains, or to his or her designated representative.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Equal Employment Opportunity.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 227, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees or applicants for employment who have filed complaints of discrimination against the Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Affidavits concerning the complaint; correspondence and written documentation related to the complaint; and copies of personnel records and information covering how the complaint was resolved.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 11478; Pub. L. 92-261; and Pub. L. 93-259.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain records of discrimination complaints filed by employees or applicants for employment with the Section, and all documentation and information pertaining thereto.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by name alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained for 7 years after close of the matter, and then destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Equal Employment Opportunity, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 227, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Bulding, 4110 Rio Bravo El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From employees of, or applicants for employment with, the Section involved as complainants, witnesses, etc., in discrimination complaints; reports of investigations, and other materials prepared by the Equal Employment Opportunity Director, Equal Employment Opportunity Assistant, counselors, coordinators, and investigators; copies of Section documents relevant to any Equal Employment Opportunity investigations; and records of hearings on complaints.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Occupational Health and Injury Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section who have sustained injuries or have other occupational health problems.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Accident reports (CA-1 and CA-2); claims for compensation for injury or occupational disease (CA-4); claims for continuance of compensation on account of disability (CA-8); logs of employees receiving medical services or who have sustained a work-related injury or disease; health and medical records, including medical reports on the compensation forms or in response to medical treatment and examination; and related correspondence.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 81; 5 U.S.C. 7153; 5 U.S.C. 7901; The Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970; and Executive Order 11807.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide information, including statistical data, required by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, Department of Labor, and Office of Workers's Compensation Programs, Department of Labor.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by name alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in a lockable metal file cabinet in a secured area, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are maintained indefinitely while individual is in employ of the Section. Upon separation, records are retained for 5 years and then destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Official records are maintained by the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs (OWCP), New Orleans, Louisiana, or other district offices of the OWCP, and records contested must be filed with that agency under its contesting procedures. Information and address may be obtained from the Comptroller, address as noted under notification section above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From employees who have suffered a work-related illness or injury; Section supervisory personnel; medical authorities treating or examining employee; and witnesses to an accident or occurrence giving rise to a claim.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Pub. L. 93-579, 552a, Sec. 3. (k)(1) and (4). Records maintained under this system are unofficial copies of OWCP records and are maintained to assist in processing compensation claims. Persons seeking information under this system should follow the directions given in the notification procedure above. Information will be given to supervisors and to the employee covered by the record if the material is not considered detrimental to the employee's well-being. Requests for information which appear detrimental will be referred to the OWCP for opinion prior to release.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Motor Vehicle Operator Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section who are seeking or holding a United States Government Motor Vehicle Operator's Identification Card.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications for Government driver's licenses, Social Security Numbers, physical fitness statements, driving violation records, road test results, and pertinent correspondence.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended (40 U.S.C. 471, et. seq.).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide the Section with information necessary and relevant to the accomplishment of its functions covering motor vehicle operators; and to request information from State and local police departments to determine an employee's eligibility for a Government license.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by name alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in secured rooms or secured premises with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained 3 years after separation of employee or 3 years after rescission of authorization to operate a government-owned vehicle, whichever occurs earlier; then destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals to whom records pertain, witnesses to driving violations, police and court records, and road test examiners.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employees' Travel Records--Initial Appointment and/or Change of Duty Stations.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees and applicants selected for appointment in shortage category occupations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names, addresses, estimated travel expenses, modes of travel, employment service agreements, and travel orders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; Accounting and Auditing Act of 1950; and Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To document authority for change of duty station travel and the payment of authorized travel expenses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Manual and machine-readable paper copy.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed in chronological order.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured premises with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained according to General Services Administration Federal Travel Regulations, and then disposed of and destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individual, supervisors, and Finance Office standard references.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Freedom of Information Act Requests for Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 212, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons requesting copies of records from the United States Section under the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act, as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names, addresses and telephone numbers of requesters; description or identification of records requested, furnished, and/or denied; dates of request and response; amount of fees paid, reduced, or waived, if any; payment delinquencies, if any; petitions of indigency; appeals of denials; final determinations; and names and titles of denying officials and determining officials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information Act, as amended (Pub. L. 93-502).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For Annual Report to the Congress under section (d) of the Freedom of Information Act, as amended; and available for public inspection at all times.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Indexed chronologically by date received.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Approved requests and denied requests which do not result in appeals or litigation: Completed actions cut off at close of fiscal year and destroyed two years after cutoff in accordance with standard procedures. Denied requests resulting in appeals or litigation: Cut off at close of fiscal year in which final determination is made. Transferred to Federal Archives Records Center, Fort Worth, Texas, two years after cut off, and destroyed ten years after cutoff in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individuals, Section officers, and employees engaged in processing or making determinations with respect to Freedom of Information Act requests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">General Personnel Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902, or Field Office where individual is employed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>General correspondence and files relating to employment or conditions of employment; promotion, Notification of Personnel Action (SF-50), and Request for Personnel Action (SF-52) files; leave and training records; Central Personnel Data File (CPDF), and retirement records relating to personnel actions and determinations concerning an individual while employed. These records may contain information about an individual relating to name; date of birth; home address; telephone number; emergency addresses; Social Security Number; Veteran's Preference; tenure; work connected injuries; handicap code; employment history; qualification background; past and present salaries; grades and position titles; training; awards and other recognition; counseling; performance appraisal; conduct; pay and leave; and data documenting reasons for personnel actions; decisions or recommendations concerning an employee; and background data and documentation leading to an adverse action being taken against an employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 1302, 2951, 4118, 4308, 4506, 7501, 7511, 7521; and Executive Order 10561.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records may be used:
</p><p>(A) By an agency of the Federal government having oversight or review authority, such as the United States Civil Service Commission.
</p><p>(B) In the event an appeal is made outside the Section, records which are relevant may be referred to the appropriate agency charged with rendering a decision on the appeal.
</p><p>(C) Information, without prior employee consent, can be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the Public: Employee name; position title/grade (past/present); salary (past/present); and duty station (past/present--as specific as building/room number).
</p><p>2. To a prospective Federal employer: All items on Request for Preliminary Employment Data (SF-75).
</p><p>3. To a prospective nonfederal employer: Employee name; position title/grade (past/present); salary (past/present); duty station (past/present); tenure of employment; Civil Service status; length of service (Section/Federal government); and date/reason for separation (from Notification of Personnel Action SF-50).
</p><p>4. To a police department/court: Any information requested for law enforcement purposes.
</p><p>5. To a credit firm:
</p><p>(a) May be provided: Employee name; position title/grade (past/present); salary (past/present); duty station (past/present).
</p><p>(b) May only be verified (the firm may be advised if its information is correct; if not correct, it is not permitted to disclose the "right answer"): Tenure of employment; Civil Service status; and length of service (Section/Federal government).
</p><p>Any other disclosure requires prior written consent.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>File folders, index cards, and computer printouts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by any combination of name, date of birth, Social Security Number, or employee identification number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in locked metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained during the period of individual's employment with the Section; transferred to individual's Official Personnel Folder upon resignation, transfer or separation from Section service.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned, appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From information supplied by applicable individuals, or as provided by applicable Section supervisors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Investigative Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, date and place of birth; citizenship status; physical characteristics; employment and military service history; arrest records; Federally-employed relatives; dates and purposes of visits to foreign countries; passport numbers; names of spouses, relatives, and personal associates; activities; and conflicts of interest, security, and suitability material.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Orders 10450 and 11652.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To determine suitability for Federal employment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by employee name alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records consist of confidential background investigations for Section employees; and are filed in manila envelopes attached on the outside of the Official Personnel Folder, the envelopes bearing employee name and Social Security Number. When the employee transfers or separates, these records are placed in the Official Personnel Folder and disposed of as part of such Official Personnel Folder.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications and other personnel and security forms furnished by the individual; investigative and other record material furnished by other Federal agencies; notices of personnel actions furnished by other Federal agencies; personal investigations or written inquiries from sources such as employers, educational institutions, references, neighbors, associates, police departments, courts, credit bureaus, medical records, probation officials, prison officials, newspapers, magazines, periodicals, and other publications; and published hearings of Congressional Committees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>Certain records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), (I), and (f). Reference Section's rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employees; Vehicle Accident Reports.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 229, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Full names and addresses of persons involved and their individual statements; vehicle tag number; service and repairs required; invoice number; cost code; and applicable appropriation symbol.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1941, as amended (40 U.S.C.471, et seq.).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For Finance Section employees to complete billing procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By employee name, date of accident, and invoice number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retain on hand 3 fiscal years, and then dispose of and destroy in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From subject individual, supervisors and/or Finance Section's standard references.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Records of Cash Receipts.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 229, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals and companies making payments to cover goods acquired and services rendered; reimbursements for overpayments; and miscellaneous monies received by the Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names of individuals or companies; goods acquired or services rendered; amounts, dates; check numbers; locations; bank deposit information; and United States Treasury deposit numbers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; Budget and Accounting Procedures act of 1950; and 31 U.S.C. 665.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Accounting for all monies received by the Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Manual and machine-readable paper copy.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name and/or account or invoice number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained for one year following the end of the fiscal year; then transferred to Federal Archives Records Center, Fort Worth, Texas.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Financial Services, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individual and/or company.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Disciplinary Action, Appeal, and Grievance Files; and Unfair Labor Practice Charges/Complaints.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Section employees who have had disciplinary actions taken against them, and who have filed appeals or grievances.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Warning letters and official reprimand files; grievance files (Section or negotiated); adverse action decision letters; disciplinary action files; appeals hearing transcripts (if held); background information in support of disciplinary and adverse actions; and unfair labor practice charges/complaints.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Orders 10987, 11491, 11787; and 5 U.S.C. 77.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>(a) To the United States Civil Service Commission upon request in conjunction with any appeal or in conjunction with its official duties pertaining to personnel matters and investigations regarding complaints of Federal employees or applicants for employment.
</p><p>(b) To designated officers and employees of other Federal agencies conducting investigations of an individual for the purpose of granting security clearance or access determination, and having a need to evaluate qualifications, suitability and loyalty to the United States Government in connection with employment.
</p><p>(c) In the event of any indication of violation or potential violation of the law, to the appropriate Federal agency charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcement or implementation of the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>(d) To respond to a court subpoena or response to a district court in connection with a civil suit.
</p><p>(e) To designated hearing examiners, arbitrators, and third-party appellate authorities involved in the hearing or appeal processes.
</p><p>(f) To investigate officials of the Department of Labor and Federal Labor Relations Council for settlement of a complaint or appeal.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By employee name, filed alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records involving court actions are retained permanently; all others retained 7 years after completion of action, and then disposed of in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the Federal Register (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals to whom records pertain; Section officials; affidavits or statements from employees; testimony of witnesses; official documents relating to appeals, grievances, or complaints; and correspondence from specific organizations or individuals.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-16</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Official Personnel Folders.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Official Personnel Folders containing name, Social Security Number; date of birth; employment history; education; job and pay data; performance reviews; letters of commendation; reprimands; training certificates; salary and benefits information, to include allowance and insurance data; travel orders and general correspondence; other personnel data such as security clearance, loyalty, military service evidence, injury reports, suggestions, health qualification records, etc.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 10561; and United States Civil Service Commission Regulations (Federal Personnel Manual Chapters 293 and 294).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>(A) To provide hard-copy documentation on employees' current job and pay data, past job history, career progression, etc. Used to determine qualifications and to provide information for processing personnel actions.
</p><p>(B) Information, without prior employee consent, can be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. To the public: Employee name; position title/grade (past/present); salary (past/present); and duty station (past/present--as specific as building/room number).
</p><p>2. To a prospective Federal employer: All items on Request for Preliminary Employment Data (SF-75).
</p><p>3. To a prospective nonfederal employer: Employee name; position title/grade (past/present); salary (past/present); duty station (past/present); tenure of employment; Civil Service status; length of service (Section/ Federal Government); and date/reason for separation (from notification of Personnel Action SF-50).
</p><p>4. To a police department/court: Any information requested for law enforcement purposes.
</p><p>5. To a credit firm:
</p><p>(a) May be provided: Employee name; position title/grade (past/present); salary (past/present); duty station (past/present).
</p><p>(b) May only be verified (the firm may be advised if its information is correct; if not, it is not permitted to disclose the "right answer"): Tenure of employment; Civil Service status; and length of service (Section/Federal Government).
</p><p>Any other disclosure requires prior written consent.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by employee name--alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained for duration of employment, and then folders are transmitted to the Personnel Records Center (Civilian) at 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri, 63118, within 30 days after separation--except for those employees leaving on military furlough, or with retirement applications pending, or compensation cases which are pending and which have not been adjudicated.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Sections's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (41 FR 19625).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications for employment; applications for fidelity bonds; college transcripts; personnel actions; performance reviews and/or personnel evaluation reports; letters of commendation or reprimand; training certificates; travel orders; employee insurance data; certificates of clearance; and loyalty affidavits.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-17</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Service Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Official summary of employment history to include name, Social Security Number, date of birth, service computation date, Veteran's Preference, life insurance enrollment, retirement data, handicap code, performance reviews (date and type), service award data, and employment record to include date, type, job, pay, and separation data.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>United States Civil Service Commission Regulations (Federal Personnel Manual Chapter 293-31).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To have a ready reference to official summary of employment histories, chronology of personal and service data of employees, and provide information for processing personnel actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records filed in Kardex or file box.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Arranged by (a) budgeted position in organization sequence; (b) pay plan; and (c) descending grade level within each pay plan.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retain 3 years after employee's separation from the Section, then dispose of in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned, appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel actions, performance reviews and/or personnel evaluation reports; application forms, and training and service award certificates.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-18</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employment Resources Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Applicants for employment with the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications for employment; personal qualifications statement (SF-171); and other pertinent employment data.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301; 15 U.S.C. 634(b)(6); and 44 U.S.C. 3101.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain a source of qualified applicants for the purpose of filing vacancies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records files in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Grouped by positions for which applicants appear qualified; arranged by name within position groupings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications considered active for 2 years; then destroyed after 2 years from date signed, in accordance with standard procedures--except upon written request that they be returned to individuals.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned, appear in the Section's rules published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Applicants; previous employers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-19</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Incentive Awards Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section, or non-employees who submit suggestions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Award certificates; letters of commendation, citation, and awards; letters of non-adoption of suggestions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 45.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To document staff or other agency comments in support of justification for, or disapproval of, award nominations in order to present findings to Incentive Awards Committee or other Section officials or, at its request, to the United States Civil Service Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Suggestions--by number; performance nominations--chronologically by type of award.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured room or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Cut off at end of calendar year, retained for 2 years, and then disposed of in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Personnel, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, Room 223, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the notification section above, and conform to the inquired provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees, supervisors, management officials, Incentive Awards Committee, officials of other agencies, and members of the public, if appropriate.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec20" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-20</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Travel Advance Information Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 229, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section who are required to travel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees' names, areas of assignment, and dollar amounts advanced.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950; and 31 U.S.C. 665.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>By the Finance Section to monitor travel advance expenditures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Index card records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed by employee name, alphabetically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in metal card file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Cut off at end of fiscal year; retained for 3 years, and then destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Financial Services, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned, appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From Imprest fund receipts signed by employee-traveler when amount is under
</p><p>150.00, and from Bureau schedules for checks issued by the United States Treasury to employee-traveler when the amount is above
</p><p>150.00.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec21" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-21</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employer's Tax Return Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Room 229, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All employees of the United States Section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal and State Monthly and/or quarterly employee withholding tax for information; computer printouts, magnetic tapes and related documents showing reports of federal and State taxes withheld from employees, and the banking and payment thereof.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950; and 31 U.S.C. 665.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For reconciliation and payment of taxes withheld from employees and employer's share; to provide Internal Revenue Service with record representing wages covered by Social Security.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Manual and machine-readable copy.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name and/or employee number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Cut off at the close of fiscal year, retained for 2 years, and then destroyed in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Financial Services, United States Section International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned, appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data stored in payroll master file.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sec22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>SEC.-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Privacy Act Request File.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting information on records concerning them or someone on whose behalf the individual is authorized to act which are in the custody of the United States Section, or individuals requesting access or amendment to such records under the provisions of The Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Copies of correspondence between individuals and Section custodian official; written summaries of conversations with individuals; coordination documents between the Section and other Federal, State, and local government agencies when records which are the subject of an individual inquiry were originated by another agency; and copies of documents which are the subject of an individual inquiry. Originals of amendment requests, refusals, and appeals accumulated by the custodian of the records concerned are included in the file containing those records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To process and coordinate requests for information, access, and amendment of personal records; to process and record appeals by individuals against Section rulings; and to assure timely response to requesters.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed alphabetically by requester's name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in lockable metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises, with access limited to those individuals whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Approved and/or denied requests not resulting in appeals or litigation--completed actions cut off at close of fiscal year and destroyed 2 years after cutoff in accordance with standard procedures. Denied requests resulting in appeals or litigation--cut off at close of fiscal year in which final determination is made; transferred to Federal Archives Record Center, Fort Worth, Texas, 2 years after cutoff; destroyed 10 years after cutoff in accordance with standard procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the FOIA Administrator, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, IBWC Building, 4110 Rio Bravo, El Paso, Texas 79902.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the FOIA Administrator, same address as stated in the Notification Section above, and conform to the inquiry provisions of the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Rules for access for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the Section's rules as published in the <i>Federal Register</i> (42 FR 48291).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual requesters, and agencies of the Federal, State, and local governments.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    
<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="22">
<heading> Foreign Relations </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XI">
<heading> International Boundary and Water Commission </heading>
<regulationsPart number="1101">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>1101.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>1101.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>1101.3 General policy: Collection and use of personal information.
</p>
<p>1101.4 Reports on new systems of records; computer matching programs.
</p>
<p>1101.5 Security, confidentiality and protection of records.
</p>
<p>1101.6 Requests for access to records.
</p>
<p>1101.7 Disclosure of records to individuals who are subjects of those records.
</p>
<p>1101.8 Disclosure of records to third parties.
</p>
<p>1101.9 Exemptions.
</p>
<p>1101.10 Accounting for disclosures.
</p>
<p>1101.11 Fees.
</p>
<p>1101.12 Request to correct or amend a record.
</p>
<p>1101.13 Agency review of request to correct or amend a record.
</p>
<p>1101.14 Appeal of Agency decision not to correct or amend a record.
</p>
<p>1101.15 Judicial review.
</p>
<p>1101.16 Criminal penalties.
</p>
<p>1101.17 Annual Report to Congress.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 57 FR 24945, June 12, 1992, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.1
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>The purpose of these regulations is to prescribe responsibilities, rules, guidelines, and policies and procedures to implement the Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579, as amended; 5 U.S.C. 552a) to assure that personal information about individuals collected by the United States Section is limited to that which is legally authorized and necessary and is maintained in a manner which precludes unwarranted intrusions upon individual privacy. Further, these regulations establish procedures by which an individual can: (a) Determine if the United States Section maintains records or a system of records which includes a record pertaining to the individual and (b) gain access to a record pertaining to him or her for the purpose of review, amendment or correction.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For the purpose of these regulations:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Act</i> means the Privacy Act of 1974.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Agency</i> is defined to include any executive department, military department, Government corporation, Government controlled corporation or other establishment in the executive branch of the Government (including the Executive Office of the President, or any independent regulatory agency) (5 U.S.C. 552)).
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Commission</i> means the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Commissioner</i> means head of the United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use, or disseminate.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by an agency, including, but not limited to, his education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history and that contains his name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print or a photograph.
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it is collected.
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Section</i> means the United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico.
</p>
<p>(j) <i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual, except as provided by 13 U.S.C. 8 (Census data).
</p>
<p>(k) <i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of any agency from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.3
 General policy: Collection and use of personal information.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Heads of Divisions, Branches, and the projects shall ensure that all Section personnel subject to their supervision are advised of the provisions of the Act, including the criminal penalties and civil liabilities provided therein, and that Section personnel are made aware of their responsibilities to protect the security of personal information, to assure its accuracy, relevance, timeliness and completeness, to avoid unauthorized disclosure either orally or in writing, and to ensure that no system of records concerning individuals, no matter how small or specialized, is maintained without public notice.
</p>
<p>(b) Section personnel shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Collect no information of a personal nature from individuals unless authorized to collect it to achieve a function or carry out a responsibility or function of the Section.
</p>
<p>(2) Collect from individuals only that information which is necessary to Section responsibilities or functions;
</p>
<p>(3) Collect information, wherever possible, directly from the individual to whom it relates;
</p>
<p>(4) Inform individuals from whom information is collected of the authority for collection, the purpose thereof, the uses that will be made of the information, and the effects, both legal and practical, of not furnishing the information;
</p>
<p>(5) Neither collect, maintain, use nor disseminate information concerning an individual's religious or political beliefs or activities or his membership in associations or organizations, unless (i) the individual has volunteered such information for his own benefit; (ii) the information is expressly authorized by statute to be collected, maintained, used or disseminated; or (iii) the activities involved are pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized investigation or adjudication activity;
</p>
<p>(6) Advise an individual's supervisors of the existence or contemplated development of any system of records which retrieves information about individuals by individual identified;
</p>
<p>(7) Maintain an accounting of all disclosures of information to other than Section personnel;
</p>
<p>(8) Disclose no information concerning individuals to other than Section personnel except when authorized by the Act or pursuant to a routine use published in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(9) Maintain and process information concerning individuals with care in order to ensure that no inadvertent disclosure of the information is made to other than Section personnel; and
</p>
<p>(10) Call to the attention of the PA Officer any information in a system maintained by the Section which is not authorized to be maintained under the provisions of the Act, including information on First Amendment activities, information that is inaccurate, irrelevant or so incomplete as to risk unfairness to the individual concerned.
</p>
<p>(c) The system of records maintained by the Section shall be reviewed annually by the PA Officer to ensure compliance with the provisions of the Act.
</p>
<p>(d) Information which may be used in making determinations about an individual's rights, benefits, and privileges shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be collected directly from that individual. In deciding whether collection of information from an individual, as opposed to a third party source, is practicable, the following criteria, among others, may be considered:
</p>
<p>(1) Whether the nature of the information sought is such that it can only be obtained from a third party;
</p>
<p>(2) Whether the cost of collecting the information from the individual is unreasonable when compared with the cost of collecting it from a third party;
</p>
<p>(3) Whether there is a risk that information requested from the third parties, if inaccurate, could result in an adverse determination to the individual concerned;
</p>
<p>(4) Whether the information, if supplied by the individual, would have to be verified by a third party; or
</p>
<p>(5) Whether provisions can be made for verification by the individual of information collected from third parties.
</p>
<p>(e) Employees whose duties require handling of records subject to the Act shall, at all times, take care to protect the integrity, security and confidentiality of these records.
</p>
<p>(f) No employee of the section may alter or destroy a record subject to the Act unless (1) such alteration or destruction is properly undertaken in the course of the employee's regular duties or (2) such alteration or destruction is required by a decision of the Commissioner or the decision of a court of competent jurisdiction.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.4
 Reports on new systems of records; computer matching programs.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Before establishing any new systems of records, or making any significant change in a system of records, the Section shall provide adequate advance notice to:
</p>
<p>(1) The Committee on Government Operations of the House of Representatives;
</p>
<p>(2) The Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and
</p>
<p>(3) The Office of Management and Budget.
</p>
<p>(b) Before participating in any computerized information "matching program," as that term is defined by 5 U.S.C. 552a(a)(8) the Section will comply with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(o), and will provide adequate advance notice as described in &#167; 1101.4(a) above.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.5
 Security, confidentiality and protection of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Act requires that records subject to the Act be maintained with appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to ensure the security and confidentiality of records and to protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to their security or integrity which could result in substantial harm, embarrassment, inconvenience or unfairness to any individual on whom information is maintained.
</p>
<p>(b) When maintained in manual form (typed, printed, handwritten, etc.) records shall be maintained, at a minimum, subject to the following safeguards, or safeguards affording comparable protection:
</p>
<p>(1) Areas in which the records are maintained or regularly used shall be posted with an appropriate warning stating that access to the records is limited to authorized persons. The warning shall also summarize the requirements of &#167; 1101.3 and state that the Act contains a criminal penalty for the unauthorized dislosure of records to which it applies.
</p>
<p>(2) During working hours: (i) The area in which the records are maintained or regularly used shall be occupied by authorized personnel or (ii) access to the records shall be restricted by their storage in locked metal file cabinets or a locked room.
</p>
<p>(3) During non-working hours, access to the records shall be restricted by their storage in locked metal file cabinets or a locked room.
</p>
<p>(4) Where a locked room is the method of security provided for a system, that security shall be supplemented by: (i) Providing lockable file cabinets or containers for the records or (ii) changing the lock or locks for the room so that they may not be opened with a master key. For purposes of this paragraph, a master key is a key which may be used to open rooms other than the room containing records subject to the Act, unless those rooms are utilized by officials or employees authorized to have access to the records subject to the Act.
</p>
<p>(5) Personnel handling personal information during routine use will ensure that the information is properly controlled to prevent unintentional or unauthorized disclosure. Such information will be used, held, or stored only where facilities or conditions are adequate to prevent unauthorized or unintentional disclosure.
</p>
<p>(c) When the records subject to the Act are maintained in computerized form, safeguards shall be utilized based on those recommended in the National Bureau of Standard's booklet "Computer Security Guidelines for Implementing the Privacy Act of 1974" (May 30, 1975), and any supplements thereto, which are adequate and appropriate to assuring the integrity of the records.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.6
 Requests for access to records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual may submit an inquiry to the Section to ascertain whether a system of records contains a record pertaining to him or her.
</p>
<p>(b) The inquiry should be made either in person or by mail addressed to the PA Officer, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, 4171 North Mesa, Suite C-310, El Paso, TX 79902-1422. The PA Officer shall provide assistance to the individual making the inquiry to assure the timely identification of the appropriate systems of records. The office of the PA Officer is located in Suite C-316 and is open to an individual between the hours of 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday (excluding holidays).
</p>
<p>(c) Inquiries submitted by mail should be marked "PRIVACY ACT REQUEST" on the bottom left-hand corner of the envelope.
</p>
<p>(d) The letter should state that the request is being made under the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(e) Inquiries concerning whether a system of records contains a record pertaining to an individual should contain the following:
</p>
<p>(1) Name, address and telephone number (optional) of the individual making the inquiry;
</p>
<p>(2) Name, address and telephone number (optional) of the individual to whom the record pertains, if the inquiring individual is either the parent of a minor or the legal guardian of the individual to whom a record pertains;
</p>
<p>(3) A certified or authenticated copy of documents establishing parentage or guardianship;
</p>
<p>(4) Whether the individual to whom the record pertains is a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence into the United States;
</p>
<p>(5) Name of the system of records, as published in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(6) Location of the system of records, as published in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(7) Such additional information as the individual believes will or might assist the Section in responding to the inquiry and in verifying the individual's identity (for example: date of birth, place of birth, names of parents, place of work, dates of employment, position title, etc.);
</p>
<p>(8) Date of inquiry; and
</p>
<p>(9) Signature of the requester.
</p>
<p>The Section reserves the right to require compliance with the identification procedures appearing at paragraph (f) of this section where conditions warrant.
</p>
<p>(f) The requirement for identification of individuals seeking access to records are as follows:
</p>
<p>(1) In person: Each individual making a request in person shall be required to present satisfactory proof of identity. The means of proof, in the order of preference and priority, are:
</p>
<p>(i) A document bearing the individual's photograph (for example, driver's license, passport or military or civilian identification card);
</p>
<p>(ii) A document bearing the individual's signature, preferably issued for participation in a federally sponsored program (for example, Social Security card, unemployment insurance book, employer's identification card, national credit card and professional, craft or union membership card); and
</p>
<p>(iii) A document bearing either the photograph or the signature of the individual, preferably issued for participation in a federally sponsored program (for example, Medicaid card). In the event the individual can provide no suitable documentation of identity, the Section will require a signed statement asserting the individual's identity and stipulating that the individual understands the penalty provision of 5 U.S.C. 552a(i)(3).
</p>
<p>(2) Not in person: If the individual making a request does not appear in person before the PA Officer, a certificate of a notary public or equivalent officer empowered to administer oaths must accompany the request.
</p>
<p>(3) Parents of minors and legal guardians: An individual acting as the parent of a minor or the legal guardian of the individual or an heir or legal representative of a deceased person to whom a record pertains shall establish his or her personal identity in the manner prescribed in either paragraph (f)(1) or (2) of this section. In addition, such individual shall establish his or her identity in the representative capacity of parent or legal guardian. In the case of the parent of a minor, the proof of identity shall be a certified or authenticated copy of the minor's birth certificate. In the case of a legal guardian of an individual who has been declared incompetent due to physical or mental incapacity or age by a court of competent jurisdiction, the proof of identity shall be a certified or authenticated copy of the court's order. A parent or legal guardian may act only for a living individual, not for a decedent. A parent or legal guardian may be accompanied during personal access to a record by another individual, provided the requirements of paragraph (f) of &#167; 1101.7 are satisfied. In the case of an heir or legal representative of a deceased person the proof of identity shall be a certified copy of the Will, if any; the order of a court of competent jurisdiction admitting the Will to probate; the order of a court of competent jurisdiction appointing an executor, executrix, or administrator; a letter of administration; or any other documentary evidence which establishes the identity of the individual as an heir or legal representative of a deceased person.
</p>
<p>(g) When the provisions of this part are alleged to have the effect of impeding an individual in exercising his or her right to access, the Section will consider, from an individual making a request, alternative suggestions regarding proof of identity and access to records.
</p>
<p>(h) An inquiry which is not addressed as specified in paragraph (b) of this section or which is not marked as specified in paragraph (c) of this section will be so addressed and marked by the Section's personnel and forwarded immediately to the PA Officer. An inquiry which is not properly addressed by the individual will not be deemed to have been "received" for purposes of measuring time periods for response until forwarding of the inquiry to the PA Officer has been effected. In each instance when an inquiry so forwarded is received, the PA Officer shall notify the individual that his or her inquiry was improperly addressed and the date when the inquiry was received at the proper address.
</p>
<p>(i) Each inquiry received shall be acted upon promptly by the PA Officer. Although there is no fixed time when an agency must respond to a request for access to records under the Act, every effort will be made to respond within ten (10) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and holidays) of the date of receipt. If a response cannot be made within ten (10) days, the PA Officer shall send an acknowledgment during that period providing information on the status of the inquiry and asking for such further information as may be necessary to process the inquiry. Every effort will be made to provide the requested records within thirty (30) days.
</p>
<p>(j) An individual shall not be required to state a reason or otherwise justify his or her inquiry.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.7
 Disclosure of records to individuals who are subjects of those records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Each request received shall be acted upon promptly by the PA Officer. Every effort will be made to respond within ten (10) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) of the date of receipt. If a response cannot be made within ten (10) days due to unusual circumstances, the PA Officer shall send an acknowledgment during that period providing information on the status of the request and asking for such further information as may be necessary to process the request. Every effort will be made to provide the requested records within thirty (30) days. "Unusual circumstances" shall include circumstances where a search for and collection of requested records from inactive storage, field facilities or other establishments are required, cases where a voluminous amount of data is involved, instances where information on other individuals must be separated or expunged from the particular record, and cases where consultations with other agencies having a substantial interest in the determination of the request are necessary.
</p>
<p>(b) Grant of access:
</p>
<p>(1) Notification.
</p>
<p>(i) An individual shall be granted access to a record pertaining to him or her except where the record is subject to an exemption under the Act and these rules.
</p>
<p>(ii) The PA Officer shall notify the individual of such determination and provide the following information:
</p>
<p>(A) The methods of access, as set forth in paragraph (b)(2) of this section;
</p>
<p>(B) The place at which the records may be inspected;
</p>
<p>(C) The earliest date on which the record may be inspected and the period of time that the records will remain available for inspection. In no event shall the earliest date be later than thirty (30) days from the date of notification;
</p>
<p>(D) The estimated date by which a copy of the record could be mailed and the estimate of fees pursuant to &#167; 1101.11. In no event shall be estimated date be later than thirty (30) days from the date of notification;
</p>
<p>(E) The fact that the individual, if he or she wishes, may be accompanied by another individual during the personal access, subject to the procedures set forth in paragraph (f) of this section; and
</p>
<p>(F) Any additional requirements needed to grant access to a specific record.
</p>
<p>(2) Method of access: The following methods of access to records by an individual may be available depending on the circumstances of a given situation:
</p>
<p>(i) Inspection in person may be made in the office specified by the PA Officer, between the hours of 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday (excluding holidays);
</p>
<p>(ii) Transfer of records to a Federal facility more convenient to the individual may be arranged, but only if the PA Officer determines that a suitable facility is available, that the individual's access can be properly supervised at that facility, and that transmittal of the records to that facility will not unduly interfere with operations of the section or involve unreasonable costs, in terms of both money and manpower; and
</p>
<p>(iii) Copies may be mailed at the request of the individual, subject to payment of the fees prescribed in &#167; 1101.11. The Section, at its own initiative, may elect to provide a copy by mail, in which case no fee will be charged to the individual.
</p>
<p>(c) Access to medical records: Upon advice by a physician that release of medical information directly to the requester could have an adverse effect on the requester, the Section may attempt to arrange an acceptable alternative. This will normally involve release of such information to a physician named by the requester, with the requester's written consent. (Note that release to any third party, including a physician or family member, must comply with the provisions of &#167; 1101.8 of this part.)
</p>
<p>(d) The Section shall supply such other information and assistance at the time of access to make the record intelligible to the individual.
</p>
<p>(e) The Section reserves the right to limit access to copies and abstracts of original records, rather than the original records. This election would be appropriate, for example, when the record is in an automated data media such as tape of disc, when the record contains information on other individuals, and when deletion of information is permissible under exemptions (for example 5, U.S.C. 552(k)(1)). In no event shall original records of the Section be made available to the individual except under the immediate supervision of the PA Officer or his designee. Title 18 U.S.C. 2701(a) makes it a crime to conceal, mutilate, obliterate, or destroy a record filed in a public office, or to attempt to do any of the foregoing.
</p>
<p>(f) Any individual who requests access to a record pertaining to that individual may be accompanied by another individual of his or her choice. "Accompanied" includes discussion of the record in the presence of the other individual. The individual to whom the record pertains shall authorize the presence of the other individual in writing and shall include the name of the other individual, a specific description of the record to which access is sought, and the date and the signature of the individual to whom the record pertains. The other individual shall sign the authorization in the presence of the PA Officer or his designee. An individual shall not be required to state a reason or otherwise justify his or her decision to be accompanied by another individual during the personal access to a record.
</p>
<p>(g) Initial denial of access:
</p>
<p>(1) Grounds. Access by an individual to a record which pertains to that individual will be denied only upon a determination by the PA Officer that:
</p>
<p>(i) The record is subject to an exemption under the Act and these rules;
</p>
<p>(ii) The record is information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding;
</p>
<p>(iii) The provisions of &#167; 1101.7(c) pertaining to medical records have been temporarily invoked; or
</p>
<p>(iv) The individual unreasonably has failed to comply with the procedural requirements of these rules.
</p>
<p>(2) Notification. The PA Officer shall give notice of denial of access of records to the individual in writing and shall include the following information:
</p>
<p>(i) The PA Officer's name and title or position;
</p>
<p>(ii) The date of denial;
</p>
<p>(iii) The reasons for the denial, including citation to the appropriate section of the Act and these rules;
</p>
<p>(iv) The individual's opportunities for further administrative consideration, including the identity and address of the responsible official;
</p>
<p>(v) If stated to be administratively final within the Section, the individual's right to judicial review under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g) (1) and (5).
</p>
<p>(3) Administrative review: When an initial denial of a request is issued by the PA Officer, the individual's opportunities for further consideration shall be as follows:
</p>
<p>(i) As to denial under paragraph (g)(1)(i) of this section, the sole procedure is a petition for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule under 5 U.S.C. 553(e). Such petition shall be filed with the Commissioner, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, 4171 North Mesa, Suite C-310, El Paso, TX 79902-1422. If the exception was determined by another agency, the PA Officer will provide the individual with the name and address of the other agency and any relief sought by the individual shall be that provided by the regulations of the other agency. Within the Section, no such denial is administratively final until such a petition has been filed by the individual and disposed of on the merits by the Commissioner.
</p>
<p>(ii) As to denial under paragraphs (g)(1), (ii), (iii) or (iv) of this section, the individual may file for review with the Commissioner, as indicated in the PA Officer's initital denial notification.
</p>
<p>(h) If a request is partially granted and partially denied, the PA Officer shall follow the appropriate procedures of this section as to the records within the grant and the records within the denial.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.8
 Disclosure of records to third-parties.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Section will not disclose any information about an individual to any person other than the individual except in the following instances:
</p>
<p>(1) Upon written request by the individual about whom the information is maintained;
</p>
<p>(2) With prior written consent of the individual about whom the information is maintained;
</p>
<p>(3) To the parent(s) of a minor child, or the legal guardian of an incompetent person, when said parent(s) or legal guardian act(s) on behalf of said minor or incompetent person.
</p>
<p>(4) When permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) (1) through (11) which provides as follows:
</p>
<p>(i) To those officers and employees of the agency which maintains the record who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties;
</p>
<p>(ii) Required under 5 U.S.C. 552 of the U.S. Code;
</p>
<p>(iii) For a routine use as defined in the Act at 5 U.S.C. 552a(a)(7);
</p>
<p>(iv) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity pursuant to the provisions of title 13 of the U.S. Code;
</p>
<p>(v) To a recipient who has provided the agency with advance adequate written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable;
</p>
<p>(vi) To the National Archives of the United States as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the United States Government, or for evaluation by the Administrator of General Services or his designee to determine whether the record has such value;
</p>
<p>(vii) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity if the activity is authorized by law, if the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a written request to the agency which maintains the record specifying the particular portion desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought;
</p>
<p>(viii) To a person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual if upon such disclosure notification is transmitted to the last known address of such individual;
</p>
<p>(ix) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee, and to a Congressman who is acting on behalf of his constituent;
</p>
<p>(x) To the Comptroller General, or any of his authorized representatives, in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office; or
</p>
<p>(xi) Pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction;
</p>
<p>(5) When required by the Act and not covered explicitly by the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(b). These situations include the following:
</p>
<p>(i) Dissemination of a corrected or amended record or notation of a disagreement statement (5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(4));
</p>
<p>(ii) Disclosure of records to an individual to whom they pertain (5 U.S.C. 552a(d));
</p>
<p>(iii) Civil actions by an individual (5 U.S.C. 552a(g));
</p>
<p>(iv) Release of records or information to the Privacy Protection Study Commission (Section 5 of Pub. L. 93-579);
</p>
<p>(v) Fulfill the needs of Office of Management and Budget to provide continuing oversight and assistance to the section in implementation of the Act (Section 6 of Pub. L. 93-579).
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.9
 Exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>The following are exempt from disclosure under 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) and (k):
</p>
<p>(a) Any record originated by another agency which has determined that the record is exempt. If a request encompasses such a record, the Section will advise the requester of its existence, and of the name and address of the source agency.
</p>
<p>(b) Records specifically authorized under criteria established by an executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy, and which are, in fact, properly classified pursuant to such executive order.
</p>
<p>(c) Those systems of records listed as exempt in the Notice of Records of the <i>Federal Register</i>, including: Certificates of Medical Examination; Occupational Health and Injury Files; and Investigative Records.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.10
 Accounting for disclosures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Each system manager shall establish a system of accounting for all disclosures of records, either orally or in writing made outside the Section, unless otherwise exempted under this section. Accounting procedures may be established in the least expensive and most convenient form that will permit the PA Officer to advise individuals promptly upon request of the persons or agencies to which records concerning them have been disclosed. Accounting of disclosures made under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(7) relating to civil or criminal law enforcement activities shall not be made available to the individual named in the record.
</p>
<p>(b) Accounting records, at a minimum, shall include the date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure of a record and the name and address of the person or agency to whom the disclosure was made. Accounting records shall be maintained for at least five years or the life of the record, whichever is longer.
</p>
<p>(c) Accounting is not required to be kept for disclosure made within the Section or disclosures made pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act.
</p>
<p>(d) If an accounting of the disclosure was made, the PA Officer shall inform any person or other agency about any correction or notation of dispute made by the Section in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(d) of any record that has been disclosed to the person or agency.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.11
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Under the Act, fees can only be charged for the cost of copying records. No fees may be charged for the time it takes to search for the records or for the time it takes to determine if any exemptions apply. The Section will not charge a fee for the first copy of an individual's personnel record.
</p>
<p>(b) The Section will charge a fee of $0.10 per page for copies of documents which are identified by an individual and reproduced at the individual's request for retention, except that there will be no charge for requests involving costs of $1.00 or less, but the copying fees for contemporaneous request by the same individual shall be aggregated to determine the total fee.
</p>
<p>(c) Special and additional services provided at the request of the individual, such as certification or authentication, will be charged to the individual in accordance with other published regulations of the Section pursuant to statute (for example, 22 CFR part 1102--Freedom of Information Act.)
</p>
<p>(d) Remittances shall be in the form of either a personal check or bank draft drawn on a bank in the United States, a postal money order, or cash. Remittance shall be made payable to the order of the U.S. Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, and delivered to or mailed to the PA Officer, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, 4171 North Mesa, Suite C-310, El Paso, TX 79902-1422. The Section will assume no responsibility for cash sent by mail.
</p>
<p>(e) A receipt for fees paid will be given only upon request.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.12
 Request to correct or amend a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual may submit a request for correction of or amendment to a record to the Section. The request should be made either in person or by mail addressed to the PA Officer who processed the individual's request for access to the record, and to whom is delegated authority to make initial determinations on requests for correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>(b) Since the request, in all cases, will follow a request for access under &#167; 1101.6, the individual's identity will be established by his or her signature on the request.
</p>
<p>(c) A request for correction or amendment should be in writing. The envelope containing the request should be marked "Privacy Act Amendment Request" on the lower left hand corner. The request should include the following:
</p>
<p>(1) First, the letter should state that it is a request to amend a record under the Privacy Act of 1974.
</p>
<p>(2) Second, the request should identify the specific record and the specific information in the record for which an amendment is being sought.
</p>
<p>(3) Third, the request should state why the information is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete. Supporting evidence may be included with the request.
</p>
<p>(4) Fourth, the request should state what new or additional information, if any, should be included in place of the erroneous information. Evidence of the validity of new or additional information should be included. If the information in the file is wrong and needs to be removed rather than supplemented or corrected, the request should make this clear.
</p>
<p>(5) Fifth, the request should include the name, address, and telephone number (optional) of the requester.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.13
 Agency review of request to correct or amend a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) (1) Not later than ten (10) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and holidays) after receipt of a request to correct or amend a record, the PA Officer shall send an acknowledgment providing an estimate of time within which action will be taken on the request and asking for such further information as may be necessary to process the request. The estimate of time may take into account unusual circumstances as described in &#167; 1101.7(a). No acknowledgment will be sent if the request can be reviewed, processed and the individual notified of the results of review (either compliance or denial) within ten (10) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and holidays). Requests filed in person will be acknowledged in writing at the time submitted.
</p>
<p>(2) Promptly after acknowledging receipt of a request, or after receiving such further information as might have been requested, or after arriving at a decision within ten (10) days, the PA Officer shall either:
</p>
<p>(i) Make the requested correction or amendment and advise the individual in writing of such action, providing either a copy of the corrected or amended record or a statement as to the means whereby the correction or amendment was effected in cases where a copy cannot be provided (for example, erasure of information from a record maintained only in an electronic data bank); or
</p>
<p>(ii) Inform the individual in writing that his or her request is denied and provide the following information:
</p>
<p>(A) The PA Officer's name, title and position;
</p>
<p>(B) The date of denial;
</p>
<p>(C) The reasons for the denial, including citation to the appropriate sections of the Act and these rules;
</p>
<p>(D) The procedures for appeal of the denial as set forth in &#167; 1101.14.
</p>
<p>The term promptly in this paragraph means within thirty (30) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and holidays). If the PA Officer cannot make the determination within thirty (30) days, the individual will be advised in writing of the reason therefor and of the estimated date by which the determination will be made.
</p>
<p>(b) Whenever an individual's record is corrected or amended pursuant to a request by that individual, the PA Officer shall notify all persons and agencies to which copies of the record had been disclosed prior to its correction or amendment, if an accounting of such disclosure required by the Act was made. The notification shall require a receipt agency maintaining the record to acknowledge receipt of the notification, to correct or amend the record, and to apprise any agency or person to which it has disclosed the record of the substance of the correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>(c) The following criteria will be considered by the PA Officer in reviewing a request for correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>(1) The sufficiency of the evidence submitted by the individual;
</p>
<p>(2) The factual accuracy of the information;
</p>
<p>(3) The relevance and necessity of the information in terms of purpose for which it was collected.
</p>
<p>(4) The timeliness and currency of the information in light of the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(5) The completeness of the information in terms of the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(6) The degree of possibility that denial of the request could unfairly result in determinations adverse to the individual;
</p>
<p>(7) The character of the record sought to be corrected or amended; and
</p>
<p>(8) The propriety and feasibility of complying with the specific means of correction or amendment requested by the individual.
</p>
<p>(d) The Section will not undertake to gather evidence for the individual, but does reserve the right to verify the evidence which the individual submits.
</p>
<p>(e) Correction or amendment of a record requested by an individual will be denied only upon a determination by the PA Officer that:
</p>
<p>(1) The individual has failed to establish, by a preponderance of the evidence, the propriety of the correction or amendment in light of the criteria set forth in paragraph (c) of this section;
</p>
<p>(2) The record sought to be corrected or amended was compiled in a terminated judicial, quasi-judicial or quasi-legislative proceeding to which the individual was a party or participant;
</p>
<p>(3) The record sought to be corrected or amended is the subject of a pending judicial, quasi-judicial or quasi-legislative proceeding to which the individual is a party or participant;
</p>
<p>(4) The correction or amendment would violate a duly enacted statute or promulgated regulation; or
</p>
<p>(5) The individual unreasonably has failed to comply with the procedural requirements of these rules.
</p>
<p>(f) If a request is partially granted and partially denied, the PA Officer shall follow the appropriate procedures of this section as to the records within the grant and the records within the denial.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.14
 Appeal of agency decision not to correct or amend a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) An appeal of the initial refusal to amend a record under &#167; 1101.13 may be requested by the individual who submitted the request. The appeal must be requested in writing, and state that the appeal is being made under the Privacy Act of 1974, it should identify the denial that is being appealed and the records that were withheld, it should include the requester's name and address and telephone number (optional), and it should be signed by the individual making the request. It should be received by the Section within sixty (60) calendar days of the date the individual is informed of the PA Officer's refusal to amend a record in whole or in part. The request should be addressed and sent via certified mail to the Commissioner, United States Section, International Boundary and Water Commission, 4171 North Mesa, suite C-310, El Paso, TX 79902-1422. The processing of appeals will be facilitated if the words "PRIVACY APPEAL" appear in capital letters on both the envelope and the top of the appeal papers. An appeal not addressed and marked as provided herein will be marked by Section personnel when it is so identified and will be forwarded immediately to the Commissioner.
</p>
<p>(b) The time for decision on the appeal begins on the date the appeal is received by the Commissioner. The appeal should include any documentation, information or statements advanced for the amendment of the record.
</p>
<p>(c) There shall be a written record of the reason for the final determination. The final determination will be made not later than thirty (30) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and holidays) from the date the Commissioner receives the appeal; unless, for good cause shown, the Commissioner extends such determination beyond the thirty (30) day period.
</p>
<p>(d) When the final determination is that the record should be amended in accordance with the individual's request, the Commissioner shall direct the office responsible for the record to comply. The office responsible for the record shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Amend the record as directed;
</p>
<p>(2) If a distribution of the record has been made, advise all previous recipients of the record of the amendment and its substance;
</p>
<p>(3) So advise the individual in writing.
</p>
<p>(e) When the final decision is that the request of the individual to amend the record is refused, the Commissioner shall advise the individual:
</p>
<p>(1) Of the refusal and the reasons for it;
</p>
<p>(2) Of his or her right to file a concise statement of the reasons for disagreeing with the decision of the Section;
</p>
<p>(3) Of the procedures for filing the statement of disagreement;
</p>
<p>(4) That the statement which is filed will be made available to anyone to whom the record is subsequently disclosed together with, at the discretion of the Section, a brief statement by the Section summarizing its reasons for refusing to amend the record;
</p>
<p>(5) That prior recipients of the disputed record will be provided a copy of any statement of dispute to the extent that an accounting of disclosures was maintained; and
</p>
<p>(6) Of his or her right to seek judicial review of the Section's refusal to amend the record.
</p>
<p>(f) When the final determination is to refuse to amend a record and the individual has filed a statement under paragraph (e)(2) of this section, the Section will clearly annotate the record so that the fact that the record is disputed is apparent to anyone who may subsequently have access to use or disclose it. When information that is the subject of a statement of dispute filed by an individual is subsequently disclosed, the Section will note that the information is disputed and provide a copy of the individual's statement. The Section may also include a brief summary of the reasons for not making a correction when disclosing disputed information. Such statements will normally be limited to the reasons given to the individual for not amending the record. Copies of the Section's statement shall be treated as part of the individual's record for granting access; however, it will not be subject to amendment by the individual under these rules.
</p>
<p>(g) An appeal will be decided on the basis of the individual's appeal papers and the record submitted by the PA officer. No personal appearance or hearings on appeals will be allowed.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.15
 Judicial review.
</b></p>
<p>After having exhausted all administrative remedies set forth in &#167; 1101.7(g)(3) or &#167; 1101.14, a requester may bring a civil action against the Section, in a United States District Court of proper venue, within two years of the final administrative decision which the requester seeks to challenge.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.16
 Criminal penalties.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Under the provisions of the Act, it is a Federal crime for any person to knowingly and willfully request or obtain information from a Federal agency, including this Section, by false pretenses.
</p>
<p>(b) It is also a crime for any officer or employee of the Section to knowingly and willfully:
</p>
<p>(1) Make an unauthorized disclosure; or
</p>
<p>(2) Fail to publish public notice of a system of records as required by 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4).
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1101.17
 Annual report to Congress.
</b></p>
<p>(a) On or before August 1 of each calendar year the Commissioner shall submit a report covering the preceding calendar year to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate for referral to the appropriate committees of the Congress. The report shall include:
</p>
<p>(1) The U.S. Section's point of contact responsible for implementing the Privacy Act of 1974;
</p>
<p>(2) The number of active systems, new systems published, systems deleted, systems automated, either in whole or part, number of existing systems for which new routine uses were established, number of existing systems for which new exemptions were claimed, number of existing systems from which exemptions were deleted, and number of public comments received by the agency of publication of rules or notices;
</p>
<p>(3) Total number of requests for access, number of requests wholly or partially granted, number of requests totally denied, number of requests for which no record was found, number of appeals of denials of access, number of appeals in which denial was upheld, number of appeals in which denial was overturned either in whole or part, number of requests to amend records in system, number of amendment requests wholly or partially granted, number of amendment requests totally denied, number of appeals of denials of amendment requests, number of appeals in which denial was upheld, number in which denial was overturned either in whole or in part, whether the U.S. Section denied an individual access to his or her records in a system of record on any basis other than a Privacy Act exemption under 5 U.S.C. 552(j) or (k), and the legal justification for the denial, number of instances in which individuals litigated the results of appeals of access or amendment, and the results of such litigation, and a statement of our involvement in matching programs;
</p>
<p>(4) Any other information which will indicate the U.S. Section's effort to comply with the objectives of the Act, to include any problems encountered, with recommendations for solving thereof;
</p>
<p>(5) And, a copy of these regulations.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
