<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
	<agency toc="yes">
<name>Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction</name>
<abbrev>SIGAR</abbrev>
        
        
        
        
<section id="sigar1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-01</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Firearm Qualification Records. </subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202
-4135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>SIGAR employees, consultants, and detailees who are required to conduct and/or to maintain firearms qualification,
training, and proficiency activities in the performance of their regular duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records of an individual's annual qualification scores; Social Security Number (SSN); approvals of arming authority and
issue of federal officer credentials and firearms accountability and maintenance records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Law 110-181, Section 1229, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. Appendix 3,
Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; and 5 U.S.C. Section 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained and used to document the SIGAR firearms program information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To the appropriate local, state, foreign, or federal agency when records alone or in conjunction with other information,
indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by
general statute or particular program pursuant thereto.
</p><p>2. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; and (3) witnesses, potential witnesses, or their representatives and assistants, and any person possessing
information pertinent to the matter when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>3. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) compatible with the
purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: SIGAR, current or former contractors of the
agency, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or a current or former employee of SIGAR, current of
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or other United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>4. To a federal, foreign, state, or local agency to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring
or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting
of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit. The agency must deem such disclosure to be compatible with
the purpose for which the agency collected the information.
</p><p>5. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to agency officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>6. To training, administrative, and operations personnel of local law enforcement agencies in the performance of their
regular duties in order to process and to maintain documentation for investigative personnel who have been commissioned as
reserve officers or deputies.
</p><p>7. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of
harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity of this system or other
systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information;
and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with
the agency's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored as paper records and/or electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name and/or SSN.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established SIGAR
computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Access is limited to
those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to General Records Schedule 1, item 29, individual qualification scores, are destroyed when five years old or
five years after completion of a specific training program.
</p><p>Pursuant to General Records Schedule 11, item 4, credentials files, are destroyed 3 months after return to issuing office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Inspector General for Investigations, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written
inquiries to the Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters, Privacy Act Officer, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction,
Headquarters, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202. The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for
which records are sought, and the office location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Arming and arrest credential notifications and firearms qualifications results from individuals and training personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-02</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Property Accountability System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202-4135, and in SIGAR field offices in Afghanistan.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>SIGAR employees, including consultants and detailees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name and employee/custodian identification and position numbers of employees assigned equipment, account numbers,
organization, organization code, and location. Item description, date of purchase, acquired date, purchase price, purchase order
number, vendor and manufacturer, model/serial/license number, serial number, catalog number, contract number, property tag
identification, status/date, condition of property, operation number, high risk field, disposal code, storage location,
responsible officer name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Law 110-181, Section 1229, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. App. 3,
Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended,; 40 U.S.C. 524, Section 202(b), Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of
1949;41 CFR, Chapter 101, Subtitle C., Federal Property Management Regulation (FPMR); and 5 U.S.C. Section 301, Government
Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To identify employees/custodians of issued equipment and provide inventories to satisfy other Federal Procurement
Management Regulation requirements; to maintain a record of location of emergency equipment; to provide management information
necessary for the budgeting and allocation of equipment; and to provide evidence of assignment, location, and value in the event
that government property is stolen.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To any law enforcement agency as needed to provide evidence of assignment, location, and value in the event that
Government property is stolen.
</p><p>2. To the appropriate local, tribal, state, foreign or federal agency when records alone or in conjunction with other
information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether
arising by general statute or particular program pursuant thereto.
</p><p>3. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; and (3) witness, potential witness, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possess
information pertaining to the matter when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>4. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: (a) SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or (b) A current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or another United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>5. To a Federal, foreign, state, tribal, or local agency to obtain information relevant to an Agency decision concerning the
hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a
license, grant, or other benefit. SIGAR must deem such disclosure to be compatible with the purpose for which it collected the
information.
</p><p>6. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to SIGAR officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>7. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) the SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm
to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored as paper records and/or electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by tag number, license number, employee/custodian name, employee identification number, position
number, accounting information, catalog number, contract number, make, model, security logon identification, serial number,
and/or storage location.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in secured areas and/or maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are
controlled through established SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and are password
protected. Access is limited to those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to the General Records Schedule 3, item 4 and item 9, supply management and inventory files, are destroyed when
2 years old.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Inspector General for Management and Support, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written
inquiries to the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan
Reconstruction, Headquarters, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal
Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Payroll/Personnel system applications, various internal forms, accountable property representative and employees, data
processing personnel, and supply officers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-03</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Public Affairs Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202
-4135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Media representatives who request interviews with the Inspector General or agency principals; individuals who request
information from a press officer concerning an issue(s) or information about SIGAR and its policies; and representatives of
nongovernmental organizations throughout the United States; federal, foreign, state and local government officials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains contact information for individuals who are involved in the operations of SIGAR; name, address,
phone number, email addresses, and the like; assignments, biographies, speaking engagements, interviews and communications of
executive level staff, principals and members of the media; press releases; names of media organizations; information on SIGAR
employees who asked Public Affairs to publish information/articles about them.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Law 110-181, Section 1229, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; Inspector General Act
of 1978, as amended; 5 U.S.C. Appendix 3, Investigations; and 5 U.S.C. Section 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Enables SIGAR Public Affairs to establish and maintain contact with the media, members of civil society organizations
and the general public and circulate information to specific individuals or groups based on self-identified regional and policy
interests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To contact members of the media to inform them of events, travel opportunities; respond to media representatives' and
general public inquiries on various topics; and prepare briefing materials for interviewees.
</p><p>2. To other U.S. Government agencies and the White House, and to foreign, state and local governments for purposes of
planning and coordinating public engagement activities relevant to SIGAR's external and public affairs activities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored as paper records and electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By individual name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established SIGAR
computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Access is limited to
those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Public Affairs, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written
inquiries to the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan
Reconstruction, Headquarters, Privacy Act Officer, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal
Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>These records contain information obtained directly from the individual who is the subject of these records, the agency
or organization that the individual represents, published directories and/or other bureaus in SIGAR.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-04</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 1550 Crystal Drive, 9th Floor,
Arlington, VA 22202-4135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting copies of records from SIGAR under the provisions of the FOIA and the PA; individuals who submit
FOIA and PA requests, or FOIA/PA administrative appeals; individuals whose requests and/or records have been referred to the
SIGAR by other agencies; and in some instances includes attorneys representing individuals submitting such requests and appeals,
or individuals who are the subjects of such requests and appeals.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, and telephone number; description or identification of records requested, request control number,
furnished and/or denied; FOIA and PA division employee name assigned responsibility for processing request; dates of request and
actions; interim and final actions taken on request; persons or offices assigned actions on requests; copy of records requested,
furnished and/or denied; fee data, including payment delinquencies; final determinations of appeals; name/title of officials
responsible for denial of records; and case notes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Pub. L. No. 110-181, Section 1229, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. Appendix 3,
Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; 5 U.S.C. 552, Public information; agency rules, opinions, orders, records and
proceedings; and the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a, as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The processing of access requests and administrative appeals under the FOIA, access and amendment requests and
administrative appeals under the Privacy Act; for the purpose of participating in litigation regarding agency action on such
requests and appeals; and for the purpose of assisting the SIGAR in carrying out any other responsibilities under the FOIA and
the Privacy Act. Also used to produce statistical reports; and as a data source for management information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To another federal agency when consultation or referral is required to process requests.
</p><p>2. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; and (3) witness, potential witness, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possess
information pertaining to the matter when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>3. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or a current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who are acting in an official
capacity, or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or other United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>4. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to SIGAR officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>5. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to
economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored as paper and/or electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name of requester and/or assigned request control number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established SIGAR
computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Access is limited to
those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Director, Privacy, Records, and Disclosure, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written
inquiries to the Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters, Director, Privacy,
Records, and Disclosure, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
the Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters, Privacy Act Officer, 2530 Crystal
Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting copies of records and individuals responsible for processing and/or making determination on
requests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>During the course of a FOIA/PA action, exempt materials from other systems of records may become part of the case
records in this system of records. To the extent that copies of exempt records from those other systems of records are entered
into these FOIA/PA case records, SIGAR hereby claims the same exemptions for the records as claimed in the original primary
systems of records which they are a part.
</p><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)(3),
(d)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), (e)(5),(e)(8), (f), and (g) of the Privacy Act pursuant to 5
U.S.C. 552a (j)(2) and (k)(2). See 5 CFR part 9301. For additional information contact the System manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-05</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Audit Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202-4135, and in SIGAR field offices in Afghanistan.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Auditors, certain administrative support staff, contractors of SIGAR, and certain subjects and/or witnesses referenced
in SIGAR's audit activities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name of the auditor, support staff, contractors; audit reports; and working papers, which may include copies of
correspondence, evidence, subpoenas, other documents collected and/or generated by the Audit Directorate during the course of
official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Pub. L. No. 110-181, Sections 1229 and 842, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. App.
3, Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; and 5 U.S.C. &#167; 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system is maintained in order to act as a management information system for SIGAR audit projects and personnel and
to assist in the accurate and timely conduct of audits.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To appropriate Federal, foreign, state, local, Tribal or other public authorities or self-regulatory organizations
responsible for investigating or prosecuting the violation of, or for enforcing or implementing, a statute, rule, regulation,
order, or license, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a potential violation of civil or criminal law
or regulation.
</p><p>2. To the appropriate local, state, foreign or federal agency when records alone or in conjunction with other information,
indicates a violation or potential violation of law whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by
general statute or particular program pursuant thereto.
</p><p>3. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; and (3) witness, potential witness, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possess
information pertaining to the matter when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>4. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: (a) SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or (b) A current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or another United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>5. To the appropriate foreign, state, local, tribal, or other public authority or self-regulatory organization for the
purpose of (a) consulting as to the propriety of access to or amendment or correction of information obtained from that
authority or organization, or (b) verifying the identity of an individual who has requested access to or amendment or correction
of records.
</p><p>6. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to SIGAR officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>7. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) SIGAR suspects or has confirmed that the security or
confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the
suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to
the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity)
that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably
necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent,
minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>8. To any source, either private or governmental, to the extent necessary to elicit information relevant to a SIGAR audit or
investigation.
</p><p>9. In situations involving an imminent danger of death or physical injury, disclose relevant information to an individual or
individuals who are in danger.
</p><p>10. To persons engaged in conducting and reviewing internal and external peer reviews of SIGAR to ensure adequate internal
safeguards and management procedures exist within any office that had received law enforcement authorization or to ensure
auditing standards applicable to Government audits by the Comptroller General of the United States are applied and followed.
</p><p>11. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) the SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm
to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored on paper media and/or electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name of the auditor, support staff, contractors, or subject of the audit.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical
safeguards. Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established
SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Access is limited
to those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Inspector General for Audits, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request by an individual to determine if a system of records contains information about themselves should be directed
to Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction,
Headquarters, Privacy Act Officer, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters,
Privacy Act Officer, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with the SIGAR regulation implementing the Privacy Act, a request by an individual to determine if a
system of records contains information about him/her should be directed to Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of
the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters, Privacy Act Officer, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington,
VA 22202-3934. The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the
office locations(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above. Records are generally kept at locations where the work is performed. In
accordance with the SIGAR Privacy Act regulation, proper identification is required before a request is processed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from the requirement that the record source categories
be disclosed pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 522a(j)(2) and (k)(2).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)
(3), (d)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), (e)(5), (e)(8), (f), and (g) of the Privacy Act pursuant
to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2). See 5 CFR part 9301. For additional information contact the System manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-06</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Correspondence Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA
22202-4135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondents; and persons and entities upon whose behalf correspondence was initiated.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Correspondence received by SIGAR and responses generated thereto; and records used to respond to incoming
correspondence, including information included in SIGAR's other systems of records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Pub. L. No. 110-181, Sections 1229 and 842, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. App.
3, Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; and 5 U.S.C. &#167; 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system consists of correspondence received by SIGAR from individuals and their representatives; Federal, foreign,
state, local, tribal or other public authorities; entities subject to oversight by SIGAR; oversight committees; and others who
conduct business with SIGAR and the responses thereto. It serves as a record of in-coming correspondence and the steps taken to
respond.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To appropriate Federal, foreign, state, local, tribal or other public authorities or self-regulatory organizations
responsible for investigating or prosecuting violations of, or for enforcing or implementing, a statute, rule, regulation,
order, or license, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or
criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>2. To the appropriate local, state, foreign, or federal agency when records alone or in conjunction with other information,
indicates a violation or potential violation of law whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by
general statute or particular program pursuant thereto.
</p><p>3. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; and (3) witness, potential witness, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possess
information pertaining to the matter when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>4. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: (a) SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or (b) A current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or another United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>5. To the appropriate foreign, state, local, Tribal, or other public authority or self-regulatory organization for the
purpose of (a) consulting as to the propriety of access to or amendment or correction of information obtained from that
authority or organization, or (b) verifying the identity of an individual who has requested access to or amendment or correction
of records;
</p><p>6. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to SIGAR officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>7. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) SIGAR suspects or has confirmed that the security or
confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the
suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to
the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity)
that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably
necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent,
minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>8. To foreign governments or international organizations in accordance with treaties, international conventions, or
agreements.
</p><p>9. In situations involving an imminent danger of death or physical injury, a record from this system of records may be
disclosed as a routine use to an individual or individuals who are in danger.
</p><p>10. To any source, either private or governmental, to the extent necessary to elicit information relevant to a SIGAR audit or
investigation.
</p><p>11. To persons engaged in conducting and reviewing internal and external peer reviews of SIGAR to ensure adequate internal
safeguards and management procedures exist within any office that had received law enforcement authorization or to ensure
auditing standards applicable to government audits by the Comptroller General of the United States are applied and followed.
</p><p>12. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) the SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm
to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored on paper media and/or electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name, date, or subject matter.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical
safeguards. Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established
SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Classified
information is maintained in locked General Services Administration-approved Class 6 security containers. Access is limited to
those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Inspector General for Management and Support, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request by an individual to determine if a system of records contains information about themselves should be directed
to the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from the requirement that the record source categories
be disclosed pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)
(3), (d)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), (e)(5), (e)(8), (f), and (g) of the Privacy Act pursuant
to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2). See 5 CFR part 9301. For additional information contact the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-07</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">SIGAR Hotline Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA
22202-4135, and in SIGAR field offices in Afghanistan.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who are the subjects of inquiries concerning allegations of complaints, who have pertinent knowledge about
the inquiry, including SIGAR employees, and individuals authorized to furnish information; confidential informants,
complainants, SIGAR Hotline personnel, and other individuals involved in these inquiries.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name of individual or entity involved, case number, report title; records resulting from the referral of, and inquiry
into, Hotline complaints, such as the date of the complaint; the Hotline control number; the name of the complainant; the actual
allegations; referral documents to SIGAR components requesting investigation into SIGAR Hotline complaints; referral documents
from SIGAR components transmitting the SIGAR Hotline Completion Report, which normally contains the name of the examining
official(s) assigned to the case; background information regarding the investigation itself, such as the scope of the
investigation, relevant facts discovered, information received from witnesses, and specific source documents reviewed; the
investigator's findings, conclusions, and recommendations; and the disposition of the case; and internal SIGAR Hotline forms
documenting review and analysis of SIGAR Hotline Completion Reports received from SIGAR components.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Pub. L. No. 110-181, Sections 1229 and 842, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. App.
3, Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; and 5 U.S.C. &#167; 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These responsibilities include conducting and supervising investigations relating to programs and operations relating to
the expenditure of appropriated funds and funds otherwise made available for the reconstruction of Afghanistan, promoting the
economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in the administration of such programs and operations, and preventing and detecting
fraud, waste and abuse in such programs and operations. The records are used in investigations of individuals and entities
suspected of having committed illegal or unethical acts. The records are also used in any resulting criminal prosecutions, civil
proceedings, or administrative actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To appropriate Federal, foreign, state, local, tribal or other public authorities or self-regulatory organizations
responsible for investigating or prosecuting violations of, or for enforcing or implementing, a statute, rule, regulation,
order, or license, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or
criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>2. To the appropriate local, state, foreign or federal agency when records alone or in conjunction with other information,
indicates a violation or potential violation of law whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by
general statute or particular program pursuant thereto.
</p><p>3. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; (3) witnesses, potential witnesses, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possesses
information pertaining to the matter, when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>4. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: (a) SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or (b) A current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or another United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>5. To a federal agency, in response to its written request, to facilitate the requesting agency's decision concerning the
hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the
letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit, to the extent that the information is relevant and
necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter. SIGAR must deem such disclosure to be compatible with the purpose
for which it collected the information.
</p><p>6. To foreign governments or international organizations in accordance with treaties, international conventions, or
agreements.
</p><p>7. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to SIGAR officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>8. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to
economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>9. In situations involving an imminent danger of death or physical injury, a record from this system of records may be
disclosed as a routine use to an individual or individuals who are in danger.
</p><p>10. To any source, either private or governmental, to the extent necessary to elicit information relevant to a SIGAR audit or
investigation.
</p><p>11. To persons engaged in conducting and reviewing internal and external peer reviews of SIGAR to ensure adequate internal
safeguards and management procedures exist within any office that had received law enforcement authorization or to ensure
auditing standards applicable to government audits by the Comptroller General of the United States are applied and followed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored on paper media and/or electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name of individual or entity involved, case number, report title, or subject matter.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical
safeguards. Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established
SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, SIGAR Hotline, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request by an individual to determine if a system of records contains information about themselves should be directed
to Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction,
Headquarters, Privacy Act Officer, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters,
Privacy Act Officer, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individuals; individuals and organizations that have pertinent knowledge about a subject individual or corporate
entity; those authorized by an individual to furnish information; confidential informants; and Federal Bureau of Investigation
(FBI) and other Federal, foreign, state, and local entities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)
(3), (d)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), (e)(5), (e)(8), (f), and (g) of the Privacy Act pursuant
to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2). See 5 CFR part 9301. For additional information contact the System manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-08</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Investigation Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202 and at SIGAR field offices in Afghanistan.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals filing complaints of criminal, civil, or administrative violations, including fraud, waste or mismanagement;
individuals alleged to have been involved in such violations; individuals identified as having been adversely affected by
matters investigated by SIGAR; individuals who have been identified as possibly relevant to, or who are contacted as part of, a
SIGAR investigation, including: (1) current and former employees of the Departments of Defense and State and the Agency for
International Development, other Federal agencies, and federal contractors, grantees, and persons whose associations with
current and former employees relate to alleged violations under investigation; and, (2) witnesses, complainants, confidential
informants, suspects, defendants, respondents to SIGAR or other subpoenas, or parties who have been identified by SIGAR, other
agencies, or members of the general public in connection with authorized SIGAR functions; and SIGAR employees performing
investigative functions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name of subject(s), case number, title of investigative report, name of complainant, Social Security Number (SSN),
and/or names of witnesses, letters, memoranda, and other documents citing complaints of alleged criminal or administrative
misconduct.
</p><p>Investigative files: (1) reports of investigation resulting from allegations of misconduct or violations of law with related
exhibits, statements, affidavits, records or other pertinent documents (including those obtained from other sources, such as
Federal, state, local, or foreign investigative or law enforcement agencies and other government agencies) obtained during
investigations; (2) transcripts and documentation concerning requests and approval for consensual (telephone and non-telephone)
monitoring; (3) reports from or to other law enforcement bodies; (4) prior criminal or noncriminal records of individuals as
they relate to investigations; (5) subpoenas issued pursuant to SIGAR investigations, documents or other evidence produced to
SIGAR, and legal opinions, advice, and other legal documents prepared by SIGAR or other agency counsel; (6) reports of actions
taken by management personnel regarding misconduct allegations and reports of legal actions, including actions resulting from
violations of statutes referred to the United States Department of Justice for prosecution; (7) records involving the
disposition of investigations and resulting agency actions (e.g., criminal prosecutions, civil proceedings, administrative
action); and (8) other documentation and materials created during the course of or arising out of SIGAR investigations; and
records containing the name and/or other personal identifying information for SIGAR employees; names and other personal
identifying information for individuals who are investigated or involved as complainants, witnesses, informants, or otherwise in
SIGAR investigations; and details relating to investigations and complaints, such as the date of the complaint; case number(s);
name of the complainant; matters alleged; referral documents; research materials; and other documentation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Pub. L. No. 110-181, Sections 1229 and 842, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. App.
3, Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; 5 U.S.C. &#167; 301, Government Organization and Employees; and E.O. 9397
(SSN), as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used for conducting and supervising investigations relating to programs and operations regarding the
expenditure of appropriated funds and funds otherwise made available for the reconstruction of Afghanistan, promoting the
economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in the administration of such programs and operations, and preventing and detecting
fraud, waste and abuse. The records are used in investigations of individuals and entities suspected of having committed illegal
or unethical acts. The records are also used in any resulting criminal prosecutions, civil proceedings, or administrative
actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To appropriate Federal, foreign, state, local, tribal or other public authorities or self-regulatory organizations
responsible for investigating or prosecuting violations of, or for enforcing or implementing, a statute, rule, regulation,
order, or license, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or
criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>2. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; and (3) witness, potential witness, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possess
information pertaining to the matter when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>3. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: (a) SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or (b) A current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or another United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>4. To a federal agency, in response to its written request, to facilitate the requesting agency's decision concerning the
hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the
letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit, to the extent that the information is relevant and
necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter. SIGAR must deem such disclosure to be compatible with the purpose
for which the Office collected the information.
</p><p>5. To foreign governments or international organizations in accordance with treaties, international conventions, or
agreements.
</p><p>6. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to SIGAR officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>7. To persons engaged in conducting and reviewing internal and external peer reviews of SIGAR to ensure adequate internal
safeguards and management procedures exist within any office that had received law enforcement authorization or to ensure
auditing standards applicable to government audits by the Comptroller General of the United States are applied and followed.
</p><p>8. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to
economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored on paper media and/or electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name of subject(s), case number, title of investigative report, name of complainant, Social
Security Number (SSN), and/or names of witnesses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical
safeguards. Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established
SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Access is limited
to those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Inspector General for Investigations, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request by an individual to determine if a system of records contains information about themselves should be directed
to the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934. The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which
records are sought, and the office location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>A request by an individual to determine if a system of records contains information about themselves should be directed
to the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934. The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which
records are sought, and the office location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individuals; individuals and organizations that have pertinent knowledge about the subject; those authorized by
the individual to furnish information; confidential informants; the Department of Justice; Federal Bureau of Investigation
(FBI); other Federal, state, and local agencies; and foreign government agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)
(3), (d)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), (e)(5), (e)(8), (f), and (g) of the Privacy Act pursuant
to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2) and (k)(2). See 5 CFR part 9301. For additional information contact the System manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-09</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">SIGAR Legal Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 1550 Crystal
Drive, 9th Floor, Arlington, VA 22202-4135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All persons identified in files maintained by the Office of General Counsel, which includes attorneys, including:
Litigants and other claimants against SIGAR and its contractors asserting matters including, personal injury, property damage or
infringement, contract violation and harms resulting from employer-employee relationships; persons who are the subjects of
claims by SIGAR, such as persons who may have violated criminal laws, agency regulations and contracts with SIGAR and persons
against whom SIGAR considered asserting such claims; SIGAR's contractors and potential contractors; SIGAR employees, subject to
garnishment or assignments; and SIGAR employees and contractors who use Alternate Dispute Resolution (ADR).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records concerning legal matters include, (1) litigation and all other claims against, and by, SIGAR and its
contractors, which have been assigned to the Office of General Counsel; (2) SIGAR contracts; and (3) records pertaining to ADR.
Litigation and claim records may, among others, include correspondence, pleadings such as complaints, answers counterclaims and
motions; depositions, court orders and briefs. Records in this system may include documents such as accident reports, inspection
reports, investigation reports, audit reports, personnel files, contracts, consultant agreements, reports pertaining to criminal
matters of interest to SIGAR, Personnel Security Review Board documents, medical records, photographs, telephone records,
correspondence, memoranda and other related documents. Records may contain names, addresses, social security numbers and other
personally identifiable information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Pub. L. No. 110-181, Sections 1229 and 842, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. App.
3, Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; and 5 U.S.C. 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To assist SIGAR attorneys in providing legal advice to the agency on a wide variety of legal issues; to collect the
information of any individual who is, or will be, in litigation with the agency, as well as the attorneys representing the
plaintiff(s) and defendant(s) response to claims of employees, former employees, or other individuals; to assist in the
settlement of claims against the government; and to represent SIGAR in litigation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To appropriate Federal, foreign, state, local, tribal or other public authorities or self-regulatory organizations
responsible for investigating or prosecuting violations of, or for enforcing or implementing, a statute, rule, regulation,
order, or license, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or
criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>2. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to: (1) A person
representing SIGAR in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; (3) a witness, potential witness, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possesses
information pertaining to the matter, when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>3. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: (a) SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or (b) A current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or another United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>4. To a federal, foreign, state, tribal, or local agency to obtain information relevant to a SIGAR decision concerning the
hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a
license, grant, or other benefit. SIGAR must deem such disclosure to be compatible with the purpose for which SIGAR collected
the information.
</p><p>5. To facilitate the requesting agency's decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a
security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license,
grant, or other benefit, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the
matter. SIGAR must deem such disclosure to be compatible with the purpose for which SIGAR collected the information.
</p><p>6. To foreign governments or international organizations in accordance with treaties, international conventions, or
agreements.
</p><p>7. To SIGAR contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record in
the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to SIGAR officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>8. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to
economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records may be stored as paper records and/or electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name, case name, claim name, or assigned identifying number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical
safeguards. Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established
SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>General Counsel, Office of General Counsel, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>A request by an individual to determine if a system of records contains information about themselves should be directed
to Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202
-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-
3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individuals, inspection reports, other agencies, Office of General Counsel attorneys, other agency officers and
staff, contractors, investigators, and auditors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)
(3), (d)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), (e)(5), (e)(8), (f), and (g) of the Privacy Act pursuant
to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2) and (k)(2). See 5 CFR part 9301. For additional information contact the System manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Legislative Inquiries and Correspondence.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Headquarters, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202
-3934 and in SIGAR field offices in Afghanistan.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have requested assistance from their Congressional Representative(s), and the member of Congress who
corresponded with SIGAR.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name and address of constituent, date of letter by a member of Congress on behalf of the constituent; name of member of
Congress, materials forwarded by a member of Congress; and SIGAR response.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Sections 1229 and 842, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008, Pub. L. No. 110-181; Inspector
General Act of 1978, as amended; 5 U.S.C. App. 3; and 5 U.S.C. 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Maintained and used by SIGAR to record legislative inquiries on behalf of constituents and legislative inquiries from a
member or committee, to ensure proper document control of the response, and to record the agency's responses to such inquiries.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under  5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records
contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside SIGAR as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>1. To another federal agency when consultation or referral is required to process requests.
</p><p>2. To appropriate Federal, foreign, state, local, tribal or other public authorities or self-regulatory organizations
responsible for investigating or prosecuting violations of, or for enforcing or implementing, a statute, rule, regulation,
order, or license, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or
criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>3. For the purpose of an investigation, settlement of claims, or the preparation and conduct of litigation to (1) persons
representing the agency in the investigation, settlement or litigation, and to individuals assisting in such representation; (2)
others involved in the investigation, settlement, and litigation, and their representatives and individuals assisting those
representatives; (3) witnesses, potential witnesses, or their representatives and assistants, and any other person who possesses
information pertaining to the matter, when it is necessary to obtain information or testimony relevant to the matter.
</p><p>4. To the tribunals, counsel, other parties, witnesses, and the public (in publicly available pleadings, filings or
discussion in open court) when such disclosure: (1) Is relevant to, and necessary for, the proceeding; (2) is compatible with
the purpose for which SIGAR collected the records; and (3) the proceedings involve: (a) SIGAR, current or former contractors of
SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, or (b) A current or former employee of SIGAR, current or
former contractors of SIGAR, or other United States Government agencies and their components, who is acting in an official
capacity or in any individual capacity where SIGAR or another United States Government agency has agreed to represent the
employee.
</p><p>6. To agency contractors in performance of their contracts, and their officers and employees who have a need for the record
in the performance of their duties. Those provided information under this routine use are subject to the same limitations
applicable to agency officers and employees under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>7. When (1) it is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has
been compromised; (2) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to
economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security integrity if this system or other systems or
programs (whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the
disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with SIGAR's
efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records and electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name of constituent, other person of interest, or name of member of Congress.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are protected from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical
safeguards. Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established
SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Classified
information is maintained in locked General Services Administration-approved Class 6 security containers. Access is limited to
those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be retained in accordance with a schedule to be submitted for approval by the National
Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and other government-wide records schedules, as applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Public Affairs, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written
inquiries to Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction,
2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal
Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individual, member of Congress, and the author of the agency response.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Some records contained within this system of records are exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)
(3), (d)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), (e)(5), (e)(8), (f), and (g) of the Privacy Act pursuant
to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2) and (k)(2). See 5 CFR part 9301. For additional information contact the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Social Media Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202
-4135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who contact SIGAR through a social media outlet or other electronic means, including submitting feedback to
SIGAR, correspondent with SIGAR as a result of the agency's outreach using social networks, or requesting to be contacted by
SIGAR.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system may contain information pass through a social media site to facilitate interaction with SIGAR such as, but
not limited to: First name, last name, username, email address, home or work address, contact information, and phone numbers. It
may also include input and feedback from the public, such as comments, emails, videos, and other images, which may include tags,
geotags or geographic metadata. Depending on the circumstances of the individual's interaction and the social media site being
used, it may include data provided to SIGAR such as date of birth, age, security questions, IP addresses, passwords, financial
data, educational, business, or volunteer affiliation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Presidential Memorandum to the Heads of Executive Departments and Agencies on Transparency and Open Government, January
21, 2009. OMB M-10-06, Open Government Directive, Dec. 8, 2009. OMB M-10-23, Guidance for Agency Use of
Third-Party Web sites and Application, June 25, 2010.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of this system is to allow SIGAR to interact with the public and provide additional transparency to the
public through the use of social media. Registration information, username, comments, and suggestions made by the public on
third party social networks where SIGAR has an official presence may be collected by third party social networks for
registration or use of social media sites. Information and comments provided may be utilized by SIGAR to facilitate interaction
with the public, to disseminate information regarding an upcoming event, to notify the public of an emergency or breaking news,
or solicit feedback about SIGAR's programs. SIGAR may also respond to information received directly from individuals who provide
feedback from social media outreach using alternate methods, such as an email directly to SIGAR.
</p><p>Disclosures outside SIGAR may be made without the consent of the individual to whom the record pertains under the routine
uses listed:
</p><p>(1) (a) To any of the following entities or individuals, when the circumstances set forth in paragraph (b) are met:
</p><p>(i) The U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ);
</p><p>(ii) A court or an adjudicative or other administrative body;
</p><p>(iii) A party in litigation before a court or an adjudicative or other administrative body; or
</p><p>(iv) Any SIGAR employee acting in his or her individual capacity if SIGAR or DOJ has agreed to represent that employee or pay
for private representation of the employee;
</p><p>(b) When:
</p><p>(i) One of the following is a party to the proceeding or has an interest in the proceeding:
</p><p>(A) SIGAR or any component of SIGAR;
</p><p>(B) Any other Federal agency appearing before the Office of Hearings and Appeals;
</p><p>(C) Any SIGAR employee acting in his or her official capacity;
</p><p>(D) Any SIGAR employee acting in his or her individual capacity if SIGAR or DOJ has agreed to represent that employee or pay
for private representation of the employee;
</p><p>(E) The United States, when DOJ determines that SIGAR is likely to be affected by the proceeding; and
</p><p>(ii) SIGAR deems the disclosure to be:
</p><p>(A) Relevant and necessary to the proceeding; and
</p><p>(B) Compatible with the purpose for which the records were compiled.
</p><p>(2) To a congressional office in response to a written inquiry that an individual covered by the system, or the heir of such
individual if the covered individual is deceased, has made to the office.
</p><p>(3) To the Executive Office of the President in response to an inquiry from that office made at the request of the subject of
a record or a third party on that person's behalf, or for a purpose compatible for which the records are collected or
maintained.
</p><p>(4) To any criminal, civil, or regulatory law enforcement authority (whether Federal, state, territorial, local, Tribal or
foreign) when a record, either alone or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of
law--criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, and the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were
compiled.
</p><p>(5) To an official of another Federal agency to provide information needed in the performance of official duties related to
reconciling or reconstructing data files or to enable that agency to respond to an inquiry by the individual to whom the record
pertains.
</p><p>(6) To Federal, state, territorial, local, Tribal, or foreign agencies that have requested information relevant or necessary
to the hiring, firing or retention of an employee or contractor, or the issuance of a security clearance, license, contract,
grant or other benefit, when the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were compiled.
</p><p>(7) To representatives of the National Archives and Records Administration to conduct records management inspections under
the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>(8) To state and local governments and Tribal organizations to provide information needed in response to court order and/or
discovery purposes related to litigation, when the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were
compiled.
</p><p>(9) To an expert, consultant, or contractor (including employees of the contractor) of SIGAR that performs services requiring
access to these records on SIGAR's behalf to carry out the purposes of the system.
</p><p>(10) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:
</p><p>(a) It is suspected or confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been
compromised; and
</p><p>(b) SIGAR has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or
property interest, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs
(whether maintained by SIGAR or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and
</p><p>(c) The disclosure is made to such agencies, entities and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with
SIGAR's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>(11) To the Office of Management and Budget during the coordination and clearance process in connection with
</p><p>legislative affairs as mandated by OMB Circular A-19.
</p><p>(12) To the Department of the Treasury to recover debts owed to the United States.
</p><p>(13) To a consumer reporting agency if the disclosure requirements of the Debt Collection Act, as outlined at 31
</p><p>U.S.C. 3711(e)(1), have been met.
</p><p>(14) To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Public Affairs Officer in consultation with Counsel and the
Senior Agency Official for Privacy, where there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information, except
to the extent it is determined that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an
unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records are contained in file folders in file cabinets; electronic records are contained in removable drives,
computers, email, and electronic databases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be retrieved by full-text search, names, image, video, email address, user name, or date received.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked cabinets and desks. Electronic records are controlled through established SIGAR
computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical security), and they are password protected. Access is limited to
those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with SIGAR social media proposed records schedule. The disposition is
temporary, and records will be destroyed when no longer needed for agency business.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Policy official is the Director for Communications and Congressional Relations, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202
-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written
inquiries to the Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, Headquarters, Privacy Act Officer, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction,
Headquarters, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202. The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for
which records are sought, and the office location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who interact with SIGAR through social media networks or who communicate electronically with SIGAR in
response to public outreach.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="sigar12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Internal Electronic Collaboration Tools.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (SIGAR), 9th Floor, 1550 Crystal Drive,
Arlington, VA 22202-4135, and in SIGAR field offices in Afghanistan.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>SIGAR employees, interns, contractors, consultants and detailees who are given access to the SIGAR network.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>SIGAR user name, title, business and personal contact information, and organizational chart and hierarchy information.
Those users who elect to participate in MySites will be able to publish additional personal information, such as personal
photographs, information about their family status (such as whether they are married or have children), their hobbies, subject
matter areas of SIGAR business about which they are knowledgeable, personal activities, notes, messages and other content. Also,
the Internal Electronic Collaboration Tools will contain documents in electronic form covered by other SIGAR Privacy Act System
of Record Notices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Law 110-181, Section 1229, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008; 5 U.S.C. App. 3,
Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended; 40 U.S.C. 524, Section 202(b), Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of
1949; and 5 U.S.C. Section 301, Government Organization and Employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of the new system of records is to enhance and improve efficiencies in the dissemination and exchange of
information within SIGAR and allow colleagues to connect with each other. The internal electronic collaboration tools, utilizing
the Microsoft SharePoint platform, will upgrade SIGAR's intranet, allow users to set up team collaboration workspaces,
facilitate sharing of documents, policies and information, and allow limited social networking through the SharePoint "
MySites" feature. The new intranet will include SIGAR policies, procedures, forms, organization charts, news clips, links
to other sites that are helpful for staff members, and links to other SIGAR SharePoint sites containing shared documents and
other information. The intranet will include content regarding program offices, services and support, and projects and
activities. By connecting to a SIGAR network administration database, the intranet will display a directory of all SIGAR users,
including titles, contact information and the photograph used for SIGAR credentials for all employees, interns, volunteers,
consultants and contractors (collectively "users"). The MySites feature will allow SIGAR users to set up a personal
profile, upload pictures, and publish content and messages that are similar to email. MySites also allows users to join groups,
connect with colleagues and receive a newsfeed when new information is posted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The information in this system will be routinely used by SIGAR users to disseminate and share information, collaborate
and communicate with each other with the goal of more efficiently conducting SIGAR business. Also, the Internal Electronic
Collaboration Tools system will contain documents in electronic form covered by other System of Record Notices, and the routine
uses for those System of Record Notices apply. In addition, information in this system may be disclosed in accordance with the
blanket routine uses that appear in the SIGAR's Privacy Act Systems of Records Notices, see, <i>e.g.,</i> 77 FR 22626 (April 16,
2012) and 77 FR 38363 (June 27, 2012).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Electronic records, including emails, spreadsheet, PDF files, other documents and content maintained in or through this
system are stored on the SIGAR network and other electronic media as needed, such as encrypted hard drives and back-up media.
Print-outs of records in the system are stored in file folders, binders, and similar filing methods.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by name of the employee, intern, consultant, or contractor who has access to the SIGAR network.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Electronic records are controlled through established SIGAR computer center procedures (personnel screening and physical
security), and are password protected. Access is limited to those whose official duties require access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records will be maintained and dispositioned in accordance with records disposition schedules approved by the
National Archives and Records Administration.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Inspector General for Management and Support, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202-3934.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written
inquiries to the Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan
Reconstruction, Headquarters, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requester's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requester believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to
Director, Privacy, Records and Disclosure, Office of Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal
Drive, Arlington, VA 22202.
</p><p>The request should include the requestor's complete name, time period for which records are sought, and the office
location(s) where the requestor believes the records are located.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification Procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>The Internal Electronic Collaboration Tools system will contain documents in electronic form covered by other System of
Record Notices, and the exemptions for those Systems of Record Notices apply.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
        
        
        
<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="5">
<heading> Administrative Personnel </heading>
<regulationsChapter number=" LXXXIII">
<heading> Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction </heading>
<regulationsPart number="9301">
<heading> DISCLOSURE OF RECORDS AND INFORMATION </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>9301.12 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>9301.13 Rules for determining if an individual is the subject of a record.
</p>
<p>9301.14 Requests for access.
</p>
<p>9301.15 Access to the accounting of disclosures from records.
</p>
<p>9301.16 Requests for copies of records.
</p>
<p>9301.17 Requests to amend records.
</p>
<p>9301.18 Request for review.
</p>
<p>9301.19 Schedule of fees.
</p>
    <p>9301.20 Exemptions</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Privacy Act of 1974, Pub. L. 93-579, 88 Stat. 1896, codified at 5 U.S.C. 552a(f) (agency rules).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 77 FR 34180, June 11, 2012, unless otherwise noted.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.12
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>The purpose of this subpart is to provide certain safeguards for an individual against the invasion of his or her
personal privacy by SIGAR. This subpart is promulgated pursuant to the requirements applicable to all federal agencies contained
in 5 U.S.C. 552a(f).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.13
 Rules for determining if an individual is the subject of a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Individuals desiring to know if a specific system of records maintained by SIGAR contains a record pertaining to
them should address their inquiries to the Privacy Officer, Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530
Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202. As there may be delays in mail delivery, it is advisable to send the request via facsimile
to (703) 601-3804 or by email to <i>sigar.pentagon.gen-coun.mbx.privacy@mail.mil.</i> The written inquiry should contain a
specific reference to the system of records maintained by the SIGAR listed in the SIGAR Notice of Systems of Records, or it
should describe the type of record in sufficient detail reasonably to identify the system of records. Notice of SIGAR systems of
records subject to the Privacy Act will be published in the <i>Federal Register,</i> posted on the SIGAR public facing Web site,
and copies of the notices will be available upon request to the Privacy Officer when so published. A compilation of such notices
will also be made and published by the Office of the Federal Register, in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(f).
</p>
<p>(b) At a minimum, the request should contain sufficient identifying information to allow SIGAR to determine if there is a
record pertaining to the individual making the request in a particular system of records. In instances when the requester's
identification is insufficient to ensure disclosure to the individual to whom the information pertains in view of the
sensitivity of the information, SIGAR reserves the right to solicit from the person requesting access to a record additional
identifying information.
</p>
<p>(c) Ordinarily the person requesting will be informed whether the named system of records contains a record pertaining to
such person within 10 days of such a request (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal Federal holidays). Such a response will
also contain or reference the procedures which must be followed by the individual making the request in order to gain access to
the record.
</p>
<p>(d) Whenever a response cannot be made within the 10 days, the Privacy Officer will inform the person making the request the
reasons for the delay and the date on which a response may be anticipated.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.14
 Requests for access.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Requirement for written requests.</i> An individual desiring to gain access to a record pertaining to him or her
in a system of records maintained by SIGAR must submit his or her request in writing in accordance with the procedures set forth
in paragraph (b) of this section. Individuals employed by the SIGAR may make their requests on a regularly scheduled workday
(Monday through Friday, excluding legal Federal holidays) between the hours of 9:00 a.m. and 5:30 p.m. Such requests for access
by individuals employed by SIGAR need not be made in writing.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Procedures</i>--(1) <i>Content of the request.</i> The request for access to a record in a system of records
shall be addressed to the Privacy Officer at the address cited above, and shall name the system of records or contain a concise
description of such system of records. The request should state that the request is pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974. In the
absence of such a statement, if the request is for a record pertaining to the person requesting access which is maintained by
SIGAR in a system of records, the request will be considered under both the Privacy Act of 1974 and the Freedom of Information
Act, depending on which would allow greater access to the records requested. The request should contain necessary information to
verify the identity of the person requesting access (see paragraph (b)(2)(vi) of this section). In addition, such person should
include any other information which may assist in the rapid identification of the record for which access is being requested
(e.g., maiden name, dates of employment, etc.) as well as any other identifying information contained in and required by the
SIGAR Notice of Systems of Records.
</p>
<p>(i) If the request for access follows a prior request under &#167; 9301.1, the same identifying information need not be
included in the request for access if a reference is made to that prior correspondence or a copy of the SIGAR response to that
request is attached. If the individual specifically desires a copy of the record, the request should so specify under
&#167; 9301.4.
</p>
<p>(ii) [Reserved]
</p>
<p>(2) <i>SIGAR action on request.</i> A request for access will ordinarily be answered within 10 days, except when the Privacy
Officer determines otherwise, in which case the person making the request will be informed of the reasons for the delay and an
estimated date by which the request will be answered. When the request can be answered within 10 days, it shall include the
following:
</p>
<p>(i) A statement that there is a record as requested or a statement that there is not a record in the systems of records
maintained by SIGAR;
</p>
<p>(ii) A statement as to whether access will be granted only by providing a copy of the record through the mail; or the address
of the location and the date and time at which the record may be examined. In the event the person requesting access is unable
to meet the specified date and time, alternative arrangements may be made with the Privacy Officer;
</p>
<p>(iii) A statement, when appropriate, that examination in person will be the sole means of granting access only when the
Privacy Officer has determined that it would not unduly impede the right of access of the person making the request.
</p>
<p>(iv) The amount of fees charged, if any (see &#167;&#167; 9301.6 and 9301.7). (Fees are applicable only to requests for
copies);
</p>
<p>(v) The name, title, and telephone number of the SIGAR official having operational control over the record; and
</p>
<p>(vi) The documentation required by SIGAR to verify the identity of the person making the request. At a minimum, SIGAR
verification standards include the following:
</p>
<p>(A) <i>Current or former SIGAR Employees.</i> Current or former SIGAR employees requesting access to a record pertaining to
them in a system of records maintained by SIGAR may, in addition to the other requirements of this section, and at the sole
discretion of the official having operational control over the record, have his or her identity verified by visual observation.
If the current or former SIGAR employee cannot be so identified by the official having operational control over the records,
identification documentation will be required. The employee's common access card, annuitant identification, driver licenses, or
the "employee copy" of any official personnel document in the record are examples of acceptable identification
validation.
</p>
<p>(B) <i>Other than current or former SIGAR employees.</i> Individuals other than current or former SIGAR employees requesting
access to a record pertaining to them in a system of records maintained by SIGAR must produce identification documentation of
the type described in paragraph (b)(2)(vi)(A) of this section, prior to being granted access. The extent of the identification
documentation required will depend on the type of record for which access is requested. In most cases, identification
verification will be accomplished by the presentation of two forms of identification. Any additional requirements will be
specified in the system of records notices published by SIGAR pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4).
</p>
<p>(C) <i>Access granted by mail.</i> For records to be made accessible by mail, the Privacy Officer shall, to the extent
possible, establish identity by a comparison of signatures in situations where the data in the record is not so sensitive that
unauthorized access could cause harm or embarrassment to the individual to whom they pertain. No identification documentation
will be required for the disclosure to a person making a request of information under the FOIA, 5 U.S.C. 552. When, in the
opinion of the Privacy Officer the granting of access through the mail could reasonably be expected to result in harm or
embarrassment if disclosed to a person other than the individual to whom the record pertains, a notarized statement of identity
or some similar assurance of identity will be required.
</p>
<p>(D) <i>Unavailability of identification documentation.</i> If an individual is unable to produce adequate identification
documentation the individual will be required to sign a statement asserting identity and acknowledging that knowingly or
willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another person under false pretenses may result in a fine of up to
$5,000. In addition, depending upon the sensitivity of the records to which access is sought, the official having operational
control over the records may require such further reasonable assurances as may be considered appropriate; e.g., statements of
other individuals who can attest to the identity of the person making the request.
</p>
<p>(E) <i>Access by the parent of a minor, or by a legal guardian.</i> A parent of a minor, upon presenting suitable personal
identification, may act on behalf of the minor to gain access to any record pertaining to the minor maintained by SIGAR in a
system of records. A legal guardian may similarly act on behalf of an individual declared to be incompetent due to physical or
mental incapacity or age by a court of competent jurisdiction, upon the presentation of the documents authorizing the legal
guardian to so act, and upon suitable personal identification of the guardian.
</p>
<p>(F) Granting access when accompanied by another individual. When an individual requesting access to his or her record in a
system of records maintained by SIGAR wishes to be accompanied by another individual during the course of the examination of the
record, the individual making the request shall submit to the official having operational control of the record, a signed
statement authorizing that person access to the record.
</p>
<p>(G) <i>Granting access to individuals other than the subject of the record.</i> SIGAR will not disclose any record which is
contained in a system of records by any means of communication to any person, or to another agency, except pursuant to a written
request by, or with the prior written consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains, pursuant to the Privacy Act of
1974.
</p>
<p>(H) <i>Denial of access for inadequate identification documentation.</i> If the official having operation control over the
records in a system of records maintained by SIGAR determines that an individual seeking access has not provided sufficient
identification documentation to permit access, the official shall consult with the Privacy Officer prior to finally denying the
individual access.
</p>
<p>(vii) <i>Medical records.</i> The records in a system of records which are medical records shall be disclosed to the
individual to whom they pertain in such manner and following such procedures as the Privacy Officer shall direct. When SIGAR in
consultation with a physician, determines that the disclosure of medical information could have an adverse effect upon the
individual to whom it pertains, SIGAR may transmit such information to a physician named by the individual.
</p>
<p>(viii) <i>Exceptions.</i> Nothing in this section shall be construed to entitle an individual the right to access to any
information compiled in reasonable anticipation of litigation.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.15
 Access to the accounting of disclosures from records.
</b></p>
<p>Rules governing the granting of access to the accounting of disclosures are the same as those for granting access to the
records (including verification of identity) outlined in &#167; 9301.14.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.16
 Requests for copies of records.
</b></p>
<p>Rules governing requests for copies of records are the same as those for the granting of access to the records
(including verification of identity) outlined in &#167; 9301.14. (See also &#167; 9301.19 for rules regarding fees.)

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.17
 Requests to amend records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Requirement for written requests.</i> Individuals desiring to amend a record that pertains to them in a system of
records maintained by SIGAR must submit their request in writing in accordance with the procedures set forth herein unless this
requirement is waived by the official having responsibility for the system of records. Records not subject to the Privacy Act of
1974 will not be amended in accordance with these provisions. However, individuals who believe that such records are inaccurate
may bring this to the attention of SIGAR.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Procedures.</i> (1)(i) The request to amend a record in a system of records shall be addressed to the Privacy Officer.
Included in the request shall be the name of the system and a brief description of the record proposed for amendment. In the
event the request to amend the record is the result of the individual's having gained access to the record in accordance with
the provisions concerning access to records as set forth in this paragraph, copies of previous correspondence between the
individual and SIGAR will serve in lieu of a separate description of the record.
</p>
<p>(ii) When the individual's identity has been previously verified pursuant to &#167; 9301.14(b)(2)(vi), further
verification of identity is not required as long as the communication does not suggest that a need for verification has
reappeared. If the individual's identity has not been previously verified, SIGAR may require identification validation as
described in &#167; 9301.14(b)(2)(vi). Individuals desiring assistance in the preparation of a request to amend a record
should contact the Privacy Officer at the address cited above.
</p>
<p>(iii) The exact portion of the record the individual seeks to have amended should be clearly indicated. If possible, the
desired proposed alternative language should also be set forth, or at a minimum, the facts which the individual believes are not
accurate, relevant, timely, or complete should be set forth with such particularity as to permit SIGAR to understand the basis
for the request and to make an appropriate amendment to the record.
</p>
<p>(iv) The request should also set forth the reasons why the individual believes his record is not accurate, relevant, timely,
or complete. In order to avoid the retention by SIGAR of personal information merely to permit verification of records, the
burden of persuading SIGAR to amend a record will be upon the individual. The individual must furnish sufficient facts or
credible documentation to persuade the official in charge of the system of the inaccuracy, irrelevancy, untimeliness, or
incompleteness of the record.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>SIGAR action on the request.</i> To the extent possible, a decision upon a request to amend a record will be made
within 10 days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal Federal holidays. In the event a decision cannot be made within this time
frame, the individual making the request will be informed within 10 days of the expected date for a decision. The decision upon
a request for amendment will include the following:
</p>
<p>(i) The decision of SIGAR whether to grant in whole, or deny any part of the request to amend the record.
</p>
<p>(ii) The reasons for the determination for any portion of the request which is denied.
</p>
<p>(iii) The name and address of the official with whom an appeal of the denial may be lodged.
</p>
<p>(iv) The name and address of the official designated to assist, as necessary, and upon request of, the individual making the
request in the preparation of the appeal.
</p>
<p>(v) A description of the review of the appeal within SIGAR (see &#167; 9301.18).
</p>
<p>(vi) A description of any other procedures which may be required of the individual in order to process the appeal.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.18
 Request for review.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Individuals wishing to request a review of the decision by SIGAR with regard to an initial request to amend a record
in accordance with the provisions of &#167; 9301.17, should submit the request for review in writing and, to the extent
possible, include the information specified in &#167; 9301.17(a). Individuals desiring assistance in the preparation of
their request for review should contact the Privacy Officer at the address provided herein.
</p>
<p>(b) The request for review should contain a brief description of the record involved or in lieu thereof, copies of the
correspondence from SIGAR in which the request to amend was denied, and also should state the reasons why the individual
believes that the disputed information should be amended. The request for review should make reference to the information
furnished by the individual in support of his claim and the reasons, as required by &#167; 9301.17, set forth by SIGAR in
its decision denying the amendment. In order to avoid the unnecessary retention of personal information, SIGAR reserves the
right to dispose of the material concerning the request to amend a record if no request for review in accordance with this
section is received by SIGAR within 180 days of the mailing by SIGAR of its decision upon an initial request. A request for
review received after the 180 day period may, at the discretion of the Privacy Officer, be treated as an initial request to
amend a record.
</p>
<p>(c) The request for review should be addressed to the Appellate Authority, Office of the Special Inspector General for
Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington, VA 22202. As there may be delays in mail delivery, it is advisable to
send the request via facsimile to (703) 601-3804 or by email to <i>sigar.pentagon.gen-coun.mbx.privacy@mail.mil.</i>
</p>
<p>(d) Final determinations on requests for reviews within SIGAR will be made by the Appellate Authority. Additional information
may be requested by the Appellate Authority from the person requesting a review if necessary to make a determination.
</p>
<p>(e) The Appellate Authority will inform the person making the request in writing of the decision on the request for review
within 30 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal Federal holidays) from the date of receipt by SIGAR of the individual's
request for review, unless the Appellate Authority extends the 30 day period for good cause. The extension and the reasons
therefore will be sent by SIGAR to the individual within the initial 30 day period. Included in the notice of a decision being
reviewed, if the decision does not grant in full the request for review, will be a description of the steps the individual may
take to obtain judicial review of such a decision, and a statement that the individual may file a concise statement with SIGAR
setting forth the individual's reasons for his disagreement with the decision upon the request for review. The SIGAR Privacy
Officer has the authority to determine the "conciseness" of the statement, taking into account the scope of the
disagreement and the complexity of the issues. Upon the filing of a proper concise statement by the individual, any subsequent
disclosure of the information in dispute will have the information in dispute clearly noted and a copy of the concise statement
furnished, setting forth its reasons for not making the requested changes, if SIGAR chooses to file such a statement. A copy of
the individual's statement, and if it chooses, SIGAR's statement, will be sent to any prior transferee of the disputed
information who is listed on the accounting required by 5 U.S.C. 552a(c).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 9301.19
 Schedule of fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Prohibitions against charging fees.</i> Individuals will not be charged for:
</p>
<p>(1) The search and review of the record;
</p>
<p>(2) Any copies of the record produced as a necessary part of the process of making the record available for access; or
</p>
<p>(3) Any copies of the requested record when it has been determined that access can only be accomplished by providing a copy
of the record through the mail.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Waiver.</i> The Privacy Officer may, at no charge, provide copies of a record if it is determined that the production
of the copies is in the interest of the Government.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Fee schedule and method of payment.</i> Fees will be charged as provided below except as provided in paragraphs (a)
and (b) of this section.
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Duplication of records.</i> Records will be duplicated at a rate of $.10 per page for copying of 4 pages or more.
There is no charge for copying fewer pages.
</p>
<p>(2) Where it is anticipated that the fees chargeable under this section will amount to more than $25, the person making the
request shall be notified of the amount of the anticipated fee or such portion thereof as can readily be estimated. In instances
where the estimated fees will greatly exceed $25, an advance deposit may be required. The notice or request for an advance
deposit shall extend an offer to the person requesting to consult with the Privacy Officer in order to reformulate the request
in a manner which will reduce the fees, yet still meet the needs of individuals making the request.
</p>
<p>(3) Fees must be paid in full prior to issuance of requested copies. In the event the person requesting is in arrears for
previous requests copies will not be provided for any subsequent request until the arrears have been paid in full.
</p>
<p>(4) Remittances shall be in the form either of a personal check or bank draft drawn on a bank in the United States, or a
postal money order. Remittances shall be made payable to the order of the Treasury of the United States and mailed or delivered
to the Privacy Officer, Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, 2530 Crystal Drive, Arlington,
VA 22202.
</p>
<p>(5) A receipt for fees paid will be given upon request.
</p>
    <p>
        <b>&#167; 9301.20</b>
    </p>
    <p>
        Systems of records maintained by
        SIGAR are authorized to be exempted
        from certain provisions of the Privacy
        Act under the general and specific
        exemptions set forth in the Act. In
        utilizing these exemptions, SIGAR is
        exempting only those portions of
        systems that are necessary for the proper
        functioning of SIGAR and that are
        consistent with the Privacy Act. Where
        compliance would not appear to
        interfere with or adversely affect the law
        enforcement process, and/or where it
        may be appropriate to permit
        individuals to contest the accuracy of
        the information collected, e.g., public
        source materials, the applicable
        exemption may be waived, either
        partially or totally, by SIGAR, in the
        sole discretion of SIGAR, as appropriate.
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>(a) General exemptions.</i> (1)
        Individuals may not have access to
        records maintained by SIGAR that were
        provided by another agency that has
        determined by regulation that such
        information is subject to general
        exemption under 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(1). If
        such exempt records are the subject of
        an access request, SIGAR will advise the
        requester of their existence and of the
        name and address of the source agency,
        unless that information is itself exempt
        from disclosure.
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) The systems of records maintained
        by the Investigations Directorate
        (SIGAR–08), are subject to general
        exemption under 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2). All
        records contained in record system
        SIGAR–08, Investigations Records, are
        exempt from all provisions of the
        Privacy Act except sections (b), (c)(1)
        and (2), (e)(4)(A) through (F), (e)(6), (7),
        (9), (10), and (11), and (i) to the extent
        to which they meet the criteria of
        section (j)(2). These exemptions are
        necessary to ensure the effectiveness of
        the investigative, judicial, and
        protective processes. These exemptions
        are necessary to ensure the proper
        functions of the law enforcement
        activity, to protect confidential sources
        of information, to fulfill promises of
        confidentiality, to prevent interference
        with the enforcement of criminal laws,
        to avoid the disclosure of investigative
        techniques, to avoid the endangering of
        the life and safety of any individual, to
        avoid premature disclosure of the
        knowledge of potential criminal activity
        and the evidentiary bases of possible
        enforcement actions, and to maintain
        the integrity of the law enforcement
        process.
    </p>
    <p>
        (3) The systems of records maintained
        by the Investigations Directorate
        (SIGAR–08) are exempted from 5 U.S.C.
        552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and
        (I), and (f) pursuant to the provisions of
        5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1), (2), and (5). These
        exemptions are necessary to protect
        material required to be kept secret in the
        interest of national defense and foreign
        policy; to prevent individuals that are
        the subject of investigation from
        frustrating the investigatory process; to
        ensure the proper functioning and
        integrity of law enforcement activities;
        to prevent disclosure of investigative
        techniques; to maintain the confidence
        of foreign governments in the integrity
        of the procedures under which
        privileged or confidential information
        may be provided; to fulfill commitments
        made to sources to protect their
        identities and the confidentiality of
        information and to avoid endangering
        these sources and law enforcement
        personnel; and to ensure the proper
        functioning of the investigatory process,
        to ensure effective determination of
        suitability, eligibility, and qualification
        for employment and to protect the
        confidentiality of sources of
        information.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) [Reserved]
    </p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
