<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>


<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name> U.S. International Development Finance Corporation  </name>
<abbrev>
DFC</abbrev>

 <P>U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) was created by bringing together the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) and the Development Credit Authority (DCA) in 2018 </P>    

    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-07-16/pdf/2020-15398.pdf</url>
        <title>DFC SRONs added; OPIC SORNS combined, renamed, or deleted </title>
        <date year="2020" month="7" day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-15/pdf/2021-24802.pdf</url>
        <title>U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, DFC/09  Reasonable Accommodations Records </title>
        <date year="2021" month="11" day="15" />
    </previouslyPublished>


    <section id="dfc01" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-01</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Oracle E-Business Suite (EBS), DFC/01</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Business System Owner, Managing Director, Financial Management, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400. Technical System Owner, Business Information Systems Director, Office of the Chief Information Officer, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation 1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Where applicable, electronic payments are required under Federal Acquisition Regulation 52.232-25. Electronic payments require a Taxpayer Identification Number (TIN) data element. Federal financial mandates and legal authorities govern financial management systems that support the collection of the information in EBS. These mandates and authorities include the Chief Financial Officers Act of 1990, Public Law 101-576, and the Federal Financial Management Improvement Act (FFMIA) of 1996, Public Law 104-208, as well as guidance issued by OMB: OMB Circular A-123, Management’s Responsibility for Internal Control; OMB Memorandum 16-11, Improving Administrative Functions Through Shared Services; and OMB Memorandum 13-08, Improving Financial Systems Through Shared Services.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The primary purpose of Oracle EBS is to function as the financial system of record for the Agency. It is the primary application employed to record all financial transactions related to the Agency’s administrative business accounting and working capital budgets.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The categories of individuals and entities covered by this system are identified as Federal government agencies and institutions; state and local government agencies and institutions; domestic private individuals, entities, and institutions conducting business with the Agency; full- and part-time employees of the Agency; Personal Services Contractors (PSC); foreign government agencies and institutions; foreign private individuals, entities, and institutions conducting business with the Agency; and foreign entities and institutions who act as participants or intermediaries in financial transactions with the Agency.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Personally identifiable records that are stored in the system consist of individual or company names, points of contact, mailing addresses, remittance addresses, telephone numbers, contract/award numbers, email addresses, TIN, Social Security Numbers (SSN), Data Universal Numbering System (DUNS) numbers, and bank account information including routing numbers, account numbers, Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication (SWIFT) codes, International Bank Account Numbers (IBAN), and account titles.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Insight (Salesforce.com) (DFC/02): The Agency's back office software that collects data from external customers completing and submitting web-based business application electronic forms. Insight is DFC’s back-office data collection system where business- and product specific information is processed. System for Award Management (SAM) (GSA/GOVT-9): The U.S. Government’s official vendor portal where vendors self-maintain their business information. Carlson Wagonlit Sato Travel E2 Solutions System (E2) (GSA/GOVT-4): an electronic travel system that includes travel authorizations, travel vouchers, and miscellaneous reimbursements data that is directly received from the customer or employee.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed outside of DFC as a routine use under U.S.C. 552a(b)(3), as stated in the Notice and here for this modification. This modification includes a new routine use for the Do Not Pay initiative in compliance with Improper Payments, which is compatible with the following routine uses of this system of records of a financial management system: (1) the two required routine uses identified in OMB M-17-12 for notice and breach notification, which is compatible with the necessity of the government to deal with breaches; and (2) routine use for contractors, grantees, etc., and system support, which is compatible with the need of contractor support for Financial Systems. The other routine uses are compatible with the EBS system of records as a financial system. The routine use satisfies the compatibility requirement of the Privacy Act. The records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed as a routine use, as stated below. The Agency will, when so authorized, make the determination as to the relevancy of a record prior to its decision to disclose:</p>
                <p>A. To the Department of Treasury for Administering the Do Not Pay Initiative under the Improper Payments Elimination and Recovery Improvement Act of 2012 (IPERIA). As required by IPERIA, the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013, and the Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015 (FIPCA), records maintained in this system will be disclosed to (a) a Federal or state agency, its employees, agents (including contractors of its agents) or contractors; or, (b) a fiscal or financial agent designated by the Bureau of Fiscal Service or other Department of the Treasury bureau or office, including employees, agents, or contractors of such agent; or, (c) a contractor of the Bureau of Fiscal Service, for the purpose of identifying, preventing, and recovering improper payments to an applicant for, or recipient of, Federal funds. Records disclosed under this routing use may be used to conduct computerized comparison to identify, prevent, and recover improper payments, and to identify and mitigate fraud, waste, and abuse in federal payments.</p>
                <p>B. Disclosure for Enforcement, Statutory, and Regulatory Purposes. Information may be disclosed to the appropriate Federal, state, local, foreign, or self-regulatory organization or agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, implementing, issuing, or carrying out a statute, rule, regulation, order, policy, or license if the information may be relevant to a potential violation of civil or criminal law, rule, regulation, order, policy, or license.</p>
                <p>C. Disclosure to Another Federal Agency When Requesting Information. Information may be disclosed to a Federal agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of government in connection with the hiring, retaining, or assigning of an employee; the issuance of a security clearance; the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual; the classifying of jobs; the letting of a contract; the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefits by the receiving entity; or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the receiving entity to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the receiving entity’s decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>D. Disclosure to a Member of Congress and Congressional Inquiries. Information may be disclosed to a congressional office in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                <p>E. Disclosure to the Department of Justice (DOJ), a Court, an Adjudicative Body or Administrative Tribunal, or a Party in Litigation. Information may be disclosed to DOJ, a court, an adjudicative body or administrative tribunal, a party in litigation, or a witness if the Agency (or in the case of an Office of Inspector General (OIG) system, the OIG) determines, in its sole discretion, that the information is relevant and necessary to the matter.</p>
                <p>F. Disclosure to the Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB), the Office of Government Ethics (OGE), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), and Office of Special Counsel (OSC). Information may be disclosed to the EEOC, the MSPB, the OGE, or the OSC to the extent determined to be relevant and necessary to carrying out their authorized functions.</p>
                <p>G. Disclosure to the EEOC, the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), or the Fair Labor Relations Authority (FLRA) In Response to a Formal Grievance, Complaint, or Appeal Filed by an Employee. Information may be disclosed to the EEOC, OPM, FLRA, or other agency grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in the investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
                <p>H. Disclosure When Security or Confidentiality Has Been Compromised. Information may be disclosed when (1) it is suspected or confirmed that security or confidentiality of information has been compromised; (2) the Agency has determined that, as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of the system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>I. Disclosure to Contractors, Agents, and Others. Information may be disclosed to contractors, agents, or others performing work on a contract, service, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Agency and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Agency.</p>
                <p>J. Disclosure to Any Source from Which Additional Information Is Requested During the Acquisition and Procurement Contract Lifecycle Management Process. Information may be disclosed in connection with the requisitioning, commitments, obligations, invoicing, travel expense reimbursements, and reimbursements to employees for local travel expenses and other ancillary expenses.</p>
                <p>K. Disclosure of Information in Connection with Business Transaction Activities to a Federal Agency. Information may be disclosed to the Treasury Department via electronic file to enable processing of business payment and payable commitments for the life of each business transaction.</p>
                <p>L. Disclosure of Information in Connection with Business Transaction Activities to a Federal Agency. Information may be disclosed to a Federal agency in connection with initial due diligence processes in assessing new business transaction proposals and as part of the improper payment risk mitigation process that occurs for the life of each business transaction.</p>
                <p>M. Disclosure of Information to Another Federal Agency, a Court, or a Third Party. Information may be disclosed where the counterparty to a business transaction has not remitted agreed upon and contracted fees for an extended period of time.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are stored in paper and electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records can be retrieved by transaction record number, name, address, telephone numbers and other identifying information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained and disposed of as prescribed under the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) General Records Schedule. The information used to enter data into EBS is maintained for seven years. Paper records are disposed of by shredding or pulping, and records maintained on electronic media are degaussed or erased in accordance with the applicable records retention schedule and NARA guidelines.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Access to records in this system is controlled and managed pursuant to applicable policies and rules, including OPM’s Information and Security &amp; Privacy Policy. The use of password protection, system authentication, and other system protection methods also provides additional safeguards to restrict access. System access and access to the records contained within the system are limited to those individuals who have an official need for system access in order to perform their official responsibilities and duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Not Applicable</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="dfc02" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-02</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">
                <p>Salesforce Customer Relationship Management System ("Insight"); DFC/02</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Unclassified.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The system is located in an Enterprise Government Cloud Service environment. The system is hosted at secured Salesforce General Services Administration (GSA) data centers (NA–21) located in Washington, DC and Chicago, IL; one site acts as the active host and the alternative site acts as the disaster recovery location operating under near-real time replication protocol.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Business System Owner, Managing Director for Finance Program Systems and Procedures, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400. Technical Systems Owner, Business Information Systems Director, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The system covers individuals representing, guaranteeing, sponsoring, owning, or managing a potential or actual DFC project under all DFC products. Information about these individuals is entered directly into the system by potential clients filling out application forms on the Agency’s electronic forms web-portal or manually when DFC officers input data during a project’s lifecycle.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>This system contains the information needed for processing Agency projects and contains information about individuals and other entities involved in those projects. Depending on the level of connection of an individual to the project, personal information on the individual may be maintained. This includes full name, date of birth, country of birth, citizenship, personally identifying number, address, contact information, and professional experience.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>BUILD Act, 22 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.; 44 U.S.C. 3101, et seq.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>This system will facilitate project lifecycle management from project intake to project closeout for all DFC products. The information in the system will be used to administer the projects as necessary, including internally tracking and managing client contact information and the status (but not the detailed results) of Know Your Customer (KYC) due diligence performed on businesses and individuals associated with each project. Data from this system may also be used for evaluating the effectiveness of DFC’s products and programs and improving upon them.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information is collected directly from clients using a public-facing web portal which collects customer and project data from applicants. Direct input: some account, contact, and project data are input directly by DFC officers in the course of keeping project records up to date. Oracle EBS (DFC/01): pertinent financial data is sent to Insight to provide DFC officers with accessible information related to project status.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records of information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside of the Agency. The records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed as a routine use, as stated below. The Agency will, when so authorized, make the determination as to the relevancy of a record prior to its decision to disclose information under the following circumstances:</p>
                    <p>A. Disclosure for Enforcement, Statutory, and Regulatory Purposes. Information may be disclosed to the appropriate Federal, state, local, foreign, or self-regulatory organization or agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, implementing, issuing, or carrying out a statute, rule, regulation, order, policy, or license if the information may be relevant to a potential violation of civil or criminal law, rule, regulation, order, policy, or license.</p>
                    <p>B. Disclosure to a Member of Congress and Congressional Inquiries. Information may be disclosed to a congressional office in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                    <p>C. Disclosure to DOJ, a Court, an Adjudicative Body or Administrative Tribunal, or a Party in Litigation. Information may be disclosed to DOJ, a court, an adjudicative body or administrative tribunal, a party in litigation, or a witness if the Agency (or in the case of an OIG system, the OIG) determines, in its sole discretion, that the information is relevant and necessary to the matter.</p>
                    <p>D. Disclosure When Security or Confidentiality Has Been Compromised. Information may be disclosed when (1) it is suspected or confirmed that security or confidentiality of information has been compromised; (2) the Agency has determined that, as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of the system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities, and persons who are reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>E. Disclosure to Contractors, Agents, and Others. Information may be disclosed to contractors, agents, or others performing work on a contract, service, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Agency and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Agency.</p>
                    <p>F. Disclosure to Any Source from Which Additional Information Is Requested During Commitment of Payments. As needed, Insight automatically transfers information to Oracle EBS (DFC/01) to commit payments from DFC as part of the Agency’s core business transactions.</p>
                    <p>G. Disclosure of Information in Connection with Loan Payments to a Federal Agency. As needed, authorized DFC personnel manually input disbursement records into Oracle and the Treasury portal to enable loan payments.</p>
                    <p>H. Disclosure of Information in Connection with Business Transaction Activities to a Federal Agency. Information may be disclosed to a Federal agency in connection with initial due diligence processes in assessing new business transaction proposals and as part of the improper payment risk mitigation process that occurs for the life of each business transaction.</p>
                    <p>I. Disclosure of Information to Another Federal Agency, a Court, or a Third Party. Information may be disclosed where the counterparty to a business transaction has not remitted agreed upon and contracted fees for an extended period of time.</p>
                    <p>J.  Disclosure of Credit to Credit Reporting Agencies. If deemed necessary, credit information will be disclosed as the running of credit checks is performed. These credit checks are conducted confidentially, following accepted best practices with widely known and reputable credit reporting agencies.</p>
                    <p>K. Disclosure of Non-Individual Information to Publicly Available Websites: Authorized personnel utilize non-individual information from Insight (e.g., project descriptions and primary place of performance) for the following publicly available websites: USA Spending and Foreign Assistance.gov.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>System records are stored within secured Salesforce GSA data centers (NA–21) located in Washington, DC and Chicago, IL; one site acts as the active host and the alternative site acts as the disaster recovery location operating under near-real time replication protocol.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The records may be retrieved by the project name, project number, company name, associated individual’s name, or reporting tools provided on the system dashboards. Access to sensitive personally identifiable information (SPII) in the records is restricted to a small group of authorized government personnel who perform the KYC due diligence in the system, as needed. Access to the rest of the system is available to any Agency personnel with system access. The DFC uses two-factor authentication for Agency-specific users to access Insight outside of the Agency network. Any changes to the system are implemented through a change management process.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are maintained on an ongoing basis and updated by DFC staff assigned with managing the system. These records will follow the DFC’s retention schedule based on project classification.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Access to records in this system is controlled and managed pursuant to applicable policies and rules, including OPM’s Information and Security &amp; Privacy Policy. These records and the technical hardware containing these records are maintained on premises in areas designated as restricted access. The use of password protection, system authentication, user profile restrictions, and other system protection methods also provides additional safeguards to restrict access. System access and access to the records contained within the system are limited to those individuals who have an official need for system access in order to perform their official responsibilities and duties.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Same as above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Not Applicable</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    <section id="dfc03" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-03</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Payroll, Time and Attendance, Retirement, and Leave Records, DFC/03.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Business System Owner: Vice President and Chief Administrative Officer, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation 1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 5101, et seq., Government Organization and Employees; 31 U.S.C. 3512, et seq., Executive Agency Accounting and Other Financial Management Reports and Plans; 31 U.S.C. 1101, et seq., the Budget and Fiscal, Budget, and Program Information; 5 CFR part 293, subpart B, Personnel Records Subject to the Privacy Act; 5 CFR part 297, Privacy Procedures for Personnel Records; Executive Order 9397 as amended by Executive Order 13478, relating to Federal Agency Use of Social Security Numbers; and Public Law 101-576 (Nov. 15, 1990), the Chief Financial Officers (CFO) Act of 1990.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The primary purpose of the system is to manage personnel and payroll functions; ensure proper payment for salary and benefits; track time and attendance, leave, and other absences for reporting and compliance purposes; and facilitate reporting requirements to other Federal agencies, including the Department of the Treasury and OPM, for payroll, tax, and human capital management purposes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals covered by the system include current and former DFC employees, emergency workers, volunteers, contractors, and applicants for Federal employment. This system may also include limited information regarding employee spouses, dependents, emergency contacts, beneficiaries, or estate trustees who meet the definition of "individual" as defined in the Privacy Act. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system maintains records including: (1) Employee Biographical and Employment Information: employee name, other names used, citizenship, gender, date of birth, age, group affiliation, marital status, SSN, truncated SSN, legal status, place of birth, records related to position, occupation, duty location, security clearance, financial information, medical information, disability information, education information, driver's license, race, ethnicity, personal or work telephone number, personal and work email address, military status and service, home or mailing address, TIN, bank account information, professional licensing and credentials, family relationships, involuntary debt (garnishments or child support payments), employee common identifier (ECI), organization code, user identification, and any other employment information;  (2) Third-Party Information: spouse information, emergency contact, beneficiary information, savings bond co-owner name(s) and information, and family members and dependents information; (3) Salary and Benefits Information: salary data, retirement data, tax data, deductions, health benefits, allowances, union dues, insurance data, Flexible Spending Account, Thrift Savings Plan information and contributions, pay plan, payroll records, awards, court order information, back pay information, debts owed to the government as a result of overpayment, refunds owed, or a debt referred for collection on a transferred employee or emergency worker; and (4) Timekeeping Information: time and attendance records and leave records. This system may also contain correspondence, documents, and other information required to administer payroll, leave, and related functions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information is obtained from individuals on whom the records are maintained, official personnel records of individuals on whom the records are maintained, supervisors, timekeepers, previous employers, the Internal Revenue Service and state tax agencies, the Department of the Treasury, other Federal agencies, courts, state child support agencies, employing agency accounting offices, and third-party benefit providers.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>A. To DOJ, including Offices of the U.S. Attorneys, or other Federal agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative, or administrative body, when it is relevant or necessary to the litigation and one of the following is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation: (1) DFC or any component of DFC; (2) Any DFC employee or former employee acting in his or her official capacity; (3) Any DFC employee or former employee acting in his or her individual capacity when DFC or DOJ has agreed to represent that employee or pay for private representation of the employee; or (4) The United States Government or any agency thereof, when DFC determines that DFC is likely to be affected by the proceeding.</p>
                <p>B. To the Department of the Treasury or other Federal agency as required for payroll purposes, for preparation of payroll and other checks and electronic funds transfers to Federal, State, and local government agencies, non-governmental organizations, and individuals.</p>
                <p>C. To the Department of the Treasury, Internal Revenue Service, and state and local tax authorities for which an employee is or was subject to tax regardless of whether tax is or was withheld in accordance with Treasury Fiscal Requirements, as required.</p>
                <p>D. To OPM or its contractors in connection with programs administered by that office, including, but not limited to, the Federal Long-Term Care Insurance Program, the Federal Dental and Vision Insurance Program, the Flexible Spending Accounts for Federal Employees Program, and the electronic Human Resources Information Program.</p>
                <p>E. To another Federal agency to which an employee or DFC emergency worker has transferred or to which a DFC volunteer transfers in a volunteer capacity.</p>
                <p>F. To any criminal, civil, or regulatory law enforcement authority (whether Federal, state, territorial, local, tribal or foreign) when a record, either alone or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law--criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, and the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were compiled.</p>
                <p>G. To a congressional office in response to a written inquiry that an individual covered by the system, or the heir of such individual if the covered individual is deceased, has made to the office.</p>
                <p>H. To Federal, state, or local agencies where necessary to enable the employee's, DFC emergency worker's, or DFC volunteer's agency to obtain information relevant to the hiring or retention of that employee, DFC emergency worker, or DFC volunteer, or the issuance of a security clearance, contract, license, grant, or other benefit.</p>
                <p>I. To appropriate Federal and state agencies to provide reports including data on unemployment insurance.</p>
                <p>J. To the Social Security Administration to credit the employee or emergency worker account for Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI) and Medicare deductions.</p>
                <p>K. To officials of labor organizations recognized under 5 U.S.C. Chapter 71 (Labor-Management Relations) for the purpose of providing information as to the identity of DFC employees contributing union dues each pay period and the amount of dues withheld from each contributor.</p>
                <p>L. To employee or emergency worker associations to report dues deductions.</p>
                <p>M. To insurance carriers to report employee or DFC emergency worker election information and withholdings for health insurance.</p>
                <p>N. To charitable institutions when an employee designates an institution to receive contributions through salary deduction.</p>
                <p>O. To the Department of the Treasury, Internal Revenue Service, or another Federal agency or its contractor, to disclose debtor information solely to aggregate information for the Internal Revenue Service to collect debts owed to the Federal Government through the offset of tax refunds.</p>
                <p>P. To any creditor Federal agency seeking assistance for the purpose of that agency implementing administrative or salary offset procedures in the collection of unpaid financial obligations owed the United States Government from an individual.</p>
                <p>Q. To any Federal agency where the individual debtor is employed or receiving some form of remuneration for the purpose of enabling that agency to collect debts on the employee's behalf by administrative or salary offset procedures under the provisions of the Debt Collection Act of 1982.</p>
                <p>R. To the Department of the Treasury, Internal Revenue Service, and state and local authorities for the purpose of locating a debtor to collect a claim against the debtor.  </p>
                <p>S. To the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board's record keeper, which administers the Thrift Savings Plan, to report deductions, contributions, and loan payments.</p>
                <p>T. To the Office of Child Support Enforcement, within the Administration for Children and Families, within the Department of Health and Human Services, for the purposes of locating individuals to establish paternity; establishing and modifying orders of child support; identifying sources of income; and for other child support enforcement actions as required by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996.</p>
                <p>U. To an expert, consultant, grantee, or contractor (including employees of the contractor) of DFC who performs services requiring access to these records on DFC's behalf to carry out the purposes of the system, including employment verifications, unemployment claims, W-2 processing services, leave and earning statements, and 1095-C Affordable Care Act statements.</p>
                <p>V. To OPM Employee Express, which is an employee self-service system, to initiate personnel and payroll actions and to obtain payroll information.</p>
                <p>W. To the Department of Labor for processing claims for employees, emergency workers, or volunteers injured on the job or claiming occupational illness.</p>
                <p>X. To Federal agencies and organizations to support interfaces with other systems operated by the Federal agencies for which the employee or DOI emergency worker is employed, or the DFC volunteer is located, for the purpose of avoiding duplication, increasing data integrity, and streamlining government operations.</p>
                <p>Y. To another Federal agency to provide information needed in the performance of official duties related to reconciling or reconstructing data files or to enable that agency to respond to an inquiry by the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                <p>Z. To NARA to conduct records management inspections under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>AA. To OMB during the coordination and clearance process in connection with legislative affairs as mandated by OMB Circular A-19.</p>
                <p>BB. To Federal, state, territorial, local, tribal, or foreign agencies that have requested information relevant or necessary to the hiring, firing, or retention of an employee or contractor, regarding the issuance of a security clearance, license, contract, grant, or other benefit.</p>
                <p>CC. To state, territorial, and local governments, and tribal organizations to provide information needed in response to court order and/or discovery purposes related to litigation, when the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were compiled.</p>
                <p>DD. To the Department of the Treasury to recover debts owed to the United States.</p>
                <p>EE. To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Public Affairs Officer in consultation with counsel and the Senior Agency Official for Privacy (SAOP), where there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information or when disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of DFC or is necessary to demonstrate the accountability of DFC's officers, employees, or individuals covered by the system, except to the extent it is determined that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                <p>FF. To the Executive Office of the President in response to an inquiry from that office made at the request of the subject of a record or a third party on that person's behalf, or for a purpose compatible with the reason for which the records are collected or maintained.</p>
                <p>GG. To other Federal agencies and organizations to provide payroll and personnel processing services under a shared service provider cross-servicing agreement for purposes relating to DFC payroll and personnel processing.</p>
                <p>HH. To OPM, the Merit System Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in the performance of their authorized duties.</p>
                <p>II. To state offices of unemployment compensation to assist in processing an individual's unemployment, survivor annuity, or health benefit claim, or for records reconciliation purposes.</p>
                <p>JJ. To Federal Employees' Group Life Insurance or Health Benefits carriers in connection with survivor annuity or health benefits claims or records reconciliations.</p>
                <p>KK. To any source from which additional information is requested by DFC relevant to a DFC determination concerning an individual's pay, leave, or travel expenses, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p>LL. To the Social Security Administration and the Department of the Treasury to disclose pay data on an annual basis, and as necessary to execute their statutory responsibilities for the effective administration of benefits programs, payroll, and taxes.</p>
                <p>MM. To a Federal agency or in response to a congressional inquiry when additional or statistical information is requested relevant to a Federal benefit or program, such as the DFC Transit Fare Subsidy Program.</p>
                <p>NN. To the Department of Health and Human Services for the purpose of providing information on new hires and quarterly wages as required under the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996.</p>
                <p>OO. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) DFC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) DFC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, DFC (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with DFC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>PP. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when DFC determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in: (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>QQ. To an agency or organization for the purpose of performing audit or oversight operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                <p>RR. To a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, including disclosures to opposing counsel in the course of discovery, pursuant to appropriate court order or other judicial process in the course of criminal, civil, or administrative litigation.</p>
                <p>SS. In an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body, when DOJ determines that the records are arguably relevant to the proceeding; or in an appropriate proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>TT. Disclosure pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12). Disclosures may be made from this system to consumer reporting agencies as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are maintained in manual, microfilm, microfiche, electronic, imaged, and computer printout form. Original input documents are stored in standard office filing equipment and/or as imaged documents on magnetic media at all locations which prepare and provide input documents and information for data processing. Paper records are maintained in file folders stored within locking filing cabinets or locked rooms in secured facilities with controlled access. Electronic records are stored in computers, removable drives, storage devices, electronic databases, and other electronic media under the control of DFC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records may be retrieved by employee name, SSN, TIN, ECI, birth date, organizational code, or assigned person number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in accordance with OPM’s Guide to Recordkeeping; General Records Schedule (GRS) 1.0 "Finance" and GRS 2.0 "Human Resources," which are approved by NARA. The system generally maintains temporary records, and retention periods vary based on the type of record under each item and the needs of the Agency. Paper records are disposed of by shredding or pulping, and records maintained on electronic media are degaussed or erased in accordance with the applicable records retention schedule and NARA guidelines.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Not Applicable.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="dfc04" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-04</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Staff Central; DFC/04.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Sensitive but Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Business System Owner: Vice President and Chief Administrative Officer, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system covers individuals who are current and former employees of the DFC (including details, volunteers, and PSCs), as well as industrial contractors.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These are (1) security records, including records indicating level of building and network access, security badge number, and security clearance level and adjudication date; (2) emergency contact information records, including home address, phone number and email, emergency contact person information, and whether they possess first-aid or cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) certification; (3) transportation subsidy information, including commuting address, commuting days, smart trip card number, and daily commuting expenses; and (4) employee entry and exit process records, including signatures and date stamps reflecting whether department employees have been briefed on the government’s classified information program, the Corporation’s security program, and the Corporation’s records policies and procedures; have been advised of, and fully understand, applicable ethics provisions; and certifying that all required clearances for entry onboard or release of the employee’s final paycheck have been obtained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>General authority for agency records management is provided by 5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations, and 44 U.S.C. 3101, Records Management by Agency Heads. Additional authority to maintain security records is provided by 5 U.S.C. 3301, Examination, Selection and Placement, E.O. 10450, Clearance for Federal Employment, April 17, 1953, as amended; E.O. 12968, Access to Classified Information, August 4, 1995. Additional authority to maintain emergency contact information records is provided by Federal Preparedness Circular 65, Federal Executive Branch Continuity of Operations (COOP), July 26, 1999; E.O. 12656, Assignment of Emergency Preparedness Responsibilities, November 18, 1988, as amended; and Presidential Decision Directive 67, Enduring Constitutional Government and Continuity of Government Operations, October 21, 1998. Additional authority to maintain employee exit process records is provided by E.O. 12958, Classified National Security Information, April 17, 1995; 32 CFR 2003.20, Classified Information Non-Disclosure Agreement: SF–312; 5 CFR part 2637, Regulations Concerning Post Employment Conflicts of Interest; and Pub. L. l104–134, Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are used (1) as an easy reference record to determine the suitability and/or eligibility of employees and contractors for access to facilities, information systems, and classified information; (2) to account for and/or communicate with employees and contractors or their designees in the event of an emergency or disaster; (3) to process existing employees and contractors when their tenure with the DFC ends; and (4) to maintain a record of all debriefings and completed exit procedures for former employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are stored in paper and electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records related to post-employment conflict of interest debriefings are retained for six years following separation from employment. All other records are retained for one year, unless authorized, following separation from employment or contractual relationship with the DFC. All records are destroyed pursuant to existing General Records Schedules and the DFC’s records disposition schedules.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Not Applicable</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="dfc05" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-05</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>FedTalent, DFC/05.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Business System Owner: Vice President and Chief Administrative Officer, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue NW, Washington DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400. System Owner: DFC has entered into an agreement with the Department of the Interior (DOI), Interior Business Center (IBC), a Federal agency shared service provider, to host the FedTalent System on behalf of the DFC. DFC will retain ownership and control over its own data.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 4101, et seq., Government Organization and Employee Training; 5 U.S.C. 1302, 2951, 4118, 4506, 3101; 43 U.S.C. 1457; Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 as amended (42 U.S.C. 2000d); Executive Order 11348, Providing for Further Training of Government Employees, as amended by Executive Order 12107, Relating to Civil Service Commission and Labor Management in Federal Service; 5 CFR 410, Subpart C, Establishing and Implementing Training Programs; Americans with Disabilities Act (42 U.S.C. 12101); and the E-Government Act of 2002 (44 U.S.C. 3501, et seq.).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The primary purposes of the system are to: (1) manage training and learning programs; (2) plan and facilitate training courses including outreach, registration, enrollment, and payment; (3) maintain and validate training records for certification and mandatory compliance reporting; (4) meet Federal training statistical reporting requirements; (5) maintain class rosters and transcripts for course administrators, students, and learners; and (6) generate budget estimates for training requirements.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system covers the following categories of individuals: (1) DFC employees, contractors, interns, emergency workers, volunteers, and appointees who receive training related to their official duties, whether or not sponsored by DFC divisions and offices; and (2) non-DFC individuals who participate in DFC-sponsored training and educational programs, or participate in DFC-sponsored meetings and activities related to training and educational programs. Non-DFC individuals may include individuals from other Federal, state, or local agencies, private or not-for-profit organizations, universities and other schools, and members of the public.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Training, educational, and learning management records may include course registration, attendance rosters, and course information including course title, class name, objectives, description, and who should attend; class status information including begin and end dates, responsible class instructor, completion status, and certification requirements; student transcripts (course(s) completed/not completed, test scores, acquired skills); and correspondence, reports, and documentation related to training, education, and learning management programs. These records may contain: Name, SSN, employee common identifier generated from the Federal Personnel and Payroll System (FPPS), login username, password, agency or organization affiliation, work or personal address, work or personal phone and fax number, work or personal email address, gender, date of birth, organization code, position title, occupational series, pay plan, grade level, supervisory status, type of appointment, education level, duty station code, agency, bureau, office, organization, supervisor's name and phone number, date of Federal service, date of organization or position assignment, date of last promotion, occupational category, race, national origin, and adjusted basic pay. Records may also include billing information such as responsible agency, TIN, DUNS number, purchase order numbers, agency location codes, and credit card information. Records maintained on non-DFC individuals are generally limited to name, agency or organization affiliation, address, work and personal phone and fax numbers, work and personal email addresses, supervisor name and contact information, position title, occupational series, and billing information. Note: Some of these records may also become part of the OPM/GOVT-1, General Personnel Records system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about DFC employees is obtained directly from individuals on whom the records are maintained, supervisors, or existing DFC records. Historical employee training records may be obtained from other DFC learning management systems. Information from non-DFC individuals who register or participate in DFC-sponsored training programs is obtained from individuals through paper and electronic forms. Information may also be obtained by another agency, institution, or organization that sponsored the training event.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed outside the DFC as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p> 
                <p>
                    A.	To release statistical information and training reports to other organizations who are involved with the training.
                </p>
                <p>
                    B.	To disclose information to other Government training facilities (Federal, state, and local) and to non-Government training facilities (private vendors of training courses or programs, private schools, etc.) for training purposes.
                </p>
                <p>
                    C.	To provide transcript information to education institutions upon the student's request in order to facilitate transfer of credit to that institution, and to provide college and university officials with information about their students working in the Pathways Program, Volunteer Service, or other similar programs necessary to a student's obtaining credit for the experience.
                </p>
                <p>
                    D.	To Federal, state, territorial, local, tribal, or foreign agencies that have requested information relevant or necessary to the hiring, firing, or retention of an employee or contractor, or the issuance of a security clearance, license, contract, grant, or other benefit, when the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were compiled.
                </p>
                <p>
                    E.	To an expert, consultant, grantee, or contractor (including employees of the contractor) of the DFC who performs services requiring access to these records on the DFC's behalf to carry out the purposes of the system.
                </p>
                <p>
                    F.	To share logistical or attendance information with partner agencies (Government or non-Government) who, based on cooperative training agreements, have a need to know.
                </p>
                <p>
                    G.	To DOJ, including Offices of the U.S. Attorneys, or other Federal agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative, or administrative body, when it is relevant or necessary to the litigation and one of the following is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation: (1) the DFC or any component of the DFC; (2) any DFC employee or former employee acting in his or her official capacity; (3) any DFC employee or former employee acting in his or her individual capacity when the DFC or DOJ has agreed to represent that employee or pay for private representation of the employee; or (4) the United States Government or any agency thereof, when DOJ determines that the DFC is likely to be affected by the proceeding.
                </p>
                <p>
                    H.	To a congressional office when requesting information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.
                </p>
                <p>
                    I.	To an official of another Federal, state, or local government or tribal organization to provide information needed in the performance of official duties related to reconciling or reconstructing data files, in support of the functions for which the records were collected and maintained, or to enable that agency to respond to an inquiry by the individual to whom the record pertains.
                </p>
                <p>
                    J.	To representatives of NARA to conduct records management inspections under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
                </p>
                <p>
                    K.	To the Executive Office of the President in response to an inquiry from that office made at the request of the subject of a record or a third party on that person's behalf, or for a purpose compatible with the reason for which the records are collected or maintained.
                </p>
                <p>
                    L.	To any criminal, civil, or regulatory law enforcement authority (whether Federal, state, territorial, local, tribal or foreign) when a record, either alone or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law—criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, and the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were compiled.
                </p>
                <p>
                    M.	To state, territorial, and local governments and tribal organizations to provide information needed in response to court order and/or discovery purposes related to litigation, when the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were compiled.
                </p>
                <p>
                    N.	To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) the DFC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the DFC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the DFC (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with DFC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
                </p>
                <p>
                    O.	To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the DFC determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in: (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.
                </p>
                <p>
                    P.	To OMB during the coordination and clearance process in connection with legislative affairs as mandated by OMB Circular A-19.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Q.	To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Public Affairs Officer in consultation with counsel and the SAOP, where there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information, except to the extent it is determined that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.
                </p>
                <p>
                    R.	To OPM to disclose information on employee general training, including recommendations and completion, specialized training obtained, participation in government-sponsored training, or training history as required to provide workforce information for official personnel files. The collection of training data supports OPM’s Government-wide reporting responsibilities and provides valuable input into the evaluation of human capital programs at numerous levels of Government. OPM’s authority to require Federal agencies to report training data can be found in Title 5 United States Code, Chapter 4107 and part 410 of Title 5, CFR.
                </p>
                <p>S. Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), records may be disclosed to consumer reporting agencies as they are defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are stored in systems, databases, electronic media on hard disks, magnetic tapes, compact disks, and paper media.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information from this system is retrieved by either unique identifying fields (e.g., student name or email address) or by general category (e.g., course code, training location, class start date, registration date, affiliation, mandatory training compliance and payment status).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained and disposed of as prescribed under the NARA General Records Schedule. Non-mission employee training program records are temporary and destroyed when three years old, or three years after superseded or obsolete, whichever is appropriate, but longer retention is authorized if required for business use. Individual employee training records are destroyed when superseded, three years old, or one year after employee separation, whichever comes first, but longer retention is authorized if required for business use. Ethics training records are destroyed when six years old or when superseded, whichever is later, but longer retention is authorized if required for business use.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> During normal hours of operation, paper or micro format records are maintained in locked file cabinets in secured rooms under the control of authorized personnel. Information technology systems follow the NIST privacy and security standards developed to comply with 43 CFR 2.226, the Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a; the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995, Public Law 104-13; the Federal Information Security Modernization Act of 2014, Public Law 113-283, as codified at 44 U.S.C. 3551, et seq.; and the Federal Information Processing Standard 199, Standards for Security Categorization of Federal Information and Information Systems. Access to records in this system is controlled and managed pursuant to applicable policies and rules, including OPM’s Information and Security &amp; Privacy Policy. These records and the technical hardware containing these records are maintained on premises in areas designated as restricted access. The use of password protection, system authentication, and other system protection methods also provides additional safeguards to restrict access. System access and access to the records contained within the system are limited to those individuals who have an official need for system access in order to perform their official responsibilities and duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Not Applicable.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="dfc06" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-06</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Directors (Current and Former), DFC/06</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Corporate Secretary, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; and 44 U.S.C. 3101, Records Management by Agency Heads.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are used to track appointments to the Corporation’s Board of Directors, and to maintain biographical information on Board Members to share among the groups identified under routine uses.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The categories of individuals covered by this system are identified as private and public sector members of DFC’s Board of Directors, both current and former.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains (1) biographies of Board members; (2) photographs of Board members; (3) notices of commission dates or other types of appointment notices; (4) copies of Federal Register notices relating to members; and (5) resignation notices.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information is obtained from individuals on whom the records are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information may be used to distribute to the general public, communications media, the Board of Directors, and employees of the Corporation general biographical information on Board Members. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are stored in file folders. Biographies of Board Members may be kept on the Corporation’s Internet web server and made available to the public at www.dfc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Hard copy files are indexed alphabetically by surname. Electronic files are maintained on the Corporation’s computer network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained permanently.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Access to records is limited to DFC employees who have an official need for the records. Internal procedures governing the use, transfer, and photocopying of the records have been established. Records in the system are maintained in a file cabinet located in the Corporate Secretary’s Office. The office is locked each evening. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Not Applicable.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="dfc07" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-07</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Requests and Appeals, DFC/07</p>
         </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FOIA Director, Office of the General Counsel, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 552.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records are used to respond to FOIA requests and appeals pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The categories of individuals covered by this system are identified as individuals requesting information under FOIA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains letters, correspondence, relevant data provided or referenced and responses to FOIA requests and appeals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information is obtained from individuals requesting information under FOIA, as well as assigned DFC attorneys or other pertinent DFC employees generating responses.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information may be used to (1) process individuals’ FOIA requests; (2) provide a record of communications between the requester and the Corporation; (3) ensure that all relevant, necessary, and accurate data are available to support any process for appeal; and (4) prepare annual reports to DOJ as required by FOIA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records are stored in electronic format on the Agency’s network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Files are indexed (1) numerically by fiscal year and the order they are received and (2) tagged with the name of the requester. Staff retrieves request files by both labels.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained: (1) for two years from the date of DFC’s final response in cases where no adverse determination is made; (2) for six years from the date of DFC’s response in cases where an adverse determination is made or the response to an appeal in cases where an appeal is filed; or (3) for six years from the date of the court’s final order in cases involving litigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Agency’s network complies with Federal security requirements and the FOIA files are locked to anyone not on the FOIA Office staff.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Not Applicable</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="dfc08" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-08</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Executive Photographs, DFC/08</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Vice President, Office of External Affairs, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527; Phone: (202) 336-8400.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; and 44 U.S.C. 3101, Records Management by Agency Heads.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Photographs of Agency top leadership are retrieved by name to use in internal and external communications to publicize the Agency’s mission and activities.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The categories of individuals covered by this system are identified as past and current Chief Executive Officers and Executive Vice Presidents, to include any officials in an acting capacity.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains (1) portrait shots and (2) candid shots of the relevant individuals taken while performing official functions or while involved in DFC-sponsored activities.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Photographs are taken by employees or agents of the Agency, or by third parties and submitted to the Agency for review by Agency staff before inclusion in the system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Photographs are used (1) in releases to local, national, and international communications media, (2) as communication material at conferences and speaking engagements where Agency staff participate in their official capacity, (3) to provide background information on the individuals, including public biographies, via the Agency’s website, (4) in social media and other online postings regarding the activities of the individuals in their official capacity, and (5) in the Agency’s publications.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Photographs are kept in electronic format on the network drive of the Agency’s Office of External Affairs </p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Photographs are stored in an electronic file organized by the name of the individual. When a photograph is required, a staff member will access the electronic file for the relevant individual and retrieve an appropriate photograph from those available.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are updated as needed and retained until no longer needed for business use.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Access to records is limited to DFC employees who have an official need for the records. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. The request must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.21.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests by individuals to amend their record must be submitted in writing, addressed to the system manager above. Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR § 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Not Applicable.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="dfc09" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-09</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, DFC/09  Reasonable Accommodations Records</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained primarily by the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation’s Office of Human Resources Management and Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington DC 20527. Records may also be also be kept in the department of the requesting individual. Records may be located in locked cabinets and offices, on DFC’s local area network, or in designated U.S. data centers for FedRAMP-authorized cloud service providers.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Vice President and Chief Human Capital Officer, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20527, RAC@dfc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 U.S.C. 701, 791, 794; Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42 U.S.C. 2000e; 29 CFR 1605 (Guidelines on Discrimination Because of Religion); 29 CFR 1614 (Federal Sector Equal Employment Opportunity); 29 CFR 1614 (Regulations to Implement the Equal Employment Provisions of the Americans With Disabilities Act); 5 USC 302, 1103; Executive Order 13164, Requiring Federal Agencies to Establish Procedures to Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation (July 26, 2000); and Executive Order 13548, Increasing Federal Employment of Individuals with Disabilities (July 26, 2010).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of this system of records is to allow DFC to collect and maintain records on applicants for employment, employees, and other individuals who participate in DFC programs or activities who request or receive reasonable accommodations or other appropriate modifications from DFC for medical or religious reasons; to process, evaluate, and make decisions on individual requests; and to track and report the processing of such requests DFC-wide to comply with applicable requirements in law and policy.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Applicants for Federal employment, Federal employees, contractors, detailees, volunteers, visitors, and other individuals who participate in DFC programs or activities who requested and/or received reasonable accommodations or other appropriate modifications from DFC for medical or religious reasons.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requester's name;</p>
                <p>Requester's status (applicant or current employee, etc.);</p>
                <p>Date of request;</p>
                <p>Employee’s position title, grade, series, step;</p>
                <p>Position title, grade, series, step of the position the requester is applying for;</p>
                <p>Requester's contact information (addresses, phone numbers, and e-mail addresses);</p>
                <p>Description of the requester’s medical condition or disability and any medical documentation provided in support of the request;</p>
                <p>Requester’s statement of a sincerely held religious belief and any additional information provided concerning that religious belief and the need for an accommodation to exercise that belief;</p>
                <p>Description of the accommodation being requested;</p>
                <p>Description of previous requests for accommodation;</p>
                <p>Whether the request was made orally or in writing;</p>
                <p>Documentation by a DFC official concerning whether the disability is obvious, and the accommodation is obvious and uncomplicated, whether medical documentation is required to evaluate the request, whether research is necessary regarding possible accommodations, and any extenuating circumstances that prevent the DFC official from meeting the relevant timeframe;</p>
                <p>Whether the request for reasonable accommodation was granted or denied, and if denied the reason for the denial;</p>
                <p>The amount of time taken to process the request;</p>
                <p>The sources of technical assistance consulted in trying to identify a possible reasonable accommodation;</p>
                <p>Any reports or evaluations prepared in determining whether to grant or deny the request; and</p>
                <p>Any other information collected or developed in connection with the request for a reasonable accommodation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information is obtained from the individuals who request and/or receive a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modification from DFC, or their authorized representative; directly or indirectly from an individual’s medical provider or another medical professional who evaluates the request; directly or indirectly from an individual’s religious or spiritual advisors or institutions; and from management officials, including supervisors, the Office of Information Technology, and the Facilities, Travel &amp; Security Division.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed outside DFC as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>a. To the Department of Justice, including Offices of the U.S. Attorneys; another Federal agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative, or administrative body; another party in litigation before a court, adjudicative, or administrative body; or to a court, adjudicative, or administrative body. Such disclosure is permitted only when it is relevant or necessary to the litigation or proceeding, and one of the following is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation:</p>
                <p>1. DFC, or any component thereof;</p>
                <p>2. Any employee or former employee of DFC in his or her official capacity;</p>
                <p>3. Any employee or former employee of DFC in his or her capacity where the Department of Justice or DFC has agreed to represent the employee;</p>
                <p>4. The United States, a Federal agency, or another party in litigation before a court, adjudicative, or administrative body, upon the DFC General Counsel's approval, pursuant to 5 CFR part 295 or otherwise.</p>
                <p>b. To the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates or is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p>c. To a member of Congress from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                <p>d. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>e.To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) DFC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) DFC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach, there is a risk of harm to individuals, DFC (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with DFC's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>f. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when DFC determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>g. To contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for DFC when DFC determines that it is necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to DFC employees.</p>
                <p>h. To another federal agency or commission with responsibility for labor or employment relations or other issues, including equal employment opportunity and reasonable accommodation issues, when that agency or commission has jurisdiction over reasonable accommodation.</p>
                <p>i. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engages in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who requested a reasonable accommodation or other appropriate modification.</p>
                <p>j.To another Federal agency, including but not limited to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and the Office of Special Counsel to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements related to reasonable accommodation.</p>
                <p>k. To a Federal agency or entity authorized to procure assistive technologies and services in response to a request for reasonable accommodation.</p>
                <p>l. To first aid and safety personnel if the individual’s medical condition requires emergency treatment.</p>
                <p>m. To another Federal agency or oversight body charged with evaluating DFC’s compliance with the laws, regulations, and policies governing reasonable accommodation requests.</p>
                <p>n. To another Federal agency pursuant to a written agreement with DFC to provide services (such as medical evaluations), when necessary, in support of reasonable accommodation decisions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records in this system of records are stored electronically on DFC’s local area network or within a FedRAMP-authorized cloud service providers segregated from non-government traffic and data, with access limited to a small number of personnel. In addition, paper records are stored in locked file cabinets in access-restricted offices.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records may be retrieved by name or other unique personal identifiers.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system of records are maintained in accordance with GRS 2.3 and are destroyed three years after separation from the agency or all appeals are concluded, whichever is later, but longer retention is authorized if requested for business use.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in the system are protected from unauthorized access and misuse through various administrative, technical, and physical security measures. DFC security measures are in compliance with the Federal Information Security Modernization Act (Pub. L.113-283), associated Office of Management and Budget policies, and applicable standards and guidance from the National Institute of Standards and Technology. Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is stored. Access to the paper and electronic records in this system of records is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking notification of and access to their records in this system of records may submit a request in writing to the System Manager listed above.  Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals wishing to request amendment of records about them contained in this system of records may do so by writing to the System Manager above.  Requests for amendments to records and requests for review of a refusal to amend a record must comply with the requirements of 22 CFR 707.23.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Record Access Procedure."</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>



    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="22">
<heading> Foreign Relations </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="VII">
<heading> Overseas Private Investment Corporation </heading>
<regulationsPart number="707">
<heading> ACCESS TO AND SAFEGUARDING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION IN RECORDS OF THE CORPORATION </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart A--General
</b></p>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>707.11 Scope and purpose.
</p>
<p>707.12 Definitions.
</p>
<p>707.13 Preservation of records.</p>
<p><b>Subpart B--Requests for Access to Records; Amendment of Records, Accounting of Disclosures; Notice of Court Ordered Disclosures
</b></p>
<p>707.21 Requests for access to or copies of records.
</p>
<p>707.22 Requests to permit access of records to an individual other than the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>707.23 Requests for amendment of records.
</p>
<p>707.24 Requests for an accounting of record disclosures.
</p>
<p>707.25 Appeals.
</p>
<p>707.26 Notification of court-ordered disclosures.
</p>
<p>707.27 Fees.
</p><p><b>Subpart C--Exceptions
</b></p>
<p>707.31 Specific exemptions.
</p>
<p>707.32 Special exemption.
</p>
<p>707.33 Other rights and services.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
    <p><b>Source:</b> 79 FR 8614, Feb. 13, 2014, unless otherwise noted.
    </p>
<p><b>Subpart A--General
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 707.11
 Scope and purpose.</b>
</p>
<p>This part applies to all records in systems of records maintained by OPIC that are retrievable by an individual’s name or personal identifier. The rules in this part describe the procedures by which individuals may request access to records about themselves, request amendment or correction of those records, or request an accounting of disclosures of records by OPIC. These rules should be read in conjunction with the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a, which provides additional information about records maintained on individuals.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.12
 Definitions.</b>
</p>
<p>As used in this part:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use, or disseminate;
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by an agency, including, but not limited to, his education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history and that contains his name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print or photograph;
</p>
<p>(d) <i>System of records</i> mean a group of any records under the control of OPIC from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual;
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual, except as provided by 13 U.S.C. 8;
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.13
 Preservation of records.</b>
</p>
<p>OPIC preserves all correspondence pertaining to the requests that it receives under this part, as well as copies of all requested records, until disposition or destruction is authorized pursuant to title 44 of the United States Code or the General Records Schedule 14 of the National Archives and Records Administration. Records that are identified as responsive to a request will not be disposed of or destroyed while they are the subject of a pending request, appeal, or lawsuit under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>
        <b>
            Subpart B--Requests for Access to Records; Amendment of Records, Accounting of Disclosures; Notice of Court Ordered Disclosures
        </b>
    </p><p><b>&#167; 707.21
 Requests for access to or copies of records.</b>
</p>
<p>(a) <i>How to submit.</i> An individual may request access to or copies of records maintained by OPIC that are retrieved by an individual’s personal identifier. To make a request for records a requester must submit a written request to the Director of Human Resources Management either by mail or delivery to Overseas Private Investment Corporation, 1100 New York Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20527 or electronic mail to <i>Privacy@opic.gov.</i> The envelope or subject line should read "Privacy Act Request" to ensure proper routing. Access to records maintained by OPIC will be provided only by appointment. No officer or employee of OPIC shall provide an individual with any records under this part until a written request as described in paragraph (b) of this section is provided and the identity of the individual is verified as described in paragraph (c) of this section.
</p>
<p>(b<i>) Information to include.</i> All requests under this section must:
</p>
<p>(1) Be in writing and be signed by the requester. Unless the requester is a current officer or employee of OPIC, the letter must also be duly acknowledged before a notary public or other authorized public official or signed under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury as a substitute for notarization;
</p>
<p>(2) Provide information sufficient to verify the identity of the requester, including the requester’s full name, current address, date of birth, place of birth, or the system of record identification name or number. Also include a clearly legible copy of a valid form of identification. If the request is being made by a parent or guardian on behalf of another, also include the same information for the individual who is the subject of the request along with a court order, birth certificate, or similar document proving the guardianship. OPIC will review the sufficiency of identity evidence under paragraph (c) of this section;
</p>
<p>(3) Provide information sufficient to accurately identify the records or information so that OPIC staff can locate the records with a reasonable amount of effort. At minimum this should include the full name, the system of record identification name, or the system identification number for the individual who is the subject of the records. Provision of a social security number is optional. If possible, also include a description of the records as well as providing a record creation time range and the name of the systems that should be searched. A description of OPIC’s system of records can be located in the "Privacy Act Compilation" published by the National Archives and Records Administration’s Office of the Federal Register. Each system of records is also published in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(4) Specify whether the individual wishes access to or copies of the information pertaining to him. If access is requested, provide at least one preferred date and hour for which an appointment is requested during regular business hours as provided in paragraph (a) of this section. OPIC encourages appointments to be made at least one week in advance and for a requester to provide at least three preferred appointment times; and
</p>
<p>(5) Include an agreement to pay fees or an agreement to pay fees up to a specified amount under &#167; 707.27. A request that does not include an agreement to pay fees will be considered an agreement to pay fees up to $25.00.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Verification of identity.</i> Prior to providing any requested information about an individual, the Director of Human Resources Management shall verify the identity of the individual. If the requester is acting as the guardian of the individual who is the subject of the records, the Director will also verify the identity of the individual who is the subject of the records, the relationship between the requester and the subject individual, and that the requester is acting on behalf of the subject individual. In order to verify identity, the Director shall require the individual to provide reasonable proof of identity such as a valid driver’s license, identification card, passport, employee identification card, or any other identifying information. The Director shall deny any request where she determines, at her sole discretion, that the evidence offered to verify the identity of an individual is insufficient to conclusively establish the identity of the individual.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Release of records.</i> Originals and record copies will not be released from the files of OPIC. Individuals will not be permitted to disturb any record files or to remove records from designated place of examination. If copies were requested in the request letter, copies will be furnished upon payment of the fees prescribed in &#167; 707.27.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Denial of request.</i> If the Director of Human Resources Management declines any request submitted under this section, the denial will be made in writing and contain a brief description of the denial. Denials include a determination that an individual has not provided adequate evidence to verify identity under paragraph (c) of this section, a determination that the record cannot be located, and a withholding of a record in whole or in part. In the event of a denial, the requester may file a written appeal within thirty days of the date of notification, following the procedures in &#167; 707.25.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.22
 Requests to permit access of records to an individual other than the individual to whom the record pertains.</b>
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Access by an authorized individual.</i> An individual requester who wishes to be accompanied by another individual when reviewing records pertaining to the requester must provide OPIC with a signed, written statement authorizing discussion of the information contained in the records in the presence of the accompanying individual. Both parties will be required to verify their identity under &#167; 707.21(c) before access is granted.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Release to an authorized individual.</i> An individual requester who wishes to have copies of records pertaining to the requester released to another individual must provide OPIC with a written statement authorizing release of the information contained in the records to the other individual. The identity of the individual to whom the record pertains must be verified under &#167; 707.21(c) before release is authorized.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Access or release to parent or guardian.</i> Guardians will be provided access or copies under the provisions of &#167; 707.21.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.23
 Requests for amendment of records.</b>
</p>
<p>(a) <i>How to submit.</i> Unless a record is not subject to amendment, per paragraphs (g) and (h) of this section, an individual may request an amendment of a record to correct information the individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete. The request must be in writing, labeled "Privacy Act Request," and should be addressed to the Director of Human Resources Management. The request may either be mailed to OPIC or delivered to the receptionist at 1100 New York Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20527, during regular business hours, between 8:45 a.m. and 5:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, excluding public holidays. The request will be considered received when actually delivered to or, if mailed, when it is actually received by the Director of Human Resources Management.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Information to include.</i> All requests under this section must:
</p>
<p>(1) Be in writing and be signed by the requester. Unless the requester is a current officer or employee of OPIC, the letter must also be duly acknowledged before a notary public or other authorized public official or signed under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury as a substitute for notarization;
</p>
<p>(2) Provide information sufficient to verify the identity of the requester, including the requester’s full name, current address, date of birth, place of birth, or the system of record identification name or number. Also include a clearly legible copy of a valid form of identification. If the request is being made by a parent or guardian on behalf of another, also include the same information for the individual who is the subject of the request along with a court order, birth certificate, or similar document proving the guardianship. OPIC will review the sufficiency of identity evidence under paragraph (c) of this section;
</p>
<p>(3) Provide information sufficient to accurately identify each record so that OPIC staff can locate the record and information with a reasonable amount of effort. At minimum this should include the full name, the system of record identification name, or the system record identification number for the individual who is the subject of the records and the name for each system that you believe the record is located in. Provision of a social security number is optional. If possible, you should also include a description of the records and provide a record creation time range. A description of OPIC’s systems of records can be located in the "Privacy Act Compilation" published by the National Archives and Records Administration’s Office of the Federal Register. Each system of records is also published in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(4) Specify the correction requested; and
</p>
<p>(5) Detail the basis for the requester’s belief that the records and information are not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete. This includes providing substantial and reliable evidence sufficient to permit OPIC to determine whether an amendment is in order.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Verification of identity.</i> Prior to amending information about an individual, the Director of Human Resources Management shall verify the identity of the requesting individual. If the requester is acting as the guardian of the individual who is the subject of the records, the Director will also verify the identity of the individual who is the subject of the records, the relationship between the requester and the subject individual, and that the requester is acting on behalf of the subject individual. In order to verify identity, the Director shall require the individual to provide reasonable proof of identity such as a valid driver’s license, identification card, passport, employee identification card, or any other identifying information. The Director shall deny any request where she determines, at her sole discretion, that the evidence offered to verify the identity of an individual is insufficient to conclusively establish the identity of the individual.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Acknowledgment of request.</i> If a request will take longer than ten (10) business days to process, OPIC will send the requester an acknowledgment letter. Any request that Director of Human Resources Management determines does not describe records or information in enough detail to permit the staff to promptly locate the records; does not describe the correction requested in enough detail to permit the staff to make a correction; or does not reasonably specify the amendment requested or its basis will be returned without prejudice to the requester and treated as not received.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Determination.</i> The Director of Human Resources Management will provide a determination on a request under this section within thirty (30) days from receipt.
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Amendment.</i> The Director of Human Resources Management will notify the requester in writing if the amendment is made and provide the individual an opportunity to request a copy of the amended record.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Denial.</i> The Director of Human Resources Management will notify the requester in writing if she denies any portion of a request made under this section. The denial will include a brief explanation of the reason for the refusal and the right of the individual to file an appeal within thirty (30) days, following the procedures in &#167; 707.25. In the event an appeal is denied, a requester may file a statement of disagreement with OPIC as described in &#167; 707.25(c).
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Notification of amendment.</i> Within thirty (30) days of the amendment or correction of a record or the filing of a statement of disagreement, OPIC will notify all persons, organizations, or agencies to which it previously disclosed the record, if an accounting of that disclosure was made. If an individual has filed a statement of disagreement, OPIC will attach a copy of it to the disputed record whenever the record is disclosed in the future and may also attach a concise statement of its reasons for denying the request to amend or correct.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Records not subject to amendment.</i> The following records are not subject to amendment:
</p>
<p>(1) Transcripts of testimony given under oath or written statements made under oath;
</p>
<p>(2) Transcripts of grand jury proceedings, judicial proceedings, or quasi-judicial proceedings, which are the official record of those proceedings;
</p>
<p>(3) Presentence records that originated with the courts; and
</p>
<p>(4) Records in systems of records that have been exempted from amendment and correction under the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(j) or (k) or by notice published in the <i>Federal Register.</i>
</p>
<p>(h) <i>No amendment permitted.</i> No part of these rules shall be construed to permit:
</p>
<p>(1) The alteration of evidence presented in the course of judicial, quasi-judicial, or quasi-legislative proceedings;
</p>
<p>(2) Collateral attack upon any matter which has been the subject of judicial or quasi-judicial action; or
</p>
<p>(3) An amendment or correction which would be in violation of an existing statute, executive order, or regulation.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.24
 Requests for an accounting of record disclosures.</b>
</p>
<p>(a) <i>How to submit.</i> Unless an accounting of disclosures is not required to be kept under paragraph (e) of this section, an individual may request an accounting of all disclosures OPIC has made of a record, maintained in a system of records and about the individual, to another person, organization, or agency. The request must be in writing, labeled "Privacy Act Request," and should be addressed to the Director of Human Resources Management. The request may either be mailed to OPIC or delivered to the receptionist at 1100 New York Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20527, during regular business hours, between 8:45 a.m. and 5:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, excluding public holidays. The request will be considered received when actually delivered to or, if mailed, when it is actually received by the Director of Human Resources Management.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Information to include.</i> All requests under this section must:
</p>
<p>(1) Be in writing and be signed by the requester. Unless the requester is a current officer or employee of OPIC, the letter must also be duly acknowledged before a notary public or other authorized public official or signed under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury as a substitute for notarization;
</p>
<p>(2) Provide information sufficient to verify the identity of the requester, including the requester’s full name, current address, date of birth, place of birth, or the system of record identification name or number. Also include a clearly legible copy of a valid form of identification. If the request is being made by a parent or guardian on behalf of another, also include the same information for the individual who is the subject of the request along with a court order, birth certificate, or similar document proving the guardianship. OPIC will review the sufficiency of identity evidence under paragraph (c) of this section;
</p>
<p>(3) Provide information sufficient to accurately identify the records or information so that OPIC staff can locate the records with a reasonable amount of effort. At minimum this should include the full name, the system of record identification name, or the system record identification number for the individual who is the subject of the records and the name for each system that you believe the record is located in. Provision of a social security number is optional. If possible, you should also include a description of the records and provide a time range. A description of OPIC’s system of records can be located in the "Privacy Act Compilation" published by the National Archives and Records Administration’s Office of the Federal Register. Each system of records is also published in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(4) Include an agreement to pay fees or an agreement to pay fees up to a specified amount under &#167; 707.27. A request that does not include an agreement to pay fees will be considered an agreement to pay fees up to $25.00.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Verification of identity.</i> Prior to providing any requested information about an individual, the Director of Human Resources Management shall verify the identity of the requesting individual. If the requester is acting as the guardian of the individual who is the subject of the records, the Director will also verify the identity of the individual who is the subject of the records, the relationship between the requester and the subject individual, and that the requester is acting on behalf of the subject individual. In order to verify identity, the Director shall require the individual to provide reasonable proof of identity such as a valid driver’s license, identification card, passport, employee identification card, or any other identifying information. The Director shall deny any request where she determines, at her sole discretion, that the evidence offered to verify the identity of an individual is insufficient to conclusively <i>establish</i> the identity of the individual.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Determination.</i> The Director of Human Resources Management will provide a requester with one of the following:
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Provision of accounting of disclosures.</i> If the request is granted, the Director of Human Resources Management will provide the individual with an accounting containing the date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure, as well as the name and address of the person, organization, or agency to which the disclosure was made.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Denial.</i> The Director of Human Resources Management will notify the individual in writing if she denies any portion of a request made under this section. The denial will include a brief explanation of the reason for the refusal and the right of the individual to request a review thereof under the provisions of &#167; 707.25.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Disclosures where an accounting of disclosures is not required.</i> OPIC need not provide an accounting of disclosures where:
</p>
<p>(1) The disclosures are of the type for which accountings are not kept. For example, disclosures made to employees within the agency; or
</p>
<p>(2) The disclosure was made in response to a written request from a law enforcement agency for authorized law enforcement purposes.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.25
 Appeals.</b>
</p>
<p>An individual may appeal a denial made under &#167;&#167; 707.21 through 707.23 within thirty (30) days of the notification of such denial.
</p>
<p>(a) <i>How to submit.</i> The appeal must be in writing, labeled "Privacy Act Appeal," and should be addressed to the Executive Vice President. The request may either be mailed to OPIC or delivered to the receptionist at 1100 New York Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20527, during regular business hours, between 8:45 a.m. and 5:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, excluding public holidays.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Information to include.</i> All requests under this section must:
</p>
<p>(1) Be in writing and be signed by the requester;
</p>
<p>(2) Be clearly labeled "PRIVACY ACT APPEAL" on both the letter and the envelope;
</p>
<p>(3) Clearly reference the determination being appealed; and
</p>
<p>(4) Provide support for your information, including documentation provided in the initial determination and any additional information.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Appeal determination.</i> The Executive Vice President will advise the individual of OPIC’s determination within thirty (30) business days. If the Executive Vice President is unable to provide a determination within thirty business days, the individual will be advised in writing of the reason before the expiry of the thirty business days.
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Overturn initial determination.</i> If the Executive Vice President grants the appeal and overturns the initial determination in whole or part, the individual will be notified in writing and the requested action taken promptly along with any other steps OPIC would have taken had the initial determination come to the same result as the appeal.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Uphold initial determination.</i> If the Executive Vice President denies the appeal and upholds the initial determination in whole or in part, the individual will be notified in writing and provided with an explanation. In cases where a denial of amendment or correction is upheld, the individual will also be notified of the ability to file a statement of disagreement under paragraph (c) of this section.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Statement of disagreement.</i> If an individual is denied a request to amend a record in whole or in part and that denial is upheld on appeal, the individual may file a statement of disagreement. Statements of disagreement must be concise, clearly identify each part of any record that is disputed, and should be no longer than one typed page for each fact disputed. The statement of disagreement will be placed in the system of records that contains the disputed record and the record will be marked to indicate that a statement of disagreement has been filed. The statement of disagreement will be attached to any future releases of the disputed record and may be accompanied by a concise statement from OPIC explaining its denial.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.26
 Notification of court-ordered disclosures.</b>
</p>
<p>(a) Except in cases under paragraph (c) of this section, when a record pertaining to an individual is required to be disclosed by court order, OPIC will make reasonable efforts to provide notice of this to the individual. If OPIC cannot locate the individual, notice will be deemed sufficient for this part if it is mailed to the individual’s last known address. The notice will contain a copy of the order and a description of the information disclosed.
</p>
<p>(b) Notice will be given within a reasonable time after OPIC’s receipt of the order, unless the order is not a matter of public record. In those cases, the notice will be given only after the order becomes public.
</p>
<p>(c) Notice is not required if disclosure is made from an exempt system of records.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.27
 Fees.</b>
</p>
<p>(a) The fees to be charged for making copies of any records provided to an individual under this part are ten (10) cents per page. No fees will be charged for search or review.
</p>
<p>(b) At its discretion, OPIC may grant a request for special services such as mailing copies by means other than first class mail or providing document certification. All special services provided to the requester will be provided at cost.
</p>
<p>(c) OPIC considers any request under the Privacy Act to be an authorization to incur up to $25.00 in fees unless a request states otherwise.
</p>
<p>(d) OPIC may condition access to records or copies of records upon full payment of any fees due.
</p>
<p>(e) All payments under this part must be in the form of a check or bank draft denominated in U.S. currency. Checks should be made payable to the order of the United States Treasury and mailed or hand delivered to OPIC at 1100 New York Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20527.</p><p><b>
Subpart C--Exceptions
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 707.31 Specific exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>The provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I) and (f) shall not apply to any system of records maintained by OPIC that is--
</p>
<p>(a) Subject to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(1);
</p>
<p>(b) Composed of Investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes other than those specified in 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2);
</p>
<p>(c) Required by statute to be maintained and used solely as statistical records;
</p>
<p>(d) Composed of investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility or qualifications for Federal civilian employment, military service, Federal contracts or access to classified information, but only to the extent that OPIC may determine, in its sole discretion, that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of the source who, subsequent to September 27, 1975, furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence or, prior to such date, under an implied promise to such effect; and
</p>
<p>(e) Composed of testing or examination materials used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the Federal service and OPIC determines, in its sole discretion, that disclosure of such materials would compromise the fairness of the testing or examination process.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.32
 Special exemption.</b>
</p>
<p>Nothing in this part shall allow an individual access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
</p><p><b>&#167; 707.33
 Other rights and services.</b>
</p>
    <p>
        Nothing in this part shall be construed to entitle any person, as of right, to any service or to the disclosure of any record to which such person is not entitled under the Privacy Act.
    </p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>

