<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
    <agency toc="yes">    
<name>Tennessee Valley Administration</name>
<abbrev>
TVA
</abbrev>
        <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
            <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
        </previousPubs>
        <previouslyPublished>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-31/pdf/2020-19170.pdf</url>
            <title>Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Requests and Appeals Files. TVA-40</title>
            <date year="2020" month="8" day="31" />
        </previouslyPublished>


        <section id="tva1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Apprentice Training Records--TVA.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Human Resource Information Systems, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499; Computer Operations, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801; all TVA locations where apprentices are employed.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Current and former TVA apprentices.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Employment, qualifications, and evaluation information.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; National Apprenticeship Act of 1937, 50 Stat. 664.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to facilitate registration for, participation in, and the completion and documentation of apprenticeship training sponsored by TVA in support of its mission. Records in this system will be used to: determine eligibility for, and the effectiveness of, TVA apprenticeship programs; and facilitate the compilation of statistical information about TVA's apprenticeship training programs.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training, the Veterans' Administration, Tennessee Valley Trades and Labor Council, and the State and local Government agencies for reporting and evaluation purposes.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an apprentice.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    To provide the following information to a prospective employer of a TVA or former TVA employee: Job description, dates of employment, reason for separation.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information; and to request information from private individuals, if necessary, to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices, microfiche, and in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>    Records are indexed by name, craft, job code, union code, and Social Security number.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Files are kept in secured facilities.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA record retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Senior Manager, Talent Sourcing &amp; Support Services, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, craft, and location of employment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above. Access will not be granted to investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment. Federal contracts, or access to classified information to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence or, prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence. Access will not be granted to testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualification for appointment or promotion in the Federal service, the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individual to whom the record pertains; General Aptitude Test Battery scores from S\state employment security office; references from employers, military and educational institutions; and evaluations from joint committee on apprenticeship.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system is exempt from subsections (d); (e)(4)(H); and (f)(2), (3), and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) to the extent that disclosure of material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence or, prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, and to the extent that disclosure of testing and examination material would compromise the objectivity of the testing or examination process. This exemption is pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5) and (6) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Personnel Files--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   Unclassified. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Human Resources, HR Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499; Human Resource Information Systems, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499; area human resources offices throughout TVA; Information Technology, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801; National Personnel Records Center, St. Louis, MO 63118. Security/suitability investigatory files are located separately from other records in this system. Duplicate or certain specified temporary information may be maintained by human resources officers, supervisors, and administrative officers.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Current and former TVA employees, some contractors, applicants for employment, and applicants for employment by TVA contractors.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information related to education; qualifications; work history; interests and skills; test results; performance evaluation; career counseling; personnel actions; job description; salary and benefit information; service dates, including other Federal and military service; replies to congressional inquiries; medical data; and security investigation data.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Executive Order 10577; Executive Order 10450; Executive Order 11478; Executive Order 11222; Equal Employment Opportunity Act of 1972, Pub. L. 92-261, 86 Stat. 103; Veterans' Preference Act of 1944, 58 Stat. 387, as amended; various sections of title 5 of the United States Code related to employment by TVA.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to provide a repository of personnel records, performance reports, events, developments, contract arrangements and other significant matters relating to an employee"s employment with TVA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To disclose test results to State employment services.</p>
<p>   To a State employment security office in response to a request relating to a former employee's claim for unemployment compensation.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an employee, former employee, or applicant.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To request from any pertinent source directly or through a TVA contractor engaged at TVA's direction, information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To provide information or disclose to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    To provide the following information, as requested, to a prospective employer of a TVA or former TVA employee: job descriptions, dates of employment, and reasons for separation.</p>
<p>    To provide an official of Federal agency information needed in the performance of official duties related to reconciling or reconstructing data files, in support of the functions for which the records were collected and maintained.</p>
<p>    To provide information to multi-employer health and welfare and pension funds as reasonably necessary and appropriate for proper administration of the plan of benefits.</p>
<p>    To provide information to TVA contractors engaged in making suitability determinations for their prospective employees under TVA contracts.</p>
<p>    To contractors and subcontractors engaged at TVA's direction in providing support services to TVA in connection with mailing materials to TVA employees or other related services.</p>
<p>    To provide information as requested to the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to Executive Orders 10450 and 10577 and other laws.</p>
<p>    To any agency of the Federal Government having oversight or review authority with regard to TVA activities.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To transfer information necessary to support a claim for life insurance benefits under Federal Employees' Group Life Insurance to Office of Federal Employees' Group Life Insurance.</p>
<p>    To transfer information regarding claims for health insurance benefits to health insurance carrier.</p>
<p>    To union representatives in exercising their responsibilities under TVA collective-bargaining agreements.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To TVA contractors and subcontractors engaged at TVA's direction in studies and evaluation of TVA personnel management and benefits; or the investigation of nuclear safety, reprisal, or other matters involving TVA personnel practices or policies; or the implementation of TVA personnel policies.</p>
<p>    To provide pertinent information to local school districts and other Government agencies in order to study TVA project impacts and to aid school districts in qualifying for assistance under Pub. L. 81-874 and other laws.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To commemorate the month and day of employee birthday anniversaries.</p>
<p>    To the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services Federal Parent Locator System (FPLS) and Federal Tax Offset System for use in locating individuals and identifying their income sources to establish paternity, establish and modify orders of support, and for enforcement action.</p>
<p>    To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Social Security Administration for verifying social security numbers in connection with the operation of the FPLS by the Office of Child Support Enforcement.</p>
<p>    To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Department of Treasury for purposes of administering the Earned Income Tax Credit Program (Section 32, Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and verifying a claim with respect to employment in a tax return.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) The disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Information is stored electronically in the People Lifecycle Unified System (PLUS),  Enterprise Content Management (ECM) or on microfiche. Duplicate or certain specified temporary information may be maintained by human resources officers, supervisors, and administrative offices in a locked, secured location.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>    Records are indexed by name and Employee Identification number.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. Access to systems storing these records must be approved by the Senior Manager of Employee Relations Support Services. All filing systems are locked when unattended. Remote access facilities are secured through physical and system-based safeguards.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>     Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Senior Manager, Talent Acquisition, Deployment and Support, HR Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the Manager, TVA Service Center, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. Requests should include the individual's full name, job title, and date of birth. A Social Security number is not required but may expedite TVA's response; however, an Employee Identification Number may be included.</p>
<p>    Current employees should address inquiries also to their supervisors or the TVA Service Center.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to gain access to information about them in this system of records should contact the Manager, TVA Service Center, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37901-1499. In addition, current employees may present requests for access to their supervisors or the personnel officer of the employing division. Requests should include the individual's full name, job title, and date of birth. A Social Security number is not required but may expedite TVA's response; however, an Employee Identification Number may be included. Access will not be granted to investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment or access to classified information to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished  information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence. Access will not be granted to testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the Federal Service the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the Manager, TVA Service Center, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individual to whom the record pertains; educational institutions; former employers; and other reference sources; State employment services; supervisors and other TVA personnel or personnel records; medical officers; other Federal agencies.</p>
<p>    In addition to the above sources, security/suitability investigatory files contain information from law enforcement agencies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system is exempt from subsections (d); (e)(4)(H); and (f)(2), (3) and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) to the extent that disclosure of material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, and to the extent that disclosure of testing or examination material would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process. This exemption is pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(5) and (6) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Discrimination Complaint Files--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    TVA Equal Opportunity Compliance Staff, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. Duplicate copies may be maintained in the files of the TVA organization where the complaint originated.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Employees, former employees, or applicants who have received counseling or filed complaints of discrimination based on race, color, religion, sex, national origin, age, reprisal,     disability or genetic information</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records contains information or documents relating to a decision or determination made by TVA or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission affecting an individual. The records consist of the complaint, letters or notices to the individual, record of hearings when received from the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, materials placed into the record to support the decision or determination, affidavits or statements, testimonies of witnesses, investigative reports, and related correspondence, opinions, and recommendations. Also, if the case is appealed to the Federal District Court of Appeals, the records will contain a copy of the complaint on file with the Federal District Court.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Executive Order 11478; 42 U.S.C. 2000e-16; 29 U.S.C. 633a; Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964; Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967; Rehabilitation Act of 1973.; Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purpose of this system is to assist in the documentation of complaints, letters, notices, materials placed into the record to support the decision or determination, affidavits or statements, testimonies of witnesses, investigative reports, related correspondence, opinions, and recommendations  to individuals regarding potential or alleged violations of equal employment opportunity statutes and regulations and to maintain records relating to a decision or determination made by TVA or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission affecting an individual. . Records in this system will be used for: initiating, counseling, investigating, and adjudicating equal employment opportunity complaints and to resolve issues related to alleged discrimination because of race, color, religion, sex, national origin, age, physical or mental disability, and sexual orientation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    If a hearing is requested and/or an administrative appeal is filed with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, a copy of the complaint file, containing a record of investigations and a correspondence file of each complaint, is forwarded to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission.</p>
<p>    To the counselee's or complainant's representative.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of a complaint.</p>
<p>    To the parties of complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulations, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery.</p>
<p>    In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To TVA consultants, contractors, and subcontractors who are engaged in studies and evaluation of TVA's administration of its Equal Employment Opportunity program or who are providing support services to the program.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) The disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records in this system are kept in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>    Records in this system are indexed by name.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those personnel whose official duties require such access.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Director of TVA Equal Opportunity Compliance, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who have filed discrimination complaints are aware of that fact. However, inquiries may be addressed to the system manager named above. Individuals should provide their full name, the approximate date of their complaint, and their employing organization, if employed.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who have filed a discrimination complaint have been provided a copy of the record. However, an individual may gain access to a copy of their official complaint record by writing the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who have filed a discrimination complaint have had an opportunity during the complaint procedure to timely amend their record. TVA management has the same opportunity during the complaint procedure to timely amend the applicable record. However, requests for amendment or correction of items not involving the complaint procedure may be addressed to the system manager named above.</p>
<p>    The individual to whom the record pertains; TVA personnel and other records; and witnesses.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Work Injury Illness System"TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    TVA Safety Programs, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801. Accident reports may also be maintained in the file of the employing organization.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Employees and Staff Augmented contractors who have sustained a work-related injury or illness.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Personal identifying information and information related to the accident, injury, or illness.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Executive Order 12196; Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, Pub. </p>
<p>L. 93-237, 87 Stat. 1024.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to assist in compliance with the Occupational Safety and Health Act and to provide a repository of documentation of work related accidents, injuries, illnesses, and health related exposures in the workplace.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To an injured employee's representative.</p>
<p>    To the Department of Labor as required by the Occupational Safety and Health Act.</p>
<p>    To the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs in relation to an individual's claim for compensation.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an employee.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information, or other pertinent information; and to request information from private individuals, if necessary, to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purpose of this system of records.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
    <p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) The disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Information in this system is maintained on automated data storage devices and in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>    Records are indexed by name, date of injury, and Employee Identification Number.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. All filing systems are locked when unattended. Remote access facilities are secured through physical and system-based safeguards.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>      Manager, Safety Process Support, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to know whether information about them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, date of birth, and approximate date of injury.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who desire access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The individual to whom the record pertains; TVA medical records; witnesses of accidents and inquires, including appraisers of property damage.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Accounts Receivable--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Financial Services. TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499; Office of the General Counsel, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Employees or former employees who: Authorize a payment for specified purposes in their behalf; receive overpayment of earnings; receive duplicate payments; or are otherwise indebted to TVA.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Personal identifying information and information concerning indebtedness and repayment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; 5 U.S.C. Chapter 55.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to create a record of employees and former employees who are indebted to TVA .  The records in this system will be used to assist in the tracking and collection of debts owed to TVA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
<p>    Disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (b)(12): Disclosures may be made from this system to "consumer reporting agencies'' as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Debt Collection Act of 1982 (31 U.S.C. 3711(d)(4)).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on printouts, invoices, microfiche, and posting documents.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by payroll number, Social Security number, badge number, name, or invoice number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Files are kept in secured facilities.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Senior Manager, Disbursement Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to know whether information about them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name and employing organization. Provisions of the Social Security number is not required, but may expedite TVA's response and may prevent the erroneous retrieval of records for another individual with the same name.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who seek access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in the system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals to whom the record pertains; TVA payroll records; TVA disbursement voucher records.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Health Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    TVA HR Health &amp; Safety, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801; all TVA medical facilities; Computer Operations, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801; National Personnel Records Center, St. Louis, MO 63118; District Offices, Office of Workers' Compensation Programs.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Applicants for TVA employment, employees, former employees, official visitors, contractual assignees to TVA, interns, externs, employees of TVA contractors, and other Federal agencies who are examined under contract.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Health information pertinent to an individual's employment, official visit, or contractual work with TVA or other Federal agencies, including the basic Clinical Medical Record, Worker's Compensation and Rehabilitation claims and case files, Psychological and Fitness for Duty files including alcohol and drug testing information, clinical information received from outside sources, and information relative to an employee's claim for medical disability retirement. Health information includes paper documents, x-rays, microfiche, microfilm, and/or any automatic data processing media, regardless of the form or process by which it is maintained.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose for this system is to maintain records concerning individual"s medical records and treatments. Records in this system are used to: determine fitness for duty; verify an employee"s eligibility for certain services, evaluate an employee"s claim for disability retirement or other separation actions; and prepare analytical and statistical studies and reports related to the health of TVA employees.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; 5 U.S.C. 7902; Federal Employees' Compensation Act, 5 U.S.C. chapter 81, 5 U.S.C. chapter 87 (Medical information relating to life insurance program); 5 U.S.C. 3301; Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, Pub. L. 93-237, 87 Stat. 1024, Pub. L. 91-616, Federal Civilian Employee Alcoholism Program and Pub. L. 92-255, Drug Abuse among Federal Civilian Employees, which are amended in regard to confidentiality of records by Pub. L. 93-282; Public health laws (State and Federal) related to the reporting of health hazards, communicable diseases or other epidemiological information; Energy Reorganization Act of 1974, Pub. L. 93-438, 88 Stat. 1233; 49 CFR Part 382 Subpart D.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Compensation claim records are used for adjudicating claims and providing therapy. Appropriate information is exchanged with physicians, hospitals, and rehabilitation agencies approved by the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs for service to injured employees.</p>
<p>    Alcohol, drug testing and psychological fitness for duty records may be exchanged with a physician or treatment center working with an employee, or in accordance with the provisions of Pub. L. 93-282.</p>
<p>    Information in the Health Records System provided to officials of other Federal agencies responsible for other Federal benefit programs administered by Office of Workers' Compensation Programs. Retired Military Pay Centers, Veterans' Administration, Social Security Administration, and private contractors engaged in providing benefits under Federal contracts.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding an employee.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority or a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To transfer information regarding claims for health insurance or disability benefits to the health insurance carrier or plan participant.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Government agency or private individual, if necessary, to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To TVA consultants, contractors, and subcontractors who are engaged in studies and evaluation of TVA's administration of its medical and employee benefits program or who are providing support sources to the program.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To provide information to private physicians and other health care professionals or facilities designated by an employee.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Health information includes paper documents, x-rays, microfiche, microfilm, and/or any automatic data processing media, regardless of the form or process by which it is maintained.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name, Social Security number, date of birth, and/or case number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. All filing systems are locked when unattended.</p>
<p>    Remote access facilities are secured through physical and system-based safeguards. Special instructions governing the medical staff employees assure the confidentiality of health records.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with TVA rules and regulations approved by the Archivist of the United States. Retention schedules specify the length of time various records are kept. Active clinical medical records are kept indefinitely. Specific retention schedules for various components of the records systems are contained in the Comprehensive Records Schedule (CRS) which has been approved by the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for use by Health Services. These dispositions are mandatory unless TVA requests a revision from NARA. Items in this CRS should be cited as the disposition authority for transferring or destroying any records.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Manager, Occupational Health &amp; Nursing Services, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.  Inquiries and requests for psychological fitness for duty and alcohol &amp; drug testing records should be sent to Manager, Non-Nuclear Fitness for Duty, TVA, Chattanooga, TN  37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Individuals should provide their full name, Employee Identification Number (EIN) or social security number, date of birth, employing organization, and date of last employment, and employee compensation case number, if any.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who desire access to information about them in this system of records should contact or address their inquiries to the system manager named above. Inquiries should be specific as to which component of the health records system is to be accessed. If inquiries are not specific to a particular component of the health records, it will be assumed the access is directed toward the individual's clinical medical record.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The individual to whom the record pertains; TVA medical staff; private physicians and medical institutions; Office of Workers' Compensation Programs; TVA personnel records; other health agencies and departments.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Payroll Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>  Financial Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499; garnishment files are located at the Office of the General Counsel, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499; duplicate copies of some records may also be maintained in the files of the employing organization; National Personnel Records Center, St. Louis, MO 63118.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    All employees and personal service contractors selected for certain training programs and applicants for employment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Personal identifying information, pay, leave, and debt claim information.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Internal Revenue Code; Fair Labor Standards Act, 29 U.S.C. Chapter 8; 5 U.S.C. Chapter 63.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The purpose of this system is to facilitate the facilitate fiscal operations for payroll, attendance, leave, insurance, tax, retirement and cost accounting programs. Records in this system will be used to: generate W"2 forms, wage and tax statement, reports of withholding and contributions; facilitate the compilation of statistical information about TVA's payroll; and prepare comprehensive payroll related reports to other Federal agencies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To report earnings and other required information to Federal, State, and local taxing authorities as required by law.</p>
<p>    To report earnings to the Civil Service Retirement System for members of that system.</p>
<p>    To transmit payroll deduction information to financial institutions and employee organizations.</p>
<p>    To report earnings to courts when garnishments are served or in bankruptcy or wage earner proceedings.</p>
<p>    To report earnings to the Department of Housing and Urban Development, State welfare agencies, and State employment security offices where an individual has made a claim for benefit with such agency.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To provide information or disclose to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    To disclose to any agency of the Federal Government having oversight or review authority with regard to TVA activities.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To transfer information necessary to support a claim for life insurance benefits under Federal Employee's Group Life Insurance to Office of Federal Employee's Group Life Insurance.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information; and to request information from private individuals, if necessary, to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To transfer information regarding claims for health insurance benefits to health insurance carriers.</p>
<p>    To TVA contractors and subcontractors engaged in studies and evaluations of TVA payroll and personnel management.</p>
<p>    To union representatives exercising their responsibilities under TVA collective bargaining agreements.</p>
<p>    To report earnings to the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and State welfare agencies where an individual makes a claim for benefits, and to report earnings to State employment security offices in both manual and automated form for use by these offices in determining unemployment benefits.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services Federal Parent Locator System (FPLS) and Federal Tax Offset System for use in locating individuals and identifying their income sources to establish paternity, establish and modify orders of support, and for enforcement action.</p>
<p>    To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Social Security Administration for verifying social security numbers in connection with the operation of the FPLS by the Office of Child Support Enforcement.</p>
<p>    To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Department of the Treasury for purposes of administering the Earned Income Tax Credit Program (Section 32, Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and verifying a claim with respect to employment in a tax return.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
<p>    Disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12): Disclosures may be made from this system to "consumer reporting agencies'' as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Debt Collection Act of 1982 (31 U.S.C. 3711(d)(4)).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices, hard-copy printouts, and in an optical scanned electronic file.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are primarily indexed by name. They may also be retrieved by reference to employing organization, date of end of pay period, Social Security or badge number, year of birth, or job title.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Filing systems are locked when unattended. Remote access facilities are secured through physical and system-based safeguards.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Senior Manager, Disbursement Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, employing organization, and date of last employment. The Social Security number is also required to expedite TVA's response and prevent the erroneous retrieval of records for another individual with the same name.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking access to information on them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to contest or amend information on them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individual to whom the record pertains; TVA personnel records; employee's supervisor for report of hours worked.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Travel History Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Financial Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. Duplicate copies of certain records may also be maintained in the files of the employing organization.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Current and former TVA employees who traveled on official business and filed travel expense vouchers, applied for a travel advance, or transferred between official stations; recently-hired employees who filed for reimbursement of relocation expenses; candidates for TVA positions who filed for reimbursement of travel expenses; and contractors with which there is an employer/employee relationship (i.e., personal services contractors).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Travel advance requests, travel expense vouchers and supporting documentation, travel charge card program records and reports, and travel orders. Records supporting relocation expense claims also include real estate sales agreements and settlements, Federal Truth-In Lending disclosure statements, lease agreements, receipts for loss of rental deposit, and relocation income tax allowance documents.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; 5 U.S.C. 5701-5709, and related Federal travel regulations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to facilitate the planning and arrangement of official TVA travel, obtain travel authorizations, maintain documentation on TVA employees on travel or being provided travel by TVA, and assist in the generation of travel expense reports. Records in this system will also be used to support relocation expense claims and generate travel vouchers.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an employee, former employee, or applicant.</p>
<p>    To TVA contractors and subcontractors engaged at TVA's direction that are providing support services to TVA's travel charge card program.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
<p>    Disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (b)(12): Disclosures may be made from this system to  "consumer reporting agencies'' as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Debt Collection Act of 1982 (31 U.S.C. 3711(d)(4)).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on magnetic media, hard-copy printouts, microfiche, and in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name and Social Security number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Security will be provided by physical, administrative, and computer system safeguards. Files are kept in secured facilities not accessible to unauthorized individuals.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Senior Manager, Disbursement Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to know whether information about them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name and Social Security number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who seek access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name and Social Security number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name and Social Security number.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individual to whom the record pertains; TVA disbursement voucher records; TVA application for travel advance; travel charge card program records and reports.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Employment Applicant Files--TVA.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p> HR System Administration and Reporting, Chattooga TN  37402.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Applicants for employment including former employees seeking reemployment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Application forms and related correspondence.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; 5 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to provide documentation  and records on TVA applicants for employment. Records in this system will be used to rate and rank applicants for employment, facilitate in the determination of individuals" eligibility and evaluate qualifications for employment at TVA, and to facilitate the compilation of statistical information about TVA's application process</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an individual's application.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To request from any pertinent source, directly or through a TVA contractor engaged at TVA's direction, information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system or records.</p>
<p>    To disclose test results to State employment services.</p>
<p>    To provide information as requested to the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to Executive Orders 10450 and 10577 and other laws.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information is stored electronically in the People Lifecycle Unified System (PLUS),  Enterprise Content Management (ECM) or on microfiche. Duplicate or certain specified temporary information may be maintained by human resources officers, supervisors, and administrative offices in a locked, secured location. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name and Employee Identification number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. Access to systems storing these records must be approved by the Senior Manager of Employee Relations Support Services. All filing systems are locked when unattended. Remote access facilities are secured through physical and system-based safeguards.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Manager, Human Resource System Administration and Reporting TVA, 1101 Market Street Chattanooga, TN  3740202801</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the Senior Manager, Employee Relations Support Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. Requests should include the individual's full name, Social Security number, date of birth, and approximate date of application.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to gain access to information on them in this system of records should contact the Senior Manager, Employee Relations Support Services, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. Access will not be granted to investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment. Federal contracts, or access to classified information, to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.</p>
<p>    Access will not be granted to testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the Federal Service the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to Manager, TVA Service Center, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The individual on whom the record is maintained; educational institutions, employers, and other references; State employment services.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system is exempt from subsections (d); (e)(4)(H); and (f)(2), (3), and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) to the extent that disclosure of material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence and to the extent that disclosure of testing or examination material would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process. This exemption is pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k) (5) and (6) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Grievance Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Labor Relations Staff, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. Original correspondence on the initial grievance steps below the Labor Relations level is maintained in the organization in which the grievance originated. Original correspondences on grievance appeals to the corporate level are maintained in the files of the Labor Relations office.</p>
<p>    Duplicate copies of such correspondence are also maintained in the files of the organization concerned with the grievance.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    TVA employees and former employees who have formally appealed to TVA for adjustment of their grievances.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Evidence and arguments relevant to the matter giving rise to the grievance and related correspondence.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to document employee grievances,  including statements of witnesses, reports of interviews and hearings, examiner's findings and recommendations, a copy of the original and  final decision, and related correspondence and exhibits. Records in this system will be used to assist in the initiation, consideration, and adjudication of formally filed grievances by TVA employees.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an employee's grievance.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency, or private individual, if necessary, to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulations, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices in some organizations and in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name or by craft.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA record retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, Labor Relations, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who have filed grievances are aware of that fact.  Inquiries may, however, be addressed to the system manager named above.  Requests should include the individual's full name, craft, and location of employment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who have filed a grievance may gain access to the official copy of the grievance record by contacting the system manager named above. Requests should include the grievant"s full name, craft, and location of employment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The contest, amendment, or correction of a grievance record is permitted during the prosecution of that grievance. However, an individual may address requests for amendment or correction of items not involved in prosecution of the grievance to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individual to whom the record pertains; TVA personnel records; statements and testimony of witnesses and related correspondence.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-18</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Employee Supplementary Vacancy Announcement Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Human Resources, Knoxville and Chattanooga, Tennessee, and Muscle Shoals, Alabama; may also be maintained in other offices that issue or receive responses to supplementary vacancy announcements.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Employees applying for placement in positions covered by the supplementary vacancy announcement procedure.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Applications and supporting material submitted by employee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Executive Order 11478; Equal Employment Opportunity Act of 1972, Pub. L. 92-261, 86 Stat. 103; 5 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to collect, maintain, and track applications for positions covered by the supplemental vacancy announcement procedure.  This procedure allows TVA employees to apply for internal vacancies that are exempt from TVA"s policy that employees must be given the opportunity to apply for vacant positions before they are filled.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Information is stored electronically in the People Lifecycle Unified System (PLUS),  Enterprise Content Management (ECM) or on microfiche. Duplicate or certain specified temporary information may be maintained by human resources officers, supervisors, and administrative offices in a locked, secured location.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Access to systems storing these records must be approved by the Manager of Human Resources System Administration and Support.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>  Manager, Human Resource System  Administration and Reporting, 1101 Market Street,    Chattanooga, TN 3740202801</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals upon whom records are maintained in this system are aware of that fact through filing an application. However, inquiries may be addressed to the name and address to which application was submitted. Requests should include the individual's full name, position applied for, and location of job.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals upon whom records are maintained in this system have supplied all information in this system. However, requests for access may be addressed to the name and address to which application was submitted.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the name and address to which application was submitted.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The individual upon whom the record is maintained.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Consultant and Contractor Records"TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    People Lifestyle Unified System (PLUS)  contains personal, employment, job, security restriction and training information. PLUS is located in HR &amp; Accounting Solutions, TVA Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. The Contractor Workforce Management Software (IQ Navigator) for contractor time and expense reporting records is located at HR System Administration and Reporting, Chattanooga, TN 37402. </p>
<p>    For contractors requiring unescorted access, records are located at TVA Nuclear Access Service, Chattanooga, TN 37402.</p>
<p>    TVA business organizations for records on individuals who provide services under a TVA contract with an organization are kept in the files of that organization.</p>
<p>    Payment records are located at the TVA Controller office: Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
<p>    Records related to personal service contractors employed under the Comprehensive Employment and Training Act of 1973, Pub. L. 93-203, are located at the National Personnel Records Center, St. Louis, MO 63118.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who perform work for and/or provide services to TVA and who are not TVA employees or volunteers. These individuals generally are the employees of a TVA supplier of services and are retained through a contract with the supplier, but in some cases may be retained directly through a contract between TVA and the individual.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Each organization maintains its contracts, records of the qualifications, performance, and evaluation of the contractor, and related correspondence. For public service employment program participants, Human Resources maintains information related to job placement such as test scores, interest inventories, and supervisor's evaluations.  Payment information is maintained by the Controller.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Comprehensive Employment and Training Act, Pub. L. 93-203, 87 Stat. 839; Executive Order 11222; Executive Order 10450; Executive Order 10577; provisions of 5 U.S.C. applicable to employment with TVA;  Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to collect and maintain records related to TVA contractors and consultants, to support TVA"s fiscal operations by recording contractor and consultant time, expenses and payroll; to record contractor and consultant personal, employment, security restrictions and clearances, facility access, and training information; and to otherwise support the management of TVA"s contractors and consultants.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To transmit reports as requested to the Office of Personnel Management, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 3323, Executive Orders 10577 and 10450, and other laws.</p>
<p>    To report earnings information to the Internal Revenue Service and the Social Security Administration.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of a contractor or consultant.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulations, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information; and to request information from private individuals if necessary to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To transmit to the appropriate State contracting agency reports of hours worked by participants in the public service employment program, and to request reimbursement.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    To provide the following information to a prospective employer of a TVA or former TVA consultant or personal service contractor: Job descriptions, dates of employment, and reason for separation.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interest, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure is made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained in file folders and on automated data storage devices.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name, Social Security number, or contract number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. All filing systems are locked when unattended.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA record retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>  Senior Service Manager, HR &amp; Accounting Solutions, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
<p>  Manager, HR System Administration &amp; Reporting, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to know if records on them are maintained in the system should address inquiries to the system manager named above.  Requests shall include the individual's full name, employing or contracting organization, and whether the individual was a participant in the public service employment program. Social Security numbers are not required but may expedite TVA's response.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to gain access to information on them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above. Access will not be granted to investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment, Federal contracts, or access to classified information, to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence. Access will not be granted to testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the Federal Service, the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individual to whom the record pertains; educational institutions, former employers, and other reference sources; State employment services; supervisors and other TVA personnel or personnel records; medical officers; other Federal agencies.</p>
<p>    In addition to the above sources, security/suitability investigatory files contain information from law enforcement agencies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system is exempt from subsections (d); (e)(4)(H); (f)(2), (3), and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) to the extent that disclosure of material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, and to the extent that disclosure of testing or examination material would compromise the objectivity of fairness of the testing or examination process. This exemption is pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5) and (6) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva21" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-21</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Nuclear Quality Assurance Personnel Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Nuclear Quality Assurance, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801. Copies of records for Quality Assurance Auditors/Assessors are maintained electronically by the Manager, Corporate Quality Assurance/designee, and are submitted and maintained in the TVA Nuclear Electronic Data Management System (EDMS).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Employees and former employees involved in quality assurance work.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information related to the qualifications of employees.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Energy Reorganization Act of 1974, Pub. L. 93-438, 88 Stat. 1233 as implemented at Nuclear Regulatory Commission Regulatory Guides 1.58.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The purpose of this system is to collect and maintain records about TVA Nuclear Quality Assurance employees.  These employees are responsible for providing confidence that the activities affecting quality during the design, construction, operation, and maintenance of TVA"s nuclear facilities are accomplished in a manner to achieve compliance with TVA"s established quality objectives and acceptance criteria.  Information in the system is also used to respond to inspections or evaluations of the TVA Quality Assurance program.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To the Nuclear Regulatory Commission or its authorized representatives for inspection or evaluation of TVA Quality Assurance procedures.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of an employee.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information; and to request information from private individuals if necessary to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained in electronic files.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. All filing systems are locked when unattended.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    General Manager, Nuclear Quality Assurance, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to know whether information about them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Inquiries should include the individual's full name and employing organization.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who desire access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The individual on whom the record is maintained; TVA personnel records.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from subsection (d); (e)(4)(H); (f)(2), (3), and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) to the extent that disclosure of material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence. The exemption is pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Questionnaire-Land Use Surveys in Vicinity of Proposed or Licensed Nuclear Power Plant--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Environmental Radiological Monitoring and Instrumentation, Western Area Radiological Laboratory (WARL) Facility, TVA, Muscle Shoals, AL 35662-1010.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals having vegetable gardens, irrigated land, dairy cows, and milk goats within a five-mile radius of a proposed or licensed nuclear plant site.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Personal identifying information and information related to agriculture, milk consumption, water resources, and farm product value. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; National Environmental Policy Act, Pub. L. 91-190, 83 Stat. 852; Energy Reorganization Act of 1974, Pub. L. 93-438, 88 Stat. 1233.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   This system is used to collect and maintain records concerning farming, gardening, and dairy operations in the areas surrounding proposed and operating nuclear plant sites.  This information is used to prepare environmental evaluations and impact statements to assess the possible effects that such a plant might have on the production of crops and livestock in the area. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information in this system of records is used in developing environmental evaluations and impact statements. Certain relevant but nonsensitive information may be disclosed in these statements.</p>
<p>    Information may also be used:</p>
<p>    In administrative and licensing proceedings, including the presentation of evidence and disclosure to opposing counsel in the course of discovery.</p>
<p>    To disclose to any agency of the Federal Government having oversight or review authority with regards to TVA activities.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices, microfilm, microfiche, and in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by assigned number and aerial photo number and/or name of survey participant, plant site and year of survey.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Security is provided by physical, administrative and computer system safeguards. Files are kept in secured facilities not accessible to unauthorized individuals or are locked when unattended.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Manager, Environmental Radiological Monitoring and Instrumentation, TVA, Muscle Shoals, AL  35662-1010. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals on whom information is maintained in this system are aware of that fact through response to the questionnaire. However, inquiries may be addressed to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, address, and approximate date of survey.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who desire access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, address, and approximate date of survey.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals to whom the record pertains; he nearest resident, to a distance of 5 miles, in each of the 16 compass sectors around each TVA nuclear site; farms with dairy cows or milk goats within a five mile radius of each site and additional dairy farms used as control locations for environmental monitoring; and individuals within a five mile radius of each site with home gardens meeting the survey criteria.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva23" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-23</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Radiation Dosimetry Personnel Monitoring Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Nuclear Operations, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Employees, former employees, and visitors who might be exposed or are exposed to radiation while in TVA installations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information on the magnitude of exposure at TVA installations, exposure prior to employment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Energy Reorganization Act of 1974, Pub. L. 93-438, 88 Stat. 1233; 10 CFR parts 19, 20.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to fulfill TVA"s legal obligation to record the exposure, or possible exposure, of individuals to radiation at TVA facilities and to report exposures to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. This is information is used to maintain Occupational Dose records by the Nuclear Power Group for all persons monitored for occupational radiation exposure.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for its use in evaluating TVA radiological control measures.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To health-related agencies, organizations, or professionals for the purpose of compiling vital health statistics, or conducting biomedical investigations as part of employee population health monitoring which includes routine clinical and epidemiological investigations.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices, microfilm, microfiche, and in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by individual name and Social Security number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Security is provided by physical, administrative and computer system safeguards. Files are kept in secured facilities not accessible to unauthorized individuals or are locked when unattended.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Senior Manager, Radiation Protection Oversight, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals should address inquiries to the system manager named above, or if a current employee, to the Radiological Control office at the TVA facility where employed. Requests should include the individual's full name, Social Security number and date of birth.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who desire access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above, or if a current employee, to the Radiological Control office at the TVA facility where employed. Requests should include the individual's full name, Social Security number and date of birth.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information in this system of records comes from the individual; previous licensees where the individual was monitored for radiation exposure; and TVA personnel conducting radiation monitoring programs.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva26" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Retirement System Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Retirement Management, TVA, 400 W. Summit Hill Drive, Knoxville, TN </p>
<p>37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Active, retired, and former members of the TVA Retirement System; TVA employees and former employees who are members of the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees Retirement System; designated beneficiaries.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Personal identifying information; retirement, benefit, and investment information; related correspondence; and legal documents.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to support the administration of TVA"s retirement system, including the management and payment of pensions, investment accounts, and other retirement-related benefits and records.  The system is used to provide retirement program registration, retirement benefit estimates, tax forms, benefit management and disbursement, and relevant information to TVA employees, former employees, and beneficiaries.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To report earnings to the Internal Revenue Service.</p>
<p>    To disclose information to actuarial firms for valuation and projecting benefits.</p>
<p>    To disclose information to the Medical Board of the TVA Retirement System for determinations related to disability retirement.</p>
<p>    To certify insurance status to the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Federal Employees' Group Life Insurance.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of a system member.</p>
<p>    To disclose information to auditing firms for use in auditing benefit calculations and financial statements.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information; and to request information from private individuals, if necessary, to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision within the purpose of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the issuance of any benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To provide the following information on retirees to the TVA Retirees Association: Names, unique identification numbers assigned by the TVA Retirement System to each retiree, addresses, dates of birth, dates of termination of employment with TVA, retirement class (member, beneficiary, Civil Service, deferred), last official station, and dates of death (if applicable).</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To Contractors and subcontractors of TVA or the Retirement System who are provided records maintenance or other similar support service to the Retirement System.</p>
<p>    To health-related agencies, organizations, or professionals for the purpose of compiling vital health statistics, or conducting biomedical investigations for employee population health monitoring which includes routine clinical and epidemiological investigations. </p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained in an electronic document management system.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name and Social Security number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to the electronic document management system requires a password and is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Director, Retirement Management, TVA, 400 W. Summit Hill Drive, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to know whether information about them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Inquiries should include the individual's full name, date of birth, and Social Security number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals who desire access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information maintained on them in this system should address inquiries to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The individual on whom the record is maintained; TVA personnel and payroll records.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva29" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-29</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Energy Program Participant Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   Energy Right &amp; Renewable Solutions, External Relations, P.O. Box 292409, Nashville, TN 37229-2409.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals participating in the Energy Right programs.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Customer name, address, account number, meter number, telephone number, characteristics of their dwelling, including type of heating and cooling systems and number and kind of appliances; and other characteristics of study participants relevant to patterns of residential electrical use.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The purpose of this system is to support the administration of the Energy Right program. Energy Right offers programs and products to help customers save energy and incentives, including rebates, to residential customers for reductions in their electric usage.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To power distributors participating in the program.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained in automated data storage devices and in file folders in locked file cabinets.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed and retrieved by contractor name and invoice date.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. All filing systems are locked when unattended.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   Market &amp; Program Analysis, Energy Right  &amp; Renewable Solutions, External Relations TVA, P.O. Box 292409, Nashville, TN 37229-2409.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals about whom information is maintained in this system of records are aware of that fact through participation in the program. However, inquiries may be addressed to the system manager named above  Request should include the individual's full name and address.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Requests for access may be directed to the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The information in this system is solicited from the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva31" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-31</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    OIG Investigative Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Office of the Inspector General, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499. Duplicate copies of certain documents may also be located in the files of other offices and divisions.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals and entities who are or have been the subjects of investigations by the Office of the Inspector General (OIG), or who provide information in connection with such investigations, including but not limited to: Employees; former employees; current or former contractors and subcontractors and their employees; consultants; and other individuals and entities which have or are seeking to obtain business or other relations with TVA.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information relating to investigations, including information provided by known or anonymous complainants; information provided by the subjects of investigations; information provided by individuals or entities with whom the subjects are associated (e.g., coworkers, business associates, relatives); information provided by Federal, State, or local investigatory, law enforcement, or other Government or non-Government agencies; information provided by witnesses and confidential sources; information from public source materials; information from commercial data bases or information resources; investigative notes; summaries of telephone calls; correspondence; investigative reports or prosecutorial referrals; and information about referrals for criminal prosecutions, civil proceedings, and administrative actions taken with respect to the subjects.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Executive Order 10450; Executive Order 11222; Hatch Act, 5 U.S.C. 7324-7327; 28 U.S.C. 535; Proposed Plan for the Creation, Structure, Authority, and Function of the Office of Inspector General, Tennessee Valley Authority, approved by the TVA Board of Directors on October 18, 1985; TVA Code XIII INSPECTOR GENERAL, approved by the TVA Board of Directors on February 19, 1987; Inspector General Act Amendments of 1988, Public Law 100-504, 102 Stat. 2515, and 2000 amendments to the Inspector General Act, Public Law 106-422, 114 Stat. 1872.  Inspector General Reform Act of 2008. Pub. L. 110-408, 122 Stat. 4305.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The purposes of this system are to document the conduct and outcome of Office of the Inspector General (OIG) investigations; to report the results of investigations to other Federal agencies, other public authorities, or professional organizations which have the authority to bring criminal prosecutions or civil or administrative actions, or to impose other disciplinary sanctions; and to serve as a repository of information necessary to fulfill OIG reporting requirements.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation of statute, regulation, order, or similar requirement, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate entity, including Federal, State, or local agencies or other entities charged with enforcement, investigative, or oversight responsibility.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal, State, or local entity (1) in connection with the hiring or retention of an individual, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting entity to the extent that the information is relevant to a decision on such matters, or (2) in connection with any other matter properly within the jurisdiction of such other entity and related to its prosecutorial investigatory, regulatory, administrative, or other responsibilities.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate entity, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight or review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding an individual, or to report to a Member on the results of investigations, audits, or other activities of OIG.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To the subjects of an investigation and their representatives in the course of a TVA investigation of misconduct; to any other person or entity that has or may have information relevant to the investigation to the extent necessary to assist in the conduct of the investigation, such as to request information.</p>
<p>   In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To a consultant, private firm, or individual who contracts or subcontracts with TVA, to the extent necessary to the performance of the contract.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant or potentially relevant information; and to request information from private individuals or entities, if necessary, to acquire information pertinent to the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee; the issuance of a security clearance; the conduct of a background or other investigation; or other matter within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To the public when: (1) The matter under investigation has become public knowledge, or (2) when the Inspector General determines that such disclosure is necessary (a) to preserve confidence in the integrity of the OIG investigative process, or (b) to demonstrate the accountability of TVA officers, or employees, or other individuals covered by this system; unless the Inspector General determines that disclosure of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
<p>    To the news media and public when there exists a legitimate public interest (e.g., to provide information on events in the criminal process, such as indictments), or when necessary for protection from imminent threat to life or property.</p>
<p>    To members of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, for the preparation of reports to the President and Congress on the activities of the Inspectors General.</p>
<p>    To members of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the U.S. Marshals Service, as necessary, for the purpose of conducting qualitative assessment reviews of the investigative operations of TVA OIG to ensure that adequate internal safeguards and management procedures are maintained.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interest, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) The disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices, hard-copy printouts, and in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed and retrieved by individual name or case file number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Access to and use of records is limited to authorized staff in OIG and to other authorized officials and employees of TVA on a need-to-know basis as determined by OIG management. Security will be provided by physical, administrative, and computer system safeguards. Files will be kept in secured facilities not accessible to unauthorized individuals.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Inspector General, TVA, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I) and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24. This system is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), (e)(5), (e)(8), and (g) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva32" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-32</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Call Detail Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Data Center, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    TVA employees, contractor personnel, and other individuals who make telephone calls from or charge telephone calls to TVA telephones.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records relating to use of TVA telephones; records relating to long distance telephone calls charged to TVA; records relating to cellular telephone calls charged to TVA; records indicating assignment of telephone numbers and authorization numbers; records relating to locations of TVA telephones.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The purpose of this system is to maintain call records.  Call records are used to maintain a log for auditing or billing purposes. These records could be used to trace or identify call data regarding a caller threatening the safety of the public, TVA employees, or TVA property; as documentation to rebut costs provided on a monthly bill from the telephone carrier; to determine any employee conduct issues, such as repeated personal calls over a period of time; or to verify calls to or from a number for litigation purposes.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding an individual.</p>
<p>    To provide to the appropriate entity, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation of statute, regulation, order, or similar requirement, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate entity, including Federal, State, or local agencies, or other entities charged with enforcement, investigative, or oversight responsibility.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an individual, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To a telecommunications company as well as to other TVA contractors providing telecommunications support to permit servicing the account.</p>
<p>    To TVA contractors engaged at TVA's direction in investigations of abuse of TVA telephone service or other related issues.</p>
<p>    To TVA contractors and contractor personnel to determine individual responsibility for telephone calls.</p>
<p>    To TVA contractors in connection with amounts due TVA for telecommunications services provided to them.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained in file folders and on automated data storage devices.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are retrieved by name, authorization number, or telephone number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Files are kept in secured facilities. Automated data is secured through physical and system-based safeguards.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Manager, IT Vendor Management, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, employing division, job title, and official TVA telephone number and authorization number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to gain access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, employing division, job title, and official TVA telephone number and authorization number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    TVA Telecommunication Control System; telecommunications companies with which TVA contracts for telephone service; telephone and authorization number assignment records; results of administrative inquiries relating to assignment of responsibility for placement of specific long distance calls.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva34" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-34</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Project/Tract Files--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Realty, GIS, and Land Records, TVA, Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801, and secured off-site storage facility.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals or business entities from/to whom TVA is in the process of or has (1) acquired, transferred, or sold land or landrights, (2) made payment for construction, maintenance, or other damage to real property, or (3) made payment for relocation assistance. A project/tract file may name more than one individual and/or business entity involved in a transaction. (The system records that pertain to individuals and reflect personal information are subject to the Privacy Act. Noncovered records include public information and records on corporations and other business entities.)</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Maps, property descriptions, appraisal reports, and title documents on real property; reports on contracts and transaction progress; contracts and options; records of investigations, claims, and/or payments related to land transactions, damage restitution, and relocation assistance; related correspondence and reports.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; Pub. L. 87-852, 76 Stat. 1129; Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970, as amended.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>To establish and maintain a system for recording parcel of land acquisitions and the disposal of land and land rights by TVA.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding an individual.</p>
<p>    To lienholders as necessary to secure subordinations or releases of liens or to protect lienholders rights.</p>
<p>    To county clerk and register of deeds offices to document and put on record the title acquired by TVA.</p>
<p>    To landowners, prospective landowners, claimants, or trespassers to establish or cure titles, to resolve encroachments, to resolve boundary disputes, or to resolve questions about easement rights or the application of Section 26a of the TVA Act 16 U.S.C. 831y-1.</p>
<p>    To contractors to secure appraisals and title abstracts.</p>
<p>    To request information from a Federal, State, or local agency or from private individuals, as necessary, to obtain information relevant to a TVA decision to acquire or dispose of property or to pay claims or make payments related to land transactions, damage restitution, and relocation assistance.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation of statute, regulation, order, or similar requirement, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate entity, including Federal, State, or local agencies, or other entities charged with enforcement, investigative, or oversight responsibility.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an individual, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant to the requesting agency's decision on that matter.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To provide to the appropriate entity, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To report any required information to Federal, State, and local taxing authorities as required by law.</p>
<p>    To genealogical researchers, relevant portions of maps, descriptions, appraisals, and title documents on real property, after 20 years, to establish historical records.</p>
<p>    To archaeological researchers, relevant portions of maps, descriptions, appraisals, and title documents on real property, after 20 years, to reconstruct historical settings.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of a matter relating to a specific project or tract.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on registers, aperture cards, microfilm, in file folders, and/or on automated data storage devices.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are primarily indexed by tract number and project symbol. Records may also be retrieved by cross-index reference to individual and business entity names.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Files are kept in secured facilities. Remote access facilities are secured through physical and system-based safeguards.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Senior Manager, Realty GIS, and Land Records TVA, 1101 Market Street, BR-4B-C Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to know whether information about them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name and, to the extent known, any project/tract identifying information such as the project name, tract number, address, or related data.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to gain access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name, and to the extent known, any project/tract identifying information such as project name, tract number, address, or related data. Access will be granted only to individually segregable personal information about the requester and to segregable nonpersonal information in accordance with TVA regulations on release of records relating to negotiations in progress involving contracts or agreements for the acquisition or disposal of real or personal property by TVA prior to the conclusion of such negotiations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their requests to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Public records and directories, landowners, tenants, and other individuals and business entities (including financial institutions) having an interest in or knowledge related to land ownership, appraisal, or title history; TVA personnel and contractors including independent appraisers and commercial title companies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva36" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-36</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Section 26a Permit Application Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    For applications involving construction of facilities located on TVA reservoirs, such as boathouses, piers, docks, launching ramps, marine railways, beaches, utilities, and ground improvements, the records are maintained in the following locations:</p>
<p>Gray Regional Office, TVA, (Boone, Bristol Project Fort Patrick Henry, South Holston, Watauga, and Wilbur Reservoirs)) 106 Tri-Cities Business Park Drive, Gray Tennessee 376615</p>
<p>Morristown Regional Office, TVA, (Cherokee, Douglas, Nolichucky, French Broad, Holston and Norris Reservoirs) 3726 E. Morris Boulevard, Morristown, Tennessee 37813-1270</p>
<p>Lenoir City Regional Office, TVA, (Great Falls, Fort London, Melton Hill, Norris, Tellico, Fontana, and Watts Bar Reservoirs), 260 Interchange Park Drive, LCB 1A-LCT, Lenoir City, Tennessee 37772-5664</p>
<p>Chattanooga Regional Office, TVA, (Chickamauga and Nickajack Reservoirs), 4601 N. Access Road, Bldg. B,  Chattanooga, Tennessee 37402-2801</p>
<p>Murphy Regional Office, TVA (Apalachia, Blue Ridge, Chatuge, Hiwassee, Nottely, and the Ocoee Reservoirs), 4800 US Highway 64 West, Suite 102, Murphy, North Carolina 28906</p>
<p>Guntersville Regional Office, TVA, (Guntersville, Normandy and Tims Ford Reservoirs), 3696 Alabama Highway 69, CAB 1A-GVA, Guntersville, Alabama 35976-7196</p>
<p>Muscle Shoals Regional Office, TVA (Bear Creek, Cedar Creek, Duck River, Elk River, Little Bear Creek, Pickwick, Upper Bear Creek, Wheeler, and Wilson Reservoirs), Post Office Box 1010, MPB 1H, Muscle Shoals, Alabama 35662-1010</p>
<p>Paris Regional, Office, TVA (Beech River Project, Kentucky, and Lower Duck Reservoirs), 2835-A East Wood Street, Paris, Tennessee 38242-5948</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system includes individuals who have filed a Section 26a application for approval of construction of such structures as boat ramps, docks, bridges, and dams located along, across, or in the Tennessee River and its tributaries. Also included in this system may be individuals whose structures do not have Section 26a permits, or whose approved structures have deteriorated so as to pose a threat to navigation, flood control, public lands or reservations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Section 26a permit applications made by individuals, businesses and industries, utilities, and Federal, State, county and city Government agencies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Section 26a of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, as amended, requires that TVA review and approve plans for the construction, operation, and maintenance of any dam, appurtenant works, or other obstruction affecting navigation, flood control, or public lands or reservations across, along, or in the Tennessee River or any of its tributaries. The information collected is used to assess the impact of the proposed project on the statutory TVA programs and the environment and determine if the project can be approved. Rules on the application for review and approval of such plans are published in 18 CFR part 1304, Approval of Construction in the Tennessee River System and Regulation of Structures.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To State or other Federal agencies for use in program evaluation, providing assistance to program participants, or engaged at TVA's direction in providing support services to the program, to the extent necessary to the performance of those services.</p>
<p>    To TVA consultants, contractors, subcontractors or individuals who contract or subcontract with TVA, who are engaged in studies and evaluation of TVA's administration or other matters involving its Section 26a program or who are providing support services to the program, to the extent necessary to the performance of the contract.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal, State, or local entity in response to its request, in connection with the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting entity to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on such matters.</p>
<p>    To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding the status of a specific application.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To refer, where there is an indication of a violation of statute, regulation, order, or similar requirement, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate entity, including Federal, State, or local agencies or other entities charged with enforcement, investigative, or oversight responsibility.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices, in electronic format, on microfilm, and in hard copy files.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records may be retrieved by applicant name, land tract number, or Section 26a application number, stream location, reservoir, county, or subdivision. Records in field offices are interfiled with land tract records and are retrieved by land tract number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited through physical, administrative, and computer system safeguards to those persons whose official duties require such access.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Vice President, Natural Resources and Real Property Services, TVA 400 West Summit Hill Drive, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name. A land tract number, Section 26a permit application number, stream location or legal property description is not required, but may expedite TVA's response.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information in this system is solicited from the individual to whom the record pertains. Information may also be obtained from other Federal, State, county or city Government agencies; public records and directories; landowners, tenants, and other individuals and business entities, including financial institutions, having an interest in or knowledge related to land ownership, appraisal, or title history; and TVA personnel and contractors including independent appraisers and commercial title companies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>  None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva37" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-37</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    U.S. TVA Security Records--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    U.S. TVA Police and Emergency Management, TVA, 400 West Summit Hill Drive, WT-2D, Knoxville, Tennessee 37902-1499. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    A. Individuals who relate in any manner to official U.S. TVA Police investigations into incidents or events occurring within the jurisdiction of TVA, including but not limited to suspects, victims, witnesses, close relatives, medical personnel, and associates who have relevant information to an investigation.</p>
<p>    B. Individuals who are the subject of unsolicited information or who offer unsolicited information, and law enforcement personnel who request assistance and/or make inquiries concerning records.</p>
<p>    C. Individuals including, but not limited to, current or former employees; current or former contractor and subcontractor personnel; visitors and other individuals that have or are seeking to obtain business or other relations with TVA; individuals who have requested and/or have been granted access to TVA buildings or property, or secured areas within a building or property.</p>
<p>    D. Individuals who are the subject of research studies including, but not limited to, crime profiles, scholarly journals, and news media references.</p>
<p>    E. Individuals who respond to emergency situations at TVA.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Information related to case investigation reports on all forms of incidents or events, visitor and employee registers, TVA forms authorizing access for individuals into TVA buildings or secured areas within a building, and historical information on an individual's building access or denial of access; U.S. TVA Police on incidents or events; visitor and employee registers, TVA forms, or permits authorizing access for individuals into TVA buildings, property, or secured areas within buildings or property, and historical information on an individual's access or denial of access within buildings or property; emergency personnel information data bases; permit applications under the Archaeological Resources Protection Act (ARPA); risk, security, and emergency preparedness, assessments conducted by the U.S. TVA Police on facilities, property, or officials; research studies, scholarly journal articles, textbooks, training materials, and news media references of interest to U.S. TVA  personnel; an index of all detected trends, patterns, profiles and methods of operation of known and unknown criminals whose records are maintained in the system; an index of the names, address, and contact telephone numbers of professional individuals and organizations who are in a position to furnish assistance to the U.S. TVA Police; an index of public record sources for historical, statistical, geographic, and demographic data; and an alphabetical name index of all individuals whose records are maintained in the system.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; 5 U.S.C. 552a; and 28 U.S.C. 534.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purpose of this system is to collect and maintain records of processing of personnel security-related actions, for personnel actions such as removal from sensitive duties, removal from employment, or denial to a restricted or sensitive area. The system also assists in capturing background investigations and adjudications; determining eligibility for unescorted access to TVA owned, occupied, or secured facilities or information technology systems; and/or other activities relating to personnel security management responsibilities at TVA.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To the appropriate official agency, whether Federal, State, or local, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature.</p>
<p>    In litigation where TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, information may be disclosed to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To provide information to a Federal, State, or local entity in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on that matter, or in connection with any other matter properly within the jurisdiction of such other agency and related to its responsibilities to prosecute, investigate, regulate, and administrate, or other responsibilities.</p>
<p>    To any Federal, State, local or foreign Government agency directly engaged in the criminal justice process where access is directly related to a law enforcement function of the recipient agency in connection with the tracking, identification, and apprehension of persons believed to be engaged in criminal activity.</p>
<p>    To an organization or individual in both the public and private sector pursuant to an appropriate legal proceeding or if deemed necessary, to elicit information or cooperation from the recipient for use by TVA in the performance of an authorized activity.</p>
<p>    To an organization or individual in the public or private sector where there is reason to believe the recipient is or could become the target of a particular criminal activity or conspiracy and to the extent the information is relevant to the protection of life or property.</p>
<p>    To the news media and general public where there exists a legitimate public interest such as obtaining public or media assistance in the tracking, identifying, and apprehending of persons believed to be engaged in repeated acts of criminal behavior; notifying the public and/or media of arrests; protecting the public from imminent threat to life or property where necessary; and disseminating information to the public and/or media to obtain cooperation with research, evaluation, and statistical programs.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in proceedings under the TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures.</p>
<p>    To appropriately respond to congressional inquiries on behalf of constituents.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interest, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are stored manually as hard copies in a secured area and/or in computerized data storage devices at the U.S. TVA offices in Knoxville, TN. Information maintained in computerized form may be stored in memory, on disk storage, on computer tape, or on computer printed listings.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    On-line computer access to U.S. TVA Police files is achieved by using the following search descriptors:</p>
<p>    A. The names of individuals, their birth dates, physical descriptions, social security numbers, and other identification numbers, such as incident and case reports.</p>
<p>    B. As previously described, summary variables contained on incident and call are submitted to the U.S. TVA Police.</p>
<p>  C. Key word citations to research studies, scholarly journals, textbooks, training materials, and news media references.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained in restricted areas and are accessed only by U.S. TVA Police employees. Security is provided by a comprehensive program of physical, administrative, personnel, and computer system safeguards. Access to and use of records is limited to authorized U.S. TVA Police personnel and to other authorized officials and employees of TVA on a need-to-know basis. Sensitive or classified information in electronic form is encrypted prior to transmission to ensure confidentiality, security, and to prevent interception and interpretation.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules. As deemed necessary, certain records may be subject to restricted examinations by 44 U.S.C. 2104.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, TVA Police and Emergency Management, TVA, 400 West Summit Hill Drive, WT-2D, Knoxville, TN 37902-1499.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) (2) and (k) (2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) (2) and (k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system of records is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2) and (k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    This system is exempt from subsections (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I); and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24. This system of records is exempt from subsections (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(2); (e)(3); (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I); (e)(5); (e)(8); and (g) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552(j)(2) and TVA regulations at 18 CFR 1301.24.)</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva38" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-38</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Wholesale, Retail, and Emergency Data System--TVA.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>External Relations, Nashville, TN 37229-2409, and Customer Service Centers.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    TVA wholesale and retail customers' key personnel and governing bodies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Name, address, telephone number, emergency numbers, interests, key dates, associates, immediate family members, and credentials of TVA's wholesale and retail customers and their officers and other personnel.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>   The purpose of this system is to maintain TVA wholesale and retail customers' key personnel and emergency information. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To respond to a referral from a Member of Congress.</p>
<p>    To contact customer personnel during system emergencies.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Records are maintained on automated data storage devices. Hard copies of power distributor managers' key information are given to TVA staff working with distributor managers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are organized by wholesale and retail customer name and indexed by individual's name.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to persons whose official duties require such access. Files are kept in a secured database. Access requires a login ID and password.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    General Manager, Customer Strategy and Support, TVA,  26 Century Blvd, Suite 100N, Nashville, TN 37214</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the system manager named above. Requests should include the individual's full name and employer.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager named above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager named above.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    The information for this system is obtained from TVA's wholesale and retail customers and their personnel.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="tva39" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-39</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">    Nuclear Access Authorization and Fitness for Duty Records-TVA</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Nuclear Access Services, TVA, Chattanooga, Tennessee 37402-2801; various contractor locations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Current and former TVA employees, contractors, applicants for employment, applicants for employment by contractors who have been employed or sought to be employed in TVA Nuclear.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Education; qualification; work history; residence history citizenship; employment and military history; financial history; spouse/cohabitation and relatives; personal references; information received from various law enforcement agencies, federal, state and local; fingerprints; background investigation reports; psychological assessment files, drug and alcohol testing schedules and results; personnel identifying information; and additional security investigation data.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, 16 U.S.C. 831-831ee; EO 9397; EO 12038; EO 13467; Atomic Energy Act of 1954 as amended; Title II of the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974; 10 CFR Pt. 26; 10 C.F.R. "" 72.56, 73.57.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purpose of this system is to safely provide unescorted access to TVA"s nuclear sites. The Nuclear Access Authorization and Fitness for Duty Records allow TVA to provide proper consideration when providing, maintaining, or denying unescorted access to sensitive areas in and around its nuclear sites.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    To respond to a request from a member of Congress regarding the status of an employee, former employee or applicant made at the request of that individual.</p>
<p>    To refer, where the is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility if investigating and prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>    To request from any pertinent source directly or through a TVA contractor engaged at TVA"s direction, information relevant to a TVA decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>    To provide information or disclose to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency"s decision on the matter.</p>
<p>    To another licensee, contractor or vendor or their authorized representatives legitimately seeking the information as required by this section for unescorted access decisions and who have obtained a signed release from the individual. </p>
<p>    To representatives of the NRC to determine compliance with the applicable regulations and law.</p>
<p>    To the appropriate agency, whether Federal State, or local, in connection with its oversight review responsibilities or authorized law enforcement activities.</p>
<p>    To the parties or complainants, their representatives, and impartial referees, examiners, administrative judges, or other decision makers in the proceedings under TVA grievance adjustment procedures, Equal Employment Opportunity procedures, Merit Systems Protection Board, or similar procedures, but only to the extent such records document processes or procedures used in making access determinations.</p>
<p>    To those licensee representatives who have a need to have access to the information in performing assigned duties including audits of licensee"s, contractor"s, and vendors programs, determining clearance or access authorization eligibility, and reviewing access authorization determinations on appeal.</p>
<p>    In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for any use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery.  In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>    To persons deciding matters on review or appeal.</p>
<p>    To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by TVA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA"s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>    This section does not authorize the licensee, contractor or vendor to withhold evidence of criminal conduct from law enforcement officials.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>    Information is stored in hard copy files or electronically in the electronic document management system (EDMS) system.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are indexed by name and employee Social Security number</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access and with the appropriate background investigation in accordance with 10 CFR 73.22. All filing systems are located in a secured area.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with established TVA records retention schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Manager, Nuclear Access and Fitness for Duty, TVA, Chattanooga, Tennessee, 37402-2801</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals wishing to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquires to the Manager, Nuclear Access and Fitness for Duty, TVA, Chattanooga, Tennessee, 37402-2801. Requests should include the individual"s full name, and date of birth. A Social Security Number is not required but may expedite TVA"s response; additionally, an Employee Identification Number may be included.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals seeking to gain access to information about them in this system of records should contact the Manager, Nuclear Access and Fitness for Duty, TVA, Chattanooga, Tennessee 37402-2801. Requests should include the individual"s full name and date of birth.  A Social Security Number is not required but may expedite TVA"s response; additionally an Employee Identification Number may be included. Access will not be granted to investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining access authorization to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished the information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September 27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.  Access will not be granted to testing or examination material to the extent such disclosure would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process or would compromise business sensitive or Trade Secrets Act material.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>    Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the Manager, Nuclear Access and Fitness for Duty, TVA, Chattanooga, Tennessee 37402-2801.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>     Individual to whom the record pertains, educational institutions, former employees, and other reference sources, Federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies, physicians and psychologists, military and credit agencies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
    <p>
        This system is exempt from subsections (d); (e)(4)(H); and (f)(2), (3) and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 522a (section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974) to the extent that disclosure of material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence,  and to the extent that disclosure of testing or examination material would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process.  This exemption is pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(5) and (6).
    </p>
</xhtmlContent>

</subsection>


</section>

        <section id="tva40" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>-40</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName"> Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Requests and Appeals Files.</subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        Unclassified.
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The records in this system are maintained at the Tennessee Valley Authority, Knoxville, Tennessee.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> TVA FOIA Officer, Tennessee Valley Authority,  400 W Summit Hill Dr. SW, Knoxville, TN  37902.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  FOIA, 5 U.S.C. 552, as amended.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Only authorized FOIA officials will utilize this system to effectively monitor and track access requests and administrative appeals under the FOIA; and to satisfy TVA’s reporting obligations under the FOIA.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>This system contains records on individuals or their representatives who have submitted FOIA requests for records and/or FOIA administrative appeals with TVA, and individuals whose FOIA requests for records have been referred to TVA by other Federal agencies.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>This system consists of records created or compiled in response to FOIA requests for records or subsequent administrative appeals to include: the requester’s name, home phone, home address,</p>
                    <p>home email, work address, work phone, and work email; the original requests and administrative appeals; responses to such requests and appeals; all related memoranda, correspondence, notes, and other related or supporting documentation, summary of log; and in some instances copies of requested records.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  Information in this system of records is obtained from the individual submitting the request, TVA officials, and other Federal agencies, if appropriate.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>TVA may disclose information contained in a record in this system of records under the routine uses listed in this system of records without the consent of the individual if the disclosure is compatible with a purpose for which the record was collected.</p>
                    <p>(1) To respond to a request from a Member of Congress regarding an individual’s request.</p>
                    <p>(2) When a record on its face, or in conjunction with other records, indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, disclosure may be made to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, foreign, State, local, or tribal, or other public authority responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, if the information disclosed is relevant to any enforcement, regulatory, investigative or prosecute responsibility of the receiving entity.</p>
                    <p>(3) To the National Archives and Records Administration for purposes of records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    <p>(4) To the National Archives and Records Administration, Office of Government Information Services (OGIS), to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities in 5 U.S.C. 552(h), to review administrative agency policies, procedures, and compliance with the Freedom of Information Act, and to facilitate OGIS’ offering of mediation services to resolve disputes between persons making FOIA requests and administrative agencies.</p>
                    <p>(5) To contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the Federal government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                    <p>(6) To an agency, organization, or individual for the purpose of performing audit or oversight operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                    <p>(7) To a Federal agency in order to obtain advice and recommendations concerning matters on which the agency has specialized experience or particular competence, for use in making required determinations under the FOIA.</p>
                    <p>(8) To a submitter or subject of a record or information in order to obtain assistance to TVA in making a determination as to access or amendment.</p>
                    <p>(9) In litigation to which TVA is a party or in which TVA provides legal representation for a party by TVA attorneys or otherwise, for use for any purpose including the presentation of evidence and disclosure in the course of discovery. In all other litigation, to respond to process issued under color of authority or a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
                    <p>(10) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) TVA suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records, (2) TVA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, TVA (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with TVA's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>(11) To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when TVA determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Hardcopy records are stored in secure locations. Electronic records are maintained in various computer databases and in electronic files maintained by TVA component offices.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Electronic and paper records are generally retrieved by the name of the requester, tracking number, or the subject of the request.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule 4.2, but may be retained for a longer period as required by litigation, open investigation, and/or audit.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  Information in this system is safeguarded in accordance with applicable laws, rules, and policies including TVA’s automated systems security and access policies. In general, records and technical equipment are maintained in buildings with restricted access. The required use of password protection identification features and other system protection methods also restrict access. Access is limited to those employees who have an official need for access in order to perform their duty.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals seeking to gain access to information about them in this system of records should contact the system manager.  Your full name and current address should accompany requests for access.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals desiring to contest or amend information about them maintained in this system should direct their request to the system manager.  Please state clearly and concisely what information is being contested, the reasons for contesting it, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals wishing to learn if information on them is maintained in this system of records should address inquires to system manager.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> During the course of a FOIA action, material from other Privacy Act systems of records may become part of the case records in this system of records. To the extent that copies of these records from these other systems of records are entered into these case records, TVA hereby claims the same status for the records as claimed in the original, primary system of records from which they originated, or in which they are maintained.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>This is a new system of record notice.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>


        <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="18">
<heading>Conservation of Power and Water Resources</heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XIII">
<heading>Tennessee Valley Authority</heading>
<regulationsPart number="1301">
<heading>PROCEDURES</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart B--Privacy Act</b></p>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1301.11 Purpose and scope.
</p><p>1301.12 Definitions.
</p><p>1301.13 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</p><p>1301.14 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</p><p>1301.15 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</p><p>1301.16 Special procedures--medical records.
</p><p>1301.17 Requests for correction or amendment of record.
</p><p>1301.18 TVA review of request for correction or amendment of record.
</p><p>1301.19 Appeals on initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
</p><p>1301.20 Disclosure of record to persons other than individual to whom it pertains.
</p><p>1301.21 Fees.
</p><p>1301.22 Penalties.
</p><p>1301.23 General exemptions.
</p><p>1301.24 Special exemptions.
</p><p><b>Subpart B--Privacy Act</b></p>
<p><b>Authority:</b>5 U.S.C. 552 and 552a; 16 U.S.C. 831-831dd.
</p><p><b>Source:</b>40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975, unless otherwise noted. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May
29,
1979.</p>
    <p><b>Editorial Note:</b> At 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017, &#167;&#167; 1301.20—1301.24 were removed; however, the amendment could not be incorporated due to inaccurate amendatory instruction.</p>

<p><b>&#167; 1301.21
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p><p>(a) The regulations in &#167;&#167; 1301.21 to 1301.34 implement section 3 of the Privacy Act
of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a, with respect to systems of records maintained by TVA. They provide procedures by
which an individual may exercise the rights granted by the Act to determine whether a TVA system contains a
record pertaining to him; to gain access to such records; to have a copy made of all or any portion
thereof; and to request administrative correction or amendment of such records. They prescribe fees to be
charged for copying records; establish identification requirements; list penalties provided by statute for
certain violations of the Act; and establish exemptions from certain requirements of the Act for certain
TVA systems or components thereof.
</p><p>(b) Nothing in &#167;&#167; 1301.21 to 1301.34 entitles an individual to any access to any
information or record compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
</p><p>(c) Certain records of which TVA may have physical possession are the official records of another
government agency which exercises dominion and control over the records, their content, and access thereto.
In such cases, TVA's maintenance of the records is subject to the direction of the other government agency.
Except for a request for a determination of the existence of the record, when TVA receives requests related
to these records, TVA will immediately refer the request to the controlling agency for all decisions
regarding the request, and will notify the individual making the request of the referral.
        <p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and further redesignated and amended at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>

</p><p><b>&#167; 1301.22
 Definitions.
</b></p><p>For purposes of &#167;&#167; 1301.21 to 1301.34:
</p><p>(a) The Actmeans section 3 of the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a;
</p><p>(b) The terms individual, maintain, record, system of records, statistical record,and routine
usehave the meaning provided for by the Act;
</p><p>(c) The term TVA systemmeans a system of records maintained by TVA;
</p><p>(d) The term TVA system noticemeans a notice of a TVA system published in the Federal Register
pursuant to the Act. TVA has published TVA system notices about the following TVA systems:
</p>
<p>Apprentice Training Record System--TVA.
</p><p>Personnel Files--TVA.
</p><p>Upgrade Craft Training Program--TVA.
</p><p>Demonstration Farm Records--TVA.
</p><p>Discrimination Complaint Files--TVA.
</p><p>Employee Accident Information System--TVA.
</p><p>Employee Accounts Receivable--TVA.
</p><p>Employee Alleged Misconduct Investigatory Files--TVA.
</p><p>Medical Record System--TVA.
</p><p>Employee Statement of Employment and Financial Interests--TVA.
</p><p>Payroll Records--TVA.
</p><p>Travel History Records--TVA.
</p><p>Employment Applicant Files--TVA.
</p><p>Grievance Records--TVA.
</p><p>LAND BETWEEN THE LAKES Hunter Records--TVA.</p>
<p>LAND BETWEEN THE LAKES Register of Law Violations--TVA.</p>
<p>Employee Supplementary Vacancy Announcement Records--TVA.
</p><p>Consultant and Personal Service Contractor Records--TVA.
</p><p>Nuclear Quality Assurance Personnel Records--TVA.
</p><p>Questionnaire--Farms in Vicinity of Proposed or Licensed Nuclear Power Plant--TVA.
</p><p>Radiation Dosimetry Personnel Monitoring Records--TVA.
</p><p>Retirement System Records--TVA.
</p><p>Test Demonstration Farm Records--TVA.
</p><p>Woodland Resource Analysis Program Input Data--TVA.
</p><p>Electricity Use, Rate, and Service Study Records--TVA.
</p><p>LAND BETWEEN LAKES Mailing Lists--TVA.</p>
<p>OIG Investigative Records--TVA.
</p><p>Call Detail Records--TVA.
</p><p>Office of Nuclear Power Call Detail Records--TVA.
</p><p>Project/Tract Files--TVA.
</p><p>Building Access Security Records--TVA.
</p><p>Section 26a Permit Applications--TVA.
</p>
<p>(e) The term appellantmeans an individual who has filed an appeal pursuant to &#167;
1301.29(a) from an initial determination refusing to amend a record on request of the individual;
</p><p>(f) The term reviewing officialmeans TVA's Vice President, Employee Worklife, or another TVA
official designated by the Vice President in writing to decide an appeal pursuant to &#167; 1301.29;
</p><p>(g) The term day,when used in computing a time period, excludes Saturdays, Sundays, and legal
public holidays.
</p><p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and amended at 53 FR 30252, Aug. 11, 1988; 56 FR 9288, Mar. 6, 1991; 57 FR 33634, July 30, 1992; 57 FR 59803, Dec. 16, 1992; 75 FR 11736, Mar. 12, 2010; 81 FR 88999, Dec. 9, 2016. Redesignated and amended at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]

</p><p><b>&#167; 1301.23
 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</b></p><p>(a) An individual may, in accordance with this section (1) request a TVA determination whether a
record retrieved by the individual's name or other personal identifier is maintained in a TVA system, and
(2) request access to such a record. A request for determination may be combined with a request for access.
</p><p>(b) Requests under this section shall:
</p><p>(1) Be in writing and signed by the individual seeking the determination or access;
</p><p>(2) Include the individual's mailing address;
</p><p>(3) Name the TVA system as listed in the TVA system notice;
</p><p>(4) Include any additional identifying information specified in the paragraph headed "Notification
procedure" in the applicable TVA system notice;
</p><p>(5) Specify whether the request is for determination only or for both determination and access; and
</p><p>(6) Include such proof of identity as may be required by &#167; 1301.24 and the applicable system
notice.Requests may be presented in person or by mail. In-person requests shall be presented during normal
TVA business hours, as set out in &#167; 1301.24(g).
</p><p>(c) Requests for determination only shall be presented to the official designated in the paragraph
headed "Notification procedure" in the TVA system notice for the TVA system concerned. Requests for both
determination and access shall be presented to the official designated in the paragraph headed "Access
procedure" in the TVA system notice for the TVA system concerned. Certain TVA system notices designate
officials at field locations of TVA systems. With respect to such TVA systems, an individual who believes
his record is located at the field location may present a request to the designated official at the field
location. If the record is not available at that field location, the request will be forwarded to the
appropriate TVA office.
</p><p>(d) If a request is for determination only, the determination will normally be made within 10 days
after
receipt of the request. If the determination cannot be made within 10 days after receipt of a request, the
designated official will acknowledge the request in writing and state when the determination will be made.
Upon making a determination, the designated official will notify the individual making the request whether
the record exists. The notice will include any additional information necessary to enable the individual to
request access to the record.
</p><p>(e) A request which includes a request for access will be acknowledged within 10 days after receipt.
If
access can be granted as requested, the acknowledgment will provide a time and place for disclosure of the
requested record. Disclosure will normally be made within 30 days of the date of the acknowledgement, but
the designated official may extend the 30-day period for reasons found by him to be good cause. In case of
an extension, TVA will notify the individual, in writing, that disclosure will be delayed, the reasons for
delay, and the anticipated date on which the individual may expect the record to be disclosed. TVA will
attempt to accommodate reasonable requests for disclosure at specified times and dates, as set forth in a
request for access, so far as compatible with the conduct of TVA business.
        <p>40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and further redesignated and amended at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>

</p><p><b>&#167; 1301.24
 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</b></p><p>(a) TVA will require proof of identity, in accordance with this section, before it will disclose
a
record under &#167; 1301.25 of this part to an individual requesting access to the record, and before
it will disclose the existence of a record to a requester under &#167; 1301.23 of this part, if TVA
determines that disclosure of the existence of such record would constitute an unwarranted invasion of
personal privacy.
</p><p>(b) Identification normally required would be an identification card such as a valid state driver's
license or TVA or other employee identification card. A comparison of the signature of the requester with
either the signature on the card or a signature in the record may be used to confirm identity.
</p><p>(c) Because of the sensitivity of the subject matter in a TVA system, a TVA system notice may
prescribe
special identification requirements for the disclosure of the existence of or access to records in that TVA
system. In such case, the special identification requirements prescribed in the TVA system notice shall
apply in lieu of those prescribed by paragraph (b) of this section.
</p><p>(d) If TVA deems it warranted by the nature of identification presented, the subject matter of the
material to be disclosed, or other reasons found by TVA to be sufficient, TVA may require the individual
requesting access to sign a statement asserting identity and stating that the individual understands that
knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another person under false pretenses is
punishable by a fine of up to $5,000.
</p><p>(e) Where TVA is requested to provide access to records by mailing copies of records to the
requester,
the request shall contain or be accompanied by adequate identifying information to make it likely the
requester is the person he purports to be and a notarized statement asserting identity and stating that the
individual understands that knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another
person under false pretenses is punishable by a fine of up to $5,000.
</p><p>(f) Where sensitivity of record information may warrant (i.e., unauthorized access could cause harm
or
embarrassment to the individual) or disclosure by mail to third persons is requested, TVA may require in-
person confirmation of identity. If in-person confirmation of identity is required, the individual may
arrange with the designated TVA official to provide such identification at any of these TVA locations
convenient to the individual: Knoxville, Nashville, and Chattanooga, Tennessee; Muscle Shoals, Alabama;
Washington, DC, or another location agreed upon by the individual and the designated TVA official. Upon
request the TVA official will provide an address and an appropriate time for such identification to be
presented.
</p><p>(g) In general, TVA offices located in the eastern time zone are open 8 a.m. to 4:45 p.m., and those
in
the central time zone 7:30 a.m. to 4:15 p.m. Construction project offices and Land Between The Lakes are
generally open 7 a.m. to 3:30 p.m. Offices are closed on Saturdays, Sundays, and the following holidays:
New Year's Day, Birthday of Martin Luther King, Jr., Washington's Birthday, Memorial Day, Independence Day,
Labor Day, Columbus Day, Veterans Day, Thanksgiving Day, and Christmas Day.
</p><p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and amended at 53 FR 30253, Aug. 11, 1988; 75 FR 11736, Mar. 12, 2010. Redesignated and amended at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]

</p><p><b>&#167; 1301.25
 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</b></p><p>(a) All disclosure and examination of records shall normally be made in the presence of a TVA
representative. If an individual wishes to be accompanied by a third person of the individual's choosing
when the record is disclosed, TVA may require the individual to furnish TVA, in advance of disclosure of
the record, a statement signed by the individual authorizing discussion and disclosure of the record in the
presence of the accompanying person. If desired by the individual, TVA shall provide copies of any
documents reviewed in the record which are requested at the time of review. Fees shall be charged for such
copies in accordance with the fee schedule in &#167; 1301.31, and shall be payable prior to delivery
of the copies to the individual.
</p><p>(b) Where permitted by &#167; 1301.24, copies of an individual's record will be made available by
mail. A charge for copies will be made in accordance with &#167; 1301.31 of this part. All fees due
shall be paid prior to mailing of the materials. However, if TVA is unable to allow in-person review of the
record, the first copy will be made available without charge.
        <p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and further redesignated and amended at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>

</p><p><b>&#167; 1301.26
 Special procedures--medical records.
</b></p><p>If, in the judgment of TVA, the transmission of medical records, including psychological
records,
directly to a requesting individual could have an adverse effect upon such individual, TVA may refuse to
disclose such information directly to the individual. TVA will, however, disclose this information to a
licensed physician designated by the individual in writing.
            <p>[75 FR 11736, Mar. 12, 2010. Redesignated at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>

</p><p><b>&#167; 1301.27
 Requests for correction or amendment of record.
</b></p><p>(a) An individual may request amendment of records pertaining to him in a TVA system to the
extent
permitted by the Act in accordance with this section. A request for amendment shall:
</p><p>(1) Be in writing and signed by the individual seeking the amendment;
</p><p>(2) Name the TVA system in which the record is maintained;
</p><p>(3) Describe the item or items of information to be amended;
</p><p>(4) Describe the nature of the amendment requested; and
</p><p>(5) Give the reasons for the requested change.
</p><p>(b) Requests shall be made to the official designated in the paragraph headed "Contesting record
procedures" in the TVA system notice for the TVA system concerned. Before considering a request, TVA may
require proof of identity of the requester similar to that required under &#167; 1301.24 to gain
access to the record.
</p><p>(c) The individual requesting amendment has the responsibility of providing TVA with evidence of why
his
record should be amended, and must provide adequate evidence to TVA to justify his request.
</p><p>(d) The provisions of &#167;&#167; 1301.21 to 1301.34 of this part do not permit the alteration of
evidence presented or to be presented in the course of judicial or administrative proceedings; neither do
they permit collateral attack on a prior judicial or administrative action, or provide a collateral remedy
for a matter otherwise judicially or administratively cognizable.
</p><p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and amended at 53 FR 30253, Aug. 11, 1988. Redesignated and amended at 82 FR 51757, 51758, Nov. 8, 2017]

</p><p><b>&#167; 1301.28
 TVA review of request for correction or amendment of record.
</b></p><p>(a) TVA will acknowledge a request for amendment within 10 days of receipt. The acknowledgement
will be in writing, will request any additional information TVA requires to determine whether to make the
requested correction or amendment, and will indicate the date by which TVA expects to make its initial
determination.
</p><p>(b) TVA will, except in unusual circumstances, complete its consideration of requests to amend
records
within 30 days. If more time is deemed necessary, TVA will notify the individual of the delay and of the
expected date of completion of the review.
</p><p>(c) If TVA determines that a record should be corrected or amended, in whole or in part, in
accordance
with a request, it will advise the requesting individual in writing of its determination, and correct or
amend the record accordingly. If an accounting of disclosures has been made, TVA will, to the extent of the
accounting, inform prior recipients of the record of the fact that the correction was made and the
substance of the correction.
</p><p>(d) If TVA, after initial consideration of a request, determines that a record should not be
corrected
or amended, in whole or in part, in accordance with a request, it will notify the individual in writing of
its refusal to amend the record and the reasons therefor. The notification will inform the individual that
the refusal may be appealed administratively and will advise the individual of the procedures for such
appeals.

</p>
    <p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and further redesignated at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>
    <p><b>&#167; 1301.29
 Appeals on initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
</b></p><p>(a) An individual may appeal an initial determination refusing to amend that individual's record
in
accordance with this section. An appeal must be taken within 20 days of receipt of notice of TVA's initial
refusal to amend the record and is taken by delivering a written notice of appeal to the Vice President,
Employee Worklife, Tennessee Valley Authority, Knoxville, Tennessee 37902. Such notice shall be signed by
the appellant and shall state:
</p><p>(1) That it is an appeal from a denial of a request to amend the individual's records under these
regulations and under the Privacy Act of 1974;
</p><p>(2) The reasons why the appellant believes the denial to have been erroneous;
</p><p>(3) The date on which the denial was issued; and
</p><p>(4) The date on which the denial was received by the appellant.
</p><p>(b) Appeals shall be determined by a reviewing official. Such determination may be based on
information
provided for the initial determination; any additional information which TVA or the appellant may desire to
provide; and any other material the reviewing official deems relevant to the determination. The reviewing
official, in his sole discretion, may request TVA or the appellant to provide additional information deemed
relevant to the appeal. The appellant will be given an opportunity to respond to any information provided
by TVA or independently procured by the reviewing official. If in the sole discretion of the reviewing
official a hearing is deemed necessary for resolution of the appeal, the reviewing official may conduct a
hearing upon notice to TVA and the appellant, at which both TVA and the appellant shall be afforded an
opportunity to be heard on the appeal. The rules governing any hearing will be set forth in the notice of
hearing.
</p><p>(c) The reviewing official shall make final determination on the appeal within 30 days after it is
received unless such period is extended for good cause. If the reviewing official finds good cause for an
extension, TVA will inform the appellant in writing of the reason for the delay and of the approximate date
on which the reviewing official expects to complete his determination of the appeal.
</p><p>(d) If the reviewing official determines that a record should be amended in whole or in part in
accordance with an appellant's request, TVA will inform the appellant in writing of its determination and
correct or amend the record. If an accounting of disclosures has been made, TVA will, to the extent of the
accounting, inform prior recipients of the record of the fact that the correction was made and of the
substance of the correction.
</p><p>(e) If the reviewing official determines not to amend a record, in whole or in part, in accordance
with
a request, TVA will advise the individual:
</p><p>(1) Of its refusal to amend and the reasons therefor;
</p><p>(2) Of the appellant's right to file a concise statement of reasons for disagreement with the
refusal as
set out in paragraph (f) of this section;
</p><p>(3) Of the procedures for filing a statement of disagreement;
</p><p>(4) That any statement of disagreement will be made available to anyone to whom the record is
subsequently disclosed together with any statement by TVA summarizing its reasons for refusing to amend the
record;
</p><p>(5) That prior recipients of the disputed record will be provided a copy of any statement of dispute
to
the extent that an accounting of disclosures was maintained; and
</p><p>(6) Of his or her right to seek judicial review of the agency's refusal to amend a record.
</p><p>(f) If the reviewing official's final determination of an appeal is a refusal to correct or amend a
record, in whole or in part, in accordance with the request, the appellant may file with TVA a concise
statement setting forth the reasons for his or her disagreement with the refusal of TVA to amend the
records. Such statements normally should not exceed 100 words. A statement of disagreement should be
submitted within 30 days of receipt of notice of the reviewing official's decision on the appeal, and
should be sent to system manager. In any disclosure containing information about which the individual has
filed a statement of disagreement which occurs after the filing of the statement, TVA will clearly note any
portion of the record which is disputed and provide copies of the statement with the disclosure. Copies of
the statement will also be furnished to persons or other agencies to whom the record has been disclosed to
the extent that an accounting of disclosures was made. TVA may attach to the statement of disagreement a
brief summary of TVA's reasons for refusing to amend the record. Such summaries will be disclosed to the
individual, but are not subject to amendment.
</p><p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and amended at 53 FR 30253, Aug. 11, 1988; 57 FR 33634, July 30, 1992; 75 FR 11736, Mar. 12, 2010. Redesignated at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>
    <p>
        <b>
            &#167; 1301.30
            Disclosure of record to persons other than individual to whom it pertains.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        For purposes of &#167;&#167; 1301.21 to 1301.34, the parent of any minor or the legal guardian
        of any individual who has been declared incompetent due to physical or mental incapacity or age by a court
        of competent jurisdiction may act on behalf of the individual. TVA may require proof of the relationship
        prior to allowing such action. The parent or legal guardian may not act where the individual concerned
        objects to the action of the parent or legal guardian, unless a court otherwise orders.

    </p>
    <p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and further redesignated and amended at 82 FR 51757, 51758, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>
    <p>
        <b>
            &#167; 1301.31
            Fees.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) Fees to be charged, if any, to any individual for making copies of his or her record exclude
        the cost of any search and review of the record. The following fees are applicable:
    </p>
    <p>
        (1) For reproduction of material consisting of sheets no larger than 8 1/2 by 14 inches, ten
        cents
        per page; and
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) For reproduction of other materials, the direct cost of photostats or other means necessarily
        used
        for duplication.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) [Reserved]

    </p>
    <p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and further redesignated at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>
    <p>
        <b>
            &#167; 1301.32
            Penalties.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        Section 552a(i), Title 5, United States Code provides that:
    </p>
    <p>
        (1) Criminal Penalties.Any officer or employee of an agency, who by virtue of his employment or
        official position, has possession of, or access to, agency records which contain individually identifiable
        information the disclosure of which is prohibited by this section or by rules or regulations established
        thereunder, and who knowing that disclosure of the specific material is so prohibited, willfully discloses
        the material in any manner to any person or agency not entitled to receive it, shall be guilty of a
        misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) Any officer or employee of any agency who willfully maintains a system of records without
        meeting
        the notice requirements of subsection (e)(4) of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not
        more than $5,000.
    </p>
    <p>
        (3) Any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual
        from
        an agency under false pretenses shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.

    </p>
    <p>[40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and further redesignated at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]</p>
    <p>
        <b>
            &#167; 1301.33
            General exemptions.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) Individuals may not have access to records maintained by TVA but which were provided by
        another
        agency which has determined by regulation that such information is subject to general exemption under 5
        U.S.C. 552a(j). If such exempt records are within a request for access, TVA will advise the individual of
        their existence and of the name and address of the source agency. For any further information concerning
        the record and the exemption, the individual must contact that source agency.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) The TVA system "Land Between The Lakes Register of Law Violations--TVA" is exempted from
        subsections (c)(3), (4); (d); (e)(1), (2), (3), (4)(G), (4)(H), (4)(I), (5); (f); (g); and (h) of 5 U.S.C.
        552a and corresponding sections of these rules pursuant to section (j)(2) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of
        the Privacy Act). Application of these provisions of the Privacy Act to the criminal law enforcement
        records in this system might interfere with effective law enforcement at the Land Between The Lakes.
    </p>
    <p>
        [75 FR 11736, Mar. 12, 2010. Redesignated at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]

    </p>
    <p>
        <b>
            &#167; 1301.34
            Specific exemptions.
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        (a) The TVA system "Employee Alleged Misconduct Investigatory Files--TVA" is exempted from
        subsections (c)(3); (d); (e)(1), (4)(G), (4)(H), (4)(I); and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a and corresponding
        sections of these rules pursuant to section (k)(2) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act). This
        TVA system is exempted because applications of these provisions to this system might impair investigations
        of employee misconduct.
    </p>
    <p>
        (b)(1) The TVA systems "Apprentice Training Record System-TVA," "Consultant and Personal Service
        Contractor Records-TVA," "Upgrade Craft Training Program-TVA," "Employment Applicant Files-TVA," "Personnel
        Files-TVA," and "Nuclear Quality Assurance Personnel Records-TVA" are exempted from subsections (d); (e)(4)
        (H); (f)(2), (3), and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a and corresponding sections of these rules to the extent that
        disclosure of material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government
        under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to September
        27, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence. These TVA
        systems are exempted pursuant to section (k)(5) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act).
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) Each of these TVA systems contain reference letters and information concerning employees and
        other
        individuals who perform services for TVA. TVA has received this information in the past under both express
        and implied promises of confidentiality and consistent with the Privacy Act these promises will be honored.
        Pledges of confidentiality will be necessary in the future to ensure that unqualified or unsuitable
        individuals are not selected for TVA positions. Without the ability to make these promises, a potential
        source of information may be unwilling to provide needed information, or may not be sufficiently frank to
        be of value in personnel screening.
    </p>
    <p>
        (c)(1) The TVA systems "Apprentice Training Record System-TVA," "Consultant and Personal Service
        Contractor Records-TVA," "Upgrade Craft Training Program-TVA," "Employment Applicant Files-TVA," and
        "Personnel Files-TVA," are exempted from subsections (d); (e)(4)(H); (f)(2), (3), and (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a
        and corresponding sections of these rules to the extent that disclosure of testing or examination material
        used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the Federal service
        would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process. These systems are
        exempted pursuant to section (k)(6) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act).
    </p>
    <p>
        (2) This material is exempted because its disclosure would reveal information about the testing
        process
        which would potentially give an individual an unfair competitive advantage in selection based on test
        performance.
    </p>
    <p>
        (d) The TVA system OIG Investigative Records is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4),
        (G), (H), and (I) and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act) and corresponding sections of
        these rules pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). The TVA system OIG Investigative Records is exempt from
        subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), (e)(5), (e)(8), and (g) pursuant
        to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2). This system is exempt because application of these provisions might alert
        investigation subjects to the existence or scope of investigations, lead to suppression, alteration,
        fabrication, or destruction of evidence, disclose investigative techniques or procedures, reduce the
        cooperativeness or safety of witnesses, or otherwise impair investigations.
    </p>
    <p>
        (e) The TVA system TVA Police Records is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4), (G),
        (H),
        and (I) and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a (section 3 of the Privacy Act) and corresponding sections of these rules
        pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). The TVA system Police Records is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)
        (1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), (e)(5), (e)(8), and (g) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2). This
        system is exempt because application of these provisions might alert investigation subjects to the
        existence or scope of investigations, lead to suppression, alteration, fabrication, or destruction of
        evidence, disclose investigative techniques or procedures, reduce the cooperativeness or safety of
        witnesses, or otherwise impair investigations.
    </p>
    <p>
        [40 FR 45313, Oct. 1, 1975. Redesignated at 44 FR 30682, May 29, 1979, and amended at 53 FR 30253, Aug. 11, 1988; 56 FR 9288, Mar. 6, 1991; 61 FR 2111, Jan. 25, 1996; 62 FR 4644, Jan. 31, 1997; 75 FR 11736, Mar. 12, 2010; 81 FR 88999, Dec. 9, 2016. Redesignated at 82 FR 51757, Nov. 8, 2017]

    </p>   
    


</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>



