<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation</name>
<abbrev>
ONHIR</abbrev>
    
    

<section id="onhir" toc="yes">
<systemNumber/>

<subsection type="systemName">Navajo and Hopi Relocation Commission Records System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission, 2717 N. Steves Boulevard, Building A, Flagstaff, Arizona 86001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Those members of the Navajo Tribe residing in that portion of the Joint Use Area of Arizona which has been partitioned to the Hopi Tribe.
</p><p>(2) Those members of the Hopi Tribe residing in that portion of the Joint Use Area of Arizona which has been partitioned to the Navajo Tribe.
</p><p>(3) Persons who apply to the Commission for relocation benefits.
</p><p>(4) Persons who apply to the Commission for Life Estate Leases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Relocation applications
</p><p>(2) Census information
</p><p>(3) Inventories of livestock and property improvements,
</p><p>(4) Appraisal of improvements, and
</p><p>(5) Life estate applications.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>25 U.S.C. 640(d), 25 U.S.C. 361, et seq.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The primary uses of the records are to determine: (a) Those individuals who are entitled to relocation benefits, (b) the amount of benefits to which individuals are entitled, (c) where relocations may occur, and (d) those individuals who are eligible for Life Estate Leases and the location of such Life Estate Lease parcels. Disclosures outside the Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission may be made to: (a) Tribal Governments for use in adjudicating disputes and in determining the configuration of Life Estate Lease parcels, (b) to United States Courts concerned with the partition of the Joint Use Area, (c) to the Department of Justice when related to litigation or contemplated litigation, (d) to appropriate Federal, State, Local, or Foreign Agency responsible for investigating or prosecuting violations or for enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, order, or license of information indicating a violation or potential violation of a statute, regulation, rule, order, or license, (e) reports to the United States Congress, and (f) publication of rosters to assist potential relocatees in determining their application and eligibility status.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: </p><p>Manual: Letter files.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Indexed by name of individual, retrieved by manual search.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with 43 CFR 2.51.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records will be disposed of when the Commission is discharged pursuant to 25 U.S.C. 640d-11(i).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Director, Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission, 2717 North Steves Boulevard, Building A, Flagstaff, Arizona 86001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>To determine whether records in this system are maintained on an individual, the individual must contact the System Manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>For access to an individual?s records, the individual must contact the System Manager and describe as specifically as possible the records sought and, if copies are desired, indicate the maximum copy fee the individual is willing to pay.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>A petition for amendment shall be addressed to the System Manager and must meet the requirements of 43 CFR 2.71.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Information obtained from individuals who apply for relocation benefits.
</p><p>(2) Information obtained from other United States governmental agencies concerning individuals who may or may not be entitled to relocation benefits.
</p><p>(3) Information obtained from surveys taken on the Joint Use Area.
</p><p>(4) Information obtained from the Navajo Tribe or the Hopi Tribe concerning its members entitled to relocation benefits.
</p><p>(5) Information obtained from Chapter Officials of the Navajo Tribe concerning members of their chapter who may be entitled to relocation benefits.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    
    
<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="25">
<heading>Indians</heading>
<regulationsChapter number="IV">
<heading> COMMISSION OPERATIONS AND RELOCATION PROCEDURES </heading>
<regulationsPart number="700">
<heading>xx</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart K--Privacy Act
</b></p>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>700.255 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>700.257 Definitions.
</p>
<p>700.259 Records subject to Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>700.261 Standards for maintenance of records subject to the Act.
</p>
<p>700.263 Assuring integrity of records.
</p>
<p>700.265 Conduct of employees.
</p>
<p>700.267 Disclosure of records.
</p>
<p>700.269 Accounting for disclosures.
</p>
<p>700.271 Requests for notification of existence of records: Submission.
</p>
<p>700.273 Request for notification of existence of records: Action on.
</p>
<p>700.275 Requests for access to records.
</p>
<p>700.277 Requests for access to records: Submission.
</p>
<p>700.279 Requests for access to records: Initial decision.
</p>
<p>700.281 Requests for notification of existence of records and for access to records: Appeals.
</p>
<p>700.283 Requests for access to records: Special situations.
</p>
<p>700.285 Amendment of records.
</p>
<p>700.287 Petitions for amendment: Submission and form.
</p>
<p>700.289 Petitions for amendment: Processing and initial decision.
</p>
<p>700.291 Petitions for amendment: Time limits for processing.
</p>
<p>700.293 Petitions for amendment: Appeals.
</p>
<p>700.295 Petitions for amendment: Action on appeals.
</p>
<p>700.297 Statements of disagreement.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Pub. L. 99-590; Pub. L. 93-531, 88 Stat. 1712 as amended by Pub. L. 96-305, 94 Stat. 929, Pub. L. 100-666, 102 Stat. 3929 (25 U.S.C. 640d).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 47 FR 2092, Jan. 14, 1982, unless otherwise noted.</p>
<p><b>Subpart K--Privacy Act
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.255 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>This subpart contains the regulations of the Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission implementing section 3 of the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.257
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Act.</i> As used in this subpart, "Act" means section 3 of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Individual.</i> As used in this subpart, "individual" means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Maintain.</i> As used in this subpart, the term "maintain" includes maintain, collect, use or disseminate.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Record.</i> As used in this subpart, "record" means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by the Commission including, but not limited to, education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history and that contains the individual?s name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print, or a photograph.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>System of records.</i> As used in this subpart, "System of records" means a group of any records under the control of the Commission from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Medical records.</i> As used in this subpart, "medical records" means records which relate to the identification, prevention, cure or alleviation of any disease, illness or injury including psychological disorders, alcoholism and drug addiction.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Civil Service Commission personnel records.</i> As used in this subpart, "Civil Service Commission personnel records" means records maintained for the Civil Service Commission by the Commission and used for personnel management programs or processes such as staffing, employee development, retirement, and grievances and appeals.
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Statistical records.</i> As used in this subpart, "statistical records" means records in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual.
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Routine use.</i> As used in this subpart, "routine use" means a use of a record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p>
<p>(j) <i>System notice.</i> As used in this subpart, "system notice" means the notice describing a system of records required by 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4) to be published annually in the <i>Federal Register.</i>
</p>
<p>(k) <i>System manager.</i> As used in this subpart, "system manager" means the official designated in a system notice as having administrative responsibility for a system of records.
</p>
<p>(l) <i>Commission Privacy Act Officer.</i> As used in the subpart, "Commission Privacy Act Officer" means the official in the Commission charged with responsibility for assisting the Commission in carrying out the functions which he is assigned in this subpart and for coordinating the activities of the divisions of the Commission in carrying out the functions which they are assigned in this subpart.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.259
 Records subject to Privacy Act.
</b></p>
<p>The Privacy Act applies to all "records" as that term is defined in &#167; 700.257(d), which the Commission maintains in a "system of records," as that term is defined in &#167; 700.257(e).
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.261
 Standards for maintenance of records subject to the Act.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Content of records.</i> Records subject to the Privacy Act shall contain only such information about an individual as is relevant and necessary to accomplish a purpose of the agency required to be accomplished by statute or Executive Order of the President.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Standards of accuracy.</i> Records subject to the Privacy Act which are used in making any determination about any individual shall be maintained with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to assure fairness to the individual in making the determination.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Collection of information.</i> (1) Information which may be used in making determination about an individual?s rights, benefits, and privileges under Federal programs shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be collected directly from that individual.
</p>
<p>(2) In deciding whether collection of information from an individual, as opposed to a third party source, is practicable, the following factors, among others may be considered:
</p>
<p>(i) Whether the nature of the information sought is such that it can only be obtained from a third party;
</p>
<p>(ii) Whether the cost of collecting the information from the individual is unreasonable when compared with the cost of collecting it from a third party;
</p>
<p>(iii) Whether there is a risk that information collected from third parties if inaccurate, could result in an adverse determination to the individual concerned;
</p>
<p>(iv) Whether the information, if supplied by the individual, would have to be verified by a third party; or
</p>
<p>(v) Whether provisions can be made for verification, by the individual, of information collected from third parties.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Advice to individual concerning uses of information.</i> (1) Each individual who is asked to supply information about himself which will be added to a system of records shall be informed of the basis for requesting the information, how it may be used, and what the consequences, if any, are of not supplying the information.
</p>
<p>(2) At a minimum, the notice to the individual must state;
</p>
<p>(i) The authority (whether granted by statute or Executive Order of the President) which authorizes the solicitation of the information and whether disclosure of such information is mandatory or voluntary;
</p>
<p>(ii) The principal purpose or purposes for which the information is intended to be used;
</p>
<p>(iii) The routine uses which may be made of the information; and
</p>
<p>(iv) The effects on him, if any, of not providing all or any part of the requested information.
</p>
<p>(3)(i) When information is collected on a standard form, the notice to the individual shall be on the form or on a tear-off sheet attached to the form or on a separate sheet, whichever is most practical.
</p>
<p>(ii) When information is collected by an interviewer, the interviewer shall provide the individual with a written notice which the individual may retain. If the interview is conducted by telephone, however, the interviewer may summarize the notice for the individual and need not provide a copy to the individual unless the individual requests that a copy be mailed to him.
</p>
<p>(iii) An individual may be asked to acknowledge, in writing, that he has been afforded the notice required by this section.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Records concerning activity protected by the First Amendment.</i> No record may be maintained describing how any individual exercises rights guaranteed by the First Amendment to the Constitution unless (1) expressly authorized by statute or by the individual about whom the record is maintained or (2) pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized law enforcement activity.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.263
 Assuring integrity of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Statutory requirement.</i> The Privacy Act requires that records subject to the Act be maintained with appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to insure the security and confidentiality of records and to protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to their security or integrity which could result in substantial harm, embarassment, inconvenience, or unfairness to any individual on whom information is maintained, 5 U.S.C. 522a(e)(10).
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Records maintained in manual form.</i> When maintained in manual form, records subject to the Privacy Act shall be maintained, at a minimum, subject to the following safeguards, or safeguards affording comparable protection:
</p>
<p>(1) Areas in which the records are maintained or regularly used shall be posted with an appropriate warning stating that access to the records is limited to authorized persons. The warning shall also summarize the requirements of &#167; 700.265 and state that the Privacy Act contains a criminal penalty for the unauthorized disclosure of records to which it applies.
</p>
<p>(2) During working hours, (i) the area in which the records are maintained or regularly used shall be occupied by authorized personnel or (ii) access to the records shall be restricted by their storage in locked metal file cabinets or a locked room.
</p>
<p>(3) During non-working hours, access to the records shall be restricted by their storage in locked metal file cabinets or a locked room.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Records maintained in computerized form.</i> When maintained in computerized form, records subject to the Privacy Act shall be maintained, at a minimum, subject to safeguards based on those recommended in the National Bureau of Standards booklet "Computer Security Guidelines for Implementing the Privacy Act of 1974" (May 30, 1975), and any supplements thereto, which are adequate and appropriate to assuring the integrity of records in the system.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Civil Service Commission personnel records.</i> A system of records made up of Civil Service Commission personnel records shall be maintained under the security requirements set out in 5 CFR 293.108.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.265
 Conduct of employees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Handling of records subject to the Act.</i> Employees whose duties require handling of records subject to the Privacy Act shall, at all times, take care to protect the integrity, security and confidentiality of these records.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Disclosure of records.</i> No employee of the Commission may disclose records subject to the Privacy Act unless disclosure is permitted under &#167; 700.267 or is to the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Alteration of records.</i> No employee of the Commission may alter or destroy a record subject to the Privacy Act unless (1) such alteration or destruction is properly undertaken in the course of the employee?s regular duties or (2) such alteration or destruction is required by a decision under &#167;&#167; 700.287-700.295 or the decision of a court of competent jurisdiction.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.267
 Disclosure of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Prohibition of disclosure.</i> No record contained in a system of records may be disclosed by any means of communication to any person, or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>General exceptions.</i> The prohibition contained in paragraph (a) of this section does not apply where disclosure of the record would be:
</p>
<p>(1) To those officers or employees of the Commission who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties; or
</p>
<p>(2) Required by the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 522.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Specific exceptions.</i> The prohibition contained in paragraph (a) does not apply where disclosure of the record would be:
</p>
<p>(1) For a routine use as defined in &#167; 700.257(i) which has been described in a systems notice published in the <i>Federal Register;</i>
</p>
<p>(2) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity pursuant to the provisions of title 13 U.S. Code.
</p>
<p>(3) To a recipient who has provided the System Manager responsible for the system in which the record is maintained with advance adequate written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable;
</p>
<p>(4) To the National Archives of the United States as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the U.S. Government, or for evaluation by the Administrator of General Services or his designee to determine whether the record has such value;
</p>
<p>(5) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity if the activity is authorized by law, and if the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a written request to the Department specifying the particular portion desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought;
</p>
<p>(6) To a person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual if upon such disclosure notification is transmitted to the last known address of such individual;
</p>
<p>(7) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee;
</p>
<p>(8) To the Comptroller General, or any of his authorized representatives, in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office; or
</p>
<p>(9) Pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Reviewing records prior to disclosure.</i> (1) Prior to any disclosure of a record about an individual, unless disclosure is required by the Freedom of Information Act, reasonable efforts shall be made to assure that the records are accurate, complete, timely and relevant for agency purposes.
</p>
<p>(2) When a record is disclosed in connection with a Freedom of Information request made under subpart B of this part and it is appropriate and administratively feasible to do so, the requester shall be informed of any information known to the Commission indicating that the record may not be fully accurate, complete, or timely.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.269
 Accounting for disclosures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Maintenance of an accounting.</i> (1) Where a record is disclosed to any person, or to another agency, under any of the specific exceptions provided by &#167; 700.267(c), an accounting shall be made.
</p>
<p>(2) The accounting shall record (i) the date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure of a record to any person or to another agency and (ii) the name and address of the person or agency to whom the disclosure was made.
</p>
<p>(3) Accountings prepared under this section shall be maintained for at least five years or the life of the record, whichever is longer, after the disclosure for which the accounting is made.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Access to accountings.</i> (1) Except for accountings of disclosures made under &#167; 700.267(c)(5), accountings of all disclosures of a record shall be made available to the individual to whom the record relates at his request.
</p>
<p>(2) An individual desiring access to accountings of disclosures of a record pertaining to him shall submit his request by following the procedures of &#167; 700.277.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Notification of disclosure.</i> When a record is disclosed pursuant to &#167; 700.267(c)(9) as the result of the order of a court of competent juridiction, reasonable efforts shall be made to notify the individual to whom the record pertains as soon as the order becomes a matter of public record.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.271
 Requests for notification of existence of records: Submission.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Submission of requests.</i> (1)(i) An individual desiring to determine under the Privacy Act whether a system of records contains records pertaining to him shall address his inquiry to the system manager having responsibility for the system unless the system notice describing the system prescribes or permits submission to some other official or officials.
</p>
<p>(ii) If a system notice describing a system requires that an individual contact more than two officials concerning the existence of records in the system, an individual desiring to determine whether the system contains records pertaining to him may contact the system manager for assistance in determining which official is most likely to be in possession of records pertaining to that individual.
</p>
<p>(2) If an individual desires to determine whether records pertaining to him are maintained in two or more systems, he shall make a separate inquiry concerning each system.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Form of request.</i> (1) An inquiry to determine whether a system of records contains records pertaining to an individual shall be in writing.
</p>
<p>(2) To insure expeditious handling, the request shall be prominently marked, both on the envelope and on the face of the request, with the legend "PRIVACY ACT INQUIRY."
</p>
<p>(3) The request shall state that the individual is seeking information concerning records pertaining to himself and shall supply such additional identifying information, if any, as is called for in the system notice describing the system.
</p>
<p>(4) If an individual has reason to believe that information pertaining to him or her may be filed under a name other than the name he or she is currently using (e.g., a maiden name), he or she shall include this information in the request.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.273
 Request for notification of existence of records: Action on.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Decisions on request.</i> (1) An individual inquiring to determine whether a system of records contains records pertaining to him shall be advised within ten (10) days (excepting Saturdays, Sundays and legal public holidays) whether or not the system does contain records pertaining to him unless (i) the records were compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding or (ii) the system of records is one which has been excepted from the notification provisions of the Privacy Act by rulemaking.
</p>
<p>(2) If the records were compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding or the system of records is one which has been excepted from the notification provisions of the Privacy Act by rulemaking, the individual will be promptly notified that his is not entitled to notification of whether the system contains records pertaining to him.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Authority to deny requests.</i> A decision to deny a request for notification of the existence of records shall be made by the Privacy Act Officer.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Form of decision.</i> (1) No particular form is required for a decision informing an individual whether or not a system of records contains records pertaining to him.
</p>
<p>(2) A decision declining to inform an individual whether or not a system of records contains records pertaining to him shall be in writing and shall state the basis for denial of the request and shall advise the individual that he may appeal the declination to the Executive Director pursuant to &#167; 700.285 by writing to the Privacy Act Officer, Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission, P.O. Box KK, Flagstaff, Arizona 86002, and that the appeal must be received by this official within twenty (20) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) of the date of the decision.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.275
 Requests for access to records.
</b></p>
<p>The Privacy Act permits an individual, upon his request, to gain access to his record or to any information pertaining to him which is contained in a system and to review the record and have a copy made of all or any portion thereof in a form comprehensive to him, 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(1). A request for access shall be submitted in accordance with the procedures in this subpart.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.277
 Requests for access to records: Submission.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Submission of requests.</i> (1) Requests for access to records shall be submitted to the system manager having responsibility for the system in which the records are maintained unless the system notice describing the system prescribes or permits submission to some other official or officials.
</p>
<p>(2) If an individual desires access to records maintained in two or more separate systems, he shall submit a separate request for access to the records in each system.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Form of request.</i> (1) A request for access to records subject to the Privacy Act shall be in writing.
</p>
<p>(2) To insure expeditious handling, the request shall be prominently marked, both on the envelope and on the face of the request, with the legend "PRIVACY ACT REQUEST FOR ACCESS."
</p>
<p>(3) The request shall specify whether the requester seeks all of the records contained in the system which relate to him or only some portion thereof. If the requester seeks only a portion of the records which relate to him, the request shall reasonably describe the specific records sought.
</p>
<p>(4) If the requester seeks to have copies of the requested records made, the request shall state the maximum amount of copying fees which the requester is willing to pay. A request which does not state the amount of fees the requester is willing to pay will be treated as a request to inspect the requested records. Requesters are further notified that under &#167; 700.279(d) the failure to state willingness to pay fees as high as are anticipated by the Commission will delay processing of a request.
</p>
<p>(5) The request shall supply such identifying information, if any, as is called for in the system notice describing the system.
</p>
<p>(6) Requests failing to meet the requirements of this paragraph shall be returned to the requester with a written notice advising the request of the deficiency in the request.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.279
 Requests for access to records: Initial decision.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Decisions on requests.</i> A request made under this subpart for access to a record shall be granted promptly unless (1) the record was compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding or (2) the record is contained in a system of records which has been excepted from the access provisions of the Privacy Act by rulemaking.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Authority to deny requests.</i> A decision to deny a request for access under this subpart shall be made by the Privacy Act Officer.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Form of decision.</i> (1) No particular form is required for a decision granting access to a record. The decision shall, however, advise the individual requesting the record as to where and when the record is available for inspection or, as the case may be, where and when copies will be available. If fees are due under &#167; 700.279(d), the individual requesting the record shall also be notified of the amount of fees due or, if the exact amount has not been determined, the approximate amount of fees due.
</p>
<p>(2) A decision denying a request for access, in whole or part, shall be in writing and shall state the basis for denial of the request. The decision shall also contain a statement that the denial may be appealed to the Executive Director pursuant to &#167; 700.281 by writing to Privacy Act Officer, Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission, P.O. Box KK, Flagstaff, Arizona 86002, and that the appeal must be received by this official within twenty (20) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) of the date of the decision.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Fees.</i> (1) No fees may be charged for the cost of searching for or reviewing a record in response to a request made under &#167; 700.271.
</p>
<p>(2) Fees for copying a record in response to a request made under &#167; 700.271 shall be charged in accordance with the schedule of charges contained in the Commission?s Management Manual, unless the official responsible for processing the request determines that, in his/her opinion, reduction or waiver of fees is appropriate.
</p>
<p>(3) Where it is anticipated that fees chargeable in connection with a request will exceed the amount the person submitting the request has indicated he/she is willing to pay, the official processing the request shall notify the requester and shall not complete processing of the request until the requester has agreed, in writing, to pay fees as high as are anticipated.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.281
 Requests for notification of existence of records and for access to records: Appeals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Right of appeal.</i> If an individual has been notified that he/she is not entitled to notification of whether a system of records contains records pertaining to him or has been denied access, in whole or part, to a requested record that individual may appeal to the Executive Director.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Time for appeal.</i> (1) An appeal must be received by the Privacy Act Officer no later than twenty (20) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) after the date of the initial decision on a request.
</p>
<p>(2) The Executive Director may, for good cause shown, extend the time for submission of an appeal if a written request for additional time is received within twenty (20) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) of the date of the initial decision of the request.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Form of appeal.</i> (1) An appeal shall be in writing and shall attach copies of the initial request and the decision on the request.
</p>
<p>(2) The appeal shall contain a brief statement of the reasons why the appellant believes the decision on the initial request to have been in error.
</p>
<p>(3) The appeal shall be addressed to Privacy Act Officer, Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission, Box KK, Flagstaff, Arizona 86002.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Action on appeals.</i> (1) Appeals from decisions on initial requests made pursuant to &#167;&#167; 700.273 and 700.277 shall be decided for the Commission by the Executive Director after consultation with the Commission?s legal counsel.
</p>
<p>(2) The decision on an appeal shall be in writing and shall state the basis for the decision.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.283
 Requests for access to records: Special situations.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Medical records.</i> (1) Medical records shall be disclosed to the individual to whom they pertain unless it is determined, in consultation with a medical doctor, that disclosure should be made to a medical doctor of the individual?s choosing.
</p>
<p>(2) If it is determined that disclosure of medical records directly to the individual to whom they pertain could have an adverse effect on that individual, the individual may designate a medical doctor to receive the records and the records will be disclosed to that doctor.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Inspection in presence of third party.</i> (1) An individual wishing to inspect records pertaining to him which have been opened for his inspection may, during the inspection, be accompanied by a person of his own choosing.
</p>
<p>(2) When such a procedure is deemed appropriate, the individual to whom the records pertain may be required to furnish a written statement authorizing discussion of his record in the accompanying person?s presence.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.285
 Amendment of records.
</b></p>
<p>The Privacy Act permits an individual to request amendment of a record pertaining to him if be believes the record is not accurate, relevant, timely or complete, 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(2). A request for amendment of a record shall be submitted in accordance with the procedures in this subpart.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.287
 Petitions for amendment: Submission and form.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Submission of petitions for amendment.</i> (1) A request for amendment of a record shall be submitted to the system manager for the system of records containing the record unless the system notice describing the system prescribes or permits submission to a different official or officials. If an individual wishes to request amendment of records located in more than one system, a separate petition must be submitted to each system manager.
</p>
<p>(2) A petition for amendment of a record may be submitted only if the individual submitting the petition has previously requested and been granted access to the record and has inspected or been given a copy of the record.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Form of petition.</i> (1) A petition for amendment shall be in writing and shall specifically identify the record whose amendment is sought.
</p>
<p>(2) The petition shall state, in detail, the reasons why the petitioner believes the record, or the portion thereof objectionable to him, is not accurate, relevant, timely or complete. Copies of documents or evidence relied upon in support of these reasons shall be submitted with the petition.
</p>
<p>(3) The petition shall state, specifically and in detail, the changes sought in the record. If the changes involve rewriting of the record or portions thereof or involve adding new language to the record, the petition shall propose specific language to implement the changes.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.289
 Petitions for amendment: Processing and initial decision.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Decisions on petitions.</i> In reviewing a record in response to a petition for amendment, the accuracy, relevance, timeliness and completeness of the record shall be assessed against the criteria set out in &#167; 700.261. In addition, personnel records shall be assessed against the criteria for determining record quality published in the Federal Personnel Manual and the Commission Manual addition thereto.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Authority to decide.</i> An initial decision on a petition for amendment may be made only by the Privacy Act Officer.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Acknowledgement of receipt.</i> Unless processing of a petition is completed within ten (10) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted), the receipt of the petition for amendment shall be acknowledged in writing by the system manager to whom it is directed.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Inadequate petitions.</i> (1) If a petition does not meet the requirements of &#167; 700.287, the petitioner shall be so advised and shall be told what additional information must be submitted to meet the requirements of &#167; 700.287.
</p>
<p>(2) If the petitioner fails to submit the additional information within a reasonable time, his petition may be rejected. The rejection shall be in writing and shall meet the requirements of paragraph (e) of this section.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Form of decision.</i> (1) A decision on a petition for amendment shall be in writing and shall state concisely the basis for the decision.
</p>
<p>(2) If the petitioned for amendment is rejected, in whole or part, the decision shall advise the petitioner that the rejection may be appealed to the Executive Director by writing to the Privacy Act Officer, Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission, Box KK, Flagstaff, Arizona 86002, and that the appeal must be received by this official within twenty (20) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) of the date of the decision.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Implementation of initial decision.</i> If a petitioned for amendment is accepted, in whole or part, the appropriate Commission Division maintaining the record shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Correct the record accordingly and,
</p>
<p>(2) Where an accounting of disclosures has been made pursuant to &#167; 700.269 advise all previous recipients of the record that the correction was made and the substance of the correction.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.291
 Petitions for amendment: Time limits for processing.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Acknowledgement of receipt.</i> The acknowledgement of receipt of a petition required by &#167; 700.289(c) shall be dispatched not later than ten (10) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) after receipt of the petition by the system manager responsible for the system containing the challenged record, unless a decision on the petition has been previously dispatched.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Decision on petition.</i> A petition for amendment shall be processed promptly. A determination whether to accept or reject the petitioned for amendment shall be made within no more than thirty (30) days (Saturdays, Sundays, and public legal holidays excepted) after receipt of the petition by the system manager responsible for the system containing the challenged record.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Suspension of time limit.</i> The thirty (30) day time limit for a decision on a petition shall be suspended if it is necessary to notify the petitioner, pursuant to &#167; 700.289(d) that additional information in support of the petition is required. Running of the thirty (30) day time limit shall resume on receipt of the additional information by the system manager responsible for the system containing the challenged record.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Extensions of time.</i> (1) The thirty (30) day time limit for a decision on a petition may be extended if the official responsible for making a decision on the petition determines that an extension is necessary for one of the following reasons:
</p>
<p>(i) A decision on the petition requires analysis of voluminous record or records;
</p>
<p>(ii) Some or all of the challenged records must be collected from facilities other than the facility at which the official responsible for making the decision is located.
</p>
<p>(2) If the official responsible for making a decision on the petition determines that an extension is necessary, he shall promptly inform the petitioner of the extension and the date on which a decision is expected to be dispatched.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.293
 Petitions for amendment: Appeals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Right of appeal.</i> Where a petitioned-for amendment has been rejected, in whole or part, the individual submitting the petition may appeal the denial to the Executive Director.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Time for appeal.</i> (1) An appeal must be received no later than twenty (20) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) after the date of the decision on a petition.
</p>
<p>(2) The Executive Director may, for good cause shown, extend the time for submission of an appeal if a written request for additional time is received within twenty (20) days (Saturdays, Sundays and public legal holidays excepted) of the date of the decision on a petition.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Form of appeal.</i> (1) An appeal shall be in writing and shall attach copies of the initial petition and the decision on that petition.
</p>
<p>(2) The appeal shall contain a brief statement of the reasons why the appellant believes the decision on the petition to have been in error.
</p>
<p>(3) The appeal shall be addressed to Privacy Act Officer, Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission, Box KK, Flagstaff, Arizona 86002.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.295
 Petitions for amendment: Action on appeals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Authority.</i> Appeals from decisions on initial petitions for amendment shall be decided for the Commission by the Executive Director after consultation with the Commission?s legal counsel unless the record challenged by the initial petition is a Civil Service Commission personnel record maintained for the Commission by the Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission. Appeals from decisions on initial petitions requesting amendment of Civil Service Commission records maintained for the Commission by the Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission shall be transmitted by the Executive Director, for decision.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Time limit.</i> (1) A final determination on any appeal shall be made within thirty (30) days (Saturdays, Sundays and legal public holidays excepted) after receipt of the appeal.
</p>
<p>(2) The thirty (30) day period for decision on an appeal may be extended, for good cause shown, by the Commission. If the thirty (30) day period is extended, the individual submitting the appeal shall be notified of the extension and of the date on which a determination on the appeal is expected to be dispatched.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Form of decision.</i> (1) The final determination on an appeal shall be in writing and shall state the basis for the determination.
</p>
<p>(2) If the determination upholds, in whole or part, the initial decision rejecting the petitioned for amendment, the determination shall also advise the individual submitting the appeal:
</p>
<p>(i) Of his or her right to file a concise statement of the reasons for disagreeing with the decision of the agency;
</p>
<p>(ii) Of the procedure established by &#167; 700.297 for the filing of the statement of disagreement;
</p>
<p>(iii) That the statement which is filed will be made available to anyone to whom the record is subsequently disclosed together with, at the discretion of the Commission, a brief statement by the Commission summarizing its reasons for refusing to amend the record;
</p>
<p>(iv) That prior recipients of the challenged record will be provided a copy of any statement of dispute to the extent that an accounting of disclosure was maintained; and
</p>
<p>(v) Of his or her right to seek judicial review of the Commission?s refusal to amend the record.
</p>
<p>(3) If the determination reverses, in whole or in part, the initial decision rejecting the petitioned for amendment, the system manager responsible for the system containing the challenged record shall be directed to:
</p>
<p>(i) Amend the challenged record accordingly; and
</p>
<p>(ii) If an accounting of disclosure has been made, advise all previous recipients of the record which was amended of the amendment and its substance.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 700.297
 Statements of disagreement.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Filing of statements.</i> If the determination of the Executive Director under &#167; 700.295 rejects in whole or part, a petitioned for amendment, the individual submitting the petition may file with the system manager for the system containing the challenged record, a concise written statement setting forth the reasons for his disagreement with the determination of the Department.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Disclosure of statements.</i> In any disclosure of a record containing information about which an individual has filed a statement of disagreement under this section occurring after the filing of the statement, the disputed portion of the record will be clearly noted and the recipient shall be provided copies of the statement of disagreement. If appropriate, a concise statement of the reasons of the Commission for not making the requested amendments may also be provided to recipient.
</p>

</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
