<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>National Aeronautics and Space Administration</name>
<abbrev>
NASA
</abbrev>
    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-12-09/pdf/2020-27051.pdf</url>
        <title>Health Information Management System, NASA 10HIMS</title>
        <date year="20" month="12" day="9" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-15/pdf/2021-24867.pdf</url>
        <title>Reasonable Accommodation (RA) Records, NASA 10RAR</title>
        <date year="21" month="11" day="15" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-14/pdf/2021-27040.pdf.</url>
        <title>Locator and Information Services Tracking System (LISTS), GSFC 51LISTS; Rescindment</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="14" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-14/pdf/2021-27041.pdf</url>
        <title>Health Information Management System, NASA 10HIMS.</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="14" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-14/pdf/2021-27042.pdf</url>
        <title>Security Records System, NASA 10SECR.</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="14" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-16/pdf/2021-27176.pdf</url>
        <title>Equal Opportunity (EO) Records, NASA 10EEOR; Rescindment.</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>


    <section id="10acmq" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 ACMQ</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Aircraft Crewmembers' Qualifications and Performance Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Locations 1 through 11 inclusive as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on Crewmembers of NASA aircraft.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This System contains: (1) Records of experience, and currency (e.g., flight hours day, night, and instrument), types of approaches and landings, crew position, type of aircraft, flight check ratings and related examination results, and training performed; and (2) flight itineraries and passenger manifests.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a) and 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used to document flight crew experience and currency as well as itineraries and passenger manifests in case of accidents or requests.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. Records from this system may be disclosed: (1) to this system of records may be granted to Federal, State, or local agencies or to foreign governments in cases of accident investigations, including mishap and collateral investigations; (2) to Federal, State, or local agencies, companies, or governments requesting qualifications of crewmembers prior to authorization to participate in their flight programs, or to Federal, State, or local agencies, companies, or governments whose crewmembers may participate in NASA's flight programs; (3) to the public or in press releases either by prior approval of the individual, or in the case of public release of information from mishap or collateral investigation reports, pursuant to NASA regulations at 14 CFR part 1213; and (4) in accordance with NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained as hard-copy documents and on electronic media.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved from the system by aircrew identifier.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or locked file cabinets.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records for other than astronauts are maintained in Agency files and destroyed 5 years after crewmember separates from NASA in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS), Schedule 8 Item 32.  Records of crewmembers who are astronauts are permanent and will be transferred to the National Archives in accordance with NRRS, Schedule 8 Item 34.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Director, Aircraft Management Office, Location 1.</p>
<p>Subsystem Managers: Deputy Chief, Flight Control and Cockpit Integration Branch, Location 2; Chief, Dryden Research Aircraft Operations Division, Location 3; Head, Aeronautical Programs Branch, Location 4; Chief, Aircraft Operations Division, Location 5; Chief, Aircraft Operations Office, Location 6; Chief, Flight Operations and Engineering Branch, Location 7; Chief, Aircraft Operations Office, Location 8; Chief, Aircraft Operations, Location 9; Chief, Contract Management, Location 10; Aircraft Management Officer, Location 11 (Locations are set forth in Appendix A).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information may be obtained from the cognizant system or subsystem manager listed above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the same address as stated in the Notification section above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations for requesting amendments to records and contesting record contents appear at 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals, training schools or instructors, medical units or doctors.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="nasa10acsr" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 ACSR</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Astronaut Candidate Selection Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification">
    <xhtmlContent>
        <p>None.</p>
    </xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Location 5, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on persons who have applied to the agency for consideration as candidates for and recipients of training associated with NASA Astronaut and Human Space Flight Programs.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system include identifying information for the individuals in employment applications and resumes and records of specialized training, honors and awards.  The system also contains relevant human resource correspondence, records an individual"s qualifications for participation in a specialized program, evaluations of candidates, and final NASA determinations of candidates" qualification for the program.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used by NASA to facilitate processes and procedures associated with the recruitment, evaluation, and selection of United States astronaut candidates, as defined in 14 CFR 1214, Subpart 1214.11 (NASA Astronaut Candidate Recruitment and Selection Program).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>NASA standard routine uses, as set forth in Appendix B.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Stored on a secure server as electronic records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved from the system by any one or a combination of name, Discipline Area, or unique identification number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained within a secure, electronic database and protected in accordance with the requirements and procedures of FISMA, the NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605, NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 2810.1A, NASA ITS-HBK-2810.02-05, and, utilizing database servers with self-encrypting "data-at-rest" technologies, located in secured, monitored, restricted access rooms.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  An approved security plan for this system has been established in accordance with OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only key authorized employees with appropriately configured system roles can access the system through approved authentication methods, and only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure VPN connection that requires two-factor authentication. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained and transferred to the National Archives in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 8, Item 35.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Astronaut Candidate Program Manager, Location 5, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals interested in inquiring about their records should notify the System Manager at the address given above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing to the system manager.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations pertaining to access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by individual concerned are set forth in 14 CFR 1212.4.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Civil servant application information is received by the NASA Astronaut Candidate Selection System from applicants themselves via an electronic interface with the NASA Enterprise Application Competency Center (NEACC) that receives a portion of all records from the USAJobs.gov website, operated by the United States Office of Personnel Management (OPM), and into which applicants enter their own application data.  Candidate Qualification input is received directly from individuals used as references who have direct knowledge of applicant capabilities.  In certain circumstances, updates to this information may be submitted by the individual on whom the record is maintained and/or the NASA Personnel Office(s).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>


<section id="10brpa" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10BRPA</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Biographical Records for Public Affairs.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Locations 1, 3 through 9 inclusive, and Locations 11 and 18, as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system maintains information on principal and prominent management and staff officials,
program and project managers, scientists, engineers, speakers, other selected employees involved in
newsworthy activities, and other participants in Agency programs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Current biographical information about the individuals with a recent photograph when
available. Data items are those generally required by NASA or the news media in preparing news or
feature stories about the individual and/or the individual"s activity with NASA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>42 U.S.C. 2473 and 44 U.S.C. 3101.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The information contained in this system of records is compiled, updated, and maintained at
NASA Centers for ready reference material and for immediate availability when required by the news
media for news stories about the individual generally involving participation in a major NASA
activity.
</p><p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected
the information. The following are routine uses: These records are made available via the Internet
to professional societies, civic clubs, industrial and other organizations, news media
representatives, researchers, authors, Congress, other agencies and other members of the public.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained as hard-copy documents and on electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved from the system by individual"s name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Because the records are a matter of public information, no safeguard requirements are
necessary.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed when there is no longer a potential for
public interest in them in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 1, Item 40.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, News Services Division, Office of Public Affairs, Location 1. Subsystem Managers:
Public Affairs Officer at Locations 3 through 9 and Location 11; Manager, Customer Satisfaction and
Communication Office, Location 18; as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to find out if a Biographical System of Records contains a record
pertaining to him/her should call, write, or visit the Public Affairs Office at the appropriate NASA
Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual may request access to his/her record by calling, writing, or visiting the
Public Affairs Office at the appropriate NASA locations. Individuals may examine or obtain a copy of
their biographical record at any time.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The information in the record was provided voluntarily by the individual with the
understanding that the information will be used for public release. The individual is at liberty at
any time to revise, update, add, or delete information in his/her biographical record to his/her own
satisfaction.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in the biography of an individual in the system of records is provided
voluntarily by the individual generally with the aid of a form questionnaire.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="nasa10cfmr" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 CFMR</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Core Financial Management Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system is categorized in accordance with OMB Circular A-11 as a Special Management Attention Major Information System. A security plan for this system has been established in accordance with OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>George C. Marshall Space Flight Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Marshall Space Flight Center, AL 35812</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals covered by this system of records include former and current NASA employees and non-NASA individuals requiring any type of payment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are comprised of budget formulation, financial management, and employee timekeeping records and may include information about the individuals including Social Security Number (Tax Identification Number), home address, telephone number, e mail address, and bank account information.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>National Aeronautics and Space Act, as amended. 51 U.S.C. 20113(a); Federal Records Act, 44 U.S.C. 3101; Chief Financial Officers Act of 1990, 31 U.S.C. 901; Financial Management Improvement Act of 1996, 31 U.S.C. 3512.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used to process reimbursement payments to employees for travel, purchase of books or other miscellaneous items; and to process payments and collections in which an individual is reimbursing the Agency.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. The following are routine uses: (1) Furnish data to the Department of Treasury for financial reimbursement of individual expenses, such as travel, books, and other miscellaneous items; (2) Process payments and collections in which an individual is reimbursing the Agency; (3) Ongoing administration and maintenance of the records, which is performed by authorized NASA employees, both civil servants and contractors; and (4) NASA Standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained on electronic media.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved from the system by name or SSN (Tax ID).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or locked file cabinets.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are stored in the NASA Enterprise Application Competency Center (NEACC) database and managed, retained and dispositioned in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 9, Items 11, 13 and 16.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>IS01/Manager of the NEACC, George C. Marshall Space Flight Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Marshall Space Flight Center, AL 35812</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals interested in inquiring about their records should notify the System Manager at the address given above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing to the System Manager at the address given above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations governing access to records, procedures for contesting the contents and for contesting the contents and for appealing initial determinations are set forth in 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The information is received by the NEACC Financial Systems through an electronic interface from the Federal Personnel Payroll System (FPPS). In certain circumstances, updates to this information may be submitted by NASA employees and recorded directly into the NEACC Financial Systems.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="10euda" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10EDUA</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">NASA Education Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Paper-based records are located in NASA facilities in Locations 1 through 11 as set forth in Appendix A, or at other Agency-designated offices of NASA contractors. Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA and NASA contractor servers in Locations 1 through 11, or at other Agency-designated offices of NASA contractors.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on individuals engaged in the management, planning, implementation, and/or evaluation of NASA Education programs/projects, including former and current NASA civil servants, contractors, grantees, and partners serving as NASA Education program/project managers, primary investigators, project points of contact and volunteers, and session presenters. Information is also maintained on members of the public who apply to, participate in, and/or are supported by NASA Education programs, projects and activities, including students (K-12 and higher education), teachers, higher education faculty, advisors, school administrators, and participants’ parents/legal guardians.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in the system contain identifying information about individuals engaged in NASA Education endeavors.  Records include individuals’ names, mailing addresses, school/institution names and addresses, grades, levels or higher education degree information, contact information, demographic data (e.g. ethnicity, gender, race, citizenship, military status), birth dates, employment status, disabilities, medical and special needs notes, academic records, photographic identifiers, status, and response or feedback to a NASA program/project/activity.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
    <p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.  The records and information in these records may be disclosed: (1) To an individual’s next-of-kin, parent, guardian, or emergency contact in the event of a mishap involving that individual; (2) To the public about an individual’s involvement with NASA Education with the written consent of that individual; or (3) In accordance with NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Some of the records are stored electronically on secure servers; some are stored in paper format in file folders. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records may be retrieved from the system by any one or a combination of choices by authorized users to include last name, identification number, zip code, state, grade, level, and institution.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or locked file cabinets. For information systems maintained by NASA partners, who collect, store and process records on behalf of NASA, NASA requires documentation and verification of commensurate safeguards in accordance with FISMA, NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 2810.1A, and NASA ITS-HBK-2810.02-05.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS), Schedule 1, Item 68.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Evaluation Manager, NASA Office of Education, Location 1 (see Appendix A).  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Contact System Manager by mail at Location 1 (see Appendix A). </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing to the System Manager at the addresses given above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations governing access to records, procedures for contesting the contents and for appealing initial determinations are set forth in 14 CFR part 1212. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The information is obtained directly from individuals on whom it is maintained, and/or from their parents/legal guardians and individuals who serve as recommenders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="nasa10foia" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 FOIA</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">NASA Freedom of Information Act System.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Locations 1-11 and 18, as set forth in Appendix A.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals or their representatives who have submitted Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)/Privacy Act (PA) requests for records and/or FOIA administrative appeals with NASA; individuals whose requests for records have been referred to the Agency by other agencies; individuals who are the subject of such requests, appeals; and/or the NASA personnel assigned to handle such requests and appeals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system consists of records created or compiled in response to FOIA, FOIA/PA or PA requests for records or subsequent administrative appeals and may include: The requester"s name, address, telephone number, email address; the original requests and administrative appeals; responses to such requests and appeals; all related memoranda, correspondence, notes and other related or supporting documentation, and in some instances copies of requested records and records under administrative appeal.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 552; 14 CFR part 1206.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are maintained for the purpose of processing and tracking access requests and administrative appeals under the FOIA and Privacy Act; for the purpose of maintaining a FOIA or Privacy Act administrative record regarding Agency action on such requests and appeals; and for the Agency in carrying out any other responsibilities under the FOIA and Privacy Act. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.  The records and information in these records may be disclosed in accordance with a NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained in paper files; copies may also be maintained in electronic format.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information is retrieved by FOIA case file numbers.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained on a secure NASA server and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, the server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  An approved security plan is in place for the information system containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or files.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with guidelines defined in the NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 1441.1D, NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS), Schedule 1, Item 49.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>System Manager: Principal Agency FOIA Officer, Office of Communications, Location 1, as set forth in Appendix A.  Subsystem Managers: Center FOIA Officers, located within locations 2 " 11 and 18, as set forth in Appendix A.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals interested in inquiring about their records should notify the system manager or subsystem manager at the appropriate NASA Center, as set forth in Appendix A.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals seeking to access their FOIA case file should submit their request in writing to the system manager or subsystem manager at the appropriate NASA Center, as set forth in Appendix A.  The request envelope should be clearly marked, "PRIVACY ACT REQUEST FOR ACCESS."  The request should include a general description of the records sought, FOIA case file number, and must include your full name, current address, and the date.  The request must be signed and either notarized or submitted under penalty of perjury.  The system manager may require a notarized signature.  Some information may be exempt from access in accordance with FOIA regulations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations governing access to records, procedures for contesting the content and for appealing initial determinations are set forth in Title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, Part 1212.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information is collected directly from individuals, or their representatives, making Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act requests.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="10habc" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10HABC</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">History Archives Biographical Collection.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Location 1 and 11 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system maintains information on individuals who are of historical significance in aeronautics, astronautics, space science, and other concerns of NASA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographical data; speeches and articles by an individual; correspondence, interviews, and various other tapes and transcripts of program activities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>51 U.S.C. 20112(a)(3) and 44 U.S.C. 3101.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The following are routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to scholars (historians and other disciplines) or any other interested individuals for research in writing dissertations, articles, and books, for government, commercial, and nonprofit publication or developing material for other media use.
</p><p>2. NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained as hard-copy documents and on electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are retrieved from the system by the individual"s name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Because these records are archive material and, therefore, a matter of public information, there are no special safeguard procedures required.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained indefinitely in Agency reference collections in history offices, but may be destroyed when no longer needed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 1 Item 10.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Archivist, Location 1.
</p><p>Subsystem Manager: Public Affairs Officer, Location 11 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the system manager listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to same address as stated in the Notification section above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear at 14 CFR part 1212.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Press releases, newspapers, journals, copies of internal Agency records, and the individuals themselves.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="10fnms" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10FNMS</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Aeronautics and Space Administration Foreign National Management System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>The centralized data system is located at the Extranet Security Portals Group, 2720
Prosperity Avenue, Suite 30, Fairfax, VA 22031
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system maintains information on all non-U.S. citizens, to include Lawful Permanent
Residents seeking access to NASA facilities, resources, laboratories, contractor sites, Federally
Funded Research and Development Centers or NASA sponsored events for unclassified purposes to
include employees of NASA or NASA contractors; prospective NASA or NASA contractor employees;
employees of other U.S. Government agencies or their contractors; foreign students at U.S.
institutions; officials or other persons employed by foreign governments or other foreign
institutions who may or may not be involved in cooperation with NASA under international agreements;
foreign media representatives; and representatives or agents of foreign national governments seeking
access to NASA facilities, to include high-level protocol visits; or international relations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system include information about the individuals seeking access to NASA
resources. Information about individual may include, but is not limited to: Name, home address,
place of birth and citizenship, U.S. visitor/travel document numbers, employment information, Tax
Identification Numbers (Social Security number), and reason and length of proposed NASA access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Section 304(a) of the National Aeronautics and Space Act, codified at 42 USC &#167; 
2455; Federal Property Management Regulation, 41 CFR Ch. 101; 14 CFR parts 1203 through 1203b; 14
CFR 1213; 15 CFR 744; 22 CFR 62; 22 CFR 120-130; 40 USC 1441, and 44 U.S.C. 3101, and
Executive Order 9397.
</p><p>Purpose(s):
</p><p>Records are maintained and used by NASA to document, track, manage, analyze, and/or report
on foreign visit and assignment access to NASA facilities including Headquarters, Field Offices,
National Laboratories, Federally Funded Research and Development Centers, Contractor Sites,
components facilities (NASA Management Office, Wallops Flight Facility, White Sands Test Facility,
White Sands Complex, Independent Validation &amp; Verification Facility, Michoud Assembly Center,
Moffett Federal Airfield, Goldstone Deep Space Communications Complex, Goddard Institute for Space
Studies, National Scientific Balloon Facility, Plum Brook Station).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency
collected the information.
</p><p>1. A record from this system may be disclosed to authorized contractors who are responsible for
NASA security and who require this information to perform their contractual obligations to NASA.
</p><p>2. A record from this system may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, participants in
cooperative agreements, collaborating researchers, or their employees, if required for the
performance of their responsibilities with respect to national security, international visit and
assignment, or foreign access.
</p><p>3. A record from this system may be disclosed to a member of Congress submitting a request
involving a constituent when the constituent has requested assistance from the member with respect
to the subject matter of his or her own record. The member of Congress must provide a copy of the
constituent"s request for assistance.
</p><p>4. A record from this system may be disclosed to foreign governments or international
organizations if required by treaties, international conventions, or executive agreements.
</p><p>5. A record from this system may be disclosed to members of a NASA Advisory Committee or
Committees and interagency boards charged with responsibilities pertaining to international visits
and assignments and/or national security when authorized by the individual or to the extent the
committee(s) is so authorized and such disclosure is required by law.
</p><p>6. A record from this system may be disclosed to Federal intelligence organizations, when
required by applicable law.
</p><p>7. A record from this system may be disclosed to Federal agencies for the purpose of determining
preliminary visa eligibility when authorized by the individual or as required by law.
</p><p>8. A record from this system may be disclosed to respond to White House inquiries when required
by law.
</p><p>9. A record from this system may be disclosed to a NASA contractor, subcontractor, grantee, or
other Government organization involved in an investigation or administrative inquiry concerning a
violation of a Federal or State statute or NASA regulation on the part of an officer or employee of
the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, or other Government organization, when and to the extent the
information is required by law.
</p><p>10. A record from this system may be disclosed to an internal or external organization or element
thereof, conducting audit activities of a NASA contractor or subcontractor to the extent required by
law.
</p><p>11. A record from this system may be disclosed to provide personal identifying data to Federal,
State, local, or foreign law enforcement representatives seeking confirmation of identity of persons
under investigation, to the extent necessary and required by law.
</p><p>12. NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system will be stored in electronic format.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name and other personal identifiers. Records are indexed by
individual"s name, file number, badge number, decal number, payroll number, passport or visa
numbers, and/or Social Security Number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>An approved security plan for this system has been established in accordance with OMB
Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources. Individuals will have access to
the system only when and to the extent such access is legally authorized, each item of information
is required for his or her job, and the access is in accordance with approved authentication
methods. Only key authorized employees with appropriately configured system roles can access the
system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in the Foreign National Management System and managed, retained and
dispositioned in accordance with the guidelines defined in NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR)
1441.1D, NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 1, item 35.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Identity and Systems Management Division, Office of Protective Services, Location
1, as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals inquiring about their records should notify the System Manager at the address
given above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing
to the System Manager at the address given above. Requests must contain the following identifying
data concerning the requestor: First, middle, and last name; date and place of birth;
Visa/Passport/Social Security Number; period and place of visit/assignment/employment with NASA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The NASA regulations governing access to records and the procedures for contesting the
contents and appealing initial determinations are set forth in 14 CFR part 1212.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Records, including official government documentation, are provided by individuals requesting
access to NASA facilities and contractor sites, from existing databases containing this information
at Federally Funded Research and Development Centers, and from other Federally funded sources
located at NASA facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="nasa10gos" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 GOS</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">NASA Guest Operations System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Location 5, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on individuals who have been invited to attend NASA events.  These individuals can be members of the NASA community such as principal and prominent management and staff officials, program and project managers, scientists, engineers, speakers, other selected employees involved in newsworthy activities, and other participants in Agency programs, as well members of the general public who are invited to attend NASA events.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system may include personal information about the individuals invited or attending events, such as their names, home addresses, nationality and passport information. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used by the Agency for the purpose of communicating with guests to NASA events.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. Records from this system may be disclosed in accordance with NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained electronically in a central secure database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are searched and retrieved by name, business, or address. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>An approved security plan for this system has been established in accordance with OMB Circular A"130, Management of Federal Information Resources. Individuals will have access to the system only in accordance with approved authentication methods. Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Only key authorized employees with appropriately configured system roles can access the system and only from workstations within the NASA Intranet.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retained in a computer database and managed, retained and dispositioned in accordance with the guidelines defined in the NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS), Schedule 1, Item 37A.    </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>System Manager: Guest Operations Manager, Office of Communications, Location 1, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals interested in inquiring about their records should notify the system manager.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing to the system manager.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations governing access to records, procedures for contesting the contents and for appealing initial determinations are set forth in 14 CFR Part 1212. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The information contained in the GOS is obtained directly from the individuals, who provide the information on a voluntary basis. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="nasa10hims" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>10HIMS</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Health Information Management System.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records of Medical Clinics/Units and Environmental Health Offices are maintained at:</p>
                <p>Mary W. Jackson NASA Headquarters, National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), Washington, DC 20546-0001;</p>
                <p>Ames Research Center (NASA), Moffett Field, CA 94035-1000;</p>
                <p>Armstrong Flight Research Center (NASA), PO Box 273, Edwards, CA 93523-0273;</p>
                <p>John H. Glenn Research Center at Lewis Field (NASA), 21000 Brookpark Road, Cleveland, OH 44135-3191;</p>
                <p>Goddard Space Flight Center (NASA), Greenbelt, MD 20771-0001;</p>
                <p>Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center (NASA), Houston, TX 77058-3696;</p>
                <p>John F. Kennedy Space Center (NASA), Kennedy Space Center, FL 32899-0001;</p>
                <p>Langley Research Center, (NASA), Hampton, VA 23681-2199;</p>
                <p>George C. Marshall Space Flight Center (NASA), Marshall Space Flight Center, AL 35812-0001;</p>
                <p>John C. Stennis Space Center (NASA), Stennis Space Center, MS 39529-6000;</p>
                <p>Michoud Assembly Facility (NASA), PO Box 29300, New Orleans, LA 70189; and</p>
                <p>Wallops Flight Facility (NASA), Wallops Island, VA 23337.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are also hosted at:</p>
                <p>CORITY Chicago Data Center, 341 Haynes Drive, in Wood Dale, Illinois 60191;</p>
                <p>Salesforce Government Cloud in Ashburn, Virginia; and</p>
                <p>Salesforce Disaster Recovery Center in Elk Grove Village, Illinois.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Health and Medical Officer at NASA Headquarters (see System Location above for address).</p>
                <p>Subsystem Managers:</p>
                <p>Director Health and Medical Systems, Occupational Health at NASA Headquarters (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>Chief, Space Medicine Division at NASA Johnson Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>Occupational Health Contracting Officer Representatives at NASA Ames Research Center, (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Armstrong Flight Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Kennedy Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Langley Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Glenn Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Marshall Space Flight Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>NASA Stennis Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                <p>Michoud Assembly Facility (NASA) (see System Location above for address); and</p>
                <p>Wallops Flight Facility (NASA) (see System Location above for address).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 USC § 7901 – Health service programs;</p>
                <p>51 U.S.C. § 20113 (a) – Powers of the Administration in performance of functions to make and promulgate rules and regulations;</p>
                <p>44 U.S.C. § 3101 – Records management by agency heads; general duties;</p>
                <p>42 CFR Part 2 – Confidentiality of substance use disorder patient records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In order to ensure a healthy environment and workforce, information in this system of records is maintained on anyone receiving (1) exams for general wellness, (2) occupational clearances or determination of fitness for duty, (3) behavioral health assistance, (4) workplace surveillance for potential human exposure within NASA to communicable diseases and hazards such as noise and chemical exposure, repetitive motion, and (5) first aid or medical care for onsite illness or injuries through a NASA clinic outreach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains information on (1) NASA employees and applicants; (2) employees from other agencies and military detailees working at NASA; (3) active or retired astronauts and active astronaut family members; (4) other space flight personnel on temporary or extended duty at NASA; (5) contractor personnel; (6) Space Flight Participants and those engaged in commercial use of NASA facilities, (7) civil service and contractor family members; and (8) visitors to NASA Centers who use clinics or ambulance services for emergency or first-aid treatment.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system contain demographic data and private health information:</p>
                <p> (1) Wellness records including but not limited to exams provided for continuing healthcare, documentation of immunizations and other outreach records.</p>
                <p> (2) Fitness for duty and/or exposure exams/surveillance including but not limited to ergonomics, hazardous materials, radiation, noise, communicable diseases and other applicable longitudinal surveillance.</p>
                <p>(3) Qualification records including the use of offsite or onsite exams to determine suitability for duties.</p>
                <p>(4) Behavioral health and employee assistance records.</p>
                <p>(5) Records of first aid, contingency response, or emergency care, including ambulance transportation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The information in this system of records is obtained from individuals themselves, physicians, and previous medical records of individuals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.   Under the following routine uses that are unique to this system of records, information in this system may be disclosed:</p>
                <p>(1) to external medical professionals and independent entities to support internal and external reviews for purposes of medical quality assurance; (2) to private or other government health care providers for consultation, referral, or mission medical contingency support; (3) to the Office of Personnel Management, Occupational Safety and Health Administration, and other Federal or State agencies as required in accordance with the Federal agency's special program responsibilities;  (4) to insurers for referrals or reimbursement; (5) to employers of non-NASA personnel in support of the Mission Critical Space Systems Personnel Reliability Program; (6) to international partners for mission support and continuity of care for their employees pursuant to NASA Space Act agreements; (7) to non-NASA personnel performing research, studies, or other activities through arrangements or agreements with NASA; (8) to the public of pre-space flight information having mission impact concerning an individual crewmember, limited to the crewmember's name and the fact that a medical condition exists; (9) to the public, limited to the crewmember's name and the fact that a medical condition exists, if a flight crewmember is, for medical reasons, unable to perform a scheduled public event following a space flight mission/landing; (10) to the public to advise of medical conditions arising from accidents, consistent with NASA regulations; and (12) in accordance with standard routine uses as set forth here.</p>
                <p>In addition, the following routine uses of information contained in SORs are standard for many NASA systems and are compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No. 1—In the event this system of records indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the SOR may be referred to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No. 2—A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No. 3— A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No. 4—A record from this system may be disclosed to the Department of Justice including United States Attorney Offices, or other federal agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative or administrative body, when the record is relevant or necessary to the litigation or the agency has an interest in such litigation when  a) the Agency, or any component thereof; or b) any employee of the Agency in his or her official capacity; or c) any employee of the Agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the Agency has agreed to represent the employee; or d) the United States, where the Agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the Agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the Agency is deemed by the Agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No. 5—A record from this SOR may be disclosed in an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body, when NASA determines that the records are relevant to the proceeding; or in an appropriate proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No.6—A record from this SOR may be disclosed to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) NASA suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) NASA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, NASA (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with NASA’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No.7—A record from this system may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the federal government, when necessary to accomplish an Agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No.8—A record from this system may be disclosed to a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member’s behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                <p>Standard Routine Use No.9—A record from this system may be disclosed to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when NASA determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are stored in multiple formats including paper, digital, micrographic, photographic, and as medical recordings such as electrocardiograph tapes, x-rays and strip charts.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved from the system by the individual's name, date of birth, or unique assigned Numbers.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedule 1, Items 126 and 127, and NASA Records Retention Schedule 8, Item 57.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2014 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet, or remotely via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection requiring two-factor token authentication using NASA-issued computers or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  The CORITY Chicago Data Center and Salesforce Government Cloud and Disaster Recovery Center maintain documentation and verification of commensurate safeguards in accordance with FISMA, NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 2810.1A, and NASA ITS-HBK-2810.02-05.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or files.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="EXEMPTIONSCLAIMED">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    None
                </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                    <subsection type="history">
                        <xhtmlContent>
                            <p>2020-27051, 85 FR 79224, pp. 79224-79227</p>
                        </xhtmlContent>
                    </subsection>
                </section>
                <section id="GSFC 51EUI" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>GSFC 51EUI</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Earth Observing System Data and Information System (EOSDIS) User Information.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA and NASA partner servers at NASA Locations 1, 4, 7, and 9-10, as set forth in Appendix A, and at the following contractor and other Federal agency Distributed Active Archive Centers (DAACs): </p>
<p>&#8226; Alaska Satellite Facility SAR Data Center DAAC, University of Alaska, Fairbanks, AK 99775-7320.</p>
<p>&#8226;Land Processes Distributed Active Archive Center (LP DAAC), Department of Interior: Earth Resources Observation and Science (EROS), 47914 252nd Street, Sioux Falls, SD 57918-0001.</p>
<p>&#8226;National Snow and Ice Data Center, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</p>
<p>&#8226;Oak Ridge National Laboratory DAAC, Department of Energy, Oak Ridge, TN 37381-6407.</p>
<p>&#8226;Socioeconomic Data and Applications Center, Center for International Earth Science Information Network (CIESIN) at Columbia University, Palisades, NY 10964.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals from the NASA, university, and research communities, as well as the general public, who request satellite data or other data products from any of the EOSDIS DAACs indicated above, or individuals who register to save their data search parameters for reuse in the future.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system consist of information obtained from individual users to establish user accounts that enable user notification of improved or altered data and services, as well as actual science data from EOSDIS, most often via on-line mechanisms.  Records include an individual"s name, e-mail address, organizational affiliation, and country of residence. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>These records are used to establish user accounts that enable user notification of improved or altered data and services, as well as actual science data from EOSDIS, most often via on-line mechanisms.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. The records and information in these records may be disclosed:</p>
<p>(1) To  government contractors conducting OMB-approved annual user satisfaction surveys collecting user feedback for aggregating reports to OMB and enabling NASA to improve its systems, processes, and services to the user community; (2) To the European Space Agency (ESA) through public posting on a NASA website of ESA scientific data users" names, email addresses, and organizational affiliation to achieve ESA member nation awareness of the breadth of their scientific data  use (including ESA scientific data hosted by NASA); and (3) In accordance with NASA standard routine uses set forth in Appendix B.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored electronically on secure servers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>User account records are typically indexed and retrieved by user"s name.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Approved security plans for each of the DAACs at NASA and contractor facilities have been established in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A"130, Management of Federal Information Resources. The aggregation of these plans constitutes the security plan for EOSDIS.  Authorized individuals will have access to the system only in accordance with approved authentication methods.  With the exception of the records of ESA scientific data users" information posted in accordance with Routine Use (2) above, all user information is protected according to NASA guidelines for managing sensitive information.    </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The Earth Science Data and Information System (ESDIS) Project has a plan under configuration control according to which the original data are deleted in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedule (NRRS) 2, Item 15A.3.  The DAACs reauthorize specific users" information on an approved basis and user information is deleted when no longer needed in accordance with NRRS 2, Item 19A.  Mailing lists containing user information are maintained in order to permit distribution of newsletters to users and are disposed of according to the NRRS 1, Item 88.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>System Manager: 423/Deputy Project Manager for Operations, ESDIS Project, Location 4 as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
<p>Subsystem Managers: DAAC Managers at each of the locations listed under System Location above; ECHO Manager, EMS Manager, and LANCE Manager, all in Code 423 at Location 4 as set forth in Appendix A. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals inquiring about their records should contact the System Manager at the address given above and provide their name and e-mail address. The System Manager can be reached by phone at (301) 614-5048.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing to the System Manager at the address provided or by phone at (301) 614-5048.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations governing access to records and procedures for contesting the contents, and for appealing initial determinations are set forth in 14 CFR Part 1212.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The information is received electronically or via telephone directly from users needing to obtain or access NASA"s Earth science data products.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="10habc" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 HABC</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">History Archives Biographical Collection.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Location 1 and 11 as set forth in Appendix A. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on individuals who are of historical significance in aeronautics, astronautics, space science, and other concerns of NASA. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Biographical data; speeches and articles by an individual; correspondence, interviews, and various other tapes and transcripts of program activities. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20112(a)(3) and 44 U.S.C. 3101. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used by History Office staff to answer reference queries from the media and are made available to visiting historians and other researchers to support their research and writing projects.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. Records may be disclosed: (1) to scholars (historians and other disciplines) or any other interested individuals for research in writing dissertations, articles, and books, for government, commercial, and nonprofit publication or developing material for other media use; (2) by History Office staff to members of the media or NASA staff in response to reference requests, and to visiting historians and other researchers to support their research and writing projects; and (3) in accordance with NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained as hard-copy documents and on electronic media. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The records are retrieved from the system by the individual's name. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Because these records are archive material and, therefore, a matter of public information, there are no special safeguard procedures required. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retained indefinitely in Agency reference collections in history offices, but may be destroyed when no longer needed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 1 Item 10. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Chief Archivist, Location 1. </p>
<p>Subsystem Manager: Public Affairs Officer, Location 11 as set forth in Appendix A. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information may be obtained from the system manager listed above. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to same address as stated in the Notification section above. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear at 14 CFR part 1212. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Press releases, newspapers, journals, copies of internal Agency records, and the individuals themselves.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="10herd" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10HERD</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Human Experimental and Research Data Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification">
    <xhtmlContent>
        <p>None.</p>
    </xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Locations 2, 5, 6, and 8, as set forth in Appendix A.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information in this system of records is maintained on individuals who have been involved in space flight, aeronautical research flight, and/or participated in NASA tests or experimental or research programs.  Categories of individuals covered include civil service and military employees, employees of other government agencies, contractor employees, students, International Space Partner personnel, volunteers, and other human research subjects on whom information is collected as part of an experiment or study.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Record categories in this system include data obtained in the course of an experiment, test, or research medical data from in-flight records, and other information collected in connection with an experiment, test, or research.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a) and 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.  Records and information in this system may be disclosed: (1) to other individuals or organizations, including Federal, State, or local agencies, and nonprofit, educational, or private entities, who are participating in NASA programs or are otherwise furthering the understanding or application of biological, physiological, and behavioral phenomena as reflected in the data contained in this system of records; (2) to external biomedical professionals and independent entities to support internal and external reviews for purposes of research quality assurance; (3) to international partners for research activities pursuant to NASA Space Act agreements; (4) to external professionals conducting research, studies, or other activities through arrangements or agreements with NASA and for mutual benefit; and (5) in accordance with standard routine uses set forth in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored as paper documents, electronic media, micrographic media, photographs, or motion picture film, and various medical recordings such as electrocardiograph tapes, stripcharts, and x-rays.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved by the individual's name, experiment or test; arbitrary experimental subject number; flight designation; or crewmember designation on a particular space or aeronautical flight.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet, or remotely via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection requiring two-factor token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or files. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained in Agency files for varying periods of time depending on the need for use of the records and destroyed when no longer needed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 7 Item 16.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Chief Health and Medical Officer, Location 1.</p>
<p>Subsystem Managers: Director Life Sciences Directorate, Chief Space Medicine Division, and Program Scientist Human Research Program, both at Location 5; and Institutional Review Board (IRB) Chairs at Locations 2, 6, and 8, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Information may be obtained by contacting the cognizant system or subsystem manager listed above.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; and Social Security Number. .</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the same address as stated above</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear at 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information in this system is obtained from experimental test subjects, physicians and other health care providers, principal investigators and other researchers, and previous experimental test or research records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="10hims" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10HIMS</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Health Information Management System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information in this system of records is maintained on anyone receiving health or medical care in or through a NASA clinic or healthcare activity. </p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Paper-based records of Medical Clinics/Units and Environmental Health Offices are held at NASA Locations 1, 9, 11, 14, and 19, as set forth in Appendix A.  Electronic records are hosted on secure NASA servers in Locations 5 and 6, as set forth in Appendix A, and at the Medgate Chicago Data Center, 341 Haynes Drive, in Wood Dale, Illinois 60191, which is a secure, redundant, Tier III, SAS 70 certified facility.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system contains information on (1) NASA civil service employees and applicants; (2) other Agency civil service and military employees working at NASA; (3) active or retired astronauts and active astronaut family members; (4) International Space Station Partner personnel, their families, or other space flight personnel on temporary or extended duty at NASA; (5) onsite contractor personnel who receive job-related examinations under the NASA Occupational Health Program, have work-related mishaps or accidents, or visit clinics for emergency or first-aid treatment; and (6) visitors to NASA Centers who use clinics for emergency or first-aid treatment.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system contains:</p>
<p>(1) General medical records of routine health care, first aid, emergency treatment, examinations (e.g., surveillance, hazardous workplace, certification, flight, special purpose and health maintenance), exposures (e.g., hazardous materials and ionizing radiation), and consultations by non-NASA physicians.   </p>
<p>(2) Information resulting from physical examinations, laboratory and other tests, and medical history forms; treatment records; screening examination results; immunization records; administration of medications prescribed by private/personal or NASA flight surgeon physicians; consultation records; and hazardous exposure and other health hazard/abatement data.</p>
<p>(3) Medical records, behavioral health records, and physical examination records of Astronauts and their families.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>5 U.S.C. 7901; 51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101; 42 CFR Part 2.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.  The records and information in this system may be disclosed: </p>
<p>(1) to external medical professionals and independent entities to support internal and external reviews for purposes of medical quality assurance; (2) to private or other government health care providers for consultation or referral; (3) to the Office of Personnel Management, Occupational Safety and Health Administration, and other Federal or State agencies as required in accordance with the Federal agency's special program responsibilities;  (4) to insurers for referrals or reimbursement; (5) to employers of non-NASA personnel in support of the Mission Critical Space Systems Personnel Reliability Program; (6) to international partners for mission support and continuity of care for their employees pursuant to NASA Space Act agreements; (7) to non-NASA personnel performing research, studies, or other activities through arrangements or agreements with NASA and for mutual benefit; (8) to the public of pre-space flight information having mission impact concerning an individual crewmember, limited to the crewmember's name and the fact that a medical condition exists; (9) to the public, limited to the crewmember's name and the fact that a medical condition exists, if a flight crewmember is, for medical reasons, unable to perform a scheduled public event following a space flight mission/landing; (10) to the public to advise of medical conditions arising from accidents, consistent with NASA regulations; and (11) in accordance with standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in multiple formats including paper, digital, micrographic, photographic, and as medical recordings such as electrocardiograph tapes, x-rays and strip charts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved from the system by the individual's name, date of birth, and/or Social Security or other assigned Number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet, or remotely via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection requiring two-factor token authentication using NASA-issued computers or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  The Medgate Chicago Data Center maintains documentation and verification of commensurate safeguards in accordance with FISMA, NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 2810.1A, and NASA ITS-HBK-2810.02-05.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or files. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed by series in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedule 1, Item 126, and NASA Records Retention Schedule 8, Item 57.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Chief Health and Medical Officer at Location 1</p>
<p>Subsystem Managers: Director, Health and Medical Systems, Occupational Health at Location 1; Chief, Space Medicine Division at Location 5; Occupational Health Contracting Officer Representatives at Locations 2-4, 6-14, and 19.  Locations are as set forth in Appendix A. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information may be obtained by contacting the cognizant system or subsystem manager listed above.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; and Social Security Number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individual written requests for information shall be addressed to the System Manager at Location 1 or the subsystem manager at the appropriate NASA Center.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The information in this system of records is obtained from individuals, physicians, and previous medical records of individuals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p> None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="10hrcf" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10HRCF</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Harassment Report Case Files
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Locations 1 through 11 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system maintains information on individuals who have reported harassing conduct by or
against NASA civil servants. This includes but is not limited to current and former NASA employees
and contractors and others who have reported allegations of harassment by or against NASA civil
servants. It also includes information on witnesses and others contacted as part of the fact-finding
process.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system maintains records including names, position, and contact information of
individuals involved in reports or allegations of harassment, as well as facts gathered about
alleged harassment incidents. It also includes records such as fact-finding reports, findings and
corrective actions, if necessary, and close out letters.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>42 U.S.C. 2473, 44 U.S.C. 3101, 29 U.S.C. 621 et. seq.; 29 U.S.C. 791 et. seq.; 42 U.S.C.
2000e-16 et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 12101; Exec. Order No. 11478, 34 FR 12985; Exec. Order No. 13087,
63 FR 30097; Exec. Order No. 13152, 65 FR 26115.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency
collected the information. Records from this system may be disclosed, as necessary:
</p><p>(1) To any source from which additional information is requested in the course of processing a
report of harassment made pursuant to NASA policy;
</p><p>(2) To contractors conducting the fact-finding inquiry on behalf of NASA;
</p><p>(3) To an authorized grievance official, complaints examiner, administrative judge, contract
investigator, arbitrator, or duly authorized official for use in investigation, litigation, or
settlement of a non-harassment grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee;
</p><p>(4) Under NASA standard routine uses 1 through 6 as set forth in Appendix B.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>These records are maintained in paper file folders and on electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records may be retrieved by the name of the alleged harassee or by the name of the
alleged harasser.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in locked file cabinets or in secured rooms with access limited to
those whose official duties require access. Electronic data are maintained in encrypted files on
secure servers with limited access to computerized records through use of access codes and entry
logs, to only those whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>These records will be maintained for four years after the report of harassment is closed, in
accordance with the disposition authorization, when approved under NARA N1-255-11-
01, that will be incorporated in the NPR 1441.1 NASA Records Retention Schedules as Schedule 3, Item
53.5.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>System Manager: Agency Anti-Harassment Coordinator, NASA Headquarters, 300 E Street, SW.,
Mail Stop 4W39, Washington, DC 20546-0001.
</p><p>Subsystem Managers: Center Anti-Harassment Coordinators at each of the locations 1 through 11 as
set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from the cognizant system or subsystem manager of locations
listed above where the requested records are held.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing
to the System Manager or Subsystem Manager at locations listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial
determinations by the individual concerned appear in 14 CFR Part 1212.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is obtained from current and former employees, current and former contractor
employees, Fact-Finders, Agency Anti-Harassment Coordinator, and Center Anti-Harassment
Coordinators.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="10igic" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 IGIC</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Inspector General Investigations Case Files.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Some of the material contained in the system has been classified in the interests of national security pursuant to Executive Order 11652. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Locations 1, 2, 4 through 11, 16 and 17 as set forth in Appendix A.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on current and former employees of NASA, contractors, and subcontractors, and others whose actions have affected NASA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Case files pertaining to matters including, but not limited to, the following classifications of cases: (1) Fraud against the Government, (2) theft of Government property, (3) bribery, (4) lost or stolen lunar samples, (5) misuse of Government property, (6) conflict of interest, (7) waiver of claim for overpayment of pay, (8) leaks of Source Evaluation Board information, (9) improper personal conduct, (10) irregularities in awarding contracts, (11) computer crimes, (12) research misconduct, and (13) whistleblower protection investigations under various statutes and regulations. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113; 51 U.S.C. 20114; 44 U.S.C. 3101; Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. Appendix 3.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information in this system of records is collected in the course of investigating alleged crimes and other violations of law or regulations that affect NASA.  The information is used by prosecutors, Agency managers, law enforcement agencies, Congress, NASA contractors, and others to address the crimes and other misconduct discovered during investigations. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. The following are routine uses: (1) Responding to the White House, the Office of Management and Budget, and other organizations in the Executive Office of the President regarding matters inquired of; (2) disclosure to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to a written inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual; (3) providing data to Federal intelligence elements; (4) providing data to any source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation, and to identify the type of information requested; (5) providing personal identifying data to Federal, State, local, or foreign law enforcement representatives seeking confirmation of identity of persons under investigations; (6) disclosing, as necessary, to a contractor, subcontractor, or grantee firm or institution, to the extent that the disclosure is in NASA"s interest and is relevant and necessary in order that the contractor, subcontractor, or grantee is able to take administrative or corrective action; (7) disclosing to any official (including members of the Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE) and staff and authorized officials of the Department of Justice and Federal Bureau of Investigation) charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessment reviews of internal safeguards and management procedures employed in Office of Inspector General (OIG) operations; (8) disclosing to members of the CIGIE for the preparation of reports to the President and Congress on the activities of the Inspectors General; (9) disclosing to the public when: the matter under investigation has become public knowledge, or when the Inspector General determines that such disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of the OIG investigative process, or to demonstrate the accountability of NASA officers, or employees, or other individuals covered by this system, unless the Inspector General determines that disclosure of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy; (10) disclosing to the news media and public when there exists a legitimate public interest (e.g., to provide information on events in the criminal process, such as indictments), or when necessary for protection from imminent threat to life or property; (11) disclosing to any individual or entity when necessary to elicit information that will assist an OIG investigation or audit; (12) disclosing to complainants and/or victims to the extent necessary to provide such persons with information and explanations concerning the progress and/or results of the investigation or case arising from the matters of which they complained and/or of which they were a victim; (13) disclosing to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the Federal Government, who have a need to know such information in order to accomplish an agency function; (14) NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained as hard-copy documents and on electronic media.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p> Each OIG investigation is assigned a case number and all records relating to a particular investigation are filed and retrieved by that case number.  Records may also be retrieved from the system by the name of an individual.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or files.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed in accordance with NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 1441.1, NASA Records Management Program Requirements, and NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS) 1441.1, Schedule 9.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Assistant Inspector General for Investigations, Location 1.  </p>
<p>Subsystem Managers Special and Resident Agents in Charge, Location 2, 4 through 11 inclusive, 16, and 17 as set forth in Appendix A.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.  System is exempt (see below). </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.  System is exempt (see below). </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.  System is exempt (see below).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Exempt. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>(1) The Inspector General Investigations Case Files system of records is exempt from any part of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552 a), EXCEPT the following subsections: (b) relating to conditions of disclosure; (c)(1) and (2) relating to keeping and maintaining a disclosure accounting; (e)(4)(A)"(F) relating to publishing a system notice setting forth name, location, categories of individuals and records, routine uses, and policies regarding storage, retrievability, access controls, retention and disposal of the records; (e)(6), (7), (9), (10), and (11) relating to the dissemination and maintenance of records; (i) relating to criminal penalties.  This exemption applies to those records and information contained in the system of records pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws.  </p>
<p>(2) To the extent that there may exist noncriminal investigative files within this system of records, the Inspector General Investigations Case Files system of records is exempt from the following subsections of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a): (c)(3) relating to access to disclosure accounting, (d) relating to access to reports, (e)(1) relating to the type of information maintained in the records; (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I) relating to publishing the system notice information as to agency procedures for access and amendment and information as to the categories of sources of records, and (f) relating to developing agency rules for gaining access and making corrections.  </p>
<p>The determination to exempt this system of records has been made by the Administrator of NASA in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) and (k) and subpart 5 of the NASA regulations appearing in 14 CFR part 1212, for the reason that a component of the Office of Inspector General, NASA, performs as its principal function activities pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws, within the meaning of 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="10npps" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>10NPPS</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            NASA Personnel and Payroll Systems.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Locations 9 and 18, as set forth in Appendix A; in the Federal Personnel and Payroll System of the Department of Interior Federal agency Human Resources Shared Service Center located at National Business Center, 7301 W. Mansfield, Denver Co, 80235; and in the Office of Personnel Management’s Electronic Official Personnel File located at the National Business Center 7301 W. Mansfield, Denver Co, 80235.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system maintains information on present and former NASA employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The data contained in this system of records includes payroll, employee leave, insurance, labor and human resource distribution and overtime information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system are used to facilitate NASA administration of payroll functions and personnel decisions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 5501 et seq.; 5 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. The following are routine uses: (1) To furnish to a third party a verification of an employee's status upon written request of the employee; (2) to facilitate the verification of employee contributions and insurance data with carriers and collection agents; (3) to report to the Office of Personnel Management (a) withholdings of premiums for life insurance, health benefits, and retirements, and (b) separated employees subject to retirement; (4) to furnish the U.S. Treasury magnetic tape reports and/or electronic files on net pay, net savings allotments and bond transmittal pertaining to each employee; (5) to provide the Internal Revenue Service with details of wages taxable under the Federal Insurance Contributions Act and to furnish a magnetic tape listing on Federal tax withholdings; (6) to furnish various financial institutions itemized listings of employee's pay and savings allotments transmitted to the institutions in accordance with employee requests; (7) to provide various Federal, State, and local taxing authorities itemized listings of withholdings for individual income taxes; (8) to respond to requests for State employment security agencies and the U.S. Department of Labor for employment, wage, and separation data on former employees for the purpose of determining eligibility for unemployment compensation; (9) to report to various Combined Federal Campaign offices total contributions withheld from employee wages; (10) to furnish leave balances and activity to the Office of Personnel Management upon request; (11) to furnish data to labor organizations in accordance with negotiated agreements; (12) to furnish pay data to the Department of State for certain NASA employees located outside the United States; (13) to furnish data to a consumer reporting agency or bureau, private collection contractor or debt collection center in accordance with section 3711 of Title 31 of the United States Code; (14) to forward delinquent debts, and all relevant information related thereto, to the U.S. Department of Treasury, for collection; (15) to the Office of Child Support Enforcement (OCSE), Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS), National Directory of New Hires, part of the Federal Parent Locator Service and the Federal Tax Offset System, DHHS/OCSE No. 09-90-0074, for the purpose of locating individuals to establish paternity, establishing and modifying orders of child support, identifying sources of income, and for other child support enforcement actions as required by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation act (Pub. L. 104-193); (16) to consumer reporting agencies as required by the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)).; (17) to private collection contractors as required by the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966, as amended by the Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701, et seq.); and (18) NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>Records are maintained in electronic format.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved from the system by the individual's name, unique personal identification code and/or Social Security Number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards.  Additionally, NASA server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with FISMA and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers. The Department of Interior and Office of Personnel Management Federal agency servers in Denver are also compliant with the FISMA and OMB Circular A-130 security standards and requirements.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and transferred to the National Personnel Records Center (NPRC) in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 3 Item 47. Records transferred to NPRC will be destroyed when 10 years old by NPRC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Financial Management Division, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, and Assistant Administrator for Human Capital Management, Office of Human Capital Management, Location 1.  </p>
                <p>Subsystem Managers: Chief Financial Officers and Human Capital Officers, Locations 2 through 9, and 11, Director, Financial Management Division, and Director, Human Resources Division, Location  18.  Locations are as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information may be obtained from the cognizant system or subsystem manager listed above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the same address as identified in the Notification section above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear at 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individual on whom the record is maintained, personnel office(s), and the individual's supervisor.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    None.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

<section id="10oris" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10ORIS</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Occupational Radiation Information System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>NASA"s electronic health records are hosted at the Medgate Chicago Data Center, 341 Haynes Drive, in Wood Dale, Illinois 60191.  Paper-based records and non-medical electronic records are located in NASA facilities in Locations 2 through 14 as set forth in Appendix A.  </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on NASA civil service employees and applicants; other Agency civil service and military employees working at NASA; International Space Station Partner personnel who use NASA space or aeronautical vehicles; principal investigators or other visitors to NASA Centers; onsite contractor personnel who handle, use, or are exposed to ionizing or non-ionizing radiation sources and/or devices.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in the system include, but are not limited to name, date of birth, and social security number contained in: (1) Work history questionnaires and training records, including Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) training and experience documents; (2) Radiation producing source and/or device use authorizing forms; (3) Personnel licenses and/or certifications; (4) Employee radiation levels including medical, background and space radiation exposure and/or calculated radiation levels from Medical records and patient histories; and (5) Prenatal exposure counseling and pregnancy declarations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 10 CFR Part 20, 29 CFR 1910.1096; and State law and/or State agreement.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. Records and information in this system may be disclosed: (1) to State oversight agencies, the NRC, and/or Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) for verification and evidence of regulatory compliance; (2) to agency contractors, grantees, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform their activity; (3) to International Space Agencies (as appropriate) for data obtained on their national employees who are assigned, detailed and/or participating at a NASA Center or spacecraft; (4) to other Federal agencies including, but not limited to, the Air Force, Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and Food and Drug Administration (FDA), as evidence of regulatory compliance; and (5) in accordance with standard routine uses set forth in Appendix B. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are kept under controlled conditions in both physical form in file cabinets and electronic form on NASA work stations and servers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved from the system by the individual's name.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet, or remotely via computers using a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection requiring two-factor NASA-issued token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication using NASA-issued computers.  The Medgate Chicago Data Center is a secure, redundant, Tier III, SAS 70 certified facility that maintains documentation and verification of commensurate safeguards in accordance with FISMA, NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 2810.1A, and NASA ITS-HBK-2810.02-05.  Physical records are secured under locked conditions when not in use.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS), Schedule 1 Item 130; and Schedule 8 Item 57, or individual State, NRC or OSHA requirements if longer than those in the NRRS.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Chief Health and Medical Officer, Location 1.  </p>
<p>Subsystem Managers:  NASA and Contractor Radiation Safety Officers at Locations 2 through 14 as set forth in Appendix A. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information may be obtained from the subsystem managers listed above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the same address as stated in the Notification section above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in 14 CFR Part 1212.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals themselves, mishap reports, field surveys, licensing and certification authorities, and monitoring device laboratories.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p> None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="nasa10pats" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10 PATS</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Parking and Transit System (PATS).
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Locations 1 and 4, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on NASA civil servants and contractors who are holders of parking permits; applicants or members of carpools, vanpools and other ridesharing programs; applicants and recipients of fare subsidies issued by NASA; and applicants for other NASA transit benefit programs.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system may include information about individuals, including name, home address, badge number, monthly commuting cost, email address, years of government service, grade, personal vehicle make and model, and person vehicle license number. These records may be captured as parking, rideshare, or other transit program applications, status or participation reports of individuals" participation in the programs. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101; 40 U.S.C. 471; and, 40 U.S.C. 486; </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used to facilitate administration of employee and contractor participation in parking, rideshare, and transit programs.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information, which is the issuance of NASA Parking Permits and NASA Fare Subsidies.  </p>
<p>Records in this system may be disclosed: (1) to other Federal agencies to confirm that an individual is not receiving transit benefits from multiple agencies concurrently; and (2) in accordance with the NASA Standard Routine Uses as listed in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in hard copy and electronically in systems on secure NASA servers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved by name or by zip code of residence.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or locked file cabinets.     </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained and disposed of in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedule 6, Item 11 and General Records Schedule 9, Item 7.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Transportation Officer, Headquarters Facilities and Administrative Services Division, Location 1, as set forth in Appendix A.  </p>
<p>Subsystem Manager: Transportation Subsidy Program Lead, Logistics Management Division, Location 4, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals interested in inquiring about their records should notify the System Manager or Subsystem Manager at the addresses given above. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing to the System Manager or Subsystem Manager at the address given above. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations governing access to records and procedures for contesting the contents and for appealing initial determinations are set forth in 14 CFR Part 1212. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information is provided by individuals in applications submitted for parking permits, carpool and vanpool membership, ridesharing information, and fare subsidies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
    <p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="10rar" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10RAR</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p> Reasonable Accommodation (RA) Records, NASA 10RAR.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Amazon Web Services, 410 Terry Avenue North, Seattle, WA 98109</p>
            <p>Mary W. Jackson NASA Headquarters, Washington, DC 20546-0001;</p>
            <p>Ames Research Center (NASA), Moffett Field, CA 94035-1000;</p>
            <p>Armstrong Flight Research Center (NASA), PO Box 273, Edwards, CA 93523-0273;</p>
            <p>John H. Glenn Research Center at Lewis Field (NASA), 21000 Brookpark Road, Cleveland, OH 44135-3191;</p>
            <p>Goddard Space Flight Center (NASA), Greenbelt, MD 20771-0001;</p>
            <p>Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center (NASA), Houston, TX 77058-3696;</p>
            <p>John F. Kennedy Space Center (NASA), Kennedy Space Center, FL 32899-0001;</p>
            <p>Langley Research Center (NASA), Hampton, VA 23681-2199;</p>
            <p>George C. Marshall Space Flight Center (NASA), Marshall Space Flight Center, AL 35812-0001;</p>
            <p>John C. Stennis Space Center (NASA), Stennis Space Center, MS 39529-6000;</p>
            <p>NASA Shared Services Center (NSSC), Building 5100, Stennis Space Center, MS 39529-6000; and</p>
            <p>Wallops Flight Facility (NASA), Wallops Island, VA 23337.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Associate Administrator, Office of Diversity and Equal Opportunity (ODEO), NASA Headquarters (see System Location above for address).</p>
            <p>Subsystem Managers: ODEO Director, Diversity and Data Analytics Division; and Agency Disability Program Manager at NASA Headquarters (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>Center ODEO Directors and Center Disability Program Managers, at:</p>
            <p>NASA Ames Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Armstrong Flight Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Glenn Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Headquarters (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Johnson Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Kennedy Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Langley Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Marshall Space Flight Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Stennis Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
            <p>NASA Shared Services Center (NSSC) (see System Location above for address); and</p>
            <p>Wallops Flight Facility (see System Location above for address).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>29 U.S.C. § 791 et seq.; 42 U.S.C. § 12101 et seq.; 42 U.S.C. § 2000e et seq.; 44 U.S.C. § 3101; 51 U.S.C. § 20113(a); Exec. Order No. 11478; Exec. Order No. 13164; 29 CFR pt. 1605; 29 CFR pt. 1614; 29 CFR pt. 1630.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system is maintained for the purpose of considering, deciding and implementing requests for reasonable accommodation made by NASA employees and applicants for employment.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system maintains records of requests by (1) NASA employees; or (2) applicants for employment who are seeking reasonable accommodation and also contains the disposition of such requests.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records may include, but are not limited to: requests for reasonable accommodation including supporting documents for such requests; information concerning the nature of the disability or religious belief, practice, or observance and the need for accommodation;  medical records or other substantiating documentation; notes or records made during evaluation of such requests; requests for reconsideration or internal Agency appeals; and disposition all requests and appeals.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Individuals themselves; Associate Administrator for Diversity and Equal Opportunity, and all designees, including NASA Center EO Directors and Center Disability Program Managers; EEOC officials.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. Under the following routine uses that are unique to this system of records, information in this system may be disclosed:</p>
            <p> (1) to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint or appeal filed by an employee or applicant; (2) to first aid and safety personnel, when appropriate, if the disability might require emergency treatment;  (3) to Federal Government officials or any of their assignees charged with the responsibility of investigating NASA’s compliance with The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended, or the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (GINA), or Title VII of the Civil Rights Act; (4) to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Department of Labor (DOL), Office of Personnel Management (OPM), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), or Office of Special Counsel (OSC) to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements related to reasonable accommodation; and (5) in accordance with NASA standard routine uses as set forth here.</p>
            <p>In addition, the following routine uses of information contained in SORs, subject to the Privacy Act of 1974, are standard for many NASA systems. Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No. 1—In the event this system of records indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the SOR may be referred to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No. 2—A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No. 3— A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on the matter.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No. 4—A record from this system may be disclosed to the Department of Justice including United States Attorney Offices, or other federal agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative or administrative body, when the record is relevant or necessary to the litigation or the agency has an interest in such litigation when  a) the Agency, or any component thereof; or b) any employee or former employee of the Agency in his or her official capacity; or c) any employee of the Agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the Agency has agreed to represent the employee; or d) the United States, where the Agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the Agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the Agency is deemed by the Agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No.5—A record from this SOR may be disclosed in an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body, when NASA determines that the records are relevant to the proceeding; or in an appropriate proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No.6—A record from this SOR may be disclosed to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) NASA suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) NASA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, NASA (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with NASA’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No.7—A record from this system may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the federal government, when necessary to accomplish an Agency function related to this system of records.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No.8—A record from this system may be disclosed to a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member’s behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No.9—A record from this system may be disclosed to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when NASA determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use No. 10—To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) or the General Services Administration (GSA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
            <p>Standard Routine Use 11—To another agency, or organization for purpose of performing audit or oversight operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records in this system are maintained in hard-copy and electronically, and within Agency-wide Intranet database and tracking system.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records in the system are retrieved by name of the employee or applicant requesting accommodation, case identification number, or NASA Center from which the request originated.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NPR 1441.1 NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 3 Item 2.6.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605. Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers. Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy. Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources. Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods. Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication. Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or locked file cabinets.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle, and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle, and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>(15-117, 80 FR 246, pp. 79947-79949)</p>
            <p>(15-068, 80 FR 193, pp. 60410-60411)</p>
            <p>(11-091, 76 FR 200, pp. 64112-64114)</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>


<section id="10sccf" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10SCCF</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Ethics Standards of Conduct Counseling Case Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification">
    <xhtmlContent>
        <p>None.</p>
    </xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Locations 1 through 11 inclusive, and Location 18, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on current, former, and prospective NASA employees who have sought advice or have been counseled regarding conflict of interest rules and other Government ethics requirements for Federal employees.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Depending upon the nature of the problem, information collected may include employment history, financial data, and information concerning family members.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101; 18 U.S.C. 201, 203, 205, 207-209; 5 U.S.C. 7324-7327; 5 U.S.C. Appendix; 14 CFR part 1207; 5 CFR parts 2634-2641; 5 CFR part 6901; and Executive Order 12674, as modified by Executive Order 12731.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used to enable ethics officials to render advice and legal determinations to NASA employees and detailees to assure compliance with these acts and to preserve and promote the integrity of public officials and institutions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. Information from these records may be disclosed: (1) to the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Government Ethics, and Merit Systems Protection Board for investigation of possible violations of standards of conduct which the agencies directly oversee; and (2) in accordance with NASA standard routine uses for all of NASA"s systems of records as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained in paper form in loose-leaf binders or file folders, and in electronic media, including NASA"s Ethics Program Tracking System (EPTS).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved from the system by name of individual.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or locked file cabinets to which only persons authorized by the General Counsel, Agency Counsel for Ethics, or Center Chief Counsel have access. Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605 and applicable NASA policy.  Additionally, the Agency employs infrastructure encryption technologies in data transmission between servers and data management environments therein.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 1, Item 133.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>System Manager:  Agency Counsel for Ethics, General Law Practice Group, Location 1.</p>
<p>Sub-system Managers:  Chief Counsel, Locations 2 through 11, and Counsel to the Executive Director, Location 18, as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information may be obtained from the System Manager.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Requests from individuals should be addressed to the System Manager and must include employee's full name and NASA Center where employed.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA regulations and procedures for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear at 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information collected directly from individual and from his/her official employment record.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
        <section id="10secr" toc="yes">
            <systemNumber>10 SECR</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">
                Security Records System.
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>
                        None.
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The centralized data system is located at George C. Marshall Space Flight Center (NASA), Marshall Space Flight Center, AL 35812-0001.</p>
                    <p>Records are also located at:</p>
                    <p>Mary W. Jackson NASA Headquarters (NASA), Washington, DC 20546-0001;</p>
                    <p>Ames Research Center (NASA), Moffett Field, CA 94035-1000;</p>
                    <p>Armstrong Flight Research Center (NASA), PO Box 273, Edwards, CA 93523-0273;</p>
                    <p>John H. Glenn Research Center at Lewis Field (NASA), 21000 Brookpark Road, Cleveland, OH 44135-3191;</p>
                    <p>Goddard Space Flight Center (NASA), Greenbelt, MD 20771-0001;</p>
                    <p>Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center (NASA), Houston, TX 77058-3696;</p>
                    <p>John F. Kennedy Space Center (NASA), Kennedy Space Center, FL 32899-0001;</p>
                    <p>Langley Research Center (NASA), Hampton, VA 23681-2199;</p>
                    <p>George C. Marshall Space Flight Center (NASA), Marshall Space Flight Center, AL 35812-0001;</p>
                    <p>John C. Stennis Space Center (NASA), Stennis Space Center, MS 39529-6000;</p>
                    <p>Michoud Assembly Facility (NASA), PO Box 29300, New Orleans, LA 70189; and</p>
                    <p>White Sands Test Facility (NASA), PO Drawer MM, Las Cruces, NM 88004-0020.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>System Manager: Deputy Assistant Administrator of the Office of Protective Services, NASA Headquarters (see System Location above for address).</p>
                    <p>Subsystem Managers: Chief of Security/Protective Services at each subsystem location at:</p>
                    <p>NASA Headquarters (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Ames Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Armstrong Flight Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Glenn Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Johnson Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Kennedy Space Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Langley Research Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Marshall Space Flight Center (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>NASA Stennis Space Center (see System Location above for address); and</p>
                    <p>Michoud Assembly Facility (see System Location above for address);</p>
                    <p>White Sands Test Facility (see System Location above for address).</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>18 U.S.C. § 202-208 – Bribery, graft, and conflicts of interest;</p>
                    <p>18 U.S.C. § 371 – Conspiracy to commit offense or to defraud United States;</p>
                    <p>18 U.S.C. § 793-799 – Espionage and Information Control Statutes;</p>
                    <p>18 U.S.C. § 2151-2157 – Sabotage statutes;</p>
                    <p>18 U.S.C. 3056 – Powers, authorities, and duties of United States Secret Service;</p>
                    <p>40 U.S.C. § 1441 – Responsibilities regarding efficiency, security, and privacy of Federal computer systems;</p>
                    <p>42 U.S.C. § 2011 et seq. – Development and control of atomic energy; congressional declaration of policy;</p>
                    <p>44 U.S.C. § 3101 – Records management by agency heads; general duties;</p>
                    <p>50 U.S.C. – McCarran Internal Security Act;</p>
                    <p>51 U.S.C. § 20101 – National and commercial space programs; short title;</p>
                    <p>Exec. Order No. 9397, as amended – Numbering system for Federal accounts relating to individual persons;</p>
                    <p>Exec. Order No. 10450 – Security requirements for Government employment;</p>
                    <p>Exec. Order No. 10865 – Safeguarding classified information within industry;</p>
                    <p>Exec. Order No. 12968, as amended – Access to classified information;</p>
                    <p>Exec. Order No. 13526, as amended – Classified national security information;</p>
                    <p>Executive Order 13587, Structural Reform to Improve the Security of Classified Networks and Responsible Sharing and Safeguarding of Classified Information;</p>
                    <p>Pub. L. 81-733 –Summary suspension of employment of civilian officers and employees;</p>
                    <p>Pub. L. 107-347 – Federal Information Security Management Act 2002;</p>
                    <p>HSPD 12 – Policy for a common identification standard for Federal employees and contractors;</p>
                    <p>14 CFR 1203(b) – National Aeronautics and Space Administration; information security program;</p>
                    <p>14 CFR 1213 – Release of information to news and information media;</p>
                    <p>15 CFR pt. 744 – Export administration regulations; control policy: end-user and end-use based;</p>
                    <p>22 CFR pt. 62 – Department of State; exchange visitor program;</p>
                    <p>22 CFR 120-130 – Foreign Relations Export Control;</p>
                    <p>41 CFR pt. 101 – Federal property management regulations.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The maintenance of these records supports NASA protective services and security operations as well as the establishment of identities, processing of access requests, and issuance of credentials in NASA’s authoritative identity source.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>This system maintains information on NASA (1) civil servant employees and applicants; (2) committee members; (3) consultants; (4) experts; (5) Resident Research Associates; (6) guest workers; (7) contractor employees; (8) detailees; (9) visitors; (10) correspondents (written and telephonic); (11) Faculty Fellows; (12) Intergovernmental Personnel Mobility Act (IPA) Employees, interns, Grantees, and Cooperative Employees; and (13) Remote Users of NASA Non-Public Information Technology Resources.  This system also maintains information on all non-U.S. citizens, to include Lawful Permanent Residents seeking access to NASA facilities, resources, laboratories, contractor sites, Federally Funded Research and Development Centers or NASA sponsored events for unclassified purposes to include employees of NASA or NASA contractors; prospective NASA or NASA contractor employees; employees of other U.S. Government agencies or their contractors; foreign students at U.S. institutions; officials or other persons employed by foreign governments or other foreign institutions who may or may not be involved in cooperation with NASA under international agreements; foreign media representatives; and representatives or agents of foreign national governments seeking access to NASA facilities, to include high-level protocol visits; or international relations. While not considered ‘individuals’ under The Privacy Act, this system maintains records on international individuals when applicable.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Personnel Security Records, Personal Identity Records including NASA visitor files, Emergency Data Records, Criminal Matters, Traffic Management Records, and Access Management Records. Specific records fields include, but are not limited to: Name, former names, date of birth, place of birth, social security number, home address, phone numbers, email address, citizenship, duty Center, traffic infraction, security violation, security incident, security violation discipline status, action taken, access permissions, area accessed, and date accessed.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information is obtained from a variety of sources including from the employee, contractor, or applicant directly or via use of the Standard Form (SF) SF–85, SF–85P, or SF–86 and personal interviews; employers’ and former employers’ records; FBI criminal history records and other databases; financial institutions and credit reports; medical records and health care providers; educational institutions; interviews of witnesses such as neighbors, friends, coworkers, business associates, teachers, landlords, or family members; tax records; and other public records. Security violation information is obtained from a variety of sources, such as guard reports, security inspections, witnesses, supervisor’s reports, audit reports.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. Under the following routine uses that are unique to this system of records, information in this system may be disclosed:</p>
                    <p>(1) to the Department of Justice (DOJ) when: (a) The agency or any component thereof; (b) any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; (c) any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where agency or the DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or (d) the United States Government, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and by careful review, the agency determines that the records are both relevant and necessary to the litigation and the use of such records by DOJ is therefore deemed by the agency to be for a purpose compatible with the purpose for which the agency collected the records.</p>
                    <p>(2) to a court or adjudicative body in a proceeding when: (a) The agency or any component thereof; (b) any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; (c) any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where agency or the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or (d) the United States Government, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and by careful review, the agency determines that the records are both relevant and necessary to the litigation and the use of such records is therefore deemed by the agency to be for a purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which the agency collected the records.</p>
                    <p>(3) to an Agency in order to provide a basis for determining preliminary visa eligibility.</p>
                    <p>(4) to a staff member of the Executive Office of the President in response to an inquiry from the White House.</p>
                    <p>(5) to the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. §§ 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    <p>(6) to agency contractors, grantees, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform their activity. Recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. § 552a.</p>
                    <p>(7) to other Federal agencies and relevant contractor facilities to determine eligibility of individuals to access classified National Security information.</p>
                    <p>(8) to any official investigative or judicial source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.</p>
                    <p>(9) to the news media or the general public, factual information the disclosure of which would be in the public interest and which would not constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, consistent with Freedom of Information Act standards.</p>
                    <p>(10) to a Federal, State, or local agency, or other appropriate entities or individuals, or through established liaison channels to selected foreign governments, in order to enable an intelligence agency to carry out its responsibilities under the National Security Act of 1947 as amended, the CIA Act of 1949 as amended, Executive Order 12333 or any successor order, applicable national security directives, or classified implementing procedures approved by the Attorney General and promulgated pursuant to such statutes, orders or directives.</p>
                    <p>(11) in order to notify an employee’s next-of-kin or contractor in the event of a mishap involving that employee or contractor.</p>
                    <p>(12) to notify another Federal agency when, or verify whether, a PIV card is valid.</p>
                    <p>(13) to provide relevant information to an internal or external organization or element thereof conducting audit activities of a NASA contractor or subcontractor.</p>
                    <p>(14) to a NASA contractor, subcontractor, grantee, or other Government organization information developed in an investigation or administrative inquiry concerning a violation of a Federal or state statute or regulation on the part of an officer or employee of the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, or other Government organization.</p>
                    <p>(15) to foreign governments or international organizations if required by treaties, international conventions, or executive agreements.</p>
                    <p>(16) to members of a NASA Advisory Committee or Committees and interagency boards charged with responsibilities pertaining to international visits and assignments and/or national security when authorized by the individual or to the extent the committee(s) is so authorized and such disclosure is required by law.</p>
                    <p>(18) to the following individuals for the purpose of providing information on traffic accidents, personal injuries, or the loss or damage of property: (a) Individuals involved in such incidents; (b) persons injured in such incidents; (c) owners of property damaged, lost or stolen in such incidents; and/or (d) these individuals’ duly verified insurance companies, personal representatives, employers, and/or attorneys. The release of information under these circumstances should only occur when it will not: (a) interfere with ongoing law enforcement proceedings, (b) risk the health or safety of an individual, or (c) reveal the identity of an informant or witness that has received an explicit assurance of confidentiality. Social security numbers should not be released under these circumstances unless the social security number belongs to the individual requester. The intent of this use is to facilitate information flow to parties who need the information to adjudicate a claim.</p>
                    <p>(19) to the Transportation Security Administration, with consent of the individual on whom the records are maintained, to establish eligibility for the TSA Pre✓ program.</p>
                    <p>(20) in accordance with NASA standard routine uses as set forth here. In addition, the following routine uses of information contained in SORs, subject to the Privacy Act of 1974, are standard for many NASA systems. They are cited by reference in the paragraph "Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purpose of such uses" of the Federal Register Notice on those systems to which they apply.  Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 1—In the event this system of records indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the SOR may be referred to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 2—A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 3— A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on the matter.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 4—A record from this system may be disclosed to the Department of Justice including United States Attorney Offices, or other federal agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative or administrative body, when it is relevant or necessary to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation when  a) the Agency, or any component thereof; or b) any employee of the Agency in his or her official capacity; or c) any employee of the Agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the Agency has agreed to represent the employee or former employee; or d) the United States, where the Agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the Agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the Agency is deemed by the Agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 5—A record from this SOR may be disclosed in an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body, when NASA determines that the records are relevant to the proceeding; or in an appropriate proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 6—A record from this SOR may be disclosed to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) NASA suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) NASA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, NASA (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with NASA’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 7—A record from this system may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the federal government, when necessary to accomplish an Agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 8—A record from this system may be disclosed to a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member’s behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No.9—A record from this system may be disclosed to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when NASA determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use No. 10—To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) or the General Services Administration (GSA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    <p>Standard Routine Use11—To another agency, or organization for purpose of performing audit or oversight operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records in this system are maintained electronically and in hard-copy documents.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are retrieved from the system by individual’s name, file number, badge number, decal number, payroll number, Agency-specific unique personal identification code, and/or Social Security Number.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Personnel Security Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS), Schedule 1 Item 103.  Foreign national files are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NRRS, Schedule 1 Item 35.</p>
                    <p>Personal Identity Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed in accordance with NRRS, Schedule 1 Item 103.  Visitor files are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NRRS, Schedule 1 Item 114.</p>
                    <p>Emergency Data Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NRRS 1, Item 100B.</p>
                    <p>Criminal Matter Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NRRS 1, Schedule 97.5, Items A and B.</p>
                    <p>Traffic Management Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with NRRS 1, Schedule 97.5, Item C.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605. Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers. Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources (OA-9999-M-MSF-2712, OA-9999-M-MSF-2707, IE-999-M-MSF-1654). Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods. Access to electronic records is achieved only by utilizing NASA agency managed authentication mechanisms. Non-electronic records are secured in access-controlled rooms with electronic security countermeasures and agency managed, PIV enabled, physical authentication mechanisms.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
                    <p>Personnel Security Records compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment, Federal contracts, or access to classified information have been exempted by the Administrator under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5) from the access provisions of the Act.</p>
                    <p>Personal Identity Records: Requests from individuals should be addressed to the cognizant system or subsystem manager listed above.</p>
                    <p>Emergency Data Records: Requests from individuals should be addressed to the cognizant system or subsystem manager listed above.</p>
                    <p>Criminal Matter Records compiled for civil or criminal law enforcement purposes have been exempted by the Administrator under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) from the access provision of the Act.</p>
                    <p>Traffic Management Records: Requests from individuals should be addressed to the cognizant system or subsystem manager listed above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In accordance with 14 CFR part 1212, Privacy Act – NASA Regulations, information may be obtained by contacting in person or in writing the system or subsystem manager listed above at the location where the records are created and/or maintained.  Requests must contain the identifying data concerning the requester, e.g., first, middle and last name; date of birth; description and time periods of the records desired. NASA Regulations also address contesting contents and appealing initial determinations regarding records access.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Personnel Security Records compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment, Federal contracts, or access to classified information, but only to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a confidential source, are exempt from the following sections of the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) relating to access to the disclosure accounting; (d) relating to access to the records; (e)(1) relating to the type of information maintained in the records; (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I) relating to publishing in the annual system notice information as to agency procedures for access and correction and information as to the categories of sources of records; and (f) relating to developing agency rules for gaining access and making corrections. The determination to exempt the Personnel Security Records portion of the Security Records System has been made by the Administrator of NASA in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5) and Subpart 5 of the NASA regulations appearing in 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
                    <p>Criminal Matter Records to the extent they constitute investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes are exempt from the following sections of the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) relating to access to the disclosure accounting; (d) relating to access to the records; (e)(1) relating to the type of information maintained in the records; (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I) relating to publishing in the annual system notice information as to agency procedures for access and correction and information as to the categories of sources of records; and (f) relating to developing agency rules for gaining access and making corrections. The determination to exempt the Criminal Matter Records portion of the Security Records System has been made by the Administrator of NASA in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) and subpart 5 of the NASA regulations appearing in 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
                    <p>Records subject to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(1) required by Executive Order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy are exempt from the following sections of the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a:(c)(3) relating to access to the disclosure accounting; (d) relating to the access to the records; (e)(1) relating to the type of information maintained in the records; (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I) relating to publishing in the annual system notice information as to agency procedures for access and correction and information as to the categories of sources of records; and (f) relating to developing agency rules for gaining access and making corrections.</p>
                    <p>The determination to exempt this portion of the Security Records System has been made by the Administrator of NASA in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and subpart 5 of the NASA regulations appearing in 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>(15-115, 80 FR 246, pp. 79937-79947)</p>
                    <p>(15-068, 80 FR 193, pp. 60410-60411)</p>
                    <p>(11-091, 76 FR 200, pp. 64112-64114)</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="10sper" toc="yes">
    <systemNumber>10SPER</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName"> Special Personnel Records</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification">
       <xhtmlContent>
       <p>None</p> </xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Locations 1 through 9 inclusive, and locations 11 and 18 as set forth in Appendix A, and at the Department of Interior Federal Agency Human Resources Shared Service Center located at National Business Center 7301 W. Mansfield, Denver Co, 80235.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system maintains information on candidates for and recipients of awards or NASA training; civilian and active duty military detailees to NASA; participants in enrollee programs; Faculty, Science, National Research Council and other Fellows, associates and guest workers including those at NASA Centers but not on NASA rolls; NASA contract and grant awardees and their associates having access to NASA premises and records; individuals with interest in NASA matters including Advisory Committee Members; NASA employees and family members, prospective employees and former employees; former and current participants in existing and future educational programs, including the Summer High School Apprenticeship Research Program (SHARP).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Special Program Files including: (1) Foreign National Scientist files; (2) Applications for, and issuance of, passports and visas together with other information for international government travel; (3) Award files; (4) Counseling files, Life and Health Insurance, Retirement, Upward Mobility, and Work Injury Counseling files; (5) Military and Civilian detailee files; (6) Personnel Development files such as nominations for and records of training or education, Upward Mobility Program files, Intern Program files, Apprentice files, and Enrollee Program files; (7) Special Employment files such as Federal Junior Fellowship Program files, Pathways Program files, Summer Employment files, Worker-Trainee Opportunity Program files, NASA Executive Position files, Expert and Consultant files, and Cooperative Education Program files; (8) Welfare to Work files; and (9) Supervisory Appraisals under Competitive Placement Plan.</p>
            <p>Correspondence and related information including: (1) Claims correspondence and records about insurance such as life, health, and travel; (2) Congressional and other Special Interest correspondence, including employment inquiries; (3) Correspondence and records concerning travel related to permanent change of address; (4) Debt complaint correspondence; (5) Employment interview records; (6) Information related to outside employment and activities of NASA employees; (7) Placement follow-ups; (8) Preemployment inquiries and reference checks; (9) Preliminary records related to possible adverse actions; (10) Records related to reductions in force; (11) Records under administrative as well as negotiated grievance procedures; (12) Separation information including exit interview records, death certificates and other information concerning death, retirement records, and other information pertaining to separated employees; (13) Special planning analysis and administrative information; (14) Performance appraisal records; (15) Working papers for prospective or pending retirements.</p>
            <p>Special Records and Rosters including: (1) Locator files, (2) Ranking lists of employees; (3) Promotion candidate lists; (4) Retired military employee records; (5) Retiree records; (6) Follow-up records for educational programs, such as the SHARP and other existing or future programs.</p>
            <p>Agencywide and Center automated personnel information: Rosters, applications, recommendations, assignment information and evaluations of Faculty, Science, National Research Council and other Fellows, associates and guest workers including those at NASA Centers but not on NASA rolls; also, information about NASA contract and grant awardees and their associates having access to NASA premises and records.</p>
            <p>Information about members of advisory committees and similar organizations: All NASA-maintained information of the same types as, but not limited to, that information required in systems of records for which the Office of Personnel Management and other Federal personnel-related agencies publish Government wide Privacy Act Notices in the Federal Register.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>
                Records in this system enable NASA to manage Personnel records used to make personnel employment decisions and to facilitate decisions regarding employees' rights and benefits of employees, and other special personnel associated with NASA and listed in Categories of Individuals of this system notice.
            </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>51 U.S.C.  20113(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. The following are routine uses: (1) disclosures to organizations or individuals having contract, legal, administrative or cooperative relationships with NASA, including labor unions, academic organizations, governmental organizations, non-profit organizations, and contractors and to organizations or individuals seeking or having available a service or other benefit or advantage. The purpose of such disclosures is to satisfy a need or needs, further cooperative relationships, offer information, or respond to a request; (2) disclosures to Federal agencies developing statistical or data presentations having need of information about individuals in the records; (3) responses to other Federal agencies and other organizations having legal or administrative responsibilities related to programs and individuals in the records; and (4) NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Storage:</p>
            <p>Records in this system are maintained as hard-copy documents and on electronic media.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retrieved from the system by any one or a combination of name, birth date, Social Security Number, or NASA unique identification number.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, NASA server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Electronic messages sent within and outside of the Agency that convey sensitive data are encrypted and transmitted by staff via pre-approved electronic encryption systems as required by NASA policy.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers. The Department of Interior Federal agency Human Resources Shared Service Center in Denver is also compliant with the FISMA and OMB Circular A-130 security standards and requirements.</p>
            <p>Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or locked file cabinets. For information systems maintained by NASA partners, who collect, store and process records on behalf of NASA, NASA requires documentation and verification of commensurate safeguards in accordance with FISMA, NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 2810.1A, and NASA ITS-HBK-2810.02-05.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained and dispositioned in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules (NRRS) 3, Item 19.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Associate Administrator for Human Capital Management, Location 1. Subsystem Managers: Director, Personnel Division, Office of Inspector General, and Chief, Elementary and Secondary Programs Branch, Educational Division, Location 1; Director of Personnel, Locations 1, 3, 4, 6, and 8; Director of Human Resources, Location 2, 5, and 9; Director, Office of Human Resources, Location 7; Human Resources Officer, Location 11; Director, Human Resources Services Division, Location 18. Locations are as set forth in Appendix A.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Apply to the System or Subsystem Manager at the appropriate location above.  In addition to personal identification (name, Social Security Number), indicate the specific type of record, the appropriate date or period of time, and the specific category of individual applying (e.g., employee, former employee, contractor employee).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Same as Notification procedures above.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>The NASA regulations pertaining to access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by individual concerned are set forth in 14 CFR part 1212.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Individual on whom the record is maintained and Personnel Office(s).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> None.
           </p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    <section id="10xroi" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>10XROI</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Exchange Records on Individuals.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None. </p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Locations 1"9, 11, 12, 18, and 19, as set forth in Appendix A. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system maintains information on present and former employees of, and applicants for employment with, NASA Exchanges, recreational associations, and employees' clubs at NASA Centers; and civil servants and contractors, and their dependents, who are members of or participants in NASA Exchange programs, activities, clubs and/or recreational associations.  Finally, the system maintains information on children, and their parents or guardians, who participate in Exchange-operated child care and educational development programs.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>For present and former employees of NASA Exchange entities including child care and educational development center programs, records in the system relate to personnel actions and determinations during their application to and employment by the NASA Exchange.  Records contain information about individuals and their employment such as name, birth date, Social Security Number, home contact information, marital status, references, veteran preference, tenure, disabilities, position description, unemployment claims; salary, leave and payroll deduction information; and job performance and personnel actions.   </p>
<p>For civil servants, contractors, and others who apply for and participate in Exchange-sponsored programs, activities, clubs and/or recreational associations, records include employee or contractor identification number, organization, location, telephone number, and other information directly related to status or interest in participation in such activities. </p>
<p>For civil servant or contractor dependents who apply for Exchange scholarships, records in the system include information such as parents" home and work address and telephone numbers, income, and financial assistance they will provide the student; the student"s high school and colleges applied to, high school graduation date, class ranking, and transcripts; and student community activities and personal goals.  </p>
<p>For current or former participants in Exchange-operated child care and development centers, records in the system include identification and other information facilitating enrollment in the entity and proper care of the children.  Specific records include information such as home and work addresses, email addresses, and telephone numbers; financial payment information; emergency contact names, addresses and telephone numbers; children"s names and pictures as well as their health care and insurance providers; medical histories; physical, emotional, or other special care requirements; and child care and educational development center correspondence with parents/guardians such as authorizations to release the child to another person or field trip permission slips. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a) and (c)(5); 44 U.S.C. 3101; and 40 U.S.C. 590. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are used to facilitate individuals" participation in and use of NASA Exchange programs and fitness and childcare facilities; for application evaluation and award of Exchange higher education scholarships; and to execute personnel actions and determinations for applicants to, and employees of, the Exchange entities at NASA Centers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information. The following are routine uses: (1) to provide information to insurance carriers with regard to worker's compensation, health and accident, and retirement insurance coverages; (2) to provide employment or credit information to third parties as requested by a current or former Exchange employee to whom the records pertain; (3) to provide various Federal, State, and local taxing authorities itemized listing of withholdings for individual income taxes; (4) to respond to State employment compensation requests for wage and separation data on former employees; (5) to report previous job injuries to worker's compensation organizations; (6) for person to notify in an emergency; (7) to report unemployment records to appropriate State and local authorities; and (8) NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained on electronic media and/or as hard-copy documents. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>All records are retrieved from the system by the individual's name.  For children or parents/guardians associated with child care facilities, records may be retrieved by either the child"s or parent"s/guardian"s name.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Electronic records are maintained on secure NASA servers and protected in accordance with all Federal standards and those established in NASA regulations at 14 CFR 1212.605.  Additionally, server and data management environments employ infrastructure encryption technologies both in data transmission and at rest on servers.  Approved security plans are in place for information systems containing the records in accordance with the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 (FISMA) and OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information Resources.  Only authorized personnel requiring information in the official discharge of their duties are authorized access to records through approved access or authentication methods.  Access to electronic records is achieved only from workstations within the NASA Intranet or via a secure Virtual Private Network (VPN) connection that requires two-factor hardware token authentication or via employee PIV badge authentication from NASA-issued computers.  Non-electronic records are secured in locked rooms or files. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained in Agency files and destroyed in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 9 Item 6/D. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Contractor Industrial Relations Officer, Location 1. </p>
<p>Subsystem Managers: Exchange Store Operations Manager, Location 1; Exchange Council Chair, Location 2, Exchange Operations Manager, Locations 3"5; Chairperson, Exchange Council, Location 6 and 7; Treasurer, NASA Exchange, Location 8; Exchange Operations Manager, Locations 9, 12, and 19; President, NASA Exchange, Location 11; and NSSC Exchange Counsel, Location 18. Locations are as set forth in Appendix A. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals may obtain information from the cognizant subsystem managers listed above. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information on oneself or one"s child may be obtained by submitting a written request to the appropriate system or subsystem manager listed above. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The NASA rules for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial determinations by the individual concerned appear in the NASA rules at 14 CFR part 1212. </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information is obtained directly from the individual on whom the record is maintained and the individual's supervisor, or from parents/guardians of children enrolled in the child care and educational development centers. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="51eui" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>51EUI</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Earth Observing System Data and Information System (EOSDIS) User Information.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Twelve DAACs locations, Clearing House (middleware system), Earth Science Data and
Information System (ESDIS) Metrics System (system that gathers various metrics for EOSDIS) and the
Land Atmosphere Near Real-time Capability for EOS (LANCE) as listed below:
</p><p>1. Goddard Earth Sciences (GES) Data and Information Services Center (DISC) DAAC at Location 4 as
set forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>2. Level-1 Atmosphere Archive and Distribution System (LAADS) at Location 4 as set forth in
Appendix A.
</p><p>3. Ocean Biology Processing Group (OBPG) at Location 4 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>4. Crustal Dynamics Data and Information System (CDDIS) at Location 4 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>5. Atmospheric Science Data Center (ASDC) DAAC at Location 7 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>6. Global Hydrology Resource Center (GHRC) DAAC at Location 9 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>7. Physical Oceanography Distributed Active Archive Center (PO.DAAC) at Location 10 as set forth
in Appendix A.
</p><p>8. Alaska Satellite Facility SAR Data Center DAAC, University of Alaska, Fairbanks, AK 99775
-7320.
</p><p>9. Land Processes Distributed Active Archive Center (LP DAAC), Earth Resources Observation and
Science (EROS), 47914 252nd Street, Sioux Falls, SD 57918-0001.
</p><p>10. National Snow and Ice Data Center DAAC, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.
</p><p>11. Oak Ridge National Laboratory DAAC, Oak Ridge, TN 37381-6407.
</p><p>12. Socioeconomic Data and Applications Center, Center for International Earth Science
Information Network (CIESIN) at Columbia University, Palisades, NY 10964.
</p><p>13. EOS Clearing House (ECHO) at Location 4 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>14. ESDIS Metrics System (EMS) at Location 4 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>15. Land Atmosphere Near Real-time Capability for EOS (LANCE) at Location 4 as set forth in
Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals from the NASA, university, and research communities, as well as the general
public, who request satellite data or other data products from any of the EOSDIS DAACs indicated
above, or individuals who register to save their data search parameters for reuse in the future.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system consist of information obtained from individual users that enables
those users to receive notices of improved or altered data and services, as well as actual science
data from EOSDIS, most often via on-line mechanisms. Records include an individual"s name and
business contact information consisting of mailing addresses, telephone numbers and email addresses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>51 U.S.C. 20113(a).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Any disclosures of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency
collected the information. The records and information in these records may be disclosed:
</p><p>(1) To government contractors conducting OMB-approved annual user satisfaction surveys collecting
user feedback for aggregating reports to OMB and enabling NASA to improve its systems, processes,
and services to the user community;
</p><p>(2) To the European Space Agency (ESA) through public posting on a NASA Web site of ESA
scientific data users" professional information such as their name, address, and organizational
affiliation to achieve ESA member nation awareness of the breadth of their scientific data use (this
applies to ESA scientific data hosted by NASA); and
</p><p>(3) In accordance with NASA standard routine uses set forth in Appendix B.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records at all the entities named in section titled System Location are stored in electronic
form.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>User account records are typically indexed and retrieved by user"s name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are in commercial data base management systems that are password-protected for
access by only key authorized employees with appropriately configured system roles. Approved
security plans for each of the 15 entities listed in the section titled System Location have been
established in accordance with OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Information
Resources. The aggregation of these plans constitutes the security plan for EOSDIS. Individuals will
have access to the system only in accordance with approved authentication methods. With the
exception of the records of ESA scientific data users" information posted in accordance with Routine
Use (3) above, all specific user information kept in our systems is managed according to NASA
guidelines for managing sensitive information. Paper and electronic copies are kept offline in
locked cabinets. This information is updated on a yearly basis, and superseded records deleted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The EOSDIS Project has a plan under configuration control according to which the original
data are deleted in accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedule 2, Item 15A.3. Only aggregated
statistics on those original records are kept. The DAACs reauthorize specific users" information on
an approved basis and user information is deleted when no longer needed in accordance with NASA
Records Retention Schedule 2, Item 19A. Mailing lists containing user information are maintained in
order to permit distribution of newsletters to users and are disposed of according to the NASA
Records Retention Schedule 1, Item 88.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>System Manager: 423/Science Operations Office Manager, ESDIS Project, Location 4 as set
forth in Appendix A.
</p><p>Subsystem Managers: DAAC Managers at each of the locations 1-12 whose addresses are listed
under item System Location above; and 423/ECHO Manager, 423/EMS Manager, and 423/LANCE Manager, all
at Location 4 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals inquiring about their records should contact the System Manager at the address
given above and provide their name and email address. The System Manager can be reached by phone at
(301) 614-5048.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who wish to gain access to their records should submit their request in writing
to the System Manager at the address provided or by phone at (301) 614-5048.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The NASA regulations governing access to records and procedures for contesting the contents,
and for appealing initial determinations are set forth in 14 CFR part 1212.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is received electronically or via telephone directly from users needing to
obtain or access NASA"s Earth science data products.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="72xopr" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>72XOPR</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Johnson Space Center Exchange Activities Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Location 5 as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system maintains information on employees and past employees of Johnson Space Center
(JSC) Exchange Operations, and JSC employees or JSC contractor employees participating in sports or
special activities sponsored by the Exchange.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>For present and past employees of the JSC Exchange Operations, the system includes a variety
of records relating to personnel actions and determinations made about an individual while employed
by the NASA Exchange-JSC. These records contain information about an individual relating to birth
date; Social Security Number; home address and telephone number; marital status; references; veteran
preference, tenure, handicap; position description, past and present salaries, payroll deductions,
leave; letters of commendation and reprimand; adverse actions, charges and decisions on charges;
notice of reduction in force; personnel actions, including but not limited to, appointment,
reassignment, demotion, detail, promotion, transfer and separation; minority group; records relating
to life insurance, health and retirement benefits; designation of beneficiary; training; performance
ratings; physical examinations; criminal matters; data documenting the reasons for personnel actions
or decisions made about an individual; awards; and other information relating to the status of the
individual.
</p><p>For participants in social or sports activities sponsored by the Exchange, information includes
employees" or contractors" employee identification number, organization, location, telephone number,
and other information directly related to status or interest in participation in such activities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>42 U.S.C. 2473; 44 U.S.C. 3101; NASA Policy Directive 9050.6; Treasury Fiscal Requirement
Manual, Part III.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The following are routine uses for information maintained on JSC Exchange Operations
employees only: (1) Provide information in accordance with legal or policy directives and
regulations to the Internal Revenue Service, Department of Labor, Department of Commerce, Texas
State Government Agencies, labor unions; (2) provide information to insurance carriers with regard
to worker"s compensation, health and accident, and retirement insurance coverages; (3) provide
employment or credit information to other parties as requested by a current or former employee of
the JSC Exchange Operations; and (4) NASA standard routine uses as set forth in Appendix B.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are maintained as hard-copy documents and on electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>For JSC Exchange employees, records are retrieved from the system by name and filed as
current or past employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Payroll records are located in locked metal file cabinets with access limited to those whose
official duties require access. Other records are located in file cabinets available only in rooms
where the access is limited to those whose official duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel records of JSC Exchange operations employees are retained indefinitely in Agency
space to satisfy payroll, reemployment, unemployment compensation, tax, and employee retirement
purposes. For successful applicants under the JSC Exchange Scholarship Program, records are
maintained until completion of awarded scholarship and are then destroyed. Records pertaining to
unsuccessful applicants are destroyed. For participants in social or sports activities, records are
maintained for stated participation period and are then destroyed. These dispositions are in
accordance with NASA Records Retention Schedules, Schedule 9 Item 6/E.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Manager, Exchange Operations, NASA Exchange-JSC, Location 5, as set forth in Appendix A.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals may obtain information from the System Manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The NASA regulations for access to records and for contesting contents and appealing initial
determinations by the individual concerned appear in 14 CFR part 1212.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>For employees of the JSC Exchange Operations, information is obtained from the individual
employee, the employee references, insurance carriers, JSC Health Services Division, JSC Security,
employment agencies, Texas Employment Commission, credit bureaus, and creditors. For JSC employees
and JSC contractor employees participating in social or sports activities sponsored by the Exchange,
information is obtained from the individual participant.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
	


<appendix id="appa" toc="yes" letter="A">
<title>Location Numbers and Mailing Addresses of NASA Installations at Which Records Are Located
</title>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><i>Location 1
</i></p><p>NASA Headquarters, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Washington, DC 20546
-0001.
</p>
<p><i>Location 2
</i></p>
<p>Ames Research Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Moffett Field, CA 94035
-1000.
</p>
<p><i>Location 3
</i></p>
<p>Dryden Flight Research Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, PO Box 273,
Edwards, CA 93523-0273.
</p>
<p><i>Location 4
</i></p>
<p>Goddard Space Flight Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Greenbelt, MD
20771-0001.
</p>
<p><i>Location 5
</i></p>
<p>Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Houston, TX
77058-3696.
</p>
<p><i>Location 6
</i></p>
<p>John F. Kennedy Space Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Kennedy Space
Center, FL 32899-0001.
</p>
<p><i>Location 7
</i></p>
<p>Langley Research Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Hampton, VA 23681
-2199.
</p>
<p><i>Location 8
</i></p>
<p>John H. Glenn Research Center at Lewis Field, National Aeronautics and Space Administration,
21000 Brookpark Road, Cleveland, OH 44135-3191.
</p>
<p><i>Location 9
</i></p>
<p>George C. Marshall Space Flight Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration,
Marshall Space Flight Center, AL 35812-0001.
</p>
<p><i>Location 10
</i></p>
<p>HQ NASA Management Office--JPL, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 4800 Oak
Grove Drive, Pasadena, CA 91109-8099.
</p>
<p><i>Location 11
</i></p>
<p>John C. Stennis Space Center, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Stennis Space
Center, MS 39529-6000.
</p>
<p><i>Location 12
</i></p>
<p>JSC White Sands Test Facility, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, PO Drawer MM,
Las Cruces, NM 88004-0020.
</p>
<p><i>Location 13
</i></p>
<p>GRC Plum Brook Station, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Sandusky, OH 44870.
</p>
<p><i>Location 14
</i></p>
<p>MSFC Michoud Assembly Facility, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, PO Box 29300,
New Orleans, LA 70189.
</p>
<p><i>Location 15
</i></p>
<p>NASA Independent Verification and Validation Facility (NASA IV&amp;V), 100 University Drive,
Fairmont, WV 26554.
</p>
<p><i>Location 16
</i></p>
<p>New Jersey Post of Duty, 402 East State Street, Trenton, NJ 08608.
</p>
<p><i>Location 17
</i></p>
<p>Western Field Office, Glenn Anderson Federal Building, 501 West Ocean Blvd., Long Beach, CA
90802-4222.
</p>
<p><i>Location 18
</i></p>
<p>NASA Shared Services Center (NSSC), Building 5100, Stennis Space Center, MS 39529-
6000.
</p>
<p><i>Location 19</i></p>
<p>NASA Wallops Flight Facility, Wallops Island, VA 23337.
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>

<appendix id="appb" toc="yes" letter="B">
<title>Standard Routine Uses</title>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>The following routine uses of information contained in SORs, subject to the Privacy Act of 1974,
are standard for many NASA systems. They are cited by reference in the paragraph "Routine uses
of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purpose of such uses" of the <i>Federal Register</i> Notice on those systems to which they apply. Any disclosures
of information will be compatible with the purpose for which the Agency collected the information.
Standard Routine Use No. 1--In the event this system of records indicates a violation or
potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by
general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant
thereto, the relevant records in the SOR may be referred to the appropriate agency, whether Federal,
State, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such
violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued
pursuant thereto.
</p><p>Standard Routine Use No. 2--A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal, State, or
local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other
pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to an
agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security
clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit.
</p><p>Standard Routine Use No. 3--A record from this SOR may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in
response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of
a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract,
or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that
the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency"s decision on the matter.
</p><p>Standard Routine Use No. 4--A record from this system may be disclosed to the Department of
Justice when (a) the Agency, or any component thereof; or (b) any employee of the Agency in his or
her official capacity; or (c) any employee of the Agency in his or her individual capacity where the
Department of Justice or the Agency has agreed to represent the employee; or (d) the United States,
where the Agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the Agency or any of its components,
is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the
Department of Justice or the Agency is deemed by the Agency to be relevant and necessary to the
litigation provided, however, that in each case it has been determined that the disclosure is
compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>Standard Routine Use No. 5--A record from this system may be disclosed in a proceeding
before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when: (a) The
Agency, or any component thereof; or (b) any employee of the Agency in his or her official capacity;
or (c) any employee of the Agency in his or her individual capacity where the Agency has agreed to
represent the employee; or (d) the United States, where the Agency determines that litigation is
likely to affect the Agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in
such litigation, and the use of such records by the Agency is deemed to be relevant and necessary to
the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the Agency has determined that the disclosure
is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>Standard Routine Use No. 6--A record from this SOR may be disclosed to appropriate agencies,
entities, and persons when (1) NASA suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality
of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) NASA has determined that as a
result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property
interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other
systems or programs (whether maintained by NASA or another agency or entity) that rely upon the
compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is
reasonably necessary to assist in connection with NASA"s efforts to respond to the suspected or
confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>Standard Routine Use No. 7--A record from this system may be disclosed to contractors,
grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service,
grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the federal government, when necessary to
accomplish an Agency function related to this system of records.
</p><p>Standard Routine Use No. 8--A record from this system may be disclosed to a Member of
Congress or staff acting upon the Member"s behalf when the Member or staff requests the information
on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>
	

<regulations id="reg1" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="14">
<heading> Aeronautics and Space </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="V">
<heading> National Aeronautics and Space Administration </heading>
<regulationsPart number="1212">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT--NASA REGULATIONS </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.1--Basic Policy</b>
</p>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>1212.100 Scope and purpose.
</p>
<p>1212.101 Definitions.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.2--Requests for Access to Records</b>
</p>
<p>1212.200 Procedures for requesting records subject to the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>1212.201 Requesting a record.
</p>
<p>1212.202 Identification procedures.
</p>
<p>1212.203 Disclosures.
</p>
<p>1212.204 Fees.
</p>
<p>1212.205 Exceptions to individuals’ rights of access.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.3--Amendments to Privacy Act Records
</b></p>
<p>1212.300 Requesting amendment.
</p>
<p>1212.301 Processing the request to amend.
</p>
<p>1212.302 Granting the request to amend.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.4--Appeals and Related Matters
</b></p>
<p>1212.400 Appeals.
</p>
<p>1212.401 Filing statements of dispute.
</p>
<p>1212.402 Disclosure to third parties of disputed records.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.5--Exemptions to Individuals’ Rights of Access
</b></p>
<p>1212.500 Exemptions under 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) and (k).
</p>
<p>1212.501 Record systems determined to be exempt.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.6--Instructions for NASA Employees
</b></p>
<p>1212.600 General policy.
</p>
<p>1212.601 Maintenance and publication requirements for systems of records.
</p>
<p>1212.602 Requirements for collecting information.
</p>
<p>1212.603 Mailing lists.
</p>
<p>1212.604 Social security numbers.
</p>
<p>1212.605 Safeguarding information in systems of records.
</p>
<p>1212.606 Duplicate copies of records or portions of records.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.7--NASA Authority and Responsibilities
</b></p> 
<p>1212.700 NASA employees.
</p>
<p>1212.701 Associate Deputy Administrator.
</p>
<p>1212.702 The Inspector General.
</p>
<p>1212.703 NASA Chief Information Officer.
</p>
<p>1212.704 Headquarters and Field Centers or Component Facilities.
</p>
<p>1212.705 System manager.
</p>
<p>1212.706 Assistant Administrator for Procurement.
</p>
<p>1212.707 Delegation of authority.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.8--Failure To Comply With Requirements of This Part
</b></p> 
<p>1212.800 Civil remedies.
</p>
<p>1212.801 Criminal penalties.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> The National Aeronautics and Space Act, as amended, 51 U.S.C. 20101 <i>et seq.;</i> the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 88 Stat. 1896, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, unless otherwise noted.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.1--Basic Policy

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.100
 Scope and purpose.
</b></p>
<p>This part 1212 implements the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552a). It establishes procedures for individuals to access their Privacy Act records and to request amendment of information in records concerning them. It also provides procedures for administrative appeals and other remedies. This part applies to systems of records located at or under the cognizance of NASA Headquarters, NASA Field Centers, and NASA Component Installations, as defined in part 1201 of this chapter.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.101
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For the purposes of this part, the following definitions shall apply in addition to definitions contained in the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552a):
</p>
<p>(a) The term <i>individual</i> means a living person who is either a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.
</p>
<p>(b) The term <i>maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use or disseminate.
</p>
<p>(c) The term <i>record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual including, but not limited to, education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history, and that contains a name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print or a photograph.
</p>
<p>(d) The term <i>system of records</i> means a group of any records from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p>(e) The term <i>system manager</i> means the NASA official who is responsible for a system of records as designated in the system notice of that system of records published in the <i>Federal Register.</i> When a system of records includes portions located at more than one NASA Center, the term <i>system manager</i> includes any subsystem manager designated in the system notice as being responsible for that portion of the system of records located at the respective Center.
</p>
<p>(f) The term <i>systems notice</i> means, with respect to a system of records the publication of information in the <i>Federal Register</i> upon establishment or revision of the existence and character of the system of records. The notice shall include that information as required by 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4).
</p>
<p>(g) The term <i>routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of the record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p>
<p>(h) The term <i>NASA employee</i> or <i>NASA official,</i> particularly for the purpose of &#167; 1212.203(g) relates to the disclosure of a record to those who have a need for the record in the performance of their official duties, includes employees of a NASA contractor which operates or maintains a NASA system of records for or on behalf of NASA.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.2--Requests for Access to Records

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.200
 Procedures for requesting records subject to the Privacy Act.
</b></p>
<p>The procedures outlined in this subpart 1212.2 apply to the following types of requests made by individuals under the Privacy Act concerning records about themselves:
</p>
<p>(a) To determine if information on the requester is included in a system of records;
</p>
<p>(b) For access to a record under 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(1); and
</p>
<p>(c) For an accounting of disclosures of the individual’s Privacy Act records under 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3).
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.201 Requesting a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Individuals may request access to their Privacy Act records, either in person or in writing.
</p>
<p>(b) Individuals may also authorize a third party to have access to their Privacy Act records. This authorization shall be in writing, signed by the individual and contain the individual’s address as well as the name and address of the representative being authorized access. The identities of both the subject individual and the representative must be verified in accordance with the procedures set forth in &#167; 1212.202 of this part.
</p>
<p>(c)(1) Requests must be directed to the appropriate system manager, or, if unknown, to the Center Privacy Manager or Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Office at NASA Headquarters or Field Center. The request should be identified clearly on the envelope and on the letter as a "Request Under the Privacy Act."
</p>
<p>(2) Where possible, requests should contain the following information to ensure timely processing:
</p>
<p>(i) Name and address of subject.
</p>
<p>(ii) Identity of the system of records.
</p>
<p>(iii) Nature of the request.
</p>
<p>(iv) Identifying information specified in the applicable system notice to assist in identifying the request, such as location of the record, if known, full name, birth date, time periods in which the records are believed to have been compiled, etc.
</p>
<p>(d) NASA has no obligation to comply with a nonspecific request for access to information concerning an individual, e.g., a request to provide copies of "all information contained in your files concerning me," although a good faith effort will be made to locate records if there is reason to believe NASA has records on the individual. If the request is so incomplete or incomprehensible that the requested record cannot be identified, additional information or clarification will be requested in the acknowledgement, and assistance to the individual will be offered as appropriate.
</p>
<p>(e) If the Center Privacy Manager receives a request for access, the Privacy Manager will record the date of receipt and immediately forward the request to the responsible system manager for handling.
</p>
<p>(f) If the Center FOIA Office receives a first party request for records or access, the FOIA Office will process the request under the Privacy Act pursuant to this part.
</p>
<p>(g) Normally, the system manager shall respond to a request for access within 10 work days of receipt of the request and the access shall be provided within 30 work days of receipt.
</p>
<p>(1) In response to a request for access, the system manager shall:
</p>
<p>(i) Notify the requester that there is no record on the individual in the system of records and inform the requester of the procedures to follow for appeal (See &#167; 1212.4);
</p>
<p>(ii) Notify the requester that the record is exempt from disclosure, cite the appropriate exemption, and inform the requester of the procedures to follow for appeal (See &#167; 1212.4);
</p>
<p>(iii) Upon request, promptly provide copies of the record, subject to the fee requirements (&#167; 1212.204); or
</p>
<p>(iv) Make the individual’s record available for personal inspection in the presence of a NASA representative.
</p>
<p>(2) Unless the system manager agrees to another location, personal inspection of the record shall be at the location of the record as identified in the system notice.
</p>
<p>(3) When an individual requests records in a system of records maintained on a third party, the request shall be processed as a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request under 14 CFR part 1206. If the records requested are subject to release under FOIA (5 U.S.C. 552(b)), then a Privacy Act exemption may not be invoked to deny access.
</p>
<p>(4) When an individual requests records in a system of records maintained on the individual, the request shall be processed under this part. NASA will not rely on exemptions contained in FOIA to withhold any record which is otherwise accessible to the individual under this part.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012; 78 FR 8963, Feb. 7, 2013]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.202
 Identification procedures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The system manager will release records to the requester or representative in person only upon production of satisfactory identification which includes the individual’s name, signature, and photograph or physical description.
</p>
<p>(b) The system manager will release copies of records by mail only when the circumstances indicate that the requester and the subject of the record are the same. The system manager may require that the requester’s signature be notarized or witnessed by two individuals unrelated to the requester.
</p>
<p>(c) Identity procedures more stringent than those required in this section may be prescribed in the system notice when the records are medical or otherwise sensitive.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.203
 Disclosures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The system manager shall keep a disclosure accounting for each disclosure to a third party of a record from a system of records. This includes records disclosed pursuant to computer matching programs.
</p>
<p>(b) Disclosure accountings are not required but are recommended for disclosures made:
</p>
<p>(1) With the subject individual’s consent; or
</p>
<p>(2) In accordance with &#167; 1212.203(f) (1) and (2), below.
</p>
<p>(c) The disclosure accounting required by paragraph (a) of this section shall include:
</p>
<p>(1) The date, nature, and purpose of the disclosure; and
</p>
<p>(2) The name and address of the recipient person or Agency.
</p>
<p>(d) The disclosure accounting shall be retained for at least 5 years after the disclosure or for the life of the record, whichever is longer.
</p>
<p>(e) The disclosure accounting maintained under the requirements of this section is not itself a system of records. 
</p>
<p>(f) Records in a NASA system of records may not be disclosed to third parties without the consent of the subject individual. However, in consonance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), disclosure may be authorized without consent, if disclosure would be:
</p>
<p>(1) To an officer or employee of NASA who has a need for the record in the performance of official duties;
</p>
<p>(2) Required under the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552) and part 1206 of this chapter;
</p>
<p>(3) For a routine use described in the system notice for the system of records;
</p>
<p>(4) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity pursuant to the provisions of Title 13, U.S. Code;
</p>
<p>(5) To a recipient who has provided NASA with advance adequate written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable;
</p>
<p>(6) To the National Archives and Records Administration as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the United States Government or for evaluation by the Archivist of the United States or the Archivist’s designee to determine whether the record has such value;
</p>
<p>(7) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity, if the activity is authorized by law and if the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a written request to NASA specifying the particular portion desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought;
</p>
<p>(8) To a person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual if upon such disclosure notification is transmitted to the last known address of such individual;
</p>
<p>(9) To either House of Congress or, to the extent the matter is within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee, or any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee;
</p>
<p>(10) To the Comptroller General, or any of the Comptroller’s authorized representative(s), in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office;
</p>
<p>(11) Pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction; or
</p>
<p>(12) To a consumer reporting agency in accordance with section 3711(f) of Title 31.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.204
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Fees will not be charged for:
</p>
<p>(1) Search for a retrieval of the requesting individual’s records;
</p>
<p>(2) Review of the records;
</p>
<p>(3) Making a copy of a record when it is a necessary part of the process of making the record available for review;
</p>
<p>(4) Transportation of the record(s);
</p>
<p>(5) Making a copy of an amended record to provide evidence of the amendment; or
</p>
<p>(6) Copies of records if this is determined to be in the best interest of the Government.
</p>
<p>(b) Fees for the duplication of records will be assessed in accordance with &#167; 1206.700(a) of this chapter.
</p>
<p>(c) Where it appears that duplication fees chargeable under this section will exceed $25, the requester shall be provided an estimate of the fees before copies are made. Where possible, the requester will be afforded the opportunity to confer with Agency personnel in a manner which will reduce the fees, yet still meet the needs of the requester.
</p>
<p>(d) Where the anticipated fee chargeable under this section exceeds $25, an advance deposit of part or all of the anticipated fee may be required.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.205
 Exceptions to individual’s rights of access.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The NASA Administrator has determined that the systems of records set forth in &#167; 1212.501 are exempt from disclosure to the extent provided therein.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Medical records.</i> Normally, an individual’s medical record shall be disclosed to the individual, unless the system manages, in consultation with a medical doctor, determines that access to the record could have an adverse effect upon the individual. In this case, NASA shall allow access to the record by a medical doctor designated in writing by the requesting individual.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Test and qualification materials.</i> Testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the Federal service the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process and copies of certificates of eligibles and other lists of eligibles, the disclosure of which is proscribed by 5 CFR 300.201, shall be removed from an individual’s record containing such information before granting access.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Information compiled for civil actions or proceedings.</i> Nothing in this part shall allow an individual access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
</p><p><b>Subpart 1212.3--Amendments to Privacy Act Records

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.300
 Requesting amendment.
</b></p>
<p>Individuals may request that NASA amend their records maintained in a NASA system of records under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(2). This request shall be in writing, addressed to the appropriate system manager, and shall contain the following:
</p>
<p>(a) A notation on the envelope and on the letter that it is a "Request for Amendment of Individual Record under the Privacy Act;"
</p>
<p>(b) The name of the system of records;
</p>
<p>(c) Any information necessary to retrieve the record, as specified in the system notice for the system of records (See &#167; 1212.201(c)(2));
</p>
<p>(d) A description of that information in the record which is alleged to be inaccurate, irrelevant, untimely, or incomplete; and,
</p>
<p>(e) Any documentary evidence or material available to support the request.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.301
 Processing the request to amend.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Within 10 work days of receipt by NASA of a request to amend a record, the system manager shall provide the requester with a written determination or acknowledgement advising when action may be taken.
</p>
<p>(b) When necessary, NASA may utilize up to 30 work days after receipt to provide the determination on a request to amend a record.
</p>
<p>(c) If the request for amendment is denied, the determination shall explain the reasons for the denial and inform the requester of the procedures to follow for appeal (See &#167; 1212.4)).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.302
 Granting the request to amend.
</b></p>
<p>NASA shall make the requested amendment clearly on the record itself and all information deemed to be inaccurate, irrelevant, or untimely shall be deleted and destroyed. Incomplete information shall either be amended or deleted and destroyed. The individual shall then be informed in writing that the amendment has been made. If the inaccurate, irrelevant, untimely, or incomplete portion of the record has previously been disclosed, then the system manager shall notify those persons or agencies of the amended information, referencing the prior disclosures (See &#167; 1212.402).
</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.4--Appeals and Related Matters

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.400
 Appeals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Individuals may appeal when they:
</p>
<p>(1) Have requested amendment of a record and have received an adverse initial determination;
</p>
<p>(2) Have been denied access to a record; or,
</p>
<p>(3) Have not been granted access within 30 work days of their request.
</p>
<p>(b) The Associate Deputy Administrator or designee is responsible for making final determinations of appeals as specified in paragraphs (a)(1) through (3) of this section for all Agency records, with the exception of those records originating in the Office of the Inspector General for which the Inspector General is responsible for making final determinations of appeals.
</p>
<p>(c) An appeal shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Be in writing and addressed to the Associate Deputy Administrator, NASA, Washington, DC 20546 or to the Inspector General, NASA Headquarters, Washington, DC 20546, for records as specified in paragraph (b) of this section;
</p>
<p>(2) Be identified clearly on the envelope and in the letter as an "Appeal under the Privacy Act;"
</p>
<p>(3) Include a copy of any pertinent documents; and
</p>
<p>(4) State the reasons for the appeal.
</p>
<p>(d) Appeals from adverse initial determinations or denials of access must be submitted within 30 work days of the date of the requester’s receipt of the initial determination. Appeals involving failure to grant access may be submitted any time after the 30 work day period has expired (See &#167; 1212.201(f)).
</p>
<p>(e) A final determination on an appeal shall be made within 30 work days after its receipt by the Associate Deputy Administrator or Inspector General for appeals concerning records originating in the Office of the Inspector General, unless, for good cause shown, the Associate Deputy Administrator or Inspector General extends such 30 work day period. Prior to the expiration of the 30 work day period, the requester shall be notified of any such extension.
</p>
<p>(f) If a denial of a request to amend a record is upheld, the final determination shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Explain the basis for the detail;
</p>
<p>(2) Include information as to how the requester goes about filing a statement of dispute under the procedures of &#167; 1212.401; and,
</p>
<p>(3) Include a statement that the final determination is subject to judicial review under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.401
 Filing statements of dispute.
</b></p>
<p>(a) A statement of dispute shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Be in writing;
</p>
<p>(2) Set forth reasons for the individual’s disagreement with NASA’s refusal to amend the record;
</p>
<p>(3) Be concise;
</p>
<p>(4) Be addressed to the system manager; and,
</p>
<p>(5) Be identified on the envelope and in the letter as a "Statement of Dispute under the Privacy Act."
</p>
<p>(b) The system manager shall prepare an addendum to the statement explaining the basis for NASA’s refusal to amend the disputed record. A copy of the addendum shall be provided to the individual.
</p>
<p>(c) The system manager shall ensure that the statement of dispute and addendum are either filed with the disputed record or that a notation appears in the record clearly referencing the statement of dispute and addendum so that they may be readily retrieved.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.402
 Disclosure to third parties of disputed records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The system manager shall promptly provide persons or agencies to whom the disputed portion of a record was previously disclosed and for which an accounting of the disclosure exists under the requirements of &#167; 1212.203 of this part, with a copy of the statement of dispute and addendum, along with a statement referencing the prior disclosure. The subject individual shall be notified as to those individuals or agencies which are provided with the statement of dispute and addendum.
</p>
<p>(b) Any subsequent disclosure of a disputed record shall clearly note the portion of the record which is disputed and shall be accompanied by a copy of the statement of dispute and addendum.
</p><p><b>Subpart 1212.5--Exemptions to Individuals’ Rights of Access

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.500
 Exemptions under 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) and (k).
</b></p>
<p>(a) These provisions authorize the Administrator of NASA to exempt certain NASA Privacy Act systems of records from portions of the requirements of this regulation.
</p>
<p>(b) The Administrator has delegated this authority to the Associate Deputy Administrator (See &#167; 1212.701).
</p>
<p>(c) For those NASA systems of records that are determined to be exempt, the system notice shall describe the exemption and the reasons.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.501
 Record systems determined to be exempt.
</b></p>
<p>The Administrator has determined that the following systems of records are exempt to the extent provided hereinafter.
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Inspector General Investigations Case Files</i>--(1) <i>Sections of the Act from which exempted.</i> (i) The Inspector General Investigations Case Files system of records is exempt from all sections of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) except the following sections: (b) relating to conditions of disclosure; (c) (1) and (2) relating to keeping and maintaining a disclosure accounting; (e)(4) (A) through (F) relating to publishing a system notice setting forth name, location, categories of individuals and records, routine uses, and policies regarding storage, retrievability, access controls, retention and disposal of the records; (e) (6), (7), (9), (10), and (11) relating to dissemination and maintenance of records, and (i) relating to criminal penalties. This exemption applies to those records and information contained in the system of records pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws.
</p>
<p>(ii) To the extent that noncriminal investigative files may exist within this system of records, the Inspector General Investigations Case Files system of records is exempt from the following sections of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a): (c)(3) relating to access to the disclosure accounting, (d) relating to access to records, (e)(1) relating to the type of information maintained in the records; (e)(4) (G), (H), and (I) relating to publishing the system notice information as to agency procedures for access and amendment and information as to the categories of sources or records, and (f) relating to developing agency rules for gaining access and making corrections.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Reason for exemptions.</i> (i) The Office of Inspector General is an office of NASA, a component of which performs as its principal function activity pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws, within the meaning of 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2). This exemption applies only to those records and information contained in the system of records pertaining to criminal investigations. This system of records is exempt for one or more of the following reasons:
</p>
<p>(A) To prevent interference with law enforcement proceedings.
</p>
<p>(B) To avoid unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, by disclosure of information about third parties, including other subjects of investigation, investigators, and witnesses.
</p>
<p>(C) To protect the identity of Federal employees who furnish a complaint or information to the OIG, consistent with section 7(b) of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. App.
</p>
<p>(D) To protect the confidentiality of non-Federal employee sources of information.
</p>
<p>(E) To assure access to sources of confidential information, including that contained in Federal, State, and local criminal law enforcement information systems.
</p>
<p>(F) To prevent disclosure of law enforcement techniques and procedures.
</p>
<p>(G) To avoid endangering the life or physical safety of confidential sources and law enforcement personnel.
</p>
<p>(ii) Investigative records within this system of records which are compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of subsection (j)(2), are exempt under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2): <i>Provided, however,</i> That if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that they would otherwise be entitled by Federal law, or for which they would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, such material shall be provided to such individual, except to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or, prior to January 1, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the sources would be held in confidence. This system of records is exempt for one or more of the following reasons:
</p>
<p>(A) To prevent interference with law enforcement proceedings.
</p>
<p>(B) To protect investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes.
</p>
<p>(C) To avoid unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, by disclosure of information about third parties, including other subjects of investigation, law enforcement personnel, and sources of information.
</p>
<p>(D) To fulfill commitments made to protect the confidentiality of sources.
</p>
<p>(E) To protect the identity of Federal employees who furnish a complaint or information to the OIG, consistent with section 7(b) of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. App.
</p>
<p>(F) To assure access to sources of confidential information, including that contained in Federal, State, and local criminal law enforcement information systems.
</p>
<p>(G) To prevent disclosure of law enforcement techniques and procedures.
</p>
<p>(H) To avoid endangering the life or physical safety of confidential sources and law enforcement personnel.
</p>
<p>(iii) Records within this system of records comprised of investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability or eligibility for Federal civilian employment or access to classified information, are exempt under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), but only to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or prior to January 1, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence. This system of records is exempt for one or more of the following reasons:
</p>
<p>(A) To fulfill commitments made to protect the confidentiality of sources.
</p>
<p>(B) To assure access to sources of confidential information, including that contained in Federal, State, and local criminal law enforcement information systems.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Security Records System</i>--(1) <i>Sections of the Act from which exempted.</i> The Security Records System is exempted from the following sections of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a): (c)(3) relating to access to the disclosure accounting; (d) relating to access to the records; (e)(1) relating to the type of information maintained in the records; (e)(4) (G), (H), and (I) relating to publishing the system notice information as to agency procedures for access and amendment, and information as to the categories of sources of records; and (f) relating to developing Agency rules for gaining access and making corrections.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Reason for exemption.</i> (i) Personnel Security Records contained in the system of records which are compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for Federal civilian employment, Federal contracts, or access to classified information are exempt under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), but only to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of the source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or, prior to January 1, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the sources would be held in confidence. This system of records is exempt for one or more of the following reasons:
</p>
<p>(A) To fulfill commitments made to protect the confidentiality of sources.
</p>
<p>(B) To assure access to sources of confidential information, including that contained in Federal, State, and local criminal law enforcement information systems.
</p>
<p>(ii) Criminal Matter Records are contained in the system of records and are exempt under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2): <i>Provided, however,</i> That if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that they would otherwise be entitled by Federal law, or for which they would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, such material shall be provided to such individual, except to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or, prior to January 1, 1975, under an implied promise that the identity of the sources would be held in confidence. This system of records is exempt for one or more of the following reasons:
</p>
<p>(A) To prevent interference with law enforcement proceedings.
</p>
<p>(B) To protect investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes.
</p>
<p>(C) To avoid unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, by disclosure of information about third parties, including other subjects of investigation, law enforcement personnel, and sources of information.
</p>
<p>(D) To fulfill commitments made to protect the confidentiality of sources.
</p>
<p>(E) To assure access to sources of confidential information, including that contained in Federal, State, and local criminal law enforcement information systems.
</p>
<p>(F) To prevent disclosure of law enforcement techniques and procedures.
</p>
<p>(G) To avoid endangering the life or physical safety of confidential sources and law enforcement personnel.
</p>
<p>(iii) The system of records includes records subject to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(1) (required by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy), and such records are exempt under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1).
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.6--Instructions for NASA Employees

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.600
 General policy.
</b></p>
<p>In compliance with the Privacy Act and in accordance with the requirements and procedures of this regulation, NASA has an obligation to:
</p>
<p>(a) Advise individuals, when requested, as to whether any specific system of records maintained by NASA contains records pertaining to them;
</p>
<p>(b) Prevent records being maintained by NASA in a system of records for a specific purpose from being used or made available for another purpose without the individual’s consent; and,
</p>
<p>(c) Permit individuals to have access to information about themselves in a NASA system of records, to have a copy made, and, if appropriate under subpart 1212.3 of this part, to amend the records.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.601
 Maintenance and publication requirements for systems of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) In maintaining systems of records, NASA shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Maintain any record in a system of records for necessary and lawful purposes only, assure that the information is current and accurate for its intended use, and provide adequate safeguards to prevent misuse of the information.
</p>
<p>(2) Maintain only information about an individual relevant and necessary to accomplish a purpose or to carry out a function of NASA authorized by law or by Executive order of the President.
</p>
<p>(3) Maintain records used by NASA officials in making any determination about any individual with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness reasonably necessary to assure fairness to the individual in making the determination.
</p>
<p>(4) Maintain no record describing how an individual exercises rights guaranteed by the First Amendment unless expressly authorized by statute, by the individual about whom the record is maintained or unless pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized law enforcement activity.
</p>
<p>(5) Maintain and provide access to records of other agencies under NASA’s control consistent with the regulations of this part.
</p>
<p>(b) Any system of records maintained by NASA which is in addition to or substantially different from a Governmentwide systems of records described in a systems notice published by another agency shall be regarded as a NASA system of records subject to the requirements of this part.
</p>
<p>(c) NASA shall provide adequate advance notice to Congress and OMB of any proposal to establish a new system of records or alter any existing system of records as prescribed by OMB Circular No. A-130, appendix I.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.602
 Requirements for collecting information.
</b></p>
<p>In collecting information for systems of records, the following requirements shall be met:
</p>
<p>(a) Information shall be collected to the greatest extent practicable directly from the subject individual when the information may result in adverse determinations about an individual’s rights, benefits, and privileges under Federal programs. Exceptions to this policy may be made under certain circumstances, such as one of the following:
</p>
<p>(1) There is a need to verify the accuracy of the information supplied by an individual.
</p>
<p>(2) The information can only be obtained from a third party.
</p>
<p>(3) There is no risk that information collected from third parties, if inaccurate, could result in an adverse determination to the individual concerned.
</p>
<p>(4) Provisions are made to verify with the individual information collected from a third party.
</p>
<p>(b) Each individual who is asked to supply information shall be informed of the following:
</p>
<p>(1) The authority (whether granted by statute, or by Executive order of the President) for requesting the information;
</p>
<p>(2) Whether disclosure is mandatory or voluntary;
</p>
<p>(3) The intended official use of the information; 
</p>
<p>(4) The routine uses which may be made of the information, as published in the system notices;
</p>
<p>(5) The effects, if any, on the individual of not providing all or any part of the requested information.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.603
 Mailing lists.
</b></p>
<p>NASA will not sell, rent, or otherwise disclose an individual’s name and address to anyone, unless otherwise specifically authorized by law. This is not to be construed to require the withholding of names and addresses otherwise permitted to be made public.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.604
 Social security numbers.
</b></p>
<p>(a) It is unlawful for NASA to deny to individuals any rights, benefits, or privileges provided by law because of the individuals’ refusal to disclose their social security numbers, except where:
</p>
<p>(1) The disclosure is required by law; or
</p>
<p>(2) The disclosure is from a system of records in existence and operating before January 1, 1975, and was required under statute or regulation adopted before that date to verify the identity of the individual(s).
</p>
<p>(b) Any time individuals are requested to disclose their social security numbers, NASA shall indicate whether that disclosure is mandatory or voluntary, by what authority the numbers are requested, and what uses will be made of them.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.605
 Safeguarding information in systems of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Safeguards appropriate for a NASA system of records shall be developed by the system manager in a written plan approved by the Center Security Officer or Center Information Technology Security Officer for electronic records maintained in automated systems. Safeguards must insure the security and confidentiality of records and protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to their security or integrity which could result in substantial harm, embarrassment, inconvenience, or unfairness to any individual on whom information is maintained.
</p>
<p>(b) When records or copies of records are distributed within NASA they shall be prominently identified as records protected under the Privacy Act and shall be subject to the same safeguard, retention, and disposition requirements applicable to the system of records.
</p>
<p>(c) When records or copies of records are distributed to other Federal agencies, other than those having custody of the systems of records, they shall be prominently identified as records protected under the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(d) Records that are otherwise required by law to be released to the public need not be safeguarded or identified as Privacy Act records.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.606
 Duplicate copies of records or portions of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) NASA officials may maintain and use, for official purposes, duplicate copies of records or portions of records from a system of records maintained by their own organizational unit. This practice should occur only where there are justifiable organizational needs for it, e.g., where geographic distances make use of the system of records time consuming or inconvenient. These duplicate copies shall not be considered a separate NASA system of records. For example, an office head or designee may keep duplicate copies of personnel, training, or similar records on employees within the organization for administrative convenience purposes.
</p>
<p>(b) No disclosure shall be made from duplicate copies outside of the organizational unit. Any outside request for disclosure shall be referred to the appropriate system manager for response.
</p>
<p>(c) Duplicate copies are subject to the same safeguard requirements applicable to the system of records.</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.7--NASA Authority and Responsibilities

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.700
 NASA employees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Each NASA employee is responsible for adhering to the requirements of the Privacy Act and this regulation.
</p>
<p>(b) An employee shall not seek or obtain access to a record in a NASA system of records or to copies of any portion of such records under false pretenses. Only those employees with an official "need to know" may seek and obtain access to records pertaining to others.
</p>
<p>(c) Employees shall refrain from discussing or disclosing personal information about others which they have obtained because of their official need to know such information in the performance of official duties.
</p>
<p>(d) To the extent included in a contract which provides for the maintenance by or on behalf of NASA of a system of records to accomplish a function of NASA, the requirements of this section shall apply to contractor employees who work under the contract.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.701
 Associate Deputy Administrator.
</b></p>
<p>The Associate Deputy Administrator is responsible for:
</p>
<p>(a) Making final Agency determinations on appeals (&#167; 1212.400), except on those related to records originating in the Office of the Inspector General;
</p>
<p>(b) Authorizing exemptions from one or more provisions of the Privacy Act for NASA systems of records (See &#167; 1212.500); and,
</p>
<p>(c) Authorizing an extension for making a final determination on an appeal (&#167; 1212.400(d)), except for an appeal related to records originating in the Office of the Inspector General.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992, as amended at 77 FR 60621, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.702
 The Inspector General.
</b></p>
<p>The Inspector General is responsible for:
</p>
<p>(a) Making final Agency determinations on appeals related to records originating with the Office of the Inspector General (&#167; 1212.400), and
</p>
<p>(b) Authorizing an extension for making a final determination on an appeal related to records originating with the Office of the Inspector General (&#167; 1212.400(e)).
</p>
<p>[77 FR 60622, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.703
 NASA Chief Information Officer.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The NASA Chief Information Officer is responsible for the following:
</p>
<p>(1) Providing overall supervision and coordination of NASA’s policies and procedures under this regulation;
</p>
<p>(2) Approving system notices for publication in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(3) Assuring that NASA employees and officials are informed of their responsibilities and that they receive appropriate training for the implementation of these requirments; and,
</p>
<p>(4) Preparing and submitting the biennial report on implementation of the Privacy Act to OMB and special reports required under this regulation, including establishing appropriate reporting procedures in accordance with OMB Circular No. A-130.
</p>
<p>(b) The Chief Information Officer may establish a position of ‘NASA Privacy Act Officer,’designate someone to function as such an officer, and delegate to that officer any of the functions described in paragraph (a) of this section.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992. Redesignated and amended at 77 FR 60622, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.704
 Headquarters and Field Centers or Component Facilities.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Officials-in-Charge of Headquarters Offices, Directors of NASA Field Centers and Officials-in-Charge of Component Facilities are responsible for the following with respect to those systems of records maintained in their organization:
</p>
<p>(1) Avoiding the establishment of new systems of records or new routine uses of a system of records without first complying with the requirements of this regulation;
</p>
<p>(2) Ensuring that the requirements of this regulation and the Privacy Act are followed by employees;
</p>
<p>(3) Ensuring that there is appropriate coordination within NASA before a determination is made to disclose information without the individual’s consent under authority of 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) (See &#167; 1212.203(f)); and
</p>
<p>(4) Providing appropriate oversight for responsibilities and authorities exercised by system managers under their jurisdiction (&#167; 1212.705).
</p>
<p>(5) Establish a position of Center Privacy Manager to assist in carrying out the responsibilities listed in this section.
</p>
<p>(b) [Reserved]
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992. Redesignated and amended at 77 FR 60622, Oct. 4, 2012; 78 FR 8964, Feb. 7, 2013]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.705
 System manager.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Each system manager is responsible for the following with regard to the system of records over which the system manager has cognizance:
</p>
<p>(1) Overall compliance with this part, NASA Policy Directive (NPD) 1382.17 and NASA Procedural Requirements (NPR) 1382.1.
</p>
<p>(2) Ensuring that each person involved in the design, development, operation, or maintenance of the system of records is instructed with respect to the requirements of this regulation and the possible penalties for noncompliance;
</p>
<p>(3) Submitting a request to the Associate Deputy Administrator for an exemption of the system under subpart 1212.5 of this part, setting forth in proposed rulemaking form the reasons for the exemption and citing the specific provision of the Privacy Act which is believed to authorize the exemption;
</p>
<p>(4) After consultation with the Office of the General Counsel or the Chief Counsel, making reasonable efforts to serve notice on an individual when any record on such individual is made available to any person under compulsory legal process when such process becomes a matter of public record;
</p>
<p>(5) Making an initial determination on an individual’s request to correct or amend a record, in accordance with &#167; 1212.302;
</p>
<p>(6) Prior to disclosure of any record about an individual, assuring that the record is first reviewed for accuracy, completeness, timeliness, and relevance;
</p>
<p>(7) Authorizing disclosures of a record without the individual’s consent under &#167; 1212.203(f)(1) through (12);
</p>
<p>(8) Responding within the requirements of &#167; 1212.200 to an individual’s request for information as to whether the system contains a record pertaining to the individual;
</p>
<p>(9) Responding to an individual’s request for access and copying of a record, in accordance with subpart 1212.2 of this part;
</p>
<p>(10) Amending a record under subpart 1212.3 of this part, or filing in an individual’s record a statement of dispute;
</p>
<p>(11) Preparing an addendum to an individual’s statement of dispute to be filed in the individual’s records, in accordance with &#167; 1212.401;
</p>
<p>(12) Maintaining disclosure accountings in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(c) and &#167; 1212.203 of this part. This includes records disclosed pursuant to any computer matching programs;
</p>
<p>(13) Notifying persons to whom a record has been disclosed and for which an accounting was made as to disputes and corrections involving the record; and
</p>
<p>(14) Developing appropriate safeguards for the system of records in accordance with &#167; 1212.605(a).
</p>
<p>(b) Where a system of records has subsystems described in the system notice, the subsystem manager will have the responsibilities outlined in paragraph (a) of this section. Although the system manager has no line authority over subsystem managers, the system manager does have overall functional responsibility for the total system, and may issue guidance to subsystem managers on implementation of this part. When furnishing information for required reports, the system manager will be responsible for reporting the entire system of records, including any subsystems.
</p>
<p>(c) Exercise of the responsibilities and authorities in paragraph (a) of this section by any system or subsystem managers at a NASA Center shall be subject to any conditions or limitations imposed in accordance with &#167; 1212.704(a)(4) and (5).
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992. Redesignated and amended at 77 FR 60622, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.706
 Assistant Administrator for Procurement.
</b></p>
<p>The Assistant Administrator for Procurement is responsible for developing appropriate procurement regulations and procedures under which NASA contracts requiring the maintenance of a system of records in order to accomplish a NASA function are made subject to the requirements of this part.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992. Redesignated at 77 FR 60622, Oct. 4, 2012]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.707
 Delegation of authority.
</b></p>
<p>Authority necessary to carry out the responsibilities specified in this regulation is delegated to the officials named, subject to any conditions or limitations imposed in accordance with this subpart 1212.7.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 4928, Feb. 11, 1992. Redesignated at 77 FR 60622, Oct. 4, 2012]</p>
<p><b>Subpart 1212.8--Failure To Comply With Requirements of This Part

</b></p> 
<p><b>&#167; 1212.800
 Civil remedies.
</b></p>
<p>Failure to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act and this part could subject NASA to civil suit under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1212.801
 Criminal penalties.
</b></p>
<p>(a) A NASA officer or employee may be subject to criminal penalties under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(i) (1) and (2).
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Section 552a(i)(1).</i> Any officer or employee of an agency, who by virtue of employment or official position, has possession of, or access to, agency records which contain individually identifiable information the disclosure of which is prohibited by this section or by rules or regulations established thereunder, and who knowing that disclosure of the specific material is so prohibited, willfully discloses the material in any manner to any person or agency not entitled to receive it, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Section 552a(i)(2).</i> Any officer or employee of any agency who willfully maintains a system of records without meeting the notice requirements of subsection (e)(4) of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.
</p>
<p>(3) These two provisions apply to NASA civil service employees as well as those employees of a NASA contractor with responsibilities for maintaining a Privacy Act system of records.
</p>
<p>(b) Section 552a(i)(3). Any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual from an agency under false pretenses shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>

