<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>


<pai>
<agency toc="yes"> 
<name>Corporation for National and Community Service</name>
<abbrev>
CNCS
</abbrev>

    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-01-16/pdf/2020-00581.pdf</url>
        <title>CNCS-03-OIG–Investigative Files (Corp 15)  </title>
        <date year="2020" month="1" day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-01-23/pdf/2020-01080.pdf</url>
        <title>CNCS-04-CPO-MMF–Member Management Files (MMF)--new; Corporation 3, 4, 8, and 18 rescinded.  </title>
        <date year="2020" month="1" day="23" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-05-15/pdf/2020-10477.pdff</url>
        <title>Travel Files—Corporation-7 and Travel Authorization Files—Corporation-16; rescinded.  </title>
        <date year="2020" month="5" day="15" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-05-15/pdf/2020-10478.pdf</url>
        <title>Join Senior Service Now Web-based Recruiting System (JASON)—Corporation-20; rescinded.  </title>
        <date year="2020" month="5" day="15" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-05-15/pdf/2020-10480.pdf</url>
        <title>Employee/Member Occupational Injury/Illness Reports and Claim Files—Corporation-6; rescinded.  </title>
        <date year="2020" month="5" day="15" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-02-01/pdf/2021-02071.pdf</url>
        <title>Privacy Act of 1974; Matching Program</title>
        <date year="2021" month="2 " day=" 1" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-18/pdf/2021-24868.pdf</url>
        <title>CNCS-10-CEO-PHRI, Personal Health and Religious Information (PHRI</title>
        <date year="2021" month="11 " day=" 18" />
    </previouslyPublished>


    <section id="CORPORATION 1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Momentum Financials Open Obligations and Automated Disbursement
Files

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Office of Accounting and Financial Management Services, Corporation for National and Community
Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Individuals to whom the agency owes money.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name of
payee, address, ABA routing
number, financial institution name and address, depositor account number, taxpayer identification number,
amount owed, date of liability, amount paid, schedule number authorizing the U.S. Department of the
Treasury to issue payment and returned or cancelled payments.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as
amended; the National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended, and the Budget and Accounting
Procedures Act of 1950, as amended; the Chief Financial Officer Act of 1990; and the Debt Collection
Improvement Act of 1996.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain a current record of amounts owed and paid by the
Corporation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>See General Routine Uses contained in Preliminary
Statement. Data is also released to the Internal Revenue Service in accordance with the Internal Revenue
Code.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Records are maintained electronically, and file folders are stored in locked metal file cabinets.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Hardcopy records are indexed alphabetically by name and
electronic records may be accessed by name or taxpayer identification number.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are available only to staff in the Office of
Accounting and Financial Management Services and other appropriate Corporation officials with the need for
such records in the performance of their duties.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Hardcopy records are held for three (3) years and
then retired to the Federal Records Center. Electronic records are archived periodically.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Accounting and Financial Management
Services, Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>To determine whether there is a record in the
system about individual, that individual should submit a request in writing to the Records Liaison Officer
giving name, taxpayer identification number, and address.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See Notification procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Anyone desiring to contest or amend
information contained in this system should write to the Records Liaison Officer at the address given and
set forth the basis for which the record is believed to be incomplete or incorrect.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data in this system is obtained from documents
submitted by individuals covered by the system as well as documents issued by Corporation officials
involved with managing and disbursing funds.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="CORPORATION 2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Momentum Financials Accounts Receivable Files.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Office of Accounting and Financial Management Services, Corporation for National and Community
Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Individuals owing money to the Corporation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name of
debtor, address, taxpayer
identification number, amount owed, date of liability, and amount collected or amount forwarded to the U.S.
Treasury for further collection action as mandated by DCIA of 1996.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as
amended; the National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended; the Budget and Accounting Procedures
Act of 1950, as amended, and the Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain a current record of amounts owed and paid to the
Corporation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>See General Routine Uses contained in Preliminary Statement. Data may be disclosed to the U.S.
Department of Justice for litigation action; the U.S. Department of the Treasury to pursue further
collection action when the Corporation is unable to collect a debt through its own efforts and/or
recommended write-off; or to the General Accounting Office in connection with inquiries, audits or
investigations related to the Corporation's debt activities.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Records are maintained in file folders which are stored in locked metal file cabinets.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by name.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are available only to staff in the Office of
Accounting and Financial Management Services, other authorized Corporation officials with the need for such
records in the performance of their duties or forwarded to the U.S. Treasury for further collection action.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are held for three (3) years and then
retired to the Federal Records Center.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Accounting and Financial Management Services,
Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>To determine whether there is a record in the
system about an individual, that individual should submit a request in writing to the Records Liaison
Officer giving name, taxpayer identification number, and address.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See Notification procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Anyone desiring to contest or amend
information contained in this system should write to the Records Liaison Officer and set forth the basis
for which the record is believed to be incomplete or incorrect.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data in this system is obtained from documents
submitted by individuals covered by the system as well as documents issued by Corporation officials
involved with managing and collecting debts.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="CORPORATION 5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee and Applicant Records Files.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Human Resources, Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW.,
Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Current and former employees; applicants; individuals involved in a grievance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) The
Staff Security Files contain
investigative information regarding an individual's character, conduct or behavior in the community;
loyalty to the U.S. Government; arrests and convictions, interviews with former supervisors, coworkers,
associates, educators, etc., about qualifications for a specific position; and inquires with law
enforcement agencies, former employers, and educational institutions.

</p><p>(2) The Grievance, Appeal and Arbitration Files contain copies of petitions, complaints, charges,
responses, rebuttals, evidentiary materials, briefs, affidavits, statements, records of hearings and
decisions or findings of fact and incidental correspondence regarding complaints and appeals.

</p><p>(3) The Employees Indebtedness Files contain correspondence regarding alleged indebtedness of
Corporation employees, including employees' responses, the Corporation's response to the employee and/or
creditor and records relating to assistance to the employee in resolving indebtedness.

</p><p>(4) The Employee Reemployment and Repromotion Priority Consideration Files list a person's name and
the positions he or she was considered for, dates of consideration and a copy of the individual's latest
Standard Form 171 and performance evaluation.

</p><p>(5) The Performance Evaluation File consists of annual evaluations of employee performance prepared
by supervisors and reviewed by supervisory reviewing officials, together with employee's comments.

</p><p>(6) The Management-Union Records System consists of printouts of an employee's name, grade, series,
title, or organizational entity and other data which determine inclusion or exclusion from the bargaining
unit under the union contract. The printout also shows of dues withheld from each employee.

</p><p>(7) The Human Resources Management Information System is a record of employees' tenure, benefits
eligibility, awards, and other data used by Human Resources and Corporation managers.

</p><p>(8) The Personnel History Program is a record of personnel actions made during employment,
forwarding address, reason for leaving, social security number, date of birth, tenure, and information
regarding date and reason for termination.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as
amended; the National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended; provisions of the Federal Personnel
Manual; Executive Orders concerning management relations with employee organizations; Executive Order
10450; and various acts of Congress relating to personnel investigations as authorized by the Office of
Personnel Management.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide an information system which supports the
Corporation's personnel management program.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>As indicated below, the subsystems incorporate all
or some of the published routine uses.

</p><p>(1) Staff Security Files--in addition to routine uses, may be disclosed to the Office of Human
Resources as part of the personnel investigation records system.

</p><p>(2) Grievance, Appeal and Arbitration Records and Files--in addition to routine uses, may be
disclosed to (a) OPM; the Merit Systems Protection Board; and the Office of Special Counsel, on request in
conjunction with an appeal or with regard to personnel investigations regarding complaints of Federal
Employees and applicants; and (b) to designated hearing examiners, arbitrators and third-party appellate
authorities involved in hears or appeals.

</p><p>(3) Employees Indebtedness Records and Files--may be released under our routine uses numbers 1 and
2, except that under routine use number 1, records may be released to an appropriate Federal agency or
referred to a court or other administrative board on matters related to probation and parole.

</p><p>(4) Employee Reemployment and Repromotion Priority Consideration Records and Files--in addition to
routine uses, may be disclosed to: (a) OPM as part of the OPM personnel management evaluation system; and
(b) to OPM for information concerning reemployment and repromotion rights.

</p><p>(5) Performance Evaluation Files--in addition to our general routine uses, may be disclosed to an
OPM request for information.

</p><p>(6) Management Union Records--in addition to routine uses, may be disclosed to: (a) The Corporation
employees' union for dues maintenance and inclusion in the bargaining unit; (b) the Treasury Department for
preparation of dues withholding; and (c) OPM for management/labor relations reports.

</p><p>(7) Human Resources Management Information System--used by Corporation officials for day-to-day work
information; statistical reports without personal identifiers and for in-house reports relating to
management. Information contained in this record is reflected in the individual's official personnel
folder.

</p><p>(8) Personnel History Program--is used by the Human Resources staff to verify service and for other
day-to-day information.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Records, including file folders, floppy disks, lists and loose-leaf binders, are stored in metal
file cabinets with locks, or in secured rooms with access limited to employees whose duties require access.
Where data is obtained via computer, controlled access is maintained through computer security control
procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by name or social security number.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are available to Corporation employees having a need
in the performance of their duties. Generally, Security Files are available only to office heads or
security personnel.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>After termination, death, retirement, or
consideration of an applicant, the Staff Security Files are retained three (3) years and then retired to a
Federal Records Center for twenty-seven (27) years and then destroyed. The Grievances, Appeals and
Arbitration Files are retained indefinitely in Human Resources. The Employee Indebtedness Files are
destroyed on a bi-annual basis or when the indebtedness is resolved. The Employee Reemployment and
Repromotion Priority Consideration Files are retained according to length of reemployment or repromotion
eligibility. The Performance Evaluation Files are retained one year or until superseded. The Human
Resources Management Information System records and the Personnel Program data are kept indefinitely in the
Office of Human Resources. The Management-Union Lists are retained until superseded by a corrected or
updated list.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Human Resources, Corporation for National and
Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary
Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the
Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Same as "Record Access Procedures".

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From the individual; the official personnel
folder; statistical and other information developed by Human Resources staff, such as the enter on duty
date, and within grade increase due dates; agency supervisors and reviewing officials; individual employee
fiscal and payroll records; alleged creditors of employees; witnesses to occurrences giving rise to a
grievance, appeal, or other action; hearing records and affidavits and other documents used or usable in
connection with grievance, appeal and arbitration hearings. Information contained in the Staff Security
files is obtained from: (a) Applications and other personnel and security forms furnished by the
individual; (b) investigative material furnished by other Federal agencies; (c) personal investigation or
written inquiry from associates, police departments, courts, credit bureaus, medical records, probation
officials, prison officials, and other sources as may be developed from the above; and (d) the individual.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="CORPORATION 9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Counselors' Report Files.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Equal Opportunity Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York, Avenue,
NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Any employee or applicant for employment, service member, or applicant or trainee for volunteer or
service status, or employee of a grantee who has contacted or requested a Corporation Equal Opportunity
Counselor for counseling, but has not filed a formal discrimination complaint.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>
Counselors' Reports, Privacy Act
notice, confidentiality agreement, notice to members of collective bargaining agreement, notice of final
interview, notes and correspondence, and copies of personnel records or other documents relevant to the
matter presented to the Counselor, and any other records relating to the counseling instance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Titles VI and VII of the Civil Rights Act of
1964, as amended; Age Discrimination in Employment Act, as amended; Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended;
Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, as amended; Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as
amended; National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended; and the Age Discrimination Act, as
amended.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To enable Equal Opportunity Counselors to look into matters
brought to their attention, provide counseling, attempt to resolve the matter, and document actions taken.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Referral or disclosure: (a) To a Federal,
state, or local agency charged with the responsibility of investigating, enforcing, or implementing the
statute, rule, regulation, or order; (b) to an investigator, Counselor, grantee or other recipient of
Federal financial assistance, or hearing officer or arbitrator charged with the above responsibilities; (c)
any and all appropriate and necessary uses of such records in a court of law or before an administrative
board or hearing; and (d) such other referrals as may be necessary to carry out the enforcement and
implementation of the statutes, rules, regulations, or orders.

</p><p>2. Disclosure to the Congressional committees having legislative jurisdiction over the program
involved, including when actions are proposed to be undertaken by suspending or terminating or refusing to
grant or to continue Federal financial assistance for violation of the statutes, rules, regulations, or
orders for recipients of Federal financial assistance from the Corporation.

</p><p>3. Disclosure to any source, either private or governmental, to the extent necessary to secure from
source information relevant to, and sought in furtherance of, a legitimate investigation or EO counseling
matter.

</p><p>4. Disclosure to a contractor, grantee or other recipient of Federal financial assistance, when the
record to be released reflects serious inadequacies with the recipient's personnel, and disclosure of the
record is for the purpose of permitting the recipient to effect corrective action in the Government's best
interests.

</p><p>5. Disclosure to any party pursuant to the receipt of a valid subpoena.

</p><p>6. Disclosure during the course of presenting evidence to a court magistrate or administrative
tribunal of appropriate jurisdiction and such disclosure may include disclosure to opposing counsel in the
course of settlement negotiations.

</p><p>7. Disclosure to a member of Congress submitting a request involving an individual who is a
constituent of such member who has requested assistance from the member with respect to the subject matter
of the record.

</p><p>8. Information in any system of records may be used as a data source, for management information,
for the production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for
which the records are collected and maintained, or for related personnel management functions or manpower
studies. Information may also be disclosed to respond to general requests for statistical information
(without personal identification of individuals) under the Freedom of Information Act.

</p><p>9. Information in any system of records to be disclosed to a Congressional office, in response to an
inquiry from any such office, made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.

</p><p>10. A record from any system of records may be disclosed as a routine use of the National Archives
and Records Administration, in records management inspection conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 209 and
290.

</p><p>11. Referral to Federal, state, local and professional licensing authorities when the record to be
released reflects on the moral, educational, or vocational qualifications of an individual seeking to be
licensed.

</p><p>12. Disclosure to the Office of Government Ethics (OGE) for any purpose consistent with OGE's
mission, including the compilation of statistical data.</p>

<p><b>Note:</b> The Agency-wide statement of general routine uses does not apply to this system
of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Files are maintained in folders or computer diskettes and locked in metal file cabinets when not in
immediate use.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Retrievability is by the name of the person who
contacted the Counselor.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the system are available only to appropriate
personnel in the Office of Equal Opportunity and other designated officials of the Corporation with a need
for such records in the performance of their duties.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Two (2) years after completion of counseling, the
files are destroyed.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Equal Opportunity, Corporation for National and
Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Request by individuals on whether a record is
maintained about himself or herself should be addressed to the System Manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Request for access to these records should be
addressed to the System Manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contest to information included in these
records should be addressed to the System Manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data in this system is obtained from the
following categories of sources: (1) Aggrieved persons, witnesses, etc., in counseling matters; (2)
Counselors' Reports; (3) Copies of documents relevant to any counseling matter; and (4) Correspondence.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="CORPORATION 10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Discrimination Complaint Files.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Equal Opportunity Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue,
NW., Washington DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Any employee or applicant for employment, AmeriCorps member or applicant or trainee for volunteer
or service status, or employee of a grantee, or program beneficiary who has filed a formal complaint with,
or against, the Corporation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Formal
complaints, Reports of
Investigation, Counseling documents, case decisions, and relevant correspondence, including settlement
agreements.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Titles VI and VII of the Civil Rights Act of
1964, as amended; the Age Discrimination in Employment Act, as amended; the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as
amended; Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, as amended; the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of
1973, as amended; the National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended; and the Age Discrimination
Act, as amended.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To enable the Corporation to investigate and adjudicate
complaints of discrimination.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Referral or disclosure: (a) To a Federal,
state, or local agency charged with the responsibility of investigating, enforcing, or implementing the
statute, rule, regulation, or order; (b) to an investigator, counselor, grantee or other recipient of
Federal financial assistance or hearing officer or arbitrator charged with the above responsibilities; (c)
any and all appropriate and necessary uses of such records in a court of law or before an administrative
board or hearing; and (d) such other referrals as may be necessary to carry out the enforcement and
implementation of the statutes, rules, regulations, or orders.

</p><p>2. Disclosure to the Congressional committees having legislative oversight over the program
involved, including when actions are proposed to be undertaken by suspending or terminating or refusing to
grant or to continue Federal financial assistance for violation of the statutes, rules, regulations, or
orders for recipients of Federal financial assistance from the Corporation.

</p><p>3. Disclosure to any source, either private or governmental, to the extent necessary to secure from
source information relevant to, and sought in furtherance of, a legitimate investigation or EO counseling
matter.

</p><p>4. Disclosure to a contractor, grantee or other recipient of Federal financial assistance, when the
record to be released reflects serious inadequacies with the recipient's personnel, and disclosure of the
record is for the purpose of permitting the recipient to effect corrective action in the Government's best
interests.

</p><p>5. Disclosure to any party pursuant to the receipt of a valid subpoena.

</p><p>6. Disclosure during the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate or administrative
tribunal of appropriate jurisdiction and such disclosure may include disclosures to opposing counsel in the
course settlement negotiations.

</p><p>7. Disclosure to a member of Congress submitting a request involving an individual who has requested
assistance from the member with respect to the subject matter of the record.

</p><p>8. Information in any system of records may be used as a data source, for management information,
for the production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for
which the records are collected and maintained, or for related personnel management functions or manpower
studies. Information may also be disclosed to respond to general requests for statistical information
(without personal identification of individuals) under the Freedom of Information Act.

</p><p>9. A record from any system of records may be disclosed as a routine use of the National Archives
and Records Administration, in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2094
and 2906.

</p><p>10. Referral to Federal, state, local and professional licensing authorities when the record to be
released reflects on the moral, educational, or vocational qualifications of an individual seeking to be
licensed.

</p><p>11. Disclosure to the Office of Government Ethics (OGE) for any purpose consistent with OGE's
mission, including the compilation of statistical data.

</p><p><b>Note:</b> The Agency-wide statement of general routine uses does not apply to this system of
records.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Files are maintained in folders or on computer diskettes which are locked in metal file cabinets
when not in immediate use.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are retrieved by the complainant's name.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the system of records are available only to
appropriate personnel in Equal Opportunity and other designated officials of the Corporation with a need of
such records in the performance of their duties.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are destroyed four (4) years after the
close of the case.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Equal Opportunity, Corporation for National and
Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Request by individuals on whether a record is
maintained about himself or herself should be addressed to the System Manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Request for access to these records should be
sent to the System Manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contest of information included in these
records should be sent to the System Manger.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data in this system is obtained from the
following categories of sources: (1) Complainants, witnesses, etc., in discrimination complaints; (2)
Reports of investigations and Counselors' Reports; (3) Copies of documents relevant to any EO
investigation; (4) Records of hearings on complaint; and (5) Correspondence.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="CORPORATION 11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Employee Pay and Leave Record Files.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Human Resources, Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW.,
Washington, DC, 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Corporation employees and former employees.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel
actions including
appointment, promotion and termination actions; savings bond applications; allotments; IRS tax
withholdings, employment applications, and records regarding collections for overpayments; and time and
attendance records.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>GAO Policy and Procedures Manual; 31 U.S.C.
66(a); and the Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950, as amended.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide a system whereby Corporation employees can track
payroll and leave information.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information from these records is routinely
provided: (1) To the U.S. Department of Treasury for payroll and savings bonds and other deduction
purposes; (2) to the Internal Revenue Service for tax deductions; and (3) to participating insurance
companies holding policies with respect to employees of the Corporation. Also, see General Routine Uses
contained in Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Records are maintained in file folders in locked metal file cabinets. Individual Time and
Attendance records maintained by designated agency timekeepers are stored in locked metal file cabinets.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are by name in alphabetical order.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are available to Corporation employees with a job
related need.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained for three (3) years after
the end of the fiscal year in which an employee terminates employment and then retired to the Federal
Records Center in accordance with General Accounting Office instructions.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Payroll Supervisor, Corporation for National and
Community Service, Human Resources, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary
Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the
Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the
Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Corporation employee to whom the record
pertains.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="CORPORATION 12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>

    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>CNCS-02-OGC-FOIA/PA - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)/Privacy Act (PA) Request Files.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
                            <p>Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent> </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Office of General Counsel, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E ST SW, Washington, DC  20525.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer, Office of General Counsel, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E ST SW, Washington, DC  20525.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> The Freedom of Information Act of 1966, as amended, and the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The Corporation for National and Community Service (CNCS) Office of General Counsel uses the system to:</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Track, process, and respond to CNCS’s FOIA and Privacy Act inquiries and any disputes involving those inquiries (collectively, "Requests");</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Create reports about those Requests for oversight and reporting purposes; and</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Execute other responsibilities related to those Requests.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The system contains records about individuals who:</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Sent a written Request to CNCS which cited to, or was handled according to, FOIA or the Privacy Act, plus anyone who represented those individuals (collectively, "Requestors");</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Participate in responding to a Request on behalf of CNCS (collectively, "Respondents");</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Are the subject of a Request;</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Are referenced in the requested records; and</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Are otherwise connected to a Request.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Records in the system may contain:</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Requests;</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Correspondence with Requestors to establish their identities, clarify Requests, discuss fees, and discuss the timing of responses;</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Intra-agency search process correspondence;</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Written decisions to release or withhold requested records;</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Redacted and unredacted copies of responsive records; and</p>
                    <p>&#149;  Final responses to Requesters.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> The sources of records in the system include Requestors and Respondents. The documents gathered to respond to a Request can come from, but are not limited to, CNCS’S system of records, individuals and their representatives, public sources, and other entities connected to CNCS.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in the system may be disclosed to authorized entities, as is determined to be relevant and necessary, as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                    <p>1. To another Federal, foreign, state, local, tribal, or other public agency with an interest in, or control over, information in records responsive to or otherwise related to a Request, for the following purposes:</p>
                    <p>a. Consulting the other agency for its views about providing access to the information or assistance in verifying the identity or background information of an individual or the accuracy of information sought to be amended or corrected;</p>
                    <p>b. Informing the other agency of CNCS’S response or intended response; or</p>
                    <p>c. Referring the request to the most appropriate federal agency for response.</p>
                    <p>2. When FOIA permits CNCS to exempt a record from disclosure, the identity of the Requestor and a description of the requested record may be disclosed to the subject of the record, or the individual or entity that provided the record, to obtain their view on whether the information should be released.</p>
                    <p>3. To the Office of the President, a Member of Congress, or their staff in response to a Request made on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record. These advocates will receive the same records that individuals would have received if they filed their own Request.</p>
                    <p>4. To the Department of Justice (DOJ) to obtain DOJ's advice on whether records must be disclosed under FOIA and the Privacy Act in response to a Request.</p>
                    <p>5. To the DOJ when:</p>
                    <p>a. The agency, or any component thereof;</p>
                    <p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity;</p>
                    <p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                    <p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components</p>
                    <p>is a party to litigation or has an interest in litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the DOJ is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
                    <p>6. To a court, administrative body, or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when:</p>
                    <p>a. The agency, or any component thereof;</p>
                    <p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity;</p>
                    <p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                    <p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components,</p>
                    <p>is a party to litigation or has an interest in litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the DOJ is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
                    <p>7. To prospective claimants and their attorneys to negotiate the settlement of an actual or prospective claim against CNCS or its current or former employees, in advance of the initiation of formal litigation or proceedings.</p>
                    <p>8. To another Federal or State agency, a court, or a party in litigation or in an administrative or adjudicative proceeding conducted by a Federal or State agency, when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding and the record is relevant and necessary to that proceeding.</p>
                    <p>9. To an appropriate Federal, State, local, tribal, international, or foreign law enforcement agency or other appropriate authority charged with investigating or prosecuting a violation or enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulatory violations and such disclosure is proper and consistent with the official duties of the person making the disclosure.</p>
                    <p>10. To an agency or organization to audit or oversee operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                    <p>11. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:</p>
                    <p>a. CNCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records;</p>
                    <p>b. CNCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CNCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and</p>
                    <p>c. The disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CNCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>12. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when CNCS determines that information from the system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in:</p>
                    <p>a. Responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or</p>
                    <p>b. Preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    <p>13. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) as needed to assist CNCS with records management, conduct inspections of CNCS’s records management practices, and carry out other activities required by 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    <p>14. To NARA’s Office of Government Information Services so that it may review agency compliance with FOIA, provide mediation services to resolve FOIA disputes, and identify policies and procedures for improving FOIA compliance, and to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities as required by 5 U.S.C. 552(h)(2-3).</p>
                    <p>15. To a Federal agency in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, vetting a service member, in response to the issuance of a security clearance, conducting of a background, suitability or security investigation of an individual, classifying jobs, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, contract, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, and to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                    <p>16. To agency contractors, grantees, interns, and other authorized individuals engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity and require access to the records to accomplish an agency function, task or assignment. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to CNCS officials and employees.</p>
                    <p>17. To the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in connection with investigations into alleged or possible discrimination practices in the Federal sector, compliance by Federal agencies with the Uniform Guidelines on Employee Selection Procedures or other functions vested in the Commission and to otherwise ensure compliance with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 7201.</p>
                    <p>18. To any official or designee charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessments at a designated statistical agency as defined under 42 U.S.C 3501 Sec. 522 (e.g., U.S. Census Bureau, U.S. Department of Labor, Social Security Administration), and other well established and trusted public or private research organizations, academic institutions, or agencies for an evaluation, study, research, or other analytic or statistical purposes.</p>
                    <p>19. To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Chief Privacy Officer in consultation with counsel, when there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information, when disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of CNCS, or when disclosure is necessary to demonstrate the accountability of CNCS’S officers, employees, or individuals covered by the system, except to the extent the Chief Privacy Officer determines that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Paper records are stored in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks. Electronic records and backups are stored on secure servers and encrypted media to include, but are not limited to, the computers and network drives used by Respondents.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Records in the system may be retrieved by year of the Request, Request tracking number, name of Requestor, or any combination of these items.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Records in the system are maintained according to General Records Schedule 4.2, Information Access and Protection Records, as listed in NARA’s most recent General Records Schedule Transmittal.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Paper records are maintained in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks when not in use. Electronic records are maintained in accordance with National Institute of Standards and Technology Special Publication 800-53 Rev. 4, Security and Privacy Controls for Federal Information Systems and Organizations or the updated equivalent. Access to the records is limited to authorized personnel who require the information to complete their assigned tasks and have been trained how to properly handle and safeguard the records.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>In accordance with 45 CFR Part 2508, Implementation of the Privacy Act of 1974, individuals wishing to access their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer by sending (1) an e-mail to FOIA@cns.gov, (2) a letter to the System Manager, or (3) a facsimile to 202-606-3467. Individuals may also go in-person to the System Location and ask to speak to the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer within the Office of General Counsel. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information (i.e. full name, current address, date, and signature) to locate their records, indicate that they want to access their records, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals who wish to contest their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer in writing via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, an explanation of why they think their records are incomplete or inaccurate, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals who wish to contest their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, indicate that they want to be notified whether their records are included in the system, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>  64 FR 10879, 10889, March 5, 1999; 65 FR 46890, 46900, August 1, 2000; 67 FR 4395, 4406, January 30, 2002.</p>
                </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>




    <section id="CORPORATION 14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Merit Promotion Plan Files.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Human Resources, Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW.,
Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Applicants for employment with the Corporation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These
files contain copies of
applications for employment (SF-612 or resumes) submitted by applicants and other background information
regarding qualifications of the applicant for positions in the Corporation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as
amended, and the National Community Service Act of 1990, as amended.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide documentation necessary to support the Corporation's
merit selection process.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The contents of these files are used as follows:
(1) To Human Resources regarding suitability or qualifications of an applicant for employment; and (2) to
any source which requests information in the course of an inquiry regarding the qualifications of an
applicant to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the inquiry, and to
identify the type of information requested. Also, see General Routine Uses contained in Preliminary
Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Records are maintained in file folders in locked metal file cabinets.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by vacancy announcement number.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are available to Corporation employees with a job
related need.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are destroyed when applications are two
(2) years old. Applications which resulted in appointment are filed in the Official Personnel Folder and
subsequently retired to the Federal Records Center, St. Louis, Missouri.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Human Resources, Corporation for National and
Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary
Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the
Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Record Access Procedures category.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is obtained from the following
categories of sources: applications and other personnel forms furnished by the individual; written
references from sources disclosed by the applicant, such as, employers and schools.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>



<section id="CORPORATION 17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Momentum Financials Vendor Files.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Office of Accounting and Financial Management Services, Corporation for National and Community
Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC, 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>All individuals with whom the Corporation does business.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The data
recorded includes the name
and address of the entity doing business with the Corporation, ABA routing number, financial institution
name and address, depositor account number and the taxpayer identification number; e.g., the SSN of an
individual and the TIN of an organization.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as
amended; the National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended, and the Budget and Accounting
Procedures Act of 1950, as amended.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain a single registry of entities with which the agency
does business.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Data is shared with the Department of Health and
Human Services in the servicing of Corporation grant recipients; data may be disclosed to the U.S.
Department of Justice, the U.S. Department of Treasury or the General Accounting Office in connection with
debt servicing activities or to the Internal Revenue Service in the reporting of disbursements as required
by the Internal Revenue Code. Also, see General Routine Uses contained in Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Data is stored on magnetic media in a computer system with access controlled by a security system
that requires passwords and identification of each user.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Data can be retrieved from the system electronically by
name or TIN.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to data stored on magnetic media is controlled by a
security system that requires password and identification of each user.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are held for three (3) years and then
retired to the Federal Records Center.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Accounting and Financial Management
Services, Corporation for National and Community Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC, 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>To determine whether there is a record in the
system of records about an individual, that individual should submit a request in writing to the System
Manager giving name, taxpayer identification number, and address.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See Notification procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Anyone desiring to contest or amend
information contained in this system should write to the System Manager and set forth the basis for which
the record is believed to be incomplete or incorrect.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data in this system is obtained from documents
submitted by individuals covered by the system as well as documents issued by the Corporation officials
involved with managing funds.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>


<section id="CORPORATION 19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">USA Freedom Corps Record of Service.

</subsection><subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Corporation for National and Community Service, Office of Public Affairs, 1201 New York Avenue,
NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection><subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Individuals who have recorded information on their community service participation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>
Participant's e-mail address,
participant's length of service, and information about the volunteer's history of service.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>National and Community Service Act of 1990, as
amended.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide citizens a way to track their service time and
record their service hours.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>See General Routine Uses contained in Preliminary
Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>

<p>Records are stored in a database maintained by a Corporation contractor.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The participant's e-mail address retrieves records.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is available only to Corporation and USA
Freedom Corps staff. It is not available to anyone else without the express written consent from the
individual to release his/her information.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are maintained permanently.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Webmaster, Corporation for National and Community
Service, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>To determine whether there is a record in the
system about an individual, a participant should contact the Corporation for National and Community
Service, Attn: Webmaster, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525, and provide his/her e-mail
address.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See Notification procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Anyone desiring to contest or amend information maintained in his/her electronic record may do so
by addressing such request to the Corporation for National and Community Service, Attn: Privacy Act
Officer, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20525.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data is obtained from the electronic entries
made by the participant into our registration system.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>


    <section id=" CNCS-01" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/-01</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> CNCS-01-OGC–Office of General Counsel (OGC) Legal Files.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Office of General Counsel, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E ST SW, Washington, DC 20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Law Office Manager, Office of General Counsel, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E ST SW, Washington, DC  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 28 U.S.C. Chapter 171 – Tort Claims Procedure, 31 U.S.C. Chapter 37 – Claims, 40 U.S.C. Subtitle I – Federal Property and Administrative Services, and 42 U.S.C. 12651c – Corporation for National and Community Service.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Corporation for National and Community Service (CNCS) Office of General Counsel (OGC) uses the system to track, store, and manage the records it develops and acquires on matters that could or have led to investigations, mediation, or other legal actions before a judicial, administrative, or adjudicative body (collectively, "legal action records"). OGC also uses the system to track, store, and manage the records it develops and acquires to complete legal reviews, provide legal opinions, oversee transactions, coordinate with other agencies, and perform other legal activities on behalf of CNCS (collectively, "legal advice and guidance records").</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Categories of individuals covered by the system may include individuals who are or were involved in:</p>
                <p>&#149;  Potential or actual legal actions with CNCS or referenced in the legal action. That may include parties to the legal action, mediators, arbiters, judges, other court personnel, witnesses, individuals with information that pertains to the legal action, CNCS employees, grantees, service members, and applicants.</p>
                <p>&#149;  A transaction with CNCS, contract involving CNCS, or a CNCS program or matter that involves a legal or compliance review or other legal activity.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Legal action records may include, but are not limited to: complaints, appeals documents, investigation reports, discovery documents, affidavits, declarations, witness statements, notes from interviews, correspondence within CNCS, documents and correspondence between the parties, the courts, or other individuals or entities involved in the legal action, court filings, mediations, personnel documents, grievance proceedings, and other internal working documents. The personal information in these documents may include, but are not limited to: names, dates of birth, addresses, telephone numbers, Social Security Numbers (SSNs), and salary information.</p>
                <p>Legal advice and guidance records may include, but are not limited to: contracts, internal reports, notes, legal memoranda, correspondence to and from CNCS employees, contractors, grantees, service members, and applicants, information regarding grantees, service members, and applicants, and other documents about CNCS’ operations and services that have been reviewed by OGC. The personal information in these documents may include, but are not limited to: names, SSNs, National Service Participant Identification (NSPID) Numbers, home addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, dates of birth, financial information, medical records, salary information, and personnel records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records sources may include: individuals and entities involved in a legal action with CNCS and their authorized agents, individuals and entities with information relevant to a legal issue or action with CNCS and their authorized agents, CNCS employees, service members, grantees, applicants, information systems managed and controlled by CNCS and its contractors, information gathered from public sources, investigators, mediators, court records, grievance proceedings, contractors, and other Federal agencies.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, all or a portion of the records or information contained in the system may be disclosed to authorized entities, as is determined to be relevant and necessary, as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>1. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:</p>
                <p>a. CNCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records;</p>
                <p>b. CNCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CNCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and</p>
                <p>c. The disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CNCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>2. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when CNCS determines that information from the system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in:</p>
                <p>a. Responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or</p>
                <p>b. Preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>3. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) as needed to assist CNCS with records management, conduct inspections of CNCS’s records management practices, and carry out other activities required by 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>4. To NARA’s Office of Government Information Services so that it may review agency compliance with the Freedom of Information Act of 1967, as amended, (FOIA) provide mediation services to resolve FOIA disputes, and identify policies and procedures for improving FOIA compliance, and to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities as required by 5 U.S.C. 552(h)(2)(A-B) and (3).</p>
                <p>5. To a Federal agency in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, vetting a service member in response to the issuance of a security clearance, conducting a background check for suitability or security investigation of an individual, classifying jobs, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, contract, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, and to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>6. To the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in connection with investigations into alleged or possible discrimination practices in the Federal sector, compliance by Federal agencies with the Uniform Guidelines on Employee Selection Procedures, or other functions vested in the Commission and to otherwise ensure compliance with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 7201.</p>
                <p>7. To the Office of the President, a Member of Congress, or their personnel in response to a request made on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record. These advocates will receive the same records that individuals would have received if they filed their own request.</p>
                <p>8. To any official or designee charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessments at a designated statistical agency and other well established and trusted public or private research organizations, academic institutions, or agencies for an evaluation, study, research, or other analytical or statistical purpose.</p>
                <p>9. To agency contractors, grantees, interns, and other authorized individuals engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a project, contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity and require access to the records to accomplish an agency function, task, or assignment. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to CNCS employees.</p>
                <p>10. To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Chief Privacy Officer in consultation with counsel, when there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information, when disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of CNCS, or when disclosure is necessary to demonstrate the accountability of CNCS' officers, employees, or individuals covered by the system, except to the extent the Chief Privacy Officer determines that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                <p>11. To an appropriate Federal, State, local, tribal, international, or foreign law enforcement agency or other appropriate authority charged with investigating or prosecuting a violation or enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulatory violations and such disclosure is proper and consistent with the official duties of the person making the disclosure.</p>
                <p>12. To consumer reporting agencies (as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 14 U.S.C. 1681a(f), or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966, 31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)), the U.S. Department of the Treasury, other Federal agencies maintaining debt servicing centers, and private collection contractors to collect a debt owed to the Federal Government as provided in regulations promulgated by CNCS.</p>
                <p>13. To a contractor, grantee, or other recipient of Federal funds indebted to the Federal Government through its receipt of Federal Government funds if release of the record would allow the debtor to collect from a third party.</p>
                <p>14. The names, SSNs, home addresses, dates of birth, dates of hire, quarterly earnings, employer identifying information, and state of hire of employees may be disclosed to the Office of Child Support Enforcement Federal Parent Locator Service and the Treasury Offset Program to locate individuals owing child support and identify their income sources, establish and modify orders of child support, and for other child support enforcement actions.</p>
                <p>15. To a contractor, grantee, or other recipient of Federal funds when the record to be released reflects serious inadequacies with the recipient’s personnel, and disclosure of the record permits the recipient to effect corrective action in the Federal Government’s best interests.</p>
                <p>16. To the Department of Justice (DOJ) when:</p>
                <p>a. The agency, or any component thereof;</p>
                <p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity;</p>
                <p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components</p>
                <p>is a party to litigation or has an interest in litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the DOJ is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
                <p>17. To a court, administrative body, or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when:</p>
                <p>a. The agency, or any component thereof;</p>
                <p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity;</p>
                <p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components,</p>
                <p>is a party to litigation or has an interest in litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the DOJ is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
                <p>18. To a Federal or State agency, judicial body, administrative body, adjudicative body, another party or their representative to a legal matter, or witness when (a) the Federal Government is a party or potential party to a judicial, administrative, or adjudicative proceeding and (b) the record is both necessary and relevant or potentially relevant to that proceeding.</p>
                <p>19. To an arbiter, mediator, or another individual authorized to investigate or settle a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who is the subject of, or party to, the record.</p>
                <p>20. To any agency, entity, or individual when necessary to acquire information relevant to an investigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records are stored in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks. Electronic records and backups are stored on secure servers and encrypted media to include, but are not limited to, the computers and network drives used by OGC attorneys.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Records in the system may be retrieved by a variety of unique identifiers including case numbers, NSPID Numbers, names, CNCS email addresses, and SSNs.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> System records are retained and disposed according to CNCS records maintenance and disposition schedules and the legal records retention and disposal requirements of NARA. The records are retained for a minimum of five years and many records are retained indefinitely.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are maintained in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks when not in use. Electronic records are maintained in accordance with National Institute of Standards and Technology Special Publication 800-53 Rev. 4, Security and Privacy Controls for Federal Information Systems and Organizations or the updated equivalent. Access to the records is limited to authorized personnel who require the information to complete their assigned tasks and have been trained how to properly handle and safeguard the records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> In accordance with 45 CFR Part 2508 – Implementation of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, individuals wishing to access their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer by sending (1) an email to FOIA@cns.gov or (2) a letter to the System Manager. Individuals may also go in-person to the System Location and ask to speak to the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer within OGC. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information (i.e. full name, current address, date, and signature) to locate their records, indicate that they want to access their records, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals who wish to contest their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer in writing via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, an explanation of why they think their records are incomplete or inaccurate, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals who wish to contest their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, indicate that they want to be notified whether their records are included in the system, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Pursuant to, and limited by, 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(5) and 45 CFR 2508.19, the system is exempted from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(5) and 45 CFR 2508.4 insofar as the system contains information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>64 FR 10879, 10889, March 5, 1999; 65 FR 46890, 46901, August 1, 2000; 67 FR 4395, 4406, January 30, 2002.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="cncs-03" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>cncs03</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            CNCS-03-OIG–Investigative Files
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Inspector General, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E ST SW Suite 400, Washington, DC  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Inspector General, Office of Inspector General, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E ST SW Suite 400, Washington, DC  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended (5 U.S.C. App. 3) and The National and Community Service Trust Act of 1993 (42 U.S. Code Chapter 129).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Corporation for National and Community Service (CNCS) Office of Inspector General (CNCS-OIG) uses the system to track and maintain the files acquired and developed when CNCS-OIG investigates individuals associated with a CNCS program or operation pursuant to the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended.  CNCS-OIG is statutorily directed to conduct and supervise investigations relating to CNCS programs and operations to promote economy, efficiency and effectiveness in the administration of such programs and operations, and to prevent and detect fraud, waste and abuse in such programs and operations.  Accordingly, the records in the system are used to investigate individuals and entities suspected of having committed illegal or improper acts and to conduct criminal prosecutions, civil proceedings, and administrative actions against those individuals and entities.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In connection with CNCS-OIG’s investigative duties, the system maintains records on the following categories of individuals:</p>
                <p>&#149;  Individuals or entities that are or have been the subject of inquiries or investigations conducted by CNCS-OIG.  These include current and former employees of CNCS, and current and former contractors (or applicants for contracts), subcontractors, consultants, or the recipients of (or applicants for) CNCS grants, subgrants, or cooperative agreements, and their current or former employees; and,</p>
                <p>&#149;  Individuals who are witnesses, complainants, confidential or nonconfidential informants, and other parties who have been identified by CNCS-OIG (on the basis of information received or developed by CNCS-OIG) as potentially possessing information relevant to an investigation under CNCS-OIG’s jurisdiction.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records in the system include:</p>
                <p>&#149;  Letters, memoranda, hotline forms, and other documents describing complaints or alleged criminal, civil, or administrative misconduct;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Investigative files such as statements, affidavits, subpoenas, analyses, and records obtained during the investigation; and,</p>
                <p>&#149;  Final reports on the investigation and any related exhibits, which may include information about any follow-up actions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The subjects of investigations, and individuals with whom the subjects of investigations are associated, such as:</p>
                <p>&#149;  Current and former CNCS employees;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Current and former employees of grantees, contractors and subcontractors;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Current and former National Service participants;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Federal, state, local, and foreign law enforcement and non-law enforcement agencies;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Members of the public;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Witnesses;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Confidential and nonconfidential informants; and</p>
                <p>&#149;  Information gathered from public sources.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in the system may be disclosed to authorized entities, as is determined to be relevant and necessary, as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>1. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:</p>
                <p>a. CNCS-OIG or CNCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records,</p>
                <p>b. CNCS-OIG or CNCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CNCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal government, or national security, and</p>
                <p>c. The disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CNCS-OIG’s or CNCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>2. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when CNCS determines that information from the system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in:</p>
                <p>a. Responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or</p>
                <p>b. Preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>3. To National Archives and Records Administration.  A record may be disclosed during a records management inspection conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2906, and for mediation services to resolve disputes under 5 U.S.C. 552(h)(2).</p>
                <p>4. To Federal, State, Local, or Foreign Investigative or Prosecutorial Authorities.  A record which indicates either by itself or in combination with other information within CNCS-OIG’s possession, a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory, may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the appropriate Federal, foreign, state or local agency or professional or licensing organization charged with the responsibility of investigating, enforcing, or prosecuting such violation.</p>
                <p>5. For Certain Disclosures to Other Federal Agencies – To a Federal agency, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee; the conducting of a suitability or security investigation of an individual and issuance of a security clearance; the classification of jobs; the procurement of a contract; or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>6. To the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission – When requested in connection with investigations into alleged or possible discrimination practices in the Federal sector, compliance by Federal agencies with the Uniform Guidelines on Employee Selection Procedures or other functions vested in the Commission and to otherwise ensure compliance with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 7201.</p>
                <p>7. To the Office of the President, or a Member of Congress or His or Her Staff – In response to a request made on behalf of and at the request of the individual who is the subject of the record, when the Office of the President or the member of Congress has shown the appropriate official that the individual to whom the record pertains has authorized the Office of the President or the member of Congress to have access.</p>
                <p>8. To a Federal or State Grand Jury.  Pursuant to a Federal or state grand jury subpoena, or prosecution request, a record may be disclosed for the purpose of its introduction to a grand jury.</p>
                <p>9. To a Contractor, Grantee, Subgrantee or Other Recipient of Federal Funds.  A record may be disclosed when the record reflects serious inadequacies with the award recipient’s personnel, and disclosure of the record is for the purpose of permitting the award recipient to effect corrective action in the government’s best interest.</p>
                <p>10. To Outside Entities During an Investigation or Audit.  A record may be disclosed to any source, either private or governmental, to the extent necessary to secure from such source information relevant to, and sought in furtherance of, an OIG investigation, audit, or evaluation.</p>
                <p>11. To a Government Agency Pursuant to a Bid Protest.  A record may be disclosed to a Board of Contract Appeals, the General Accounting Office, or other tribunal hearing a bid protest involving a CNCS or CNCS-OIG procurement.</p>
                <p>12. To the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) for a Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act Consultation.  A record may be disclosed in order to obtain DOJ’s advice regarding CNCS-OIG’s obligations under the Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act.</p>
                <p>13. To the White House Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for a Privacy Act Consultation.  A record may be disclosed in order to obtain OMB’s advice regarding CNCS-OIG’s obligations under the Privacy Act.</p>
                <p>14. To Federal Agencies for Tax Records.  A record may be disclosed to the U.S. Department of the Treasury or DOJ when CNCS or CNCS-OIG is seeking to obtain taxpayer information from the Internal Revenue Service.</p>
                <p>15. To a Consumer Reporting Agency.  A record may be disclosed to a ‘‘consumer reporting agency’’ as that term is defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)), and the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701 (a)(3)), in order to obtain information in the course of an investigation or audit.</p>
                <p>16. To a Government Agency under a Computer Matching Program.  A record may be disclosed to a Federal, state, or local agency for use in computer matching programs to prevent and detect fraud and abuse in benefit or other programs, to support civil and criminal law enforcement activities of those agencies and their components, and to collect debts and overpayments owed to those agencies and their components.</p>
                <p>17. For Litigation and Mediation Purposes.  A record may be disclosed to DOJ or a state or local prosecutor, in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or mediation service before which CNCS-OIG is authorized to appear, when —</p>
                <p>a. CNCS-OIG, CNCS, or any component thereof;</p>
                <p>b. Any employee of CNCS-OIG or CNCS in his or her official capacity;</p>
                <p>c. Any employee of CNCS-OIG or CNCS in his or her individual capacity, where the government has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>d. The United States, where CNCS-OIG determines that the litigation is likely to affect CNCS-OIG, CNCS, or any of its components,</p>
                <p>is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by DOJ is deemed relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
                <p>18. For Certain Disclosures to the Public.  Unless CNCS-OIG or a designee determines that disclosure of the specific information, in the context of a particular case, would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, a record may be disclosed to the public:</p>
                <p>a. When the matter under investigation has become public knowledge because information about it is publicly available; or,</p>
                <p>b. When CNCS-OIG or a designee determines that such disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of the CNCS-OIG investigative process; or</p>
                <p>c. To demonstrate the accountability of CNCS-OIG or CNCS employees or other individuals covered by the system.</p>
                <p>19. To Sources of Investigations, Audits, and Inspections.  A record may be disclosed to:</p>
                <p>a. Complainants and/or victims to the extent necessary to provide such persons with information and explanations concerning the results of the investigation or case arising from the matters about which they complained and/or with respect to which they were a victim; and,</p>
                <p>b. An individual who has been interviewed or contacted by CNCS-OIG pursuant to an investigation, audit, or inspection, to the extent that CNCS-OIG may provide copies of that individual's statements, testimony, or records produced.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are stored in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks.  Electronic records and backups are stored on secure servers and encrypted media to include, but are not limited to, CNCS-OIG’s computers and network drives.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Each CNCS-OIG investigation file is assigned a case number and all records related to a particular investigation are filed and retrieved by that case number.  Records may also be retrieved by the name of the subjects, witnesses, and/or complainants.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Closed Investigation Files are retained for three years and then retired to the Federal Records Center and held for ten years after the fiscal year they were closed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>&#149;  Access to the records is limited to authorized personnel who require the information to complete their assigned tasks and have been trained how to properly handle and safeguard the records.</p>
                <p>&#149;  Electronic records are maintained in accordance with National Institute of Standards and Technology Special Publication 800-53 Rev. 4, Security and Privacy Controls for Federal Information Systems and Organizations or the updated equivalent.</p>
                <p>&#149;  Paper records are maintained in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks when not in use.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In accordance with 45 CFR Part 2508, Implementation of the Privacy Act of 1974, individuals wishing to access their own records must contact the System Manager at the address listed above, state that they want access to their own records, and furnish his or her name, address, telephone number, and a copy of an identification card such as a driver’s license.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The major part of the system is exempted from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), (k)(1), and (k)(2).  To the extent that the system of records is not subject to exemption, it is subject to contest.  A determination as to exemption shall be made at the time a request for contest is received.  Requesters shall direct their request to the System Manager listed above, stating clearly and concisely what information is being contested, the reason for contesting it, and the proposed amendment to the information.  Individuals should also be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To determine whether the system of records contains a record pertaining to the requesting individual, the individual should write to the System Manager at the address listed above.  Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, indicate that they want to be notified whether their records are included in the system, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.  Upon receipt, the System Manager will respond within 30 days in the same manner that the request was received e.g., for a request received by email CNCS-OIG will provide notification via email.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>&#149;  Pursuant to, and limited by 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and 45 CFR 2508.19(a)(1), the system of records maintained by CNCS-OIG that contains the Investigative Files shall be exempted from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a, except subsections (b), (c) (1) and (2), (e)(4) (A) through (F), (e)(6)(7), (9), (10), and (11), and (I), and 45 CFR 2508.11, 2508.12, 2508.13, 2508.14, 2508.15, 2508.16, and 2508.17, insofar as the system contains information pertaining to criminal law enforcement investigations.</p>
                <p>&#149;  Pursuant to, and limited by 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) and 45 CFR 2508.19(a)(2), the system of records maintained by CNCS-OIG that contains the Investigative Files shall be exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4) (G), (H), and (I), and (f), and 45 CFR 2508.11, 2508.12, 2508.13, 2508.14, 2508.15, 2508.16, and 2508.17, insofar as the system contains investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>64 FR 10879, 10890, March 5, 1999; 65 FR 46890, 46902, August 1, 2000; 67 FR 4395, 4407, January 30, 2002.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <section id="cncs-04" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>cncs04</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            CNCS-04-CPO-MMF–Member Management Files (MMF)
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief of Program Operations Immediate Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E Street, SW, Suite 300 Washington, D.C.  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief of Program Operations, Chief of Program Operations Immediate Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E Street, SW, Suite 300 Washington, D.C.  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>42 U.S.C. Chapter 129 - National and Community Service, 42 U.S.C. Chapter 66 - Domestic Volunteer Services, and Executive Order 9397, as amended.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Corporation for National and Community Service (CNCS) uses the system to select, place, manage, oversee, and support individuals who apply to become an AmeriCorps Service Member (Applicants) and those who are or have been an active AmeriCorps Service Member (Members). For example:</p>
                <p>&#149;  Determining eligibility of Applicants and selection of Members;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Assessing Member performance and responding to Member needs (e.g., requests for vacations and accommodations);</p>
                <p>&#149;  Approving and managing service-related travel, trainings, and living arrangements;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Calculating and processing living allowances, Segal AmeriCorps Education Awards (Education Awards), reimbursements, and other payments;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Determining eligibility for health benefits, loan forbearance, and other benefits; and</p>
                <p>&#149;  Tracking alumni contact information and their interest in alumni-related services.</p>
                <p>CNCS also uses the system to research and evaluate AmeriCorps’ effectiveness and how to enhance the program.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains records about individuals who apply to become an AmeriCorps Service Member, individuals who are or have been an active AmeriCorps Service Member, and individuals from the public asked to provide a reference for those individuals (References).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This is the primary system that CNCS uses to maintain records about Applicants, Members, and their References. It may contain personal identifiers about each Applicant and Member including their name, email addresses, physical addresses, phone numbers, Social Security Number, demographic information (including race, ethnicity, and any disabilities), birth date and location, username and password, National Service Participation Identification number (NSPID), marital status, fingerprints, citizenship status, and government-provided identification documents.</p>
                <p>It may contain information about each Applicant and Member’s:</p>
                <p>&#149;  Application to become a Member (e.g., reason for applying, educational history, employment history, military history, prior community service activities, criminal history, medical history, skills, certifications, voter registration status);</p>
                <p>&#149;  Relatives who served in AmeriCorps and the military,</p>
                <p>&#149;  AmeriCorps service history and experience (e.g. descriptions of activities, performance reviews, disciplinary concerns, accidents and other health concerns related to service, special accommodations, living arrangements, leave requests, service-related travel and trainings);</p>
                <p>&#149;  Benefits (e.g., health benefits, childcare benefits, Education Awards, stipends, loan forbearance);</p>
                <p>&#149;  Oath of office, plus other certifications and consents;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Living allowances, reimbursements, and banking information;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Emergency contacts and beneficiaries;</p>
                <p>&#149;  Automobile and driving history (including insurance coverage and any accidents); and</p>
                <p>&#149;  Post-service plans and interest in alumni activities.</p>
                <p>It may also contain communications with and about each Applicant and Member.</p>
                <p>The system may also contain each References’ name, email, title, employer, address, phone number, relationship to the Applicant or Member, and assessment of the Applicant or Member.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The sources of records in the system may include, but are not limited to, Applicants, Members, References (including those selected by an Applicant or Member, parole officers, prior workplace supervisors), institutions that may receive an Education Award, organizations that request and receive Members (Project Sponsors), CNCS employees and contractors, other CNCS systems, the Social Security Administration (SSA), Department of Justice (DOJ) criminal history databases, Congresspersons and their staff, and members of the public.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, all or a portion of the records or information contained in the system may be disclosed to authorized entities, as is determined to be relevant and necessary, as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>1. To the SSA to confirm an Applicant or Member’s citizenship status.</p>
                <p>2. To the DOJ to obtain an Applicant or Member’s criminal history information.</p>
                <p>3. To Project Sponsors to recruit, select, place, manage, oversee, and support Members.</p>
                <p>4. To a Member’s emergency contacts and beneficiaries if that Member experiences an emergency or death.</p>
                <p>5. To the Department of the Treasury to pay living allowances, reimbursements, and Education Awards.</p>
                <p>6. If a Member asks to send all or part of their Education Award to an institution, CNCS may disclose information from the system to confirm and coordinate the Member’s request.</p>
                <p>7. All records about FEMA Corps Members may be shared with the Federal Emergency Management Agency to operate FEMA Corps and manage those Members.</p>
                <p>8. To other Members for alumni-related activities when the Member gives permission.</p>
                <p>9. To the Office of the President, a Member of Congress, or their personnel in response to a request made on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record. These advocates will receive the same records that individuals would have received if they filed their own request.</p>
                <p>10. To any component of the Department of Justice for the purpose of representing CNCS or its components, officers, employees, or members in pending or potential litigation to which the record is pertinent.</p>
                <p>11. In an appropriate proceeding before a court, judicial, administrative, or adjudicative body, or official, when CNCS or another agency representing CNCS determines the records are relevant and necessary to the proceeding, or in an appropriate proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>12. To a Federal or State agency, judicial, administrative, or adjudicative body, another party, or their representative to a legal matter, or witness when (a) the Federal Government is a party or potential party to a judicial, administrative, or adjudicative proceeding and (b) the record is both necessary and relevant or potentially relevant to that proceeding.</p>
                <p>13. To prospective claimants and their attorneys to negotiate a settlement of an actual or prospective claim against CNCS or its current or former employees, in advance of the initiation of a formal legal proceeding.</p>
                <p>14. To an arbiter, mediator, or another individual authorized to investigate or settle a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who is the subject of, or party to, the record.</p>
                <p>15. To any agency, entity, or individual when necessary to acquire information relevant to an investigation.</p>
                <p>16. To an appropriate Federal, State, local, tribal, international, or foreign law enforcement agency or other appropriate authority charged with investigating or prosecuting a violation or enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulatory violations.</p>
                <p>17. To a former CNCS employee for the purpose of responding to an official inquiry by a Federal, State, local, territorial, or tribal entity or professional licensing authority, for the purpose of facilitating communications with a former employee that may be necessary for personnel-related or other official purposes where the CNCS requires information and/or consultation assistance from the former employee regarding a matter within that person's former area of responsibility.</p>
                <p>18. To unions recognized as exclusive bargaining representatives under the Civil Service Reform Act of 1978, 5 U.S.C. 7111 and 7114, the Merit Systems Protection Board, arbitrators, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, and other parties responsible for the administration of the Federal labor-management program for the purpose of processing any corrective actions, or grievances, or conducting administrative hearings or appeals.</p>
                <p>19. To the Merit Systems Protection Board and the Office of the Special Counsel for the purpose of litigation, including administrative proceedings, appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems; review of Office of Personnel Management (OPM) or component rules and regulations; investigation of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices, including administrative proceedings involving any individual subject of a CNCS investigation.</p>
                <p>20. To OPM for the purpose of addressing civilian pay and leave, benefits, retirement deduction, and any other information necessary for the OPM to carry out its legally authorized government-wide personnel management functions and studies.</p>
                <p>21. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:</p>
                <p>a. CNCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records;</p>
                <p>b. CNCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CNCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and</p>
                <p>c. The disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CNCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>22. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when CNCS determines that information from the system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in:</p>
                <p>a. Responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or</p>
                <p>b. Preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>23. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) as needed to assist CNCS with records management, conduct inspections of CNCS’s records management practices, and carry out other activities required by 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>24. To NARA’s Office of Government Information Services so that it may review agency compliance with the Freedom of Information Act of 1967, as amended, (FOIA) provide mediation services to resolve FOIA disputes, and identify policies and procedures for improving FOIA compliance, and to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities as required by 5 U.S.C. 552(h)(2)(A-B) and (3).</p>
                <p>25. To respond to a FOIA request per the processes established in 45 CFR Part 2507 or a Privacy Act request per the requirements in 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
                <p>26. To a Federal agency in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, vetting an Applicant, Member, or employee in response to the issuance of a security clearance, conducting a background check for suitability or security investigation of an individual, classifying jobs, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, contract, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, and to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>27. To agency contractors, grantees, Project Sponsors, interns, and other authorized individuals engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a project, contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity when it requires access to the records to accomplish an agency function, task, or assignment. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to CNCS employees.</p>
                <p>28. To the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in connection with investigations into alleged or possible discrimination practices in the Federal sector, compliance by Federal agencies with the Uniform Guidelines on Employee Selection Procedures, or other functions vested in the Commission and to otherwise ensure compliance with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 7201.</p>
                <p>29. To an agency or organization to audit or oversee CNCS’s or a vendor’s operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                <p>30. To any official or designee charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessments at a designated statistical agency and other well established and trusted public or private research organizations, academic institutions, or agencies for an evaluation, study, research, or other analytical or statistical purpose.</p>
                <p>31. To a contractor, grantee, or other recipient of Federal funds when the record to be released reflects serious inadequacies with the recipient’s personnel, and disclosure of the record permits the recipient to effect corrective action in the Federal Government’s best interests.</p>
                <p>32. To a contractor, grantee, or other recipient of Federal funds indebted to the Federal Government through its receipt of Federal funds if release of the record would allow the debtor to collect from a third party.</p>
                <p>33. To consumer reporting agencies (as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 14 U.S.C. 1681a(f), or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966, 31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)), the U.S. Department of the Treasury, other Federal agencies maintaining debt servicing centers, and private collection contractors to collect a debt owed to the Federal Government as provided in regulations promulgated by CNCS.</p>
                <p>34. To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Chief Privacy Officer in consultation with counsel, when there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information, when disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of CNCS, or when disclosure is necessary to demonstrate the accountability of CNCS's officers, employees, or individuals covered by the system, except to the extent the Chief Privacy Officer determines that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records are stored in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks. Electronic records and backups are stored on secure servers and encrypted media to include computers and network drives.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records in the system may be retrieved by any of the personal identifiers listed or described in CATEGORIES OF RECORDS IN THE SYSTEM.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>All records in the system will be retained until their retention and disposal schedule is approved by NARA, then retained and disposed according to the applicable schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In accordance with 45 CFR Part 2508 - Implementation of the Privacy Act, individuals wishing to access their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer by sending (1) an email to FOIA@cns.gov or (2) a letter to the System Manager. Individuals may also go in-person to the address in the System Location section of this notice and ask to speak to the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer within the Office of General Counsel. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information (i.e., full name, current address, date, and signature) to locate their records, indicate that they want to access their records, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals who wish to contest their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer in writing via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, an explanation of why they think their records are incomplete or inaccurate, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Individuals seeking to determine whether the system of records contains information about themselves should contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer in writing via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, indicate that they want to be notified whether their records are included in the system, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id=" CNCS-06 " toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/-06</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> CNCS-06-CPO-ACB–AmeriCorps Child Care Benefit System (ACB)</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief of Program Operations Immediate Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E St SW, Washington, DC  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>ACB Information Owner, Chief of Program Operations Immediate Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E St SW, Washington, DC  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended (42 U.S.C. 12501 et seq.), the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as amended (42 U.S.C. 4950 et seq.), and Executive Order 9397, as amended.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Corporation for National and Community Service (CNCS) uses the system to manage, administer, and evaluate the child care benefits program offered to eligible AmeriCorps Service Members (Members).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains information about Members who have applied for, or received, child care benefits, plus their AmeriCorps supervisors, children who required child care, spouses, and other household members.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system may include names, genders, dates of birth, ages, phone numbers, email addresses, physical addresses, National Service Participation Identification (ID) numbers, Social Security Numbers, Tax ID Numbers, Driver’s License numbers and information, State issued ID card information, information on income including tax documents, employment information (e.g., roles and dates of service), information on businesses (e.g., licenses and tax documents), academic enrollment information, child custody agreements, court orders, birth certificates, information on family relationships, and information about child care services.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The sources of records in the system can include, but are not limited to, Members and their representatives, child care providers and their representatives, other CNCS systems of records, and public sources.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, (Privacy Act) all or a portion of the records or information contained in the system may be disclosed to authorized entities, as is determined to be relevant and necessary, as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>1. To the Office of the President, a Member of Congress, or their personnel in response to a request made on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record. These advocates will receive the same records that individuals would have received if they filed their own request.</p>
                <p>2. To the Department of Justice (DOJ) when:</p>
                <p>a. The agency, or any component thereof;</p>
                <p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity;</p>
                <p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components</p>
                <p>is a party to litigation or has an interest in litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the DOJ is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
                <p>3. To a court, administrative body, or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when:</p>
                <p>a. The agency, or any component thereof;</p>
                <p>b. Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity;</p>
                <p>c. Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>d. The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components,</p>
                <p>is a party to litigation or has an interest in litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the DOJ is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
                <p>4. To a Federal or State agency, judicial body, administrative body, adjudicative body, another party or their representative to a legal matter, or witness when (a) the Federal Government is a party or potential party to a judicial, administrative, or adjudicative proceeding and (b) the record is both necessary and relevant or potentially relevant to that proceeding.</p>
                <p>5. To prospective claimants and their attorneys to negotiate the settlement of an actual or prospective claim against CNCS or its current or former employees, in advance of the initiation of formal litigation or proceedings.</p>
                <p>6. To an arbiter, mediator, or another individual authorized to investigate or settle a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who is the subject of, or party to, the record.</p>
                <p>7. To any agency, entity, or individual when necessary to acquire information relevant to an investigation.</p>
                <p>8. To an appropriate Federal, State, local, tribal, international, or foreign law enforcement agency or other appropriate authority charged with investigating or prosecuting a violation or enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulatory violations and such disclosure is proper and consistent with the official duties of the person making the disclosure.</p>
                <p>9. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:</p>
                <p>a. CNCS suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records;</p>
                <p>b. CNCS has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, CNCS (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and</p>
                <p>c. The disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with CNCS’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>10. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when CNCS determines that information from the system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in:</p>
                <p>a. Responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or</p>
                <p>b. Preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>11. To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) as needed to assist CNCS with records management, conduct inspections of CNCS’s records management practices, and carry out other activities required by 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>12. To NARA’s Office of Government Information Services so that it may review agency compliance with the Freedom of Information Act of 1967, as amended, (FOIA) provide mediation services to resolve FOIA disputes, and identify policies and procedures for improving FOIA compliance, and to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities as required by 5 U.S.C. 552(h)(2)(A-B) and (3).</p>
                <p>13. To respond to a FOIA request per the processes established in 45 CFR Part 2507 or a Privacy Act request per the requirements in 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
                <p>14. To a Federal agency in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, vetting a Member or employee in response to the issuance of a security clearance, conducting a background check for suitability or security investigation of an individual, classifying jobs, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, contract, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, and to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>15. To agency contractors, grantees, interns, and other authorized individuals engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a project, contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other activity and require access to the records to accomplish an agency function, task, or assignment. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to CNCS employees.</p>
                <p>16. To the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in connection with investigations into alleged or possible discrimination practices in the Federal sector, compliance by Federal agencies with the Uniform Guidelines on Employee Selection Procedures or other functions vested in the Commission, and to otherwise ensure compliance with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 7201.</p>
                <p>17. To an agency or organization to audit or oversee operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                <p>18. To any official or designee charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessments at a designated statistical agency and other well established and trusted public or private research organizations, academic institutions, or agencies for an evaluation, study, research, or other analytical or statistical purpose.</p>
                <p>19. To a contractor, grantee, or other recipient of Federal funds when the record to be released reflects serious inadequacies with the recipient’s personnel, and disclosure of the record permits the recipient to effect corrective action in the Federal Government’s best interests.</p>
                <p>20. To a contractor, grantee, or other recipient of Federal funds indebted to the Federal Government through its receipt of Federal funds if release of the record would allow the debtor to collect from a third party.</p>
                <p>21. To consumer reporting agencies (as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 14 U.S.C. 1681a(f), or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966, 31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)), the U.S. Department of the Treasury, other Federal agencies maintaining debt servicing centers, and private collection contractors to collect a debt owed to the Federal Government as provided in regulations promulgated by CNCS.</p>
                <p>22. To the news media and the public, with the approval of the Chief Privacy Officer in consultation with counsel, when there exists a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information, when disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of CNCS, or when disclosure is necessary to demonstrate the accountability of CNCS' officers, employees, or individuals covered by the system, except to the extent the Chief Privacy Officer determines that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are stored in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks. Electronic records and backups are stored on secure servers and encrypted media to include computers and network drives.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in the system about a Member may be retrieved by their name and email address.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>All records in the system will be retained until their retention and disposal schedule is approved by NARA, then retained and disposed according to the applicable schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Paper records are maintained in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks when not in use. Electronic records are maintained in accordance with National Institute of Standards and Technology Special Publication 800-53 Rev. 4, Security and Privacy Controls for Federal Information Systems and Organizations or the updated equivalent. Access to the records is limited to authorized personnel who require the information to complete their assigned tasks and have been trained how to properly handle and safeguard the records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In accordance with 45 CFR Part 2508, Implementation of the Privacy Act, individuals wishing to access their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer by sending (1) an email to FOIA@cns.gov or (2) a letter to the System Manager. Individuals may also go in-person to the System Location and ask to speak to the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer within the Office of General Counsel. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information (i.e. full name, current address, date, and signature) to locate their records, indicate that they want to access their records, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who wish to contest their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer in writing via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, an explanation of why they think their records are incomplete or inaccurate, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who wish to contest their own records as stored within the system of records may contact the FOIA Officer / Privacy Act Officer via the contact information in the RECORD ACCESS PROCEDURES section. Individuals who make a request must include enough identifying information to locate their records, indicate that they want to be notified whether their records are included in the system, and be prepared to confirm their identity as required by 45 CFR Part 2508.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id=" CNCS-10 " toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/-10</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>CNCS-10-CEO-PHRI, Personal Health and Religious Information (PHRI).</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>CEO Immediate Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E Street, SW, Suite 300 Washington, D.C.  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>CEO Immediate Office, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E Street, SW, Suite 300 Washington, D.C.  20525.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The authority to collect this information derives from Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, as amended, sections 501 and 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended, section 175 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990, as amended, and section 417 of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, as amended. The substantive standards of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, as amended (42 U.S.C. §§ 12101 et seq.) apply to the Federal Government through the Rehabilitation Act. (29 U.S.C. §§ 791 et seq.). Additional authority is derived from 5 U.S.C. chapters 11 and 79, and in discharging the functions directed under Executive Order 14043, Requiring Coronavirus Disease 2019 Vaccination for Federal Employees (Sept. 9, 2021), Executive Order 14042, Ensuring Adequate COVID Safety Protocols for Federal Contractors (Sept. 2, 2021), Executive Order 13163, Increasing Opportunity for Individuals With Disabilities To Be Employed in the Federal Government (Jul. 26, 2000), and Executive Order 13164, Requiring Federal Agencies to Establish Procedures to Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation (Jul. 26, 2000).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>AmeriCorps’ Equal Employment Opportunity Program (EEOP) proposes to collect this information to maintain personal health and religious information collected in response to (1) medical-based and religious-based reasonable accommodation requests; (2) public health emergency or similar health and safety incidents, such as a pandemic, epidemic, or man-made emergency; and/or (3) any other lawful collection of health-related information that is necessary to ensure a safe and healthy environment for individuals who are occupying AmeriCorps facilities, attending AmeriCorps-sponsored events, participating in AmeriCorps programs, or otherwise engaged in official business on behalf of the agency. The system will assist the agency in the collection, storing, dissemination, and disposal of personal health and religious information collected and maintained by the agency.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals covered by the system include all AmeriCorps employees (including political appointees, career employees, detailees, and interns), applicants and candidates for employment, contractors, national service members, volunteers, applicants and candidates for AmeriCorps national service programs, and visitors to AmeriCorps facilities.  This includes authorized individuals or representatives who file a request for a reasonable accommodation on behalf of any of the above-referenced parties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The personal health and religious information records system may contain some or all of the following information: general personal information including, but not limited to, the name, address, social security number, maiden name, place of birth, financial information, alias, gender, telephone number, military service, age, email address, physical characteristics, race/ethnicity, education, other contact information, and medical information including vaccination status; reasonable accommodation requests, including requestor’s name and contact information (if different than the employee/service member who needs an accommodation); date request was initiated; information concerning the nature of the disability and the need for accommodation, including appropriate medical documentation and other supporting documents; information concerning religious affiliation, the nature of the sincerely held religious belief, practice, or observance, and the need for accommodation, including any appropriate documentation; details of the accommodation requests, such as: Type of accommodation requested, how the requested accommodation would assist the individual in the performance of their job, essential duties of the position, information relating to an individual’s capability to satisfactorily perform the duties of the position currently held, estimated cost of accommodation, action by deciding official, and other supporting documents relating to reasonable accommodation, the sources of technical assistance consulted in trying to identify alternative reasonable accommodation, any additional information provided by the requestor related to the processing of the request, and whether the request was approved or denied, and whether the accommodation was approved for a trial period; and notification(s) to the employee/service member and his/her supervisor(s) regarding the accommodation. These records may also contain work-related data, including but not limited to service information, occupation, telephone number, salary, job title, email address, work history, work address, business associates, and/or program office to which the employee is assigned.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system are obtained directly from employees (including political appointees, career employees, detailees, and interns), applicants and candidates for employment, contractors, national service members, volunteers, applicants and candidates for AmeriCorps national service programs, or any family member, health professional, or other person responding to an information request as a representative of any of the above-referenced parties, or visitors when obtaining necessary health information; therefore, the accuracy is ensured by collecting the information from the source who may be required to certify under penalty of perjury that the information is true and accurate to the best of their knowledge.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a (b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed outside AmeriCorps as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p> A.	A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to a prospective employer of a Government employee. Upon transfer of the employee to another Federal agency, the information is transferred to such agency.</p>
                <p> B.	A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to provide information to the OPM and/or MSPB for review, audit, or reporting purposes.</p>
                    <p>C.	To the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating. prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order where the record, either alone or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of a civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                        <p> D.	To other federal agencies if required to operate a jointly managed national service program and manage those members.</p>
                            <p> E.	To the Office of the President, a Member of Congress, or their personnel in response to a request made on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record. These advocates will receive the same records that individuals would have received if they filed their own request.</p>
                                <p> F.	To another Federal agency or a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency, when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding, and such information is the subject of a court order directing disclosure or deemed by AmeriCorps to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
                <p> G.	To NARA’s Office of Government Information Services so that it may review agency compliance with the Freedom of Information Act of 1967, as amended, (FOIA) provide mediation services to resolve FOIA disputes, and identify policies and procedures for improving FOIA compliance, and to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities as required by 5 U.S.C. 552(h)(2)(A-B) and (3).</p>
                <p>H.	By AmeriCorps, in the production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the records are collected and maintained, or for related workforce studies. While published statistics and studies do not contain individual identifiers, in some instances, the selection of elements of data included in the study may be structured in such a way as to make the data individually identifiable by inference.</p>
                <p> I.	A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to provide information to the OPM and/or MSPB for review, audit, or reporting purposes.</p>
                <p> J.	A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to AmeriCorps-paid experts or consultants, and those under contract with the AmeriCorps on a "need-to-know" basis for a purpose within the scope of the pertinent AmeriCorps task. This access will be granted to an AmeriCorps contractor or employee of such contractor by a system manager only after satisfactory justification has been provided to the system manager.</p>
                <p>K.	The United States, when AmeriCorps determines that litigation is likely to affect AmeriCorps or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or AmeriCorps is deemed by AmeriCorps to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
                <p> L.	To disclose information to officials of the Merit Systems Protection Board or the Office of the Special Counsel, when requested in connection with appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of OPM rules and regulations, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices, and such other functions as promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, or as may be authorized by law.</p>
                <p> M.	To disclose information to the U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in connection with investigations into alleged or possible discrimination practices in the Federal sector, examination of Federal affirmative employment programs, compliance by Federal agencies with the Uniform Guidelines of Employee Selection Procedures, or other functions vested in the Commission.</p>
                <p> N.	To disclose information to the Federal Labor Relations Authority or its General Counsel when requested in connection with investigations of allegations of unfair labor practices of matters before the Federal Service Impasses Panel.</p>
                    <p>O.	To disclose information to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage of the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB circular No. A-19.</p>
                <p> P.	To provide authorized AmeriCorps officials, vendors or staff members information needed in the performance of official duties related to succession planning, workforce analysis, skills gap closure, training and development, or recruitment and retention.</p>
                <p> Q.	To authorized contractors, vendors, grantees, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or job for AmeriCorps or the Federal government that is in the performance of a Federal duty to which the information is deemed relevant.</p>
                <p> R.	To disclose to a requesting Federal agency, information in connection with the hiring, retention, separation, or retirement of an employee; the issuance of a security clearance; the reporting of an investigation of an employee; the letting of a contract; the classification of a job; or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that AmeriCorps determines that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting party's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p> S.	To an appeal, grievance, hearing, or complaints examiner; an equal opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or mediator; and an exclusive representative or other person authorized to investigate or settle a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                <p> T.	For Data Breach and Mitigation Response to provide information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:</p>
                <p>a. AmeriCorps suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records.</p>
                <p>b. AmeriCorps has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, AmeriCorps (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security. and</p>
                <p>c. The disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with AmeriCorps’ efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p> U.	To provide information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when AmeriCorps determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach, or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Paper records are stored in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks. Electronic records and backups are stored on secure servers and encrypted media to include computers and network drives.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information covered by this system of records notice may be retrieved by the name of the individual.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>All records in the system will be retained until their retention and disposal schedule is approved by NARA, then retained and disposed according to the applicable schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>AmeriCorps has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. AmeriCorps has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with its security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals. Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with either Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards or by assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically. Paper records are maintained in locked rooms, file cabinets, and desks when not in use.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals requesting access to their individual records should follow the Notification Procedure below.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals contesting the content of records about themselves contained in this system of records should follow the Notification Procedure below.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals requesting notification of the existence of records on themselves or requesting access to their individual records must send a signed, written inquiry that includes their name, address, date of birth, and verification of identity to Gina Cross, Senior Agency Official for Privacy, Corporation for National and Community Service, 250 E Street, SW, Suite 300 Washington, D.C.  20525, or email gcross@cns.gov. The request envelope (or subject line) and letter should both be clearly marked "PRIVACY ACT INQUIRY."  A request for notification must meet the requirements of 43 CFR 2.235.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="45">
<heading>Public Welfare</heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XXV">
<heading>Corporation for National and Community Service</heading>
<regulationsPart number="2508">
<heading>IMPLEMENTATION OF THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p><p>2508.1 Definitions.
</p><p>2508.2 What is the purpose of this part?
</p><p>2508.3 What is the Corporation's Privacy Act policy?
</p><p>2508.4 When can Corporation records be disclosed?
</p><p>2508.5 When does the Corporation publish its notice of its system of records?
</p><p>2508.6 When will the Corporation publish a notice for new routine uses of information in its system
of records?
</p><p>2508.7 To whom does the Corporation provide reports to regarding changes in its system of records?
</p><p>2508.8 Who is responsible for establishing the Corporation's rules of conduct for Privacy Act
compliance?
</p><p>2508.9 What officials are responsible for the security, management and control of Corporation record
keeping systems?
</p><p>2508.10 Who has the responsibility for maintaining adequate technical, physical, and security
safeguards to prevent unauthorized disclosure or destruction of manual and automatic record systems?
</p><p>2508.11 How shall offices maintaining a system of records be accountable for those records to
prevent unauthorized disclosure of information?
</p><p>2508.12 What are the contents of the systems of records that are to be maintained by the
Corporation?
</p><p>2508.13 What are the procedures for acquiring access to Corporation records by an individual about
whom a record is maintained?
</p><p>2508.14 What are the identification requirements for individuals who request access to records?
</p><p>2508.15 What are the procedures for requesting inspection of, amendment or correction to, or appeal
of an individual's records maintained by the Corporation other than that individual's official personnel
file?
</p><p>2508.16 What are the procedures for filing an appeal for refusal to amend or correct records?
</p><p>2508.17 When shall fees be charged and at what rate?
</p><p>2508.18 What are the penalties for obtaining a record under false pretenses?
</p><p>2508.19 What Privacy Act exemptions or control of systems of records are exempt from disclosure?
</p><p>2508.20 What are the restrictions regarding the release of mailing lists?
</p><p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a; 42 U.S.C. 12501 <i>et seq.</i>; 42 U.S.C. 4950 <i>et seq.</i>
</p><p><b>Source:</b> 64 FR 19294, Apr. 20, 1999, unless otherwise noted.</p>

<p><b>&#167;2508.1 Definitions.
</b></p><p>(a) <i>Amend</i> means to make a correction to, or expunge any portion of, a record about an
individual which that individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Appeal Officer</i> means the individual delegated the responsibility to act on all appeals filed
under the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Chief Executive Officer</i> means the Head of the Corporation.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Corporation</i> means the Corporation for National and Community Service.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Individual</i> means any citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent
residence.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Maintain</i> means to collect, use, store, disseminate or any combination of these recordkeeping
functions; exercise of control over and therefore, responsibility and accountability for, systems of
records.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Personnel record</i> means any information about an individual that is maintained in a system of
records by the Corporation that is needed for personnel management or processes such as staffing,
employment development, retirement, grievances, and appeals.
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Privacy Act Officer</i> means the individual delegated the authority to allow access to, the
release of, or the withholding of records pursuant to an official Privacy Act request. The Privacy Act
Officer is further delegated the authority to make the initial determination on all requests to amend
records.
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Record</i> means any document or other information about an individual maintained by the agency
whether collected or grouped, and including, but not limited to, information regarding education, financial
transactions, medical history, criminal or employment history, or any other personal information that
contains the name or other personal identification number, symbol, etc. assigned to such individual.
</p>
<p>(j) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a
purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p>
<p>(k) <i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the maintenance and control of the
Corporation from which information is retrieved by use of the name of an individual or by some personal
identifier of the individual.

</p>
<p><b>&#167;2508.2
 What is the purpose of this part?
</b></p><p>The purpose of this part is to set forth the basic policies of the Corporation governing the
maintenance of its system of records which contains personal information concerning its employees as
defined in the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a). Records included in this part are those described in aforesaid
act and maintained by the Corporation and/or any component thereof.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.3
 What is the Corporation's Privacy Act policy?
</b></p><p>It is the policy of the Corporation to protect, preserve, and defend the right of privacy of any
individual about whom the Corporation maintains personal information in any system of records and to
provide appropriate and complete access to such records including adequate opportunity to correct any
errors in said records. Further, it is the policy of the Corporation to maintain its records in such a
manner that the information contained therein is, and remains material and relevant to the purposes for
which it is received in order to maintain its records with fairness to the individuals who are the subjects
of such records.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.4
 When can Corporation records be disclosed?
</b></p><p>(a) (1) The Corporation will not disclose any record that is contained in its system of records
by any means of communication to any person, or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request by,
or with the prior written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains, unless disclosure of the
record would be:
</p><p>(i) To employees of the Corporation who maintain the record and who have a need for the record in
the performance of their official duties;
</p><p>(ii) When required under the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552);
</p><p>(iii) For routine uses as appropriately published in the annual notice of the Federal Register;
</p><p>(iv) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or
related activity pursuant to the provisions of title 13;
</p><p>(v) To a recipient who has provided the Corporation with advance adequate written assurance that the
record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be
transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable;
</p><p>(vi) To the National Archives and Records Administration of the United States as a record which has
sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the United States Government,
or for evaluation by the Archivist of the United States or the designee of the Archivist to determine
whether the record has such value;
</p><p>(vii) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under
the control of the United States for civil or criminal law enforcement activity if the activity is
authorized by law, and if the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a written request to the
Corporation for such records specifying the particular portion desired and the law enforcement activity for
which the record is sought. Such a record may also be disclosed by the Corporation to the law enforcement
agency on its own initiative in situations in which criminal conduct is suspected provided that such
disclosure has been established as a routine use or in situations in which the misconduct is directly
related to the purpose for which the record is maintained;
</p><p>(viii) To a person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety
of any individual if, upon such disclosure, notification is transmitted to the last known address of such
individual;
</p><p>(ix) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, any committee
or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee;
</p><p>(x) To the Comptroller General or any of his or her authorized representatives, in the course of the
performance of official duties in the General Accounting Office;
</p><p>(xi) Pursuant to an order of a court of competent jurisdiction served upon the Corporation pursuant
to 45 CFR 1201.3, and provided that if any such record is disclosed under such compulsory legal process and
subsequently made public by the court which issued it, the Corporation must make a reasonable effort to
notify the individual to whom the record pertains of such disclosure;
</p><p>(xii) To a contractor, expert, or consultant of the Corporation (or an office within the
Corporation) when the purpose of the release to perform a survey, audit, or other review of the
Corporation's procedures and operations; and
</p><p>(xiii) To a consumer reporting agency in accordance with section 3711(f) of title 31.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.5
 When does the Corporation publish its notice of its system of records?
</b></p><p>The Corporation shall publish annually a notice of its system of records maintained by it as
defined herein in the format prescribed by the General Services Administration in the <i>Federal
Register</i>; provided, however, that such publication shall not be made for those systems of records
maintained by other agencies while in the temporary custody of the Corporation.

</p>
<p><b>&#167;2508.6
 When will the Corporation publish a notice for new routine uses of information in its system of records?
</b></p><p>At least 30 days prior to publication of information under the preceding section, the
Corporation shall publish in the <i>Federal Register</i> a notice of its intention to establish any new
routine use of any system of records maintained by it with an opportunity for public comments on such use.
Such notice shall contain the following:
</p>
<p>(a) The name of the system of records for which the routine use is to be established.
</p><p>(b) The authority for the system.
</p><p>(c) The purpose for which the record is to be maintained.
</p><p>(d) The proposed routine use(s).
</p><p>(e) The purpose of the routine use(s).
</p><p>(f) The categories of recipients of such use. In the event of any request for an addition to the
routine uses of the systems which the Corporation maintains, such request may be sent to the following
office: Corporation for National and Community Service, Director, Administration and Management Services,
Room 6100, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20525.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.7
 To whom does the Corporation provide reports regarding changes in its system of records?
</b></p><p>The Corporation shall provide to the Committee on Government Operations of the House of
Representatives, the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Office of Management and
Budget, advance notice of any proposal to establish or alter any system of records as defined herein. This
report will be submitted in accordance with guidelines provided by the Office of Management and Budget.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.8
 Who is responsible for establishing the Corporation's rules of conduct for Privacy Act compliance?
</b></p><p>(a) The Chief Executive Officer shall ensure that all persons involved in the design,
development, operation or maintenance of any system of records as defined herein are informed of all
requirements necessary to protect the privacy of individuals who are the subject of such records. All
employees shall be informed of all implications of the Act in this area including the civil remedies
provided under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1) and the fact that the Corporation may be subject to civil remedies for
failure to comply with the provisions of the Privacy Act and this regulation.
</p><p>(b) The Chief Executive Officer shall also ensure that all personnel having access to records
receive adequate training in the protection of the security of personal records, and that adequate and
proper storage is provided for all such records with sufficient security to assure the privacy of such
records.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.9
 What officials are responsible for the security, management and control of Corporation record keeping
 systems?
</b></p><p>(a) The Director of Administration and Management Services shall have overall control and
supervision of the security of all systems of records and shall be responsible for monitoring the security
standards set forth in this regulation.
</p><p>(b) A designated official (System Manager) shall be named who shall have management responsibility
for each record system maintained by the Corporation and who shall be responsible for providing protection
and accountability for such records at all times and for insuring that such records are secured in
appropriate containers whenever not in use or in the direct control of authorized personnel.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.10
 Who has the responsibility for maintaining adequate technical, physical, and security safeguards to
 prevent unauthorized disclosure or destruction of manual and automatic record systems?
</b></p><p>The Chief Executive Officer has the responsibility of maintaining adequate technical, physical,
and security safeguards to prevent unauthorized disclosure or destruction of manual and automatic record
systems. These security safeguards shall apply to all systems in which identifiable personal data are
processed or maintained, including all reports and outputs from such systems that contain identifiable
personal information. Such safeguards must be sufficient to prevent negligent, accidental, or unintentional
disclosure, modification or destruction of any personal records or data, and must furthermore minimize, to
the extent practicable, the risk that skilled technicians or knowledgeable persons could improperly obtain
access to modify or destroy such records or data and shall further insure against such casual entry by
unskilled persons without official reasons for access to such records or data.
</p><p>(a) <i>Manual systems.</i> (1) Records contained in a system of records as defined herein may be
used, held or stored only where facilities are adequate to prevent unauthorized access by persons within or
outside the Corporation.
</p>
<p>(2) All records, when not under the personal control of the employees authorized to use the records,
must be stored in a locked metal filing cabinet. Some systems of records are not of such confidential
nature that their disclosure would constitute a harm to an individual who is the subject of such record.
However, records in this category shall also be maintained in locked metal filing cabinets or maintained in
a secured room with a locking door.
</p><p>(3) Access to and use of a system of records shall be permitted only to persons whose duties require
such access within the Corporation, for routine uses as defined in &#167; 2508.4 as to any given system, or
for such other uses as may be provided herein.
</p><p>(4) Other than for access within the Corporation to persons needing such records in the performance
of their official duties or routine uses as defined in &#167; 2508.4, or such other uses as provided
herein, access to records within a system of records shall be permitted only to the individual to whom the
record pertains or upon his or her written request to the Director, Administration and Management Services.
</p><p>(5) Access to areas where a system of records is stored will be limited to those persons whose
duties require work in such areas. There shall be an accounting of the removal of any records from such
storage areas utilizing a written log, as directed by the Director, Administration and Management Services.
The written log shall be maintained at all times.
</p><p>(6) The Corporation shall ensure that all persons whose duties require access to and use of records
contained in a system of records are adequately trained to protect the security and privacy of such
records.
</p><p>(7) The disposal and destruction of records within a system of records shall be in accordance with
rules promulgated by the General Services Administration.
</p><p>(b) <i>Automated systems.</i> (1) Identifiable personal information may be processed, stored or
maintained by automated data systems only where facilities or conditions are adequate to prevent
unauthorized access to such systems in any form. Whenever such data, whether contained in punch cards,
magnetic tapes or discs, are not under the personal control of an authorized person, such information must
be stored in a locked or secured room, or in such other facility having greater safeguards than those
provided for herein.
</p>
<p>(2) Access to and use of identifiable personal data associated with automated data systems shall be
limited to those persons whose duties require such access. Proper control of personal data in any form
associated with automated data systems shall be maintained at all times, including maintenance of
accountability records showing disposition of input and output documents.
</p><p>(3) All persons whose duties require access to processing and maintenance of identifiable personal
data and automated systems shall be adequately trained in the security and privacy of personal data.
</p><p>(4) The disposal and disposition of identifiable personal data and automated systems shall be done
by shredding, burning or in the case of tapes or discs, degaussing, in accordance with any regulations now
or hereafter proposed by the General Services Administration or other appropriate authority.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.11
 How shall offices maintaining a system of records be accountable for those records to prevent unauthorized
 disclosure of information?
</b></p><p>(a) Each office maintaining a system of records shall account for all records within such system
by maintaining a written log in the form prescribed by the Director, Administration and Management
Services, containing the following information:
</p><p>(1) The date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure of a record to any person or to another agency.
Disclosures made to employees of the Corporation in the normal course of their duties, or pursuant to the
provisions of the Freedom of Information Act, need not be accounted for.
</p><p>(2) Such accounting shall contain the name and address of the person or agency to whom the
disclosure was made.
</p><p>(3) The accounting shall be maintained in accordance with a system of records approved by the
Director, Administration and Management Services, as sufficient for the purpose but in any event sufficient
to permit the construction of a listing of all disclosures at appropriate periodic intervals.
</p><p>(4) The accounting shall reference any justification or basis upon which any release was made
including any written documentation required when records are released for statistical or law enforcement
purposes under the provisions of subsection (b) of the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a).
</p><p>(5) For the purpose of this part, the system of accounting for disclosures is not a system of
records under the definitions hereof, and need not be maintained within a system of records.
</p><p>(6) Any subject individual may request access to an accounting of disclosures of a record. The
subject individual shall make a request for access to an accounting in accordance with &#167; 2508.13. An
individual will be granted access to an accounting of the disclosures of a record in accordance with the
procedures of this subpart which govern access to the related record. Access to an accounting of a
disclosure of a record made under &#167; 2508.13 may be granted at the discretion of the Director,
Administration and Management Services.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.12
 What are the contents of the systems of record that are to be maintained by the Corporation?
</b></p><p>(a) The Corporation shall maintain all records that are used in making determinations about any
individual with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to assure
fairness to the individual in the determination;
</p><p>(b) In situations in which the information may result in adverse determinations about such
individual's rights, benefits and privileges under any Federal program, all information placed in a system
of records shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be collected from the individual to whom the record
pertains.
</p><p>(c) Each form or other document that an individual is expected to complete in order to provide
information for any system of records shall have appended thereto, or in the body of the document:
</p><p>(1) An indication of the authority authorizing the solicitation of the information and whether the
provision of the information is mandatory or voluntary.
</p><p>(2) The purpose or purposes for which the information is intended to be used.
</p><p>(3) Routine uses which may be made of the information and published pursuant to &#167; 2508.6.
</p><p>(4) The effect on the individual, if any, of not providing all or part of the required or requested
information.
</p><p>(d) Records maintained in any system of records used by the Corporation to make any determination
about any individual shall be maintained with such accuracy, relevancy, timeliness, and completeness as is
reasonably necessary to assure fairness to the individual in the making of any determination about such
individual, provided, however, that the Corporation shall not be required to update or keep current retired
records.
</p><p>(e) Before disseminating any record about any individual to any person other than an employee in the
Corporation, unless the dissemination is made pursuant to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act
(5 U.S.C. 552), the Corporation shall make reasonable efforts to ensure that such records are, or were at
the time they were collected, accurate, complete, timely and relevant for Corporation purposes.
</p><p>(f) Under no circumstances shall the Corporation maintain any record about any individual with
respect to or describing how such individual exercises rights guaranteed by the First Amendment of the
Constitution of the United States, unless expressly authorized by statute or by the individual about whom
the record is maintained, or unless pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized law enforcement
activity.
</p><p>(g) In the event any record is disclosed as a result of the order of a court of appropriate
jurisdiction, the Corporation shall make reasonable efforts to notify the individual whose record was so
disclosed after the process becomes a matter of public record.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.13
 What are the procedures for acquiring access to Corporation records by an individual about whom a record
 is maintained?
</b></p><p>(a) Any request for access to records from any individual about whom a record is maintained will
be addressed to the Corporation for National and Community Service, Office of the General Counsel, Attn:
Privacy Act Officer, Room 8200, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20525, or delivered in person
during regular business hours, whereupon access to his or her record, or to any information contained
therein, if determined to be releasable, shall be provided.
</p><p>(b) If the request is made in person, such individual may, upon his or her request, be accompanied
by a person of his or her choosing to review the record and shall be provided an opportunity to have a copy
made of any record about such individual.
</p><p>(c) A record may be disclosed to a representative chosen by the individual as to whom a record is
maintained upon the proper written consent of such individual.
</p><p>(d) A request made in person will be promptly complied with if the records sought are in the
immediate custody of the Corporation. Mailed requests or personal requests for documents in storage or
otherwise not immediately available, will be acknowledged within 10 working days, and the information
requested will be promptly provided thereafter.
</p><p>(e) With regard to any request for disclosure of a record, the following procedures shall apply:
</p><p>(1) Medical or psychological records shall be disclosed to an individual unless, in the judgment of
the Corporation, access to such records might have an adverse effect upon such individual. When such
determination has been made, the Corporation may require that the information be disclosed only to a
physician chosen by the requesting individual. Such physician shall have full authority to disclose all or
any portion of such record to the requesting individual in the exercise of his or her professional
judgment.
</p><p>(2) Test material and copies of certificates or other lists of eligibles or any other listing, the
disclosure of which would violate the privacy of any other individual, or be otherwise exempted by the
provisions of the Privacy Act, shall be removed from the record before disclosure to any individual to whom
the record pertains.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.14
 What are the identification requirements for individuals who request access to records?
</b></p><p>The Corporation shall require reasonable identification of all individuals who request access to
records to ensure that records are disclosed to the proper person.
</p><p>(a) In the event an individual requests disclosure in person, such individual shall be required to
show an identification card such as a drivers license, etc., containing a photo and a sample signature of
such individual. Such individual may also be required to sign a statement under oath as to his or her
identity, acknowledging that he or she is aware of the penalties for improper disclosure under the
provisions of the Privacy Act.
</p><p>(b) In the event that disclosure is requested by mail, the Corporation may request such information
as may be necessary to reasonably ensure that the individual making such request is properly identified. In
certain cases, the Corporation may require that a mail request be notarized with an indication that the
notary received an acknowledgment of identity from the individual making such request.
</p><p>(c) In the event an individual is unable to provide suitable documentation or identification, the
Corporation may require a signed notarized statement asserting the identity of the individual and
stipulating that the individual understands that knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to
records about another person under false pretenses is punishable by a fine of up to $5,000.
</p><p>(d) In the event a requestor wishes to be accompanied by another person while reviewing his or her
records, the Corporation may require a written statement authorizing discussion of his or her records in
the presence of the accompanying representative or other persons.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.15
 What are the procedures for requesting inspection of, amendment or correction to, or appeal of an
 individual's records maintained by the Corporation other than that individual's official personnel file?
</b></p><p>(a) A request for inspection of any record shall be made to the Director, Administration and
Management Services. Such request may be made by mail or in person provided, however, that requests made in
person may be required to be made upon a form provided by the Director of Administration and Management
Services who shall keep a current list of all systems of records maintained by the Corporation and
published in accordance with the provisions of this regulation. However, the request need not be in writing
if the individual makes his or her request in person. The requesting individual may request that the
Corporation compile all records pertaining to such individual at any named Service Center/State Office,
AmeriCorps*NCCC Campus, or at Corporation Headquarters in Washington, DC, for the individual's inspection
and/or copying. In the event an individual makes such request for a compilation of all records pertaining
to him or her in various locations, appropriate time for such compilation shall be provided as may be
necessary to promptly comply with such requests.
</p><p>(b) Any such requests should contain, at a minimum, identifying information needed to locate any
given record and a brief description of the item or items of information required in the event the
individual wishes to see less than all records maintained about him or her.
</p><p>(1) In the event an individual, after examination of his or her record, desires to request an
amendment or correction of such records, the request must be submitted in writing and addressed to the
Corporation for National and Community Service, Office of the General Counsel, Attn: Privacy Act Officer,
Room 8200, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20525. In his or her written request, the individual
shall specify:
</p><p>(i) The system of records from which the record is retrieved;
</p><p>(ii) The particular record that he or she is seeking to amend or correct;
</p><p>(iii) Whether he or she is seeking an addition to or a deletion or substitution of the record; and,
</p><p>(iv) His or her reasons for requesting amendment or correction of the record.
</p><p>(2) A request for amendment or correction of a record will be acknowledged within 10 working days of
its receipt unless the request can be processed and the individual informed of the Privacy Act Officer's
decision on the request within that 10 day period.
</p><p>(3) If the Privacy Act Officer agrees that the record is not accurate, timely, or complete, based on
a preponderance of the evidence, the record will be corrected or amended. The record will be deleted
without regard to its accuracy, if the record is not relevant or necessary to accomplish the Corporation's
function for which the record was provided or is maintained. In either case, the individual will be
informed in writing of the amendment, correction, or deletion and, if accounting was made of prior
disclosures of the record, all previous recipients of the record will be informed of the corrective action
taken.
</p><p>(4) If the Privacy Act Officer does not agree that the record should be amended or corrected, the
individual will be informed in writing of the refusal to amend or correct the record. He or she will also
be informed that he or she may appeal the refusal to amend or correct his or her record in accordance with
&#167; 2508.17.
</p><p>(5) Requests to amend or correct a record governed by the regulation of another government agency
will be forwarded to such government agency for processing and the individual will be informed in writing
of the referral.
</p><p>(c) In the event an individual disagrees with the Privacy Act Officer's initial determination, he or
she may appeal such determination to the Appeal Officer in accordance with &#167; 2508.17. Such request for
review must be made within 30 days after receipt by the requestor of the initial refusal to amend.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.16
 What are the procedures for filing an appeal for refusal to amend or correct records?
</b></p><p>(a) In the event an individual desires to appeal any refusal to correct or amend records, he or
she may do so by addressing, in writing, such appeal to the Corporation for National and Community Service,
Office of the Chief Operating Officer, Attn: Appeal Officer, 1201 New York Avenue NW, Washington, DC 20525.
Although there is no time limit for such appeals, the Corporation shall be under no obligation to maintain
copies of original requests or responses thereto beyond 180 days from the date of the original request.
</p><p>(b) An appeal will be completed within 30 working days from its receipt by the Appeal Officer;
except that, the appeal authority may, for good cause, extend this period for an additional 30 days. Should
the appeal period be extended, the individual appealing the original refusal will be informed in writing of
the extension and the circumstances of the delay. The individual's request for access to or to amend or
correct the record, the Privacy Act Officer's refusal to amend or correct the record, and any other
pertinent material relating to the appeal will be reviewed. No hearing will be held.
</p><p>(c) If the Appeal Officer determines that the record that is the subject of the appeal should be
amended or corrected, the record will be amended or corrected and the individual will be informed in
writing of the amendment or correction. Where an accounting was made of prior disclosures of the record,
all previous recipients of the record will be informed of the corrective action taken.
</p><p>(d) If the appeal is denied, the subject individual will be informed in writing:
</p><p>(1) Of the denial and reasons for the denial;
</p><p>(2) That he or she has a right to seek judicial review of the denial; and
</p><p>(3) That he or she may submit to the Appeal Officer a concise statement of disagreement to be
associated with the disputed record and disclosed whenever the record is disclosed.
</p><p>(e) Whenever an individual submits a statement of disagreement to the Appeal Officer in accordance
with paragraph (d)(3) of this section, the record will be annotated to indicate that it is disputed. In any
subsequent disclosure, a copy of the subject individual's statement of disagreement will be disclosed with
the record. If the appeal authority deems it appropriate, a concise statement of the Appeal Officer's
reasons for denying the individual's appeal may also be disclosed with the record. While the individual
will have access to this statement of reasons, such statement will not be subject to correction or
amendment. Where an accounting was made of prior disclosures of the record, all previous recipients of the
record will be provided a copy of the individual's statement of disagreement, as well as the statement, if
any, of the Appeal Officer's reasons for denying the individual's appeal.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.17
 When shall fees be charged and at what rate?
</b></p><p>(a) No fees shall be charged for search time or for any other time expended by the Corporation
to review or produce a record except where an individual requests that a copy be made of the record to
which he or she is granted access. Where a copy of the record must be made in order to provide access to
the record (e.g., computer printout where no screen reading is available), the copy will be made available
to the individual without cost.
</p><p>(b) The applicable fee schedule is as follows:
</p><p>(1) Each copy of each page, up to 8 1/2 x 14", made by photocopy or similar process is
$0.10 per page.
</p><p>(2) Each copy of each microform frame printed on paper is $0.25.
</p><p>(3) Each aperture card is $0.25.
</p><p>(4) Each 105-mm fiche is $0.25.
</p><p>(5) Each 100-foot role of 35-mm microfilm is $7.00.
</p><p>(6) Each 100-foot role of 16-mm microfilm is $6.00.
</p><p>(7) Each page of computer printout without regard to the number of carbon copies concurrently
printed is $0.20.
</p><p>(8) Copying records not susceptible to photocopying (e.g., punch cards or magnetic tapes), at actual
cost to be determined on a case-by-case basis.
</p><p>(9) Other copying forms (e.g., typing or printing) will be charged at direct costs, including
personnel and equipment costs.
</p><p>(c) All copying fees shall be paid by the individual before the copying will be undertaken. Payments
shall be made by check or money order payable to the "Corporation for National and Community Service,"  and
provided to the Privacy Act Officer processing the request.
</p><p>(d) A copying fee shall not be charged or collected, or alternatively, it may be reduced, when it is
determined by the Privacy Act Officer, based on a petition, that the petitioning individual is indigent and
that the Corporation's resources permit a waiver of all or part of the fee. An individual is deemed to be
indigent when he or she is without income or lacks the resources sufficient to pay the fees.
</p><p>(e) Special and additional services provided at the request of the individual, such as certification
or authentication, postal insurance and special mailing arrangement costs, will be charged to the
individual.
</p><p>(f) A copying fee totaling $5.00 or less shall be waived, but the copying fees for contemporaneous
requests by the same individual shall be aggregated to determine the total fee.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.18
 What are the penalties for obtaining a record under false pretenses?
</b></p><p>The Privacy Act provides, in pertinent part that:
</p><p>(a) Any person who knowingly and willfully requests to obtain any record concerning an individual
from the Corporation under false pretenses shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000
(5 U.S.C. 552a(I)(3)).
</p><p>(b) A person who falsely or fraudulently attempts to obtain records under the Privacy Act also may
be subject to prosecution under such other criminal statutes as 18 U.S.C. 494, 495 and 1001.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.19
 What Privacy Act exemptions or control of systems of records are exempt from disclosure?
</b></p><p>(a) Certain systems of records that are maintained by the Corporation are exempted from
provisions of the Privacy Act in accordance with exemptions (j) and (k) of 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p><p>(1) Exemption of Inspector General system of records. Pursuant to, and limited by 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)
(2), the system of records maintained by the Office of the Inspector General that contains the
Investigative Files shall be exempted from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a, except subsections (b), (c) (1)
and (2), (e)(4) (A) through (F), (e)(6)(7), (9), (10), and (11), and (I), and 45 CFR 2508.11, 2508.12,
2508.13, 2508.14, 2508.15, 2508.16, and 2508.17, insofar as the system contains information pertaining to
criminal law enforcement investigations.
</p><p>(2) Pursuant to, and limited by 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), the system of records maintained by the Office
of the Inspector General that contains the Investigative Files shall be exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3),
(d), (e)(1), (e)(4) (G), (H), and (I), and (f), and 45 CFR 2508.11, 2508.12, 2508.13, 2508.14, 2508.15,
2508.16, and 2508.17, insofar as the system contains investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement
purposes.
</p><p>(b) Exemptions to the General Counsel system of records. Pursuant to, and limited by 5 U.S.C.
552a(d)(5), the system of records maintained by the Office of the General Counsel that contains the Legal
Office Litigation/Correspondence Files shall be exempted from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(5), and 45
CFR 2508.4, insofar as the system contains information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil
action or proceeding.

</p><p><b>&#167;2508.20
 What are the restrictions regarding the release of mailing lists?
</b></p><p>An individual's name and address may not be sold or rented by the Corporation unless such action
is specifically authorized by law. This section does not require the withholding of names and addresses
otherwise permitted to be made public.</p>

</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>





