<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>


<pai>
<agency toc="yes"> 
<name>Gulf Ecosystem Restoration Council</name>
<abbrev>Council</abbrev>
<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="40">
<heading>Protection of Environment</heading>
<regulationsChapter number="VIII">
<heading>GULF COAST ECOSYSTEM RESTORATION COUNCIL
</heading>
    
    
    
    
<regulationsPart number="1850">
<heading>-AVAILABILITY OF RECORDS</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart B--Production or Disclosure Under the Privacy Act</b>
</p>
<p>1850.31 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>1850.32 Definitions.
</p>
<p>1850.33 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</p>
<p>1850.34 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</p>
<p>1850.35 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</p>
<p>1850.36 Special procedures: Medical records.
</p>
<p>1850.37 Request for correction or amendment to record.
</p>
<p>1850.38 Council review of request for correction or amendment to record.
</p>
<p>1850.39 Appeal of initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>1850.40 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</p>
<p>1850.41 Fees.
</p>
<p>1850.42 Penalties.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 33 U.S.C. 1321(t); 5 U.S.C. 552; 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 80 FR 29451, May 22, 2015, unless otherwise noted.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.31
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>This subpart contains the regulations of the Gulf Coast Ecosystem Restoration Council (Council) implementing the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a. It sets forth the basic responsibilities of the Council under the Privacy Act (the Act) and offers guidance to members of the public who wish to exercise any of the rights established by the Act with regard to records maintained by the Council. Council records that are contained in a government-wide system of records established by the U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM), the General Services Administration (GSA), the Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB), the Office of Government Ethics (OGE), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) or the Department of Labor (DOL) for which those agencies have published systems notices are subject to the publishing agency’s Privacy Act regulations. Where the government-wide systems notices permit access to these records through the employing agency, an individual should submit requests for access to, for amendment of or for an accounting of disclosures to the Council in accordance with &#167; 1850.33.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.32
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) For purposes of this subpart, the terms <i>individual, maintain, record,</i> and <i>system of records</i> shall have the meanings set forth in 5 U.S.C. 552a(a).
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Working days</i> are business days and do not include Saturday, Sunday, or federal holidays.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.33
 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any person who wishes to be notified if a system of records maintained by the Council contains any record pertaining to him or her, or to request access to such record or to request an accounting of disclosures made of such record, shall submit a written request, either in person or by mail, in accordance with the instructions set forth in the system notice published in the <i>Federal Register.</i> The request shall include:
</p>
<p>(1) The name of the individual making the request;
</p>
<p>(2) The name of the system of records (as set forth in the system notice to which the request relates);
</p>
<p>(3) Any other information specified in the system notice;
</p>
<p>(4) When the request is for access to records, a statement indicating whether the requester desires to make a personal inspection of the records or be supplied with copies by mail; and
</p>
<p>(5) Any additional information required by &#167; 1850.34 for proper verification of identity or authority to access the information.
</p>
<p>(b) Requests pertaining to records contained in a system of records established by the Council and for which the Council has published a system notice should be submitted to the person or office indicated in the system notice. Requests pertaining to Council records contained in the government-wide systems of records listed below should be submitted as follows:
</p>
<p>(1) For systems OPM/GOVT-1 (General Personnel Records), OPM/GOVT-2 (Employee Performance File System Records), OPM/GOVT-3 (Records of Adverse Actions and Actions Based on Unacceptable Performance), GSA/GOVT-4 (Contracted Travel Services Program), OPM/GOVT-5 (Recruiting, Examining and Placement Records), OPM/GOVT-6 (Personnel Research and Test Validation Records), OPM/GOVT-7 (Applicant Race, Sex, National Origin, and Disability Status Records), OPM/GOVT-9 (Files on Position Classification Appeals, Job Grading Appeals and Retained Grade or Pay Appeals), OPM/GOVT-10 (Employee Medical File System Records) and DOL/ESA-13 (Office of Workers’ Compensation Programs, Federal Employees’ Compensation File), or any other government-wide system of record not specifically listed, to the <i>restorecouncil@restorethegulf.gov</i>]; and
</p>
<p>(2) For systems OGE/GOVT-1 (Executive Branch Public Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Ethics Program Records), OGE/GOVT-2 (Confidential Statements of Employment and Financial Interests) and MSPB/GOVT-1 (Appeal and Case Records), to the General Counsel at <i>restorecouncil@restorethegulf.gov.</i>
</p>
<p>(c) Any person whose request for access under paragraph (a) of this section is denied, may appeal that denial in accordance with &#167; 1850.39.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.34
 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</b></p>
<p>(a) If a person submitting a request for access under &#167; 1850.33 has asked that the Council authorize a personal inspection of records pertaining to that person, and the appropriate Council official has granted that request, the requester shall present himself or herself at the time and place specified in the Council’s response or arrange another, mutually convenient time with the appropriate Council official.
</p>
<p>(b) Prior to personal inspection of the records, the requester shall present sufficient personal identification (<i>e.g.,</i> driver’s license, employee identification card, social security card, credit cards). If the requester is unable to provide such identification, the requester shall complete and sign in the presence of a Council official a signed statement asserting his or her identity and stipulating that he or she understands that knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another individual under false pretenses is a misdemeanor punishable by fine up to $5,000.
</p>
<p>(c) Any person who has requested access under &#167; 1850.3 to records through personal inspection, and who wishes to be accompanied by another person or persons during this inspection, shall submit a written statement authorizing disclosure of the record in such person’s or persons’ presence.
</p>
<p>(d) If an individual submitting a request by mail under &#167; 1850.33 wishes to have copies furnished by mail, he or she must include with the request a signed and notarized statement asserting his or her identity and stipulating that he or she understands that knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another individual under false pretenses is a misdemeanor punishable by fine up to $5,000.
</p>
<p>(e) A request filed by the parent of any minor or the legal guardian of any incompetent person shall: State the relationship of the requester to the individual to whom the record pertains; present sufficient identification; and, if not evident from information already available to the Council, present appropriate proof of the relationship or guardianship.
</p>
<p>(f) A person making a request pursuant to a power of attorney must possess a specific power of attorney to make that request.
</p>
<p>(g) No verification of identity will be required where the records sought are publicly available under the Freedom of Information Act.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.35
 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Upon receipt of request for notification as to whether the Council maintains a record about an individual and/or request for access to such record:
</p>
<p>(1) The appropriate Council official shall acknowledge such request in writing within 10 working days of receipt of the request. Wherever practicable, the acknowledgement should contain the notification and/or determination required in paragraph (a)(2) of this section.
</p>
<p>(2) The appropriate Council official shall provide, within 30 working days of receipt of the request, written notification to the requester as to the existence of the records and/or a determination as to whether or not access will be granted. In some cases, such as where records have to be recalled from the Federal Records Center, notification and/or a determination of access may be delayed. In the event of such a delay, the Council official shall inform the requester of this fact, the reasons for the delay, and an estimate of the date on which notification and/or a determination will be forthcoming.
</p>
<p>(3) If access to a record is granted, the determination shall indicate when and where the record will be available for personal inspection. If a copy of the record has been requested, the Council official shall mail that copy or retain it at the Council to present to the individual, upon receipt of a check or money order in an amount computed pursuant to &#167; 1850.41.
</p>
<p>(4) When access to a record is to be granted, the appropriate Council official will normally provide access within 30 working days of receipt of the request unless, for good cause shown, he or she is unable to do so, in which case the requester shall be informed within 30 working days of receipt of the request as to those reasons and when it is anticipated that access will be granted.
</p>
<p>(5) The Council shall not deny any request under &#167; 1850.33 concerning the existence of records about the requester in any system of records it maintains, or any request for access to such records, unless that system is exempted from the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p>(6) If the Council receives a request pursuant to &#167; 1850.33 for access to records in a system of records it maintains which is so exempt, the appropriate Council official shall deny the request.
</p>
<p>(b) Upon request, the appropriate Council official shall make available an accounting of disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), unless that system is exempted from the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p>(c) If a request for access to records is denied pursuant to paragraph (a) or (b) of this section, the determination shall specify the reasons for the denial and advise the individual how to appeal the denial in accordance with &#167; 1850.39. All appeals must be submitted in writing to the General Counsel at <i>GeneralCounsel@restorethegulf.gov.</i>
</p>
<p>(d) Nothing in 5 U.S.C. 552a or this subpart allows an individual access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.36
 Special procedures: Medical records.
</b></p>
<p>In the event the Council receives a request pursuant to &#167; 1850.33 for access to medical records (including psychological records) and the appropriate Council official determines disclosure could be harmful to the individual to whom they relate, he or she may refuse to disclose the records directly to the requester but shall transmit them to a physician designated by that individual.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.37
 Request for correction or amendment to record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any person who wishes to request correction or amendment of any record pertaining to him or her that is contained in a system of records maintained by the Council, shall submit that request in writing in accordance with the instructions set forth in the system notice for that system of records. If the request is submitted by mail, the envelope should be clearly labeled “Personal Information Amendment.” The request shall include:
</p>
<p>(1) The name of the individual making the request;
</p>
<p>(2) The name of the system of records as set forth in the system notice to which the request relates;
</p>
<p>(3) A description of the nature (<i>e.g.,</i> modification, addition or deletion) and substance of the correction or amendment requested; and
</p>
<p>(4) Any other information specified in the system notice.
</p>
<p>(b) Any person submitting a request pursuant to paragraph (a) of this section shall include sufficient information in support of that request to allow the Council to apply the standards set forth in 5 U.S.C. 552a(e) requiring the Council to maintain accurate, relevant, timely, and complete information.
</p>
<p>(c) All requests to amend pertaining to personnel records described in &#167; 1850.33(b) shall conform to the requirements of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section and may be directed to the appropriate officials as indicated in &#167; 1850.33(b). Such requests may also be directed to the system manager specified in the OPM’s systems notices.
</p>
<p>(d) Any person whose request under paragraph (a) of this section is denied may appeal that denial in accordance with &#167; 1850.39.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.38
 Council review of request for correction or amendment to record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) When the Council receives a request for amendment or correction under &#167; 1850.37(a), the appropriate Council official shall acknowledge that request in writing within 10 working days of receipt. He or she shall promptly either:
</p>
<p>(1) Determine to grant all or any portion of a request for correction or amendment; and:
</p>
<p>(i) Advise the individual of that determination;
</p>
<p>(ii) Make the requested correction or amendment; and
</p>
<p>(iii) Inform any person or agency outside the Council to whom the record has been disclosed, and where an accounting of that disclosure is maintained in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(c), of the occurrence and substance of the correction or amendments; or
</p>
<p>(2) Inform the requester of the refusal to amend the record in accordance with the request; the reason for the refusal; and the procedures whereby the requester can appeal the refusal to the General Counsel of the Council in accordance with &#167; 1850.39.
</p>
<p>(b) If the Council official informs the requester of the determination within the 10-day deadline, a separate acknowledgement is not required.
</p>
<p>(c) In conducting the review of a request for correction or amendment, the Council official shall be guided by the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(e).
</p>
<p>(d) In the event that the Council receives a notice of correction or amendment from another agency that pertains to records maintained by the Council, the Council shall make the appropriate correction or amendment to its records and comply with paragraph (a)(1)(iii) of this section.
</p>
<p>(e) Requests for amendment or correction of records maintained in the government-wide systems of records listed in &#167; 1850.35(c) shall be governed by the appropriate agency’s regulations cited in that paragraph.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.39
 Appeal of initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
</b></p>
<p>(a) If a request for correction or amendment of a record in a system of records maintained by the Council is denied, the requester may appeal the determination in writing to the General Counsel at <i>GeneralCounsel@restorethegulf.gov.</i>
</p>
<p>(b) The General Counsel shall make a final determination with regard to an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section not later than 30 working days from the date on which the individual requests a review, unless for good cause shown, this 30-day period is extended and the requester is notified of the reasons for the extension and of the estimated date on which a final determination will be made. Such extensions will be used only in exceptional circumstances and will not normally exceed 30 working days.
</p>
<p>(c) In conducting the review of an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section, the General Counsel shall be guided by the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(e).
</p>
<p>(d) If the General Counsel determines to grant all or any portion of a request on an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section, he or she shall so inform the requester, and the appropriate Council official shall comply with the procedures set forth in &#167; 1850.38(a)(1)(ii) and (iii).
</p>
<p>(e) If the General Counsel determines in accordance with paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section not to grant all or any portion of a request on an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section, he or she shall inform the requester:
</p>
<p>(1) Of this determination and the reasons for it;
</p>
<p>(2) Of the requester’s right to file a concise statement of reasons for disagreement with the determination of the General Counsel;
</p>
<p>(3) That such statements of disagreement will be made available to anyone to whom the record is subsequently disclosed, together with (if the General Counsel deems it appropriate) a brief statement summarizing the General Counsel’s reasons for refusing to amend the record;
</p>
<p>(4) That prior recipients of the disputed record will be provided with a copy of the statement of disagreement together with (if the General Counsel deems it appropriate) a brief statement of the General Counsel’s reasons for refusing to amend the record, to the extent that an accounting of disclosure is maintained under 5 U.S.C. 552a(c); and
</p>
<p>(5) Of the requester’s right to file a civil action in Federal district court to seek a review of the determination of the General Counsel in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).
</p>
<p>(f) The General Counsel shall ensure that any statements of disagreement submitted by a requester are made available or distributed in accordance with paragraphs (e)(3) and (4) of this section.
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.40
 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</b></p>
<p>The Counsel shall not disclose any record which is contained in a system of records it maintains, by any means of communication to any person or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains, unless the disclosure is authorized by one or more provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(b).
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.41
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) No fee shall be charged for searches necessary to locate records. No charge shall be made if the total fees authorized are less than $1.00. Fees shall be charged for services rendered under this subpart as follows:
</p>
<p>(1) For copies made by photocopy--$0.05 per page (maximum of 10 copies). For copies prepared by computer, such as tapes or printouts, the Council will charge the direct cost incurred by the agency, including operator time. For other forms of duplication, the Council will charge the actual costs of that duplication.
</p>
<p>(2) For attestation of documents--$25.00 per authenticating affidavit or declaration.
</p>
<p>(3) For certification of documents--$50.00 per authenticating affidavit or declaration.
</p>
<p>(b) All required fees shall be paid in full prior to issuance of requested copies of records. Requesters must pay fees by check or money order made payable to the “Treasury of the United States.”
</p><p><b>&#167; 1850.42
 Penalties.
</b></p>
         <p>
             The criminal penalties which have been established for violations of the Privacy Act of 1974 are set forth in 5 U.S.C. 552a(i). Penalties are applicable to any officer or employee of the Council; to contractors and employees of such contractors who enter into contracts with the Council, and who are considered to be employees of the Council within the meaning of 5 U.S.C. 552a(m); and to any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual from the Council under false pretenses.
         </p>
    </xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
