<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>


<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Agency for International Development</name>
<abbrev>
AID

</abbrev>
    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-01-14/pdf/2021-00450.pdf</url>
        <title>Partner-Vetting System, USAID – 27</title>
        <date year="2021" month="1" day="14" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-15/pdf/2021-27096.pdf</url>
        <title>Travel and Transportation Records, USAID-19.</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="15" />
    </previouslyPublished>




    <routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Statement of General Routine Uses</b></p>
<p>The following routine uses apply to, and are incorporated by reference into each system of records set forth below to
the extent therein applicable:
</p><p>1. In the event of an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory
in nature, and whether arising by statute or particular program pursuant thereto, a record in this system of records may
be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the
responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or
rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a federal, state or local agency
maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information if necessary to
obtain information relevant to an Agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a
security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the approval of a grant or other benefits</p>
<p>3. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a federal agency, in response to its
request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of
an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, approval of a grant or other
benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's
decision on the matter</p>
<p>4. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, in the course of presenting evidence to a
court, magistrate or administrative tribunal, including disclosures to opposing counsel in the course of settlement
negotiations</p>
<p>5. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as routine use, to the Department of State and its posts
abroad for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency, or for purposes related
to the responsibilities of the Department of State in conducting United States foreign policy or protecting United States
citizens, such as the assignment of employees to positions abroad, the reporting of accidents abroad, evacuation of
employees and dependents, and other purposes for which officers and employees of the Department of State have a need for
the records in the performance of their duties</p>
<p>6. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a foreign government or international
agency in response to its request for information to facilitate the conduct of U.S. relations with that government or
agency through the issuance of such documents as visas, country clearances, identification cards, drivers' licenses,
diplomatic lists, licenses to import or export personal effects, and other official documents and permits routinely
required in connection with the official service or travel abroad of the individual and his or her dependents</p>
<p>7. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to Federal agencies with which the Agency
has entered into an agreement to provide services to assist the Agency in carrying out its functions under the Foreign
Assistance Act of 1961, as amended. Such disclosures would be for the purpose of transmission of information between
organizational units of the Agency; of providing to the original employing agency information concerning the services of
its employee while under the supervision of the Agency, including performance evaluations, reports of conduct, awards and
commendations, and information normally obtained in the course of personnel administration and employee supervision; or
of providing other information directly related to the purposes of the inter-agency agreement as set forth therein, and
necessary and relevant to its implementation</p>
<p>8. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a Member of Congress or a Congressional
staff representative of the Member in response to an inquiry from a Member made at the request of an individual</p>
<p>9. A record in those systems of records which contains medical information may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the
medical adviser of any individual submitting a request for access to the record under the Act and 15 CFR part 4b if, in
the sole judgment of the Agency, disclosure could have an adverse effect upon the individual, under the provision of 5
U.S.C. 552a(f)(3) and implementing regulations at 15 CFR 4b.6</p>
<p>10. A record contained in this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the Office of Management and
Budget in connection with the review of private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19 at any stage of
the legislative coordination and clearance process as set forth in that Circular</p>
<p>11. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the Foreign Service Grievance Board in
the course of the Board's consideration of matters properly before it

</p><p>12. A record in this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use: To the Defense Manpower Data Center,
Department of Defense and to the U.S. Postal Service, to conduct computer matching programs for the purpose of
identifying and locating individuals who are receiving Federal salaries or benefit payment and delinquent in their
repayment of debts owed to the U.S. Government under certain programs administered by USAID in order to collect the debts
under the provisions of the Debt Collection Act of 1982 (Pub. L. 97-365) by voluntary repayment, or by
administrative or salary offset procedures; and to any other Federal agency for the purpose of effecting administrative
or salary offset procedures against a person employed by that agency or receiving or eligible to receive some benefit
payments from the agency when USAID as a creditor has a claim against that person. Disclosure of information about
persons who are receiving Federal salaries or benefit payments and are delinquent in their repayment of debts owed to the
U.S. Government under certain programs administered by USAID may be made to other Federal agencies, but only to the
extent of determining whether the person is employed by that agency and if so, effecting administrative or salary offset
procedures against the person</p>
<p>13. A record in the following systems of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>Claims Records (AID-20)
</p><p>Employee Payroll Records (AID-15)
</p><p>Litigation Records (AID-26) and
</p><p>Travel and Transportation Records (AID-19)
</p><p>14. A record in the following systems of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the Internal Revenue Service
(a) to obtain mailing addresses of debtors in order to collect a Federal debt; and (b) to offset a Federal debt against
the debtor's income tax refund:
</p><p>Claims Records (AID-20), Employee Payroll Records (AID-15), Litigation Records (AID-26), and Travel
and Transportation Records (AID-19)</p></xhtmlContent>
		</routineUses>
<section id="aid1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
	<subsection type="systemName">
	Foreign Service Personnel Records.</subsection>
	<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523 and other USAID offices in the United States and throughout the world; U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), National Finance Center (NFC), New Orleans, LA 70129; U.S. Department of the Treasury, Internal Revenue Service, IRS-Enterprise Computing Center-Detroit, Detroit, MI 48232; Washington National Records Center, 4205 Suitland Road, Suitland, MD 20746-8001; and National Personnel Records Center, National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, MO 63118.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>The system encompasses all individuals who are current or former employees hired under the Foreign Service Act authority by 1) USAID or 2) another federal agency and on detail to USAID.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>This system consists of records created or compiled for Foreign Service Act personnel actions, including official personnel files; work experience, education level achieved, and specialized education or training obtained both inside and outside of Foreign Service; Federal service, past and present positions held, grades, salaries, duty station locations; notices of all personnel actions, such as appointments, transfers, reassignments, details, promotions, demotions, reductions-in-force, resignations, separations, suspensions, and removals; life and health insurance benefits; position classification; recruiting, examining, and placement; disability, race/ethnicity, and national origin classification data; evaluation and performance management; employee conduct and discipline; executive assignments; orientation and training; awards and incentives; workers compensation; designations for lump-sum death benefits; classified information nondisclosure agreements; Thrift Savings Plan; and ethics pledges and all pledge waiver certifications.   Medical records, forms, and reports are included when they are related to the application for and employment as a Foreign Service position, including health records related to workers’ compensation claims, employee health promotion and wellness activities, and drug testing.  All categories of records may include identifying information, such as name, Social Security Number, mailing address, home telephone number, cell phone number, resume, clearance level, pay grade, salary, direct-deposit financial information, position title, and position number.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>The system was established and is maintained pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 5 U.S.C. 302, Delegation of Authority; 22 U.S.C. Ch. 32, Foreign Assistance, Subchapter I, International Development; 22 U.S.C. Ch. 52, Foreign Service.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>The records are collected, used, maintained, and disseminated for the purpose of documenting all processes associated with individual Foreign Service employment histories and career progression, including screening qualifications of employees; determining status, eligibility, and employee’s rights and benefits; computing length of service; other Foreign Service personnel services; and making personnel management determinations about Foreign Service personnel throughout their Foreign Service careers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b), all or a portion of the records contained in this system of records may be disclosed outside USAID as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
	<p>(1) To a court, magistrate, or other administrative body in the course of presenting evidence, including disclosures to counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations or in connection with criminal proceedings, when USAID is a party to the proceeding or has a significant interest in the proceeding, to the extent that the information is determined to be relevant and necessary.</p>
	<p>(2) To the Department of Justice or other appropriate Federal Government agency when the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding in a court or other tribunal in which USAID or a USAID official in his or her official capacity is a party or has an interest, or when the litigation is likely to affect USAID.</p>
	<p>(3) To a Federal Government agency or entity that furnished the record or information for the purpose of permitting that agency or entity to make a decision as to access to or correction of the record or information.</p>
	<p>(4) In the event of an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by statute or particular program pursuant thereto, to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
	<p>(5) To the Department of State and its posts abroad for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency, or for purposes related to the responsibilities of the Department of State in conducting United States foreign policy or protecting United States citizens, such as the assignment of employees to positions abroad, the reporting of accidents abroad, evacuation of employees and dependents, and other purposes for which officers and employees of the Department of State have a need for the records in the performance of their duties.</p>
	<p>(6) To a foreign government or international agency in response to its request for information to facilitate the conduct of U.S. relations with that government or agency through the issuance of such documents as visas, country clearances, identification cards, drivers' licenses, diplomatic lists, licenses to import or export personal effects, and other official documents and permits routinely required in connection with the official service or travel abroad of the individual and his or her dependents.</p>
	<p>(7) To Federal agencies with which USAID has entered into an agreement to provide services to assist USAID in carrying out its functions under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended.  Such disclosures would be for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of USAID; of providing to the original employing agency information concerning the services of its employee while under the supervision of USAID, including performance evaluations, reports of conduct, awards and commendations, and information normally obtained in the course of personnel administration and employee supervision; or of providing other information directly related to the purposes of the inter-agency agreement as set forth therein, and necessary and relevant to its implementation.</p>
	<p>(8) To appropriate officials and employees of a Federal Government agency or entity when the information is relevant to a decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; the assignment, detail or deployment of an employee; the issuance, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation; the letting of a contract; or the issuance of a grant or benefit.</p>
	<p>(9) To a committee or subcommittee of Congress and the Government Accountability Office for the purposes of responding to inquiries.</p>
	<p>(10) To the National Archives and Records Administration, Information Security Oversight Office, Interagency Security Classification Appeals Panel, for the purpose of adjudicating an appeal from a USAID denial of a request for mandatory declassification review of records, made under the applicable executive order(s) governing classification.</p>
	<p>(11) To the National Archives and Records Administration, Office of Government Information Services (OGIS), to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities in 5 U.S.C. 552(h), to review administrative agency policies, procedures, and compliance with the Freedom of Information Act, and to facilitate OGIS’ offering of mediation services to resolve disputes between persons making FOIA requests and administrative agencies.</p>
	<p>(12) To the National Archives and Records Administration for the purposes of records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
	<p>(13) To a former employee of USAID for purposes of responding to an official inquiry by a Federal, State, or local government entity or professional licensing authority, in accordance with applicable agency regulations; or facilitating communications with a former employee that may be necessary for personnel-related or other official purposes where USAID requires information and/or consultation assistance from the former employee regarding a matter within that person’s former area of responsibility.</p>
	<p>(14) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) USAID suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) USAID has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the USAID or another agency, entity, or person) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with USAID’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
	<p>(15) To attorneys, union representatives, or other persons designated by USAID employees in writing to represent them in complaints, grievance, appeal, or litigation cases. </p>
	<p>(16) To requestors in determining a former spouse's entitlement to benefits and other inquiries related to retirement benefits.</p>
	<p>(17) To labor organization officials when such information is relevant to personnel policies affecting employment conditions and necessary for exclusive representation by the labor organization.</p>
	<p>(18) To officials of foreign governments and other U.S. government agencies for clearance before a Federal employee is assigned to that country as well as for the procurement of necessary services for American personnel assigned overseas, such as permits of free entry and identity cards.</p>
	<p>(19) To the Department of Labor, Department of Veterans Affairs, Social Security Administration, Department of Defense, or any other Federal agencies that have special civilian employee retirement and disability programs; or to a national, state, county, municipal, or other publicly recognized income administration agency (e.g. State unemployment compensation agencies), when necessary to adjudicate a claim under the retirement, insurance, unemployment or health benefits programs of USAID or an agency cited above, or to an agency to conduct an analytical study or audit of benefits being paid under such programs.</p>
	<p>(20) To the Office of Federal Employees Group Life Insurance, information necessary to verify election, declination, or waiver of regular and/or optional life insurance coverage, or eligibility for payment of a claim for life insurance.</p>
	<p>(21) To health insurance carriers contracting with the Federal government to provide a health benefits plan under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, information necessary to identify enrollment in a plan, to verify eligibility for payment of a claim for health benefits, or to carry out the coordination or audit of benefit provisions of such contracts.</p>
	<p>(22) To any person who is responsible for the care of an individual to whom a record pertains who is mentally incompetent or under other legal disability. Information in the individual's record may be disclosed to said person to the extent necessary to assure payment of benefits to which the individual is entitled.</p>
	<p>(23) To public and private organizations, including news media, which grant or publicize employee recognition to consider and select employees for incentive awards and other honors and to publicize awards and honors granted.</p>
	<p>(24) To the Department of Justice in connection with proceedings before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body when any of the following is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation and USAID determines that the use of such records is arguably relevant and necessary to the litigation of (1) the USAID or any component thereof, (2) any employee of the USAID in his or her official capacity, (3) any employee of the USAID in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the USAID has agreed to represent the employee, or (4) the United States, when the USAID determines that litigation is likely to affect the USAID or any of its components.</p>
	<p>(25) To implement court decisions and/or terms of settlement agreements reached by the parties.</p>
	<p>(26) To prepare reports to the courts in compliance with monitoring requirements.</p>
	<p>(27) To courts or federal agencies including, but not limited to, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Foreign Service Grievance Board, and the Merit Systems Protection Board, in response to an order directing the production of personnel records.</p>
	<p>(28) To other Government agencies and private organizations, institutions or individuals to verify employment, to process security clearances and to request record or credit checks.</p>
	<p>(29) To officials of other Federal agencies for purposes of performance of official duties in support of the functions for which the records were collected and maintained.</p>
	<p>(30) To disclose information to Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) counselors and EEO investigators in connection with EEO complaints and to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in connection with investigations of alleged or possible discrimination practices in the Federal sector, examination of Federal affirmative employment programs, compliance by Federal agencies with the Uniform Guidelines on Employee Selection Procedures, or other functions vested in the Commission.</p>
	<p>(31) To the Department of Labor's Office of Workers' Compensation programs relating to benefits under the Federal Employees Compensation Act.</p>
	<p>(32) To disclose information to the news media and the public when a matter involving the USAID has become public knowledge; the Assistant Administrator Under Secretary for Management determines that in response to the matter in the public domain, disclosure is necessary to provide an accurate factual record on the matter; and the Assistant Administrator for Management determines that there is a legitimate public interest in the information disclosed.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Storage:</p>
	<p>Paper and microfiche records are maintained by USAID and are safeguarded in secured cabinets within secured rooms.  The electronic records are stored in the HR Connect system, Electronic Official Personnel File (eOPF) system, and National Finance Center Payroll/Personnel System, which are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies, including all applicable USAID automated systems security and access policies.  Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is being stored.  Access to the records is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Records are retrieved by the name of the Foreign Service personnel and numeric identifier.  </p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Information in this system is safeguarded in accordance with applicable laws, rules and policies, including the agency’s automated directive system.  In general, records and technical equipment are maintained in buildings with restricted access.  The required use of password protection identification features and other system protection methods also restrict access.  Access is limited to those officers and authorized USAID employees who have an official need to access the records in the performance of their official duties.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with the National Archives Records Administration’s General Records Disposition Schedules and the agency’s approved disposition schedules.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Director, Foreign Service Center, Human Capital and Talent Management, United States Agency for International Development, Office of Human Resources, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC  20523.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Same as Record Access Procedures.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Under the Privacy Act, individuals may request access to records about themselves.  If an agency or a person, who is not the individual who is the subject of the records, requests access to records about an individual, the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records is required.</p>
	<p> Requesters may submit requests for records under the Privacy Act: (1) by mail to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701; (2) via Facsimile to 202-216-3070; (3) via email to foia@usaid.gov;  (4) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia-requests; or (5) in person during regular business hours at USAID, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523-2701, or at USAID overseas missions.</p>
	<p> Requesters using 1 through 4 may provide a written statement or may complete and submit USAID Form 507-1, Freedom of Information / Privacy Act Record Request Form, which can be obtained: (a) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia -requests; (b) by email request to foia@usaid.gov; or (c) by writing to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701, and provide information that is necessary to identify the records, including the following:  Requester’s full name; present mailing address; home telephone; work telephone; name of subject, if other than requester; requester relationship to subject; description of type of information or specific records; and purpose of requesting information.  Requesters should provide the system of record identification name and number, if known; and, to facilitate the retrieval of records contained in those systems of records which are retrieved by Social Security Numbers, the Social Security Number of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
	<p>In addition, requesters using 1 through 4 must include proof of identity information by providing copies of two (2) source documents that must be notarized by a valid (un-expired) notary public.  Acceptable proof-of-identity source documents include:  an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card (both sides); unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.  </p>
	<p> Requesters using 1 through 4 must also provide a signed and notarized statement that they are the person named in the request; that they understand that any falsification of their statement is punishable under the provision of 18 USC 1001 by a fine, or by imprisonment of not more than five years or, if the offense involves international or domestic terrorism (as defined in section 2331), imprisonment of not more than eight years, or both; and that requesting or obtaining records under false pretenses is punishable under the provisions of 5 USC 552a(i)(3) as a misdemeanor and by a fine of not more than $5,000.  </p>
	<p>Requesters using 5 must provide such personal identification as is reasonable under the circumstances to verify the requester’s identity, including the following: an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card; unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.</p>
	</xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Individuals seeking to contest or amend records maintained on himself or herself must clearly and concisely state that information is being contested, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.  Requests to amend a record must follow the Record Access Procedures above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>These records contain information provided directly by the individuals who are the subject of these records; and from administrative officers in USAID bureaus and missions, Office of Human Resources employees, and other sources of records maintained in the official personnel files of Foreign Service personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
	<p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(1), subject to the provisions of section 552(b)(1), records are exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I), and (f) to protect material required to be kept Secret.  Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(4), records contained within this system that are maintained solely for statistical purposes are also exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I), and (f).  Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(5) and (k)(7), certain records contained within this system contain confidential source information and are exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I), and (f).  Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(6), records that contain testing or examination material the release of which may compromise testing or examination procedures are also exempted from 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I), and (f).  See USAID Rules published in 22 CFR 215.13 and 215.14.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
	<section id="aid2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
	<subsection type="systemName"> [Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-2, General Personnel Records]</subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Employees Automated Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: USAID-3 Employees Automated Records is covered by several government-wide systems of records notices OPM/Govt-1 General Personnel Records (December 11, 2013, 77 FR 73694); OPM/Govt-2 Employee Performance File System of Records (June 19, 2006, 71 FR 35342, 35347); OPM/Govt-3 Records of Adverse Actions, Performance Based Reduction in Grade and Removal Actions, and Termination of Probationers (June 19, 2006, 71 FR 35342, 35350); OPM/Govt-5 Recruiting, Examining, and Placement Records (June 19, 2006, 71 FR 35342, 35351); OPM/Govt-7 Applicant Race, Sex, National Origin, and Disability Status Records (June 19, 2006, 71 FR 35342, 35356); and EEOC/Govt-1 Equal Employment Opportunity in the Federal Government Complaint and Appeal Records (July 30, 2002, 67 FR 49338, 49354, as amended April 6, 2006, 71 FR 24704, 24705). USAID-3 can therefore be deleted.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Position Classification Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Personnel and Manpower, State Annex 2, 515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Employees of A.I.D.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Position descriptions, appeals, correspondence relating to position
classification, reviews of classifications and the determinations made thereon, and Notifications of Personnel Actions
(SF-50's) relating to the position.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended sec. 621 and the
Foreign Service Act of 1946 as amended; 5 U.S.C. 301, 1302, 2951, 4118, 4308, and Executive Orders 10561 and 10987.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, and Members of Congress, for the purposes set forth in the Statement of General Routine Uses
immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copies in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> Name of individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Located in metal file cabinets with three-way combination locks in a secure space or secured
premises with access limited to those whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Retained by A.I.D. as long as five years (in case of appeals against position
classification actions), then destroyed by shredding.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> For Civil Service personnel: Chief, Civil Service Personnel, Office of
Personnel and Manpower, Agency for International Development, 515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For Foreign Service personnel: Chief, Position Management &amp;Foreign National Branch, Office of Personnel and
Manpower, Agency for International Development, 515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be addressed to:
</p><p>Director
</p><p>Office of Personnel and Manpower (SER/PM)
</p><p>Attn: Privacy Liaison Officer
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC 20523
</p><p>or presented in person at State Annex 2, 515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>Information Required: Individual's name, place and date of birth. The determination as to the existence of a record
will be facilitated by the provision of the individual's Social Security number and dates and places of service.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed or presented in person to the same
addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests should be accompanied by information sufficient to identify the individual pursuant to &#167; 215.4(c) or
(d) of the Agency's Regulations as published in this issue of the <i>Federal Register</i>.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Written requests from individuals to amend their record should be mailed or
presented in person to the same addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests for review of a refusal to amend a record should be made in writing and mailed to:
</p><p>Administrator
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC 20523
</p><p>ATTENTION: Executive Secretary--Privacy Review Request</p>
<p>Both the envelope and the letter should be clearly marked Attention: Executive Secretary--Privacy Review
Requests.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> The individual concerned and A.I.D. employees acting in their official capacities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="aid5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">[Reserved]</subsection></section>
<section id="aid6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">[Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-5, Recruiting, Examining, Placement and Employee Records]</subsection></section>
<section id="aid7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">[Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-2, Employee Performance File System Records]</subsection></section>

   <section id="aid8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber> 
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security and Suitability Investigations Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Secret.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records covered by this system are maintained at the following locations: (Paper) USAID Office of Security,
1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, Washington, DC 20523; (Electronic copies) Terremark NAP of the Americas, 2 S Biscayne
Blvd., Miami FL 33131.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Categories of individuals maintained in this system are: current and former USAID employees; contractor
personnel (Personal Service Contractors and Institutional Contractors); applicants for employment; persons and
entities performing business with USAID to include consultants, volunteers, grantees and recipients; individuals
employed from other Federal Agencies through a detail, Participating Agency Service Agreement, Resources Support
Services Agreement, or the Interagency Personnel Act; individuals working at USAID through government agreements
(second agreement); paid and unpaid interns; and visitors requiring access to USAID facilities; and the U.S.
Citizen and/or non-U.S. Citizen spouse, intended spouse, family members, and/or cohabitants of the above listed
individuals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Categories of records maintained in this system are: name; address; date of birth; social security number (or
other identifying number); citizenship status; information regarding an individual's character, conduct and
behavior in the community where they presently live and/or previously lived; arrests and/or convictions; medical
records; educational institutions attended; employment records; reports from interviews and other inquiries;
electronic communication cables; facility access authorizations/restrictions; photographs, fingerprints;
financial records including credit reports; previous clearances levels granted; resulting clearance levels;
documentation of release of security files; request for special access; records of infractions; and records of
facility accesses and credentials issued.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 10450: Security requirements for Government Employment; Homeland Security Presidential
Directive 12 (HSPD-12): Policy for a Common Identification Standard for Federal Employees and Contractors;
Executive Order 12968: Access to Classified Information,; Executive Order 12333: United States Intelligence
Activities; Executive Order 13381: Strengthening Processes Relating to Determining Eligibility for Access to
Classified National Security Information; Executive Order 13467: Reforming Processes Related to Suitability for
Government Employment, Fitness for Contractor Employees, and Eligibility for Access to Classified National
Security Information; Executive Order 13488: Granting Reciprocity on Excepted Service and Federal Contractor
Employee Fitness and Reinvestigating Individuals in Positions of Public Trust; and the Intelligence Reform and
Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (Public Law 108-458).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The Office of Security gathers information in order to create investigative records, which are used for
processing personal security background investigations to determine eligibility to be awarded a federal security
clearance, suitability or fitness determination for federal employment, access to federally owned/controlled
facilities and access to federally owned/controlled information systems.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to USAID's Statement of General Routine Uses, the Office of Security may disclose information in
this system as follows:
</p><p>(1) To consumer reporting agencies in order to obtain consumer credit reports,




</p><p>(2) To federal, international, state, and local law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government Agencies, courts,
the Department of State, Foreign Governments, to the extent necessary to further the purposes of an
investigation,
</p><p>(3) Results of the investigation may be disclosed to the Department of State or other Federal Agencies for the
purposes of granting physical and/or logical access to federally owned or controlled facilities and/or
information systems in accordance with the requirements set forth in HSPD-12.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copies of information are maintained in file folders and secured using locked cabinets and safes.
Electronic copies of information are secured using password protection and role-based protocols.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by last name, social security number, and/or USAID assigned case number or other
unique identifier attributed to the individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept within the Office of Security secured space. Access to this space is controlled by electronic
card readers, office personnel to control access, visitor escorts policy and supplemented by an armed response
force. Administrative safeguards of records are provided through the use of internal Standard Operating
Procedures and routine appraisal reviews of the personnel security and suitability program by the Director of
National Intelligence and the Office of Personnel Management.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained using the approved National Archives Records Administration, Schedule 18-Security and
Protective Services Records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, USAID: Office of Security, RRB, Suite 2.06-A, 1300 Pennsylvania Ave. NW., Washington, DC
20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are exempt from notification access, and amendment procedures in accordance with
subsection (k) (1) and (5) of the 5 U.S.C. 552a, and 22CFR 215.13 of 14. Individuals wishing to inquire whether
this system of records contains information about themselves should submit their inquires in writing to the USAID
Chief Privacy Officer, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington, VA 22202</p>
<p>The request must be in writing and include the requestor's full name, date of birth, social security number,
and current address. In addition, requestors must also reasonably specify the record contents being sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See "Notification Procedures."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual requesting amendment of a record maintained on himself or herself must identify the information
to be changed and the corrective action sought. Requests must follow the "Notification Procedures"
above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system is obtained from the individual on whom it applies; independent sources such as
other government agencies, state/local government; law enforcement agencies; credit bureaus; medical providers;
educational institutions; private organizations; information provided by personal references; and through source
interviews.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Under the specific authority provided by subsection (k) (1), (3), and (5) of 5 U.S.C. 552a, USAID has
promulgated rules specified in 22 CFR 215.14, that exempts this system from notice, access, and amendment
requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a, subsections (c) (3), (d); (e) (1); (e) (4); (G); (H); (I); and (f). The reasons
for these exemptions are to maintain confidentiality of sources, National Security, and to prevent frustration of
the federal investigative process.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Criminal Law Enforcement Records System</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive But Unclassified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Terremark NAP of the Americas, 2 S Biscayne Blvd., Miami, FL 33131.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>In connection with its investigative duties, OIG maintains records in its Criminal law Enforcement Records System on the following
categories of individuals insofar as they are relevant to any investigation or preliminary inquiry undertaken to determine whether to
commence an investigation: complainants; witnesses; confidential and non-confidential informants; contractors; subcontractors;
recipients of federal assistance or funds and their contractors/subcontractors and employees; individuals threatening USAID employees
or the USAID Administrator; current, former, and prospective employees of USAID; alleged violators of USAID rules and regulations;
union officials; individuals investigated and/or interviewed; persons suspected of violations of administrative, civil, and/or criminal
provisions; grantees; sub-grantees; lessees; licensees; and other persons engaged in official business with USAID.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The system contains investigative reports and materials gathered or created with regard to investigations of administrative, civil,
and criminal matters by OIG and other Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, or foreign regulatory or law enforcement agencies.
Categories of records may include: complaints; request to investigate; information contained in criminal, civil, or administrative
referrals; statements from subjects, targets, and/or witnesses; affidavits, transcripts, police reports, photographs, and/or documents
relative to a subject's prior criminal record; medical records, accident reports, materials and intelligence information from other
governmental investigatory or law enforcement organizations; information relative to the status of a particular complaint or
investigation, including any determination relative to criminal prosecution, civil, or administrative action; general case management
documentation; subpoenas and evidence obtained in response to subpoenas; evidence logs; pen registers; correspondence, records of
seized property; reports of laboratory examination; reports of investigation; and other data or evidence collected or generated by
OIG's Office of Investigations during the course of conducting its official duties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Inspector General Act of 1978, 5 U.S.C. App. 3, as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The records contained in this system are used by OIG to carry out its statutory responsibilities under the Inspector General Act of
1978, as amended, to conduct and supervise investigations relating to programs and operations of USAID; to promote economy, efficiency,
and effectiveness in the administration of such programs and operations; and to prevent and detect fraud, waste, and abuse in such
programs and operations. The records are used in the course of investigating individuals and entities suspected of having committed
illegal or unethical acts, and in conducting related criminal prosecutions, civil proceedings, and administrative actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>USAID's routine uses, see 42 FR 47371 (September 20, 1977) and 59 FR 52954 (October 20, 1994), apply to this system of records. As
additional routine uses for this records system, USAID/OIG may disclose information in this system as follows:
</p><p>(a) Disclosure to the Department of Justice (DOJ) or a legal representative designated by a Federal Agency in circumstances in
which:
</p><p>(1) USAID or OIG, or any component thereof:
</p><p>(2) Any employee of USAID or OIG in his or her official capacity;
</p><p>(3) Any employee of USAID or OIG in his or her individual capacity, where the DOJ has agreed to represent or is considering a
request to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(4) The United States or any of its components is a party to pending or potential litigation or has an interest in such litigation,
USAID or OIG will be affected by the litigation, or USAID or OIG determines that the use of such records by the DOJ is relevant and
necessary to the litigation; provided, however, that in each case, USAID or OIG determines that disclosure of the records to the DOJ is
a use of the information that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>(b) Disclosure to any source from which additional information is requested in order to obtain information relevant to:
</p><p>(1) A decision by either USAID or OIG concerning the hiring, assignment, or retention of an individual or other personnel action;
</p><p>(2) The issuance, renewal, retention, or revocation of a security clearance;
</p><p>(3) The execution of a security or suitability investigation;
</p><p>(4) The letting of a contract; or
</p><p>(5) The issuance, retention, or revocation of a license, grant, award, contract, or other benefit to the extent the information is
relevant and necessary to a decision by USAID or OIG on the matter.
</p><p>(c) Disclosure to a Federal, State, local, foreign, tribal, territorial, or other public authority in response to its request in
connection with:
</p><p>(1) The hiring, assignment, or retention, of an individual;
</p><p>(2) The issuance, renewal, retention or revocation of a security clearance;
</p><p>(3) The execution of a security or suitability investigation;
</p><p>(4) The letting of a contract; or
</p><p>(5) The issuance, retention, or revocation of a license, grant, award, contract, or other benefit conferred by that entity to the
extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting entity's decision on the matter.
</p><p>(d) Disclosure in the event that a record, either by itself or in combination with other information, indicates a violation or a
potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular
program stature, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto; or a violation or potential violation of a contract
provision. In these circumstances, the relevant records in the system may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate entity,
whether Federal, State, tribal, territorial, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such
violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, order or contract.
</p><p>(e) Disclosure to any source from which additional information is requested, either private or governmental, to the extent necessary
to solicit information relevant to any investigation, audit, or evaluation.
</p><p>(f) Disclosure to a foreign government pursuant to an international treaty, convention, or executive agreement entered into by the
United States.
</p><p>(g) Disclosure to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative
agreement, job or other activity for USAID or OIG, who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or
activities. When appropriate, recipients will be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974 as provided in 5
U.S.C. 552a(m).
</p><p>(h) Disclosure to representatives of the Office of Personnel Management, the Office of Special Counsel, the Merit Systems Protection
Board, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Office of Government Ethics, and other
Federal agencies in connection with their efforts to carry out their responsibilities to conduct examinations, investigations, and/or
settlement efforts, in connection with administrative grievances, complaints, claims, or appeals filed by an employee, and such other
functions promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205-06.
</p><p>(i) Disclosure to a grand jury agent pursuant to a Federal or State grand jury subpoena or to a prosecution request that such record
be released for the purpose of its introduction to a grand jury.
</p><p>(j) Disclosure in response to a facially valid subpoena for the record.
</p><p>(k) Disclosure to the National Archives and Records Administration for the purpose of records management inspections conducted under
authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904, 2906.
</p><p>(l) Disclosure to the Departments of the Treasury and Justice in circumstances in which OIG seeks to obtain, or has in fact
obtained, and ex parte court order to obtain tax return information from the Internal Revenue Service.
</p><p>(m) Disclosure to any Federal official charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessment reviews of internal
safeguards and management procedures employed in investigative operations for purposed of reporting to the President and Congress on
the activities of OIF as contemplated by the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (Pub. L. 107-296; November 25, 2002). This disclosure
category includes other Federal offices of inspectors general and members of the President's Council on Integrity and Efficiency, and
officials and administrative staff within their investigative chain of command, as well as authorized officials of DOJ and its
component, the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>Not applicable.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records and all other media (photographs, audio recordings, diskettes, CD's etc) are stored in GSA-approved security
containers with combination locks in a secured area. Electronic records are password protected and maintained on a file server in
locked facilities that are secured at all times by security systems and video surveillance cameras.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved in a database by name and or alias, as well as by non-personally identifiable information, such as case
number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to paper records is restricted to authorized OIG employees on a need-to-know basis. At all times, paper records are
maintained in locked safes in a secured area in offices that are occupied by authorized OIG employees. Access to electronic records is
restricted to authorized OIG staff members on a need-to-know basis. Each person granted access to the system must be individually
authorized to use the system.
</p><p>Disclosure of records maintained electronically is restricted through the use of passwords. The computer servers in which records
are stored are password protected. Passwords are changed on a cyclical basis. The computer servers are located in locked facilities
that are secured at all times by security systems and video surveillance cameras. The security systems provide immediate notification
of any attempted intrusion to USAID Security personnel. All data exchanged between the servers and individual computers is encrypted.
Backup tapes are stored in a locked and controlled room in a secure, off-site location.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records relating to persons covered by this system are retained for two or five years after the investigation is closed. If an
investigation does not involve allegations against a senior level USAID employee, is not of congressional interest, or does not yield a
reportable result, the records within the closed case file are maintained for a period of two years from the date of closing by OIG. If
the investigation yields a reportable result, has congressional interest, or involves allegations against a senior level USAID
employee, the records within the closed case file will be retained for five years from the date of closing by OIG. After the applicable
period (two or five years), closed investigative files will be sent from USAID, Office of Inspector General, 1300 Pennsylvania Ave.
NW., Washington, DC 20523, to the Washington National Records Center in Suitland, Maryland, where they will be retained for fifteen
years, and subsequently destroyed. Any electronic file that qualifies as a record will be printed out and treated as a hard-copy record
for disposition purposes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are exempt from notification, access, and amendment procedure in accordance with subsections (j) and (k) of 5
U.S.C. 552a, and 22 CFR 215.13 and 215.14. Individuals requesting notification of the existence of records on themselves should send
their request to the System Manager (see information above). The request must be in writing and include the requester's full name, his
or her current address, his or her date and place of birth, and a return address for transmitting the information. The request shall be
signed by either notarized signature or by signature under penalty of perjury. Requesters shall also reasonably specify the record
contents being sought.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to a record on himself or herself must submit the request in writing according to the
"Notification Procedures" above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual requesting amendment of a record maintained on himself or herself must identify the information to be changed and the
corrective action sought. Requests must follow the "Notification Procedures" above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>OIG collects information from a wide variety of sources, including information from USAID and other Federal, State and local
agencies, subjects, witnesses, complainants, confidential and/or non-confidential sources, and other nongovernmental entities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Under the specific authority provided by subsection (j)(2) of 5 U.S.C. 552a, USAID has adopted regulations, 22 CFR 215.13 and
215.14, which exempt this system from the notice, access, and amendment requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a, except subsections (b); (c)(1)
and (2); (e)(4)(A) through (F); (e)(6), (7), (9), (10), and (11); and (i). If the provision found at subsection (j)(2) of 5 U.S.C. 552a
is held to be invalid, then, under subsections (k)(1) and (2) of 5 U.S.C. 552a, this system is determined to be exempt from the
provisions of subsections (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I); and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a. See 57 FR 38276, 38280-81
(August 24, 1992). The reasons for adoption of 22 CFR 215.13 and 215.14 are to protect the materials required by Executive order to be
kept secret in the interest of national defense of foreign policy, to maintain the integrity of the law enforcement process, to ensure
the proper functioning and integrity of law enforcement activities, to prevent disclosures of investigative techniques, to maintain the
ability to obtain necessary information, to prevent subjects of investigation from frustrating the investigatory process, to avoid
premature disclosure of the knowledge of criminal activity and the evidentiary basis of possible enforcement actions, to fulfill
commitments made to sources to protect their identities and the confidentiality of information, and to avoid endangering these sources
and law enforcement personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Employee Relations Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> Confidential.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> a. For active records: Employee Relations Branch, Office of Personnel and Manpower, Agency
for International Development, 515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>b. For retired records: Washington National Records Center, 4205 Suitland Road, Suitland, Maryland.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Any A.I.D. employee or employee of another Federal Agency
assigned to A.I.D. under a Participating Agency Service Agreement who has filed a complaint, grievance or appeal; has
been the subject of an alimony or child support claim; has been listed as a prisoner of war or missing in action
(POW/MIA); or has a medical problem affecting his employment.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Correspondence and indexes covering complaints, grievances, appeals,
life insurance, health insurance, occupational health, workers' compensation, but not including those records belonging
to the Department of Labor; alimony and child support, employee medical problems (but not including medical records
maintained by the Office of the Medical Director, Department of State) and material relating to POW/MIA's.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended, especially secs. 621
and 625; Foreign Service Act of 1946, as amended; Executive Order 10450 as amended August 5, 1954; 5 U.S.C. 301, 7301,
7531, 7532, 7533; sec. 914 of Pub.L. 92-255; and sec. 201 of Pub.L. 91-616.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p> To a duly appointed Hearing Examiner or Arbitrator for the purpose of conducting a hearing in connection with an
employee's appeal involving a grievance</p>
<p>To a union representative for the purpose of representing an employee in order to protect the employee rights
negotiated under the union agreement</p>
<p>To the Office of Personnel Management for the purpose of determining if the Agency's course of action is correct</p>
<p>To a health or life insurance carrier for the purpose of determining the status of benefits paid or owed by or to an
employee pursuant to a health or life insurance compensation agreement</p>
<p>To hospitals, clinics, and other medical treatment facilities upon their request in order to provide information about
health insurance under the Federal Employees Group Health Insurance Program</p>
<p>To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, and Members of Congress, for the purposes set forth in the Statement of General Routine Uses
immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By employee name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Located in metal file cabinets with three-way combination lock in secured premises with access
limited to those whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Workers' compensation files are retired to Federal Records Center, St. Louis,
Missouri, for permanent retention after resolution of case. Alcohol and drug abuse files are destroyed by burning one to
three years after separation of employee. POW/MIA files are retained indefinitely. All other records are destroyed by
burning one to two years after resolution of a problem or final decision on a pending matter.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Chief, Employee Relations Branch, at the location shown in the Systems
Location Section above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p> Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), all investigatory
material in the record which meets the criteria of these subsections is exempted from the notice, access and contest
requirements of sections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I) and (f) 5 U.S.C. 552a in order to fulfill
commitments made to protect the confidentiality of sources, and to maintain access to sources of information which are
necessary to determine suitability for employment. See Agency Regulations published in this issue of the <i>Federal
Register.</i></p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-3, Adverse Actions and Actions Based on Unacceptable Performance.</subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-1, General Personnel Records.</subsection>
</section>
<section id="aid13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-1, General Personnel Records.</subsection>
</section>
<section id="aid14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-2, Employee Performance File System Records.</subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-1, General Personnel Records.</subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Time, Attendance, and Payroll Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained at United States Agency for International Development (USAID) offices in Washington, DC 20523 and other USAID offices in the United States and throughout the world; U.S. Department of State COOP Beltsville (BIMC), 8101 Odell Road, Floor/Room – 173, Beltsville, MD 20705; and USAID payroll and information technology services provider locations such as Terremark, 50 NE 9th Street, Miami, FL 33132, and Global Financial Service Center (GFSC-DoS) 1969 Dyess Avenue, Building A, computer Room 2A228, Charleston, SC 29405.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system encompasses all individuals who are current or former Civil Service and Foreign Service employees of USAID, including direct-hire employees assigned to positions in the United States and direct-hire employees assigned to positions overseas; and all individuals who are personal services contractors paid by USAID.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system of records consists of any and all records essential to the conduct of payroll-related activities.  These records may contain the following types of information:  </p>
<p>(1) Payroll Records:  taxes, various deductions, garnishments, salary data, retirement data, pay period, fiscal year data, benefits, and direct deposit information.</p>
<p>(2) Personnel Records:  Social Security Number, employee’s name, date of birth, gender, race or national origin, disability data, address data, duty location, position data, awards and bonuses, employment verification information, reinstatement and separation data, travel and relocation data, transfer data, education and training data, employee death records, and military and veterans data.</p>
<p>(3) Time and Attendance Records:  Number and type of hours worked (such as regular, overtime, night differential, Federal Equal Pay Act (FEPA), and Sunday differential), compensatory time earned and used, compensatory travel earned, Fair labor Standards Act compensation, tour of duty data, leave requests, leave balances and credits, training time, voluntary leave transfer records, and military leave.</p>
<p>(4) Data Reporting and Personnel and Pay Processing Tables:  Nature of action codes, Civil Service authority codes, standard remarks, signature block table, position title table; financial organization table; and salary tables.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system was established and is maintained pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 5 U.S.C. Part III, Employees, Subpart D, Pay and Allowances; 22 U.S.C. Ch. 14, Foreign Service, Subchapter I, General Provisions; 22 U.S.C. Ch. 52, Foreign Service, Subchapter IV, Compensation; 26 U.S.C. 6109, Identifying numbers; 31 U.S.C. 3512, Executive agency accounting and other financial management reports and plans, and 3513, Financial reporting and accounting system; 42 U.S.C. 659, Consent by United States to income withholding, garnishment, and similar proceedings for enforcement of child support and alimony obligations; 44 U.S.C. 3101, Records management by agency heads; general duties; Executive Order 9397, Numbering System for Federal Accounts Relating to Individual Persons, EO 9397, 3 CFR, 1943-1948 Comp., p. 283, as amended by E.O. 13478, Amendments To Executive Order 9397 Relating To Federal Agency Use of Social Security Numbers, 73 FR 70279 (Nov. 18, 2008).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purposes of this system are to ensure proper payment of salary and benefits to USAID personnel and to track time worked for reporting and compliance purposes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b), all or a portion of the records contained in this system of records may be disclosed outside USAID as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
<p> (1)  To a court, magistrate, or other administrative body of competent jurisdiction for the purposes of presenting evidence, including disclosures to counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations or in connection with criminal proceedings, when USAID is a party to the proceeding or has a significant interest in the proceeding, to the extent that the information is determined to be relevant and necessary.</p>
<p>(2)  To the Department of Justice or other appropriate United States Government Agency when the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding in a court or other tribunal of competent jurisdiction in which USAID or a USAID official in his or her official capacity is a party or has an interest, or when the litigation is likely to affect USAID.</p>
<p>(3)  In the event of an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by statute or particular program pursuant thereto, to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>(4)  To the Department of State and its posts abroad for the purposes of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency, or for purposes related to the responsibilities of the Department of State in conducting United States foreign policy or protecting United States citizens, such as the assignment of employees to positions abroad, the reporting of accidents abroad, evacuation of employees and dependents, and other purposes for which officers and employees of the Department of State have a need for the records in the performance of their duties.</p>
<p>(5)  To a foreign government or international agency in response to its request for information to facilitate the conduct of U.S. relations with that government or agency through the issuance of such documents as visas, country clearances, identification cards, drivers' licenses, diplomatic lists, licenses to import or export personal effects, and other official documents and permits routinely required in connection with the official service or travel abroad of the individual and his or her dependents.</p>
<p>(6)  To Federal agencies with which the Agency has entered into an agreement to provide services to assist the Agency in carrying out its functions under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended.  Such disclosures would be for the purposes of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency; of providing to the original employing agency information concerning the services of its employee while under the supervision of the Agency, including performance evaluations, reports of conduct, awards and commendations, and information normally obtained in the course of personnel administration and employee supervision; or of providing other information directly related to the purposes of the inter-agency agreement as set forth therein, and necessary and relevant to its implementation.</p>
<p>(7)  To Federal, State, local, foreign, and international agencies when the information is relevant to a decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; the assignment, detail or deployment of an employee; the issuance, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation; the letting of a contract; or the issuance of a grant or benefit.</p>
<p>(8)  To the National Archives and Records Administration for the purposes of records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
<p>(9)  To a former employee of USAID for purposes of responding to an official inquiry by a federal, state, or local government entity or professional licensing authority, in accordance with applicable agency regulations; or facilitating communications with a former employee that may be necessary for personnel-related or other official purposes where the agency requires information and/or consultation assistance from the former employee regarding a matter within that person’s former area of responsibility.</p>
<p>(10)  To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) USAID suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) USAID has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the USAID or another Agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with USAID’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>(11)  To the Office of Personnel Management and the Department of State for purposes of personnel management and benefits processing.</p>
<p>(12)  To the Office of Personnel Management, the Department of State, and the Social Security Administration for purposes of retirement benefits processing.</p>
<p>(13)  To the Combined Federal Campaign for purposes of charitable contributions processing.</p>
<p>(14)  To Federal agencies that provide payroll processing services under a cross-servicing agreement to provide support services for the purposes of payroll processing, including issuing pay to employees and the distribution of allotments and deductions to financial and other institutions, some through electronic transfer.</p>
<p>(15)  To labor organizations for the purposes of providing information on eligible employees and dues payments.</p>
<p>(16)  To Federal, State, and local agencies for the purposes of identifying individuals and verifying their income sources in relation to paternity, orders of support, and related court orders.</p>
<p>(18)  To judgment holders for the purposes of garnishment for the payment of alimony and child support.</p>
<p>(19)  To State and local courts of competent jurisdiction for the purposes of enforcing alimony and child support.</p>
<p>(20)  To heirs, executors, and legal representatives of beneficiaries for the purposes of probating and settling estates.</p>
<p>(21) To the Department of the Treasury for the purposes of payroll and other types of payment and offset processing.</p>
<p>(22)  To the Internal Revenue Service for the purposes of (a) processing taxable earnings and withholding; (b) handling audits, inspections, and investigations; (c) obtaining mailing addresses of debtors in order to collect a Federal debt; and (c) offsetting a Federal debt against the debtor's income tax refund.</p>
<p>(23)  To Federal agencies for the purposes of providing wage and separation information to another agency as required by law for payroll purposes.</p>
<p>(24)  To the Merit System Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and the Foreign Service Grievance Board, when requested in the performance of their authorized duties.</p>
<p>(25)  To contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, detailees, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the Federal Government, when necessary to accomplish an agency functions related to this system of records.</p>
<p>(26)  To anyone who is under contract to USAID for the purposes of fulfilling an agency function but only to the extent necessary to fulfill that function.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored in paper, microfiche, and/or electronic form; and are maintained in locked cabinets and/or user-authenticated, password-protected systems.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved by the individual's name or Social Security Number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Paper and microfiche records are maintained by USAID and are safeguarded in secured cabinets within secured rooms.  The electronic records are stored in the WebTA time and attendance system, National Finance Center Payroll/Personnel System, Phoenix Financial Management System, or other time and attendance and financial management systems, which are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies, including all applicable USAID automated systems security and access policies.  Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is being stored.  Access to the records is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Time and attendance records are destroyed after a General Accountability Office audit or when six years old, whichever is sooner.  These records are maintained in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 2, Item 7.  Individual employee payroll records are destroyed when 56 years old in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 2, Item 1.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Chief, Payroll Division, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, United States Agency for International Development, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523-2120.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Same as Record Access Procedures.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Under the Privacy Act, individuals may request access to records about themselves.  If an agency or a person, who is not the individual who is the subject of the records, requests access to records about an individual, the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records is required.</p>
<p>Requesters may submit requests for records under the Privacy Act: 1) by mail to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701; 2) via Facsimile to 202-216-3070; 3) via email to foia@usaid.gov;  4) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia-requests; or 5) in person during regular business hours at USAID, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523-2701, or at USAID overseas missions.</p>
<p>Requesters using 1 through 4 may provide a written statement or may complete and submit USAID Form 507-1, Freedom of Information / Privacy Act Record Request Form, which can be obtained: a) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia -requests; b) by email request to foia@usaid.gov; or c) by writing to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701, and provide information that is necessary to identify the records, including the following:  Requester’s full name; present mailing address; home telephone; work telephone; name of subject, if other than requester; requester relationship to subject; description of type of information or specific records; and purpose of requesting information.  Requesters should provide the system of record identification name and number, if known; and, to facilitate the retrieval of records contained in those systems of records which are retrieved by Social Security Numbers, the Social Security Number of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
<p>In addition, requesters using 1 through 4 must include proof of identity information by providing copies of two (2) source documents that must be notarized by a valid (un-expired) notary public.  Acceptable proof-of-identity source documents include:  an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card (both sides); unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.  </p>
<p>Requesters using 1 through 4 must also provide a signed and notarized statement that they are the person named in the request; that they understand that any falsification of their statement is punishable under the provision of 18 USC 1001 by a fine, or by imprisonment of not more than five years or, if the offense involves international or domestic terrorism (as defined in section 2331), imprisonment of not more than eight years, or both; and that requesting or obtaining records under false pretenses is punishable under the provisions of 5 USC 552a(i)(3) as a misdemeanor and by a fine of not more than $5,000.  </p>
<p>Requesters using 5 must provide such personal identification as is reasonable under the circumstances to verify the requester’s identity, including the following: an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card; unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals seeking to contest or amend records maintained on himself or herself must clearly and concisely state that information is being contested, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.  Requests to amend a record must follow the Record Access Procedures above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information contained in the system is obtained from the individual concerned and USAID employees acting in their official capacity.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Employee-Owned or -Leased Property Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located at various overseas offices listed in appendix A.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> U.S. Government employees and contract employees of A.I.D.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records on leasing living quarters whose rent and utility costs are
reimbursed wholly or in part by A.I.D. and personally-owned vehicles and other property at post. Records contain a
description of such property, and how property is disposed of at post.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> Foreign Assistance Act of 1961r as amended, section 636; Foreign
Service Act of 1946 as amended.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p> To the Department of State for the issuance of licenses and establishing of duty free status of A.I.D. personnel</p>
<p>To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, and members of Congress, for the purposes set forth in the Statement of General Routine Uses
immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copy in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name of individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Located in metal file cabinets with three-way combination locks in secured premises with access
limited to those whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> After employee leaves post, records on owned property are retained for four years
and on leased property for two years, then destroyed.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director, Office of Management Operations, 320 21st Street NW, Washington, DC
20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be addressed to:
</p><p>Director
</p><p>Office of Personnel and Manpower (SER/PM)
</p><p>Attn: Privacy Liaison Officer
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC 20523
</p><p>or presented in person at State Annex 2, 1601 North Kent Street, Arlington, Virginia</p>
<p>For offices abroad, to the Privacy Liaison Officer at the applicable address in appendix A</p>
<p>Information Required: Individual's name, place and date of birth. The determination as to the existence of a record
will be facilitated by the provision of the individual's Social Security number and dates and places of service.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed or presented in person to the same
addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests should be accompanied by information sufficient to identify the individual pursuant to &#167; 215.4(c) or
(d) of the Agency's Regulations as published in this issue of the <i>Federal Register</i>.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Written requests from individuals to amend their record should be mailed or
presented in person to the same addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests for review of a refusal to amend a record should be made in writing and mailed or delivered to:
</p><p>Administrator
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC 20523
</p><p>ATTENTION: Executive Secretary - Privacy Review Request</p>
<p>Both the envelope and the letter should be clearly marked Attention: Executive Secretary - Privacy Review Request.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> U.S. Government employees, local and contract employees of A.I.D. and American
Embassy personnel.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-18</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Employee Use of Property Owned or Leased by the U.S. Government Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located at Agency Washington headquarters and at offices abroad. See Appendix A
for actual location of those offices.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> U.S. Government employees, contract employees of A.I.D.,
and guests at A.I.D.-operated staff or guest houses.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Records pertaining to the occupancy or use of property owned or leased
by the U.S. Government, and to facilities and/or services provided such as: Government-leased housing; government-owned
furniture, appliances and furnishings; U.S. Government property in custody used for official purposes; government-owned
vehicles used for official or unofficial purposes; parking permits; government-purchased publications; long-distance
telephone calls made from A.I.D facilities; U.S. Government vehicle repair facilities; commissary, liquor, and post
exchange purchases; gasoline purchased from or through post exchange purchases; gasoline purchased from or through an
A.I.D. overseas post; government-furnished housing maintenance and repair services; and A.I.D. staff or guest house
facilities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 as amended, section 621, 635;
Foreign Service Act of 1946 as amended.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p> To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, and Members of Congress, for the purposes set forth in the Statement of General Routine Uses
immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copy in file folders, and card index file.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name of individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Located in metal file cabinets with three-way combination locks in secured premises with access
limited to those whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Records on the issuance of U.S. Government property are destroyed three years after
the property is turned in or otherwise accounted for. Individual trip tickets reflecting official and unofficial use of
vehicles are destroyed 6 months after the end of the fiscal year. Maintenance and repair records and related papers
pertaining to the maintenance and repair of individual residential units occupied by individuals at overseas posts are
destroyed at the end of 4 years. Destruction is by shredding or burning.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Director, Office of Managment Operations, Agency for International
Development, 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be addressed to:
</p><p>Director
</p><p>Office of Personnel and Manpower (SER/PM)
</p><p>Attn: Privacy Liaison Officer
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC 20523
</p><p>or presented in person at State Annex 2, 515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For offices abroad, to the Privacy Liaison Officer at the applicable address in appendix A</p>
<p>Information Required: Individual's name, place and date of birth. The determination as to the existence of a record
will be facilitated by the provision of the individual's Social Security number and dates and places of service.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed or presented in person to the same
addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests should be accompanied by information sufficient to identify the individual pursuant to &#167; 215.4(c) or
(d) of the Agency's Regulations as published in this issue of the <i>Federal Register</i>.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Written requests from individuals to amend their record should be mailed or
presented in person to the same addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests for review of a refusal to amend a record should be made in writing and mailed or delivered to:
</p><p>Administrator
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC 20523
</p><p>ATTENTION: Executive Secretary--Privacy Review Request</p>
<p>Both the envelope and the letter should be clearly marked Attention: Executive Secretary--Privacy Review Request.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> U.S. Government employees, local and contract employees of A.I.D., and personnel
of the Departmnent of State.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
    <section id="aid19" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Travel and Transportation Records.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Controlled Unclassified Information
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue N.W., USAID Annex, Room 10.6.4-F, Washington, DC 20523; CW Government Travel, Inc.  (CWTSatoTravel), 4300 Wilson Blvd, Suite 500, Arlington, VA 22203-4167; U.S. Department of State COOP Beltsville (BIMC), 8101 Odell Road, Floor/Room 173, Beltsville, MD 20705; and other USAID offices in the United States and throughout the world.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief, Travel and Transportation Division, Office of Management Services, Bureau for Management, United States Agency for International Development, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue N.W., USAID Annex, Room 10.6.4-F, Washington, DC 20523-2120.  Email:  TravelandTransportation-helpdesk@usaid.gov</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 5 U.S.C. Ch. 57, Travel, Transportation, and Subsistence; 22 U.S.C. Ch. 32, Foreign Assistance, Subchapter 1, International Development; 22 U.S.C. 4081, Travel and Related Expenses; and implementing Federal Travel Regulations (41 CFR Chapters 300-304).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system may be used to:  (1) manage the centralized USAID relocation and travel of USAID employees and their dependents; (2) facilitate move requests of USAID employees and their dependents; (3) manage worldwide logistics services and integrated support for the transportation of the effects of USAID employees and their dependents; (4) ensure fiscal accountability in transporting the effects of USAID employees and their dependents; (5) facilitate passport issuance and compliance; and (6) assist in substantiating a claim for missing or damaged household effects.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system encompasses all individuals (1) whose travel is paid for by USAID; (2) for whom the transportation of effects is paid by USAID; or (3) who are USAID personnel and dependents who travel on USAID business with United States diplomatic passports for the purposes of providing travel and the transportation of household goods for employees of USAID and its Missions around the world, as well as travel to interviews for certain applicants for employment with USAID.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records include name, date of birth, place of birth, sex or gender, age, citizenship, home address, personal cell phone number, personal e-mail address, work phone number, work e-mail address, passport number or green card number (optional), credit card number, Phoenix vendor identification; correspondence, itineraries, government transportation requests, card files pertaining to passports, baggage declarations, passports and records of applications for visas, arrival and departure notices, medical requirements and vaccination status for employees traveling, and record of clearances prior to departure from the United States or posts abroad.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Sources of records are from the individual whose travel and transportation of effects are paid by USAID and its Missions, and USAID officials and employees involved in the travel and transportation of household goods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>CATEGORIES OF USERS AND PURPOSES OF SUCH USES:</p>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), all or a portion of the records contained in this system of records may be disclosed outside USAID as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>(1) To the U.S. Department of the Treasury for the purposes of payment of claims.</p>
                <p>(2) To commercial travel, transportation and shipping companies and agents for the purposes of making travel and transportation arrangements.</p>
                <p>(3) To U.S. Dispatch Agents for the purposes of arranging shipment and clearance of effects.</p>
                <p>(4) To the General Services Administration and the Office of Management and Budget for the purposes of periodic reporting required by statutes, regulations, and/or Executive Order. Information provided is in the form of listings, reports, and records of all transportation and travel-related transactions, including refunds and adjustments, by the contractor, to enable audits of transportation and travel-related charges to the Government.</p>
                <p>(5) To a court, magistrate, or other administrative body in the course of presenting evidence, including disclosures to counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations, or in connection with criminal proceedings, when USAID is a party to the proceeding or has a significant interest in the proceeding, to the extent that the information is determined to be relevant and necessary.</p>
                <p>(6) To the Department of Justice or other appropriate United States Government Agency when the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding in a court or other tribunal in which USAID or a USAID official in his or her official capacity is a party or has an interest, or when the litigation is likely to affect USAID.</p>
                <p>(7) In the event of an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by statute or particular program pursuant thereto, to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
                <p>(8) To the Department of State and its posts abroad for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of USAID, or for purposes related to the responsibilities of the Department of State in conducting United States foreign policy or protecting United States citizens, such as the assignment of employees to positions abroad, the reporting of accidents abroad, ensuring fiscal accountability in transporting the effects of personnel stationed at Embassies, evacuation of employees and dependents, and other purposes for which officers and employees of the Department of State have a need for the records in the performance of their duties.</p>
                <p>(9) To a foreign government or international agency in response to its request for information to facilitate the conduct of U.S. relations with that government or agency through the issuance of such documents as visas, country clearances, identification cards, drivers' licenses, diplomatic lists, licenses to import or export personal effects, and other official documents and permits routinely required in connection with the official service or travel abroad of the individual and his or her dependents.</p>
                <p>(10) To shipping contractors limited information is provided, such as delivery address and telephone number, for the purposes of providing shipping services.</p>
                <p>(11) To federal agencies with which USAID has entered into an agreement to provide services to assist USAID in carrying out its functions under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended.  Such disclosures would be for the purpose of:  transmission of information between organizational units of USAID; providing to the original employing agency information concerning the services of its employee while under the supervision of USAID, including performance evaluations, reports of conduct, awards and commendations, and information normally obtained in the course of personnel administration and employee supervision; or providing other information directly related to the purposes of the inter-agency agreement as set forth therein, and necessary and relevant to its implementation.</p>
                <p>(12) To appropriate officials and employees of a federal agency or entity when the information is relevant to a decision concerning the:  hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; assignment, detail or deployment of an employee; issuance, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance; execution of a security or suitability investigation; letting of a contract; or issuance of a grant or benefit.</p>
                <p>(13) To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for the purposes of records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>(14) To a former employee of USAID for purposes of responding to an official inquiry by a federal, state, or local government entity or professional licensing authority, in accordance with applicable Agency regulations; or facilitating communications with a former employee that may be necessary for personnel-related or other official purposes where the Agency requires information and/or consultation assistance from the former employee regarding a matter within that person's former area of responsibility.</p>
                <p>(15) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when:  (a) USAID suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (b) USAID has determined that, as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach, there is a risk of harm to individuals, USAID (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with USAID’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>(16) To another federal department or agency or federal entity, when USAID determines information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient department or agency or entity in:  (a) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or (b) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, that might result from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>(17) To the Office of Management and Budget in connection with review of private relief</p>
                <p>legislation, as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19, at any stage of the legislative coordination</p>
                <p>and clearance process as set forth in that Circular.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system are stored on paper and/or electronic form, and are maintained in locked cabinets and/or user-authenticated, password-protected systems.  Records that contain national security information and are classified are stored in accordance with applicable Executive Orders, statutes, and Agency implementing regulations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system are retrieved by the names of the individuals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with disposition schedules approved by USAID and NARA General Records Schedule 9 for Travel and Transportation Records, and General Records Schedule 20 for Electronic Records shall apply. The data will be used, processed, and then stored.  Data will be stored for six years and three months, which is specified by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>USAID safeguards records in this system according to applicable rules and policies, including all applicable USAID Automated Directive System operational policies.  USAID has implemented controls to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is being stored.  Access to the system and its records is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for performance of their official duties and who have the appropriate clearances and permissions. USAID ensures that the practices stated in the E2E, ILMS, and Phoenix Financial Management systems’ Privacy Impact Assessment are followed by leveraging standard operating procedures (SOP), training, policies, rules of behavior, and auditing and accountability.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Under the Privacy Act, individuals may request access to records about themselves.  These individuals must be limited to citizens of the United States or aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence.  If a federal department or agency, or a person who is not the individual who is the subject of the records, requests access to records about an individual, the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records is required.</p>
                <p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system of records should address inquiries to the Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division (M/MS/IRD), USAID Annex - Room 2.4.0C, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523.  The requester may complete and sign a USAID Form 507-1, Certification of Identity Form, or submit signed, written requests that should include the individual's full name, current address, telephone number, and this System of Records Notice number.  In addition, the requester must provide either a notarized statement or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:</p>
                <p>If executed outside the United States:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)."</p>
                <p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)."</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The USAID rules for accessing records, contesting contents, and appealing initial agency determinations are contained in 22 C.F.R. § 212 or may be obtained from the program manager or system owner.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking to determine if information about themselves is contained in this system of records should address inquiries to the Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division (M/MS/IRD), USAID Annex - Room 2.4.0C, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523.  Individuals may complete and sign a USAID Form 507-1, Certification of Identity Form, or submit signed, written requests that should include the individual's full name, current address, and telephone number.  In addition, the requester must provide either a notarized statement or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:</p>
                <p>If executed outside the United States:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature).  "</p>
                <p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature).  "</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>79 FR 78381, December 30, 2014.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="aid20" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-20</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Claims Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>a. Central Records:
</p><p>Office of Personnel and Manpower, Agency for International Development, 1601 Kent Street, Arlington, Virginia for
allowance claims and health benefit claims</p>
<p>Office of the General Counsel, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC, for tort
claims</p>
<p>Office of Management Operations, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC 20523 for
claims involving loss of private personal property</p>
<p>Office of Financial Management, Agency for International Development, 1975 Florida Avenue, NW, Washington, DC, for all
other claims</p>
<p>b. Decentralized records maintained in various Washington offices and offices abroad having responsibilities for
initiating requests for claims activity. See Appendix A for actual location of these offices.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Employees who have filed claims against the Agency and
employees against whom the Agency has filed a claim.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> a. Central Records: Documentation of claims, voucher disallowances,
duplicate payment, and bills for collection</p>
<p>b. Decentralized Records: Copies of documents maintained in the central records, legal reviews and opinions, and
referrals to G.A.O.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 as amended, section 621; Foreign
Service Act of 1946, as amended; Federal Tort Claims Act and G.A.O. Policy and Procedures Manual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p> To U.S. Treasury for payment</p>
<p>To U.S. Despatch Agents to verify movement of persons and things and costs thereof</p>
<p>To Office of Operations, Department of State, for review and initial adjudication of private personal property claims</p>
<p>To the State - A.I.D. - U.S.I.A. Joint Survey Board for review of claims arising from evacuation</p>
<p>To commercial travel, transportation, and shipping companies and agents to verify actual costs of services;
</p><p>To the Office of the Director of Medical Services, Department of State to determine validity of medical claims</p>
<p>To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, and Members of Congress, for the purposes set forth in the Statement of General Routine Uses
immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copy in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name of individual or other personal identifier.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Located in metal file cabinets with three-way combination locks in secured premises with access
limited to those whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Retained for seven years and then destroyed by shredding or burning.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> a. Central Records:
</p><p>For Allowance Claims: Chief, Foreign Service Technical and Staff Support Branch, Agency for International Development,
515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For Health Benefit Claims: Chief, Employee Relations Branch, Agency for International Development, 515 22nd Street,
NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For Tort Claims: Deputy General Counsel, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC
20523</p>
<p>For Private Personal Property Claims: Office of Management Operations, Agency for International Development, 320 21st
Street, NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For Uncollectable Claims: Assistant Controller, Central Accounting Division, Office of Financial Management, Agency
for International Development, 1975 Florida Avenue, Washington, DC</p>
<p>b. Decentralized Records: Administrative and Executive Officers in A.I.D. Washington and offices abroad. See appendix
A for actual location of office.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be addressed to:
</p><p>Director
</p><p>Office of Personnel and Manpower (SER/PM)
</p><p>Attn: Privacy Liaison Officer
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC. 20523
</p><p>or presented in person at State Annex 2, 515 22nd Street NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For offices abroad, to the Privacy Liaison Officer at the applicable address in appendix A</p>
<p>Information Required: Individual's name, place and date of birth. The determination as to the existence of a record
will be facilitated by the provision of the individual's Social Security number and dates and places of service.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p> Requests from individuals should be addressed or presented in person to the same
addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests should be accompanied by information sufficient to identify the individual pursuant to &#167; 215.4(c) or
(d) of the Agency's rules as published in this issue of the <i>Federal Register</i>.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Written requests from individuals to amend their record should be mailed or
presented in person to the same addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests for review of a refusal to amend a record should be made in writing and mailed to:
</p><p>Administrator
</p><p>Agency for International Development
</p><p>320 21st Street, NW
</p><p>Washington, DC 20523
</p><p>ATTENTION: Executive Secretary--Privacy Review Request</p>
<p>Both the envelope and the letter should be clearly marked Attention: Executive Secretary--Privacy Review Request.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p> The individual concerned and A.I.D. employees acting in their official capacities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid21" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-21</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Public Information Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>a. Principal files are maintained in the Office of Public Affairs, A.I.D., 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC
20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees of A.I.D., Members of Congress, individuals associated with foreign economic assistance, and
individuals requesting information under the Freedom of Information and Privacy Acts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographical information on Members of Congress, individuals officials within the agency. Biographical
information on employees who serve as public speakers, press releases, news clippings, photographs, requests for access
to A.I.D. records under the Freedom of Information and Privacy Acts, and related correspondence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 as amended, especially sections 621, 634(b); Pub. L. 93-502; 5 U.S.C. 301;
and the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The Administrator and Deputy Administrator for personal contacts</p>
<p>Persons or organizations requesting A.I.D. to make available an employee to speak in public on A.I.D. activities are
provided a biographical sketch of the speaker in order to select and introduce the speaker</p>
<p>To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, Members of Congress, and individuals' medical advisers for the purposes set forth in the
Statement of General Routine Uses immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copies and photographs in file folders. Automated records on magnetic discs and permanently on line at the
computer center.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name of individual.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Located in metal file cabinets with three-way combination lock in a secure space or secured premises with access
limited to those whose official duties require access. The Resource Allocation Control Facility, in use on our computer
system, lessens the potential for unauthorized use.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Destroyed after five years by burning. Computerized records are deleted from the system when no longer needed for
daily operations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Public Affairs, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC
20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be addressed to: Director, Office of Public
Affairs, Attn: Privacy Liaison Officer, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street NW, Washington, DC 20523,
or presented in person at 320 21st Street NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For offices abroad, to the Privacy Liaison Officer at the applicable address in appendix A</p>
<p>Information Required: Individual's name, place and date of birth. The determination as to the existence of a record
will be facilitated by the provision of the individual's Social Security Account Number and dates and places of service.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed or presented in person to the same addresses as stated in the
Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests should be accompanied by information sufficient to identify the individual pursuant to 22 CFR 215.4 (c) or
(d).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Written requests from individuals to amend their record should be mailed or presented in person to the same
address as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests for review of a refusal to amend a record should be made in writing and mailed or delivered to:
Administrator, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street NW, Washington, DC 20523, Attention: Executive
Secretary--Privacy Review Request</p>
<p>Both the envelope and the letter should be clearly marked Attention: Executive Secretary, Privacy Review Request.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Members of Congress, employees, public media information, A.I.D. records, and individuals requesting access to
records under the Freedom of Information and Privacy Acts.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Congressional Relations, Inquiries, and Travel Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>a. Principal files are maintained in the Office of Legislative Affairs, A.I.D., 320 21st Street, NW, Washington,
DC 20523
</p><p>b. Records of Congressional inquiries concerning employees of and applicants for employment with the Office of the
General Counsel are maintained in the Office of the General Counsel, A.I.D., 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>c. Related files are maintained in certain areas of the field offices listed at Appendix A</p>
<p>d. Retired files are maintained in the Washington National Records Center, 4205 Suitland Road, Suitland, Maryland.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Members of Congress, members of their personal staffs and of Congressional Committee staffs; employees of A.I.D.
or applicants for employment who are or have been the subject of Congressional inquiries and recommendations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Congressional correspondence and memoranda of Congressional telephone calls covering (1) requests for information
and assistance on matters related to foreign assistance; (2) requests for assistance from the Agency in arranging
official travel overseas by Members of Congress, their staffs or committee staffs to inspect and observe foreign
assistance programs abroad, and (3) inquiries about A.I.D. employees and recommendations concerning employees or
applicants for employment. Also includes information about individual members of Congress derived from public media
sources, including biographic records, and extracts from the Congressional Record.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 as amended, especially section 634(b); 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C., Chapters 31 and
33.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, Members of Congress, and individuals' medical advisers for the purposes set forth in the
Statement of General Routine Uses immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copy in file folders. Automated records on magnetic discs and permanently on line at the computer center.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By name of Congressman. Access will be limited to individuals with a need to know and have the proper password.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Except for material completely in the public domain, located in a secure space or secured premises with access
limited to those whose official duties require the information. The Resources Allocation Control Facility, in use on our
computer system, lessens the potential for unauthorized use.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Except for correspondence involving matters of policy, records are destroyed by burning after no more than 15
years; files related to individual Congressmen are retired at the end of each session of Congress. Records involving
policy matters are retained permanently in archival files. The computerized records are deleted from the system when no
longer needed for daily operations.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>a. For records maintained at Location (a): Director for Legislative Affairs, A.I.D., 320 21st Street, NW,
Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>b. For records maintained at Location (b): Office of the General Counsel, A.I.D., 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC
20523</p>
<p>c. For records maintained at Location (c): Executive Office of the appropriate A.I.D. office listed at appendix A.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests by individuals concerning the existence of a record may be addressed to: Director, Office of Public
Affairs, Attn.: Privacy Liaison Officer, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street NW, Washington, DC 20523,
or presented in person at 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>For offices abroad, to the Privacy Liaison Officer at the applicable address in appendix A</p>
<p>Information Required: Individual's name. For records of Congressional correspondence, include name of Congressman and
appropriate session of Congress. The determination as to the existence of a record will be facilitated by the provision
of the individual's Social Security Account Number and dates and places of service.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests from individuals should be addressed or presented in person to the same addresses as stated in the
Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests should be accompanied by information sufficient to identify the individual pursuant to &#167; 215.4 (c)
or (d) of the Agency's Regulations as published in this issue of the <i>Federal Register</i>.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Written requests from individuals to amend their record should be mailed or presented in persons the same
addresses as stated in the Notification Section above</p>
<p>Requests for review of a refusal to amend a record should be made in writing and mailed or delivered to:
Administrator, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>Attention: Executive Secretary--Privacy Review Request. Both the envelope and the letter should be clearly marked
Attention: Executive Secretary, Privacy Review Request.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Members of Congress and their staffs; Congressional Committee Members; A.I.D. employees; Congressional Directory,
Congressional Quarterly, and Congressional Record; newspapers, magazines, and other public media.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid23" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-23</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Employees Equal Employment Opportunity Complaint Investigative Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: USAID-23 Employees' Equal Employment Opportunity Complaint Investigative Records is covered by the government-wide system of records notice EEOC/Govt-1 Equal Employment Opportunity in the Federal Government Complaint and Appeal Records (July 30, 2002, 67 FR 49354); and USAID-23 can therefore be deleted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="aid24" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-24</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Deleted, See OPM/GOVT-1, General Personnel Records.</subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid25" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-25</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Freedom of Information Act, Privacy Act, and Mandatory Declassification Review Requests Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified, Sensitive but unclassified, and Classified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20523; Terremark, 50 NE 9th Street, Miami, FL 33132; U.S. Department of State COOP Beltsville (BIMC), 8101 Odell Road, Floor/Room—173, Beltsville, MD 20705; and other USAID offices in the United States and throughout the world.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system encompasses all individuals who submit Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), Privacy Act, and Mandatory Declassification Review requests and administrative appeals to the United States Agency for International Development (USAID); individuals whose requests and/or records have been referred to USAID by other agencies; attorneys or other persons authorized to represent individuals submitting requests and appeals; individuals whose records are the subjects of such requests or appeals; and USAID personnel assigned to process such requests or appeals.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system consists of records created or compiled in response to FOIA, Privacy Act, and Mandatory Declassification Review requests and administrative appeals to USAID, including: The original requests and administrative appeals; responses to such requests and administrative appeals; all related memoranda, correspondence with the requester or requester's representative, notes, internal USAID correspondence and memoranda, and other related or supporting documentation; memoranda to or from other agencies having a substantial interest in the determination of the request; and, in some instances, copies of requested records and records under administrative appeal. These records contain names, addresses, email addresses, telephone numbers; online identity verification information (username and password); copies of identity verification documents such as passports and drivers licenses; and any other information voluntarily submitted such as tracking numbers. These records may contain personal information retrieved in response to a request. These records may contain inquiries and requests regarding other USAID systems of records subject to the FOIA and PA. In addition, information about individuals from such other USAID systems of records may become part of this system of records.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system was established and is maintained pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 301; 5 U.S.C. 552; 5 U.S.C. 552a; 44 U.S.C. 3101; and 22 CFR 212 and 215, and the applicable executive order(s) governing classified national security information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The records are collected, used, maintained, and disseminated for the purpose of processing access requests and administrative appeals made under the FOIA, access and amendment requests and administrative appeals under the Privacy Act, and requests and administrative appeals for mandatory declassification review under the applicable executive order(s) governing national security information; for the purpose of participating in litigation regarding agency action on such requests and appeals; and for the purpose of assisting USAID in carrying out any other responsibilities related to FOIA and Privacy Act such as reporting to USAID and other federal executive officials.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed outside of the USAID as a routine use as follows:</p>
<p>(1) To a court, magistrate, or other administrative body in the course of presenting evidence, including disclosures to counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations or in connection with criminal proceedings, when USAID is a party to the proceeding or has a significant interest in the proceeding, to the extent that the information is determined to be relevant and necessary.</p>
<p>(2) To the Department of Justice or other appropriate United States Government Agency when the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding in a court or other tribunal in which USAID or a USAID official in his or her official capacity is a party or has an interest, or when the litigation is likely to affect USAID.</p>
<p>(3) To the Department of Justice for the purpose of obtaining advice as to whether or not the records or information should be disclosed.</p>
<p>(4) To a Federal government agency or entity that furnished the record or information for the purpose of permitting that agency or entity to make a decision as to access to or correction of the record or information, or to a federal agency entity for purposes of providing guidance or advice regarding the handling of particular requests.</p>
<p>(5) To appropriate agencies, for the purpose of resolving an inquiry regarding federal agency compliance with the Freedom of Information Act.</p>
<p>(6) In the event of an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by statute or particular program pursuant thereto, to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>(7) To the Department of State and its posts abroad for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency, or for purposes related to the responsibilities of the Department of State in conducting United States foreign policy or protecting United States citizens, such as the assignment of employees to positions abroad, the reporting of accidents abroad, evacuation of employees and dependents, and other purposes for which officers and employees of the Department of State have a need for the records in the performance of their duties.</p>
<p>(8) To a foreign government or international agency in response to its request for information to facilitate the conduct of U.S. relations with that government or agency through the issuance of such documents as visas, country clearances, identification cards, drivers' licenses, diplomatic lists, licenses to import or export personal effects, and other official documents and permits routinely required in connection with the official service or travel abroad of the individual and his or her dependents.</p>
<p>(9) To Federal agencies with which the Agency has entered into an agreement to provide services to assist the Agency in carrying out its functions under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended. Such disclosures would be for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency; of providing to the original employing agency information concerning the services of its employee while under the supervision of the Agency, including performance evaluations, reports of conduct, awards and commendations, and information normally obtained in the course of personnel administration and employee supervision; or of providing other information directly related to the purposes of the inter-agency agreement as set forth therein, and necessary and relevant to its implementation.</p>
<p>(10) To appropriate officials and employees of a federal agency or entity when the information is relevant to a decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; the assignment, detail or deployment of an employee; the issuance, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation; the letting of a contract; or the issuance of a grant or benefit.</p>
<p>(11) To a Congressional Committee or Subcommittee.</p>
<p>(12) To the National Archives and Records Administration, Information Security Oversight Office, Interagency Security Classification Appeals Panel, for the purpose of adjudicating an appeal from a USAID denial of a request for mandatory declassification review of records, made under the applicable executive order(s) governing classification.</p>
<p>(13) To the National Archives and Records Administration, Office of Government Information Services (OGIS), to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities in 5 U.S.C. 552(h), to review administrative agency policies, procedures, and compliance with the Freedom of Information Act, and to facilitate OGIS' offering of mediation services to resolve disputes between persons making FOIA requests and administrative agencies.</p>
<p>(14) To the National Archives and Records Administration for the purposes of records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
<p>(15) To a former employee of USAID for purposes of responding to an official inquiry by a federal, state, or local government entity or professional licensing authority, in accordance with applicable agency regulations; or facilitating communications with a former employee that may be necessary for personnel-related or other official purposes where the agency requires information and/or consultation assistance from the former employee regarding a matter within that person's former area of responsibility.</p>
<p>(16) To the Foreign Service Grievance Board in the course of the Board's consideration of matters properly before it.</p>
<p>(17) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) USAID suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) USAID has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the USAID or another Agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with USAID's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
<p>These records are not disclosed to consumer reporting agencies.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored on paper and/or electronic form; and are maintained in locked cabinets and/or user-authenticated, password-protected systems. Records that contain national security information and are classified are stored in accordance with applicable executive orders, statutes, and agency implementing regulations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved by the name of the requester or appellant; the number assigned to the request or appeal; and in some instances, the name of the attorney representing the requester or appellant, the name of an individual who is the subject of such a request or appeal, and/or the name of other personal identifiers.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information in this system is safeguarded in accordance with applicable laws, rules and policies, including the agency's automated directive system. Classified information is appropriately stored in safes and in accordance with other applicable requirements. In general, records and technical equipment are maintained in buildings with restricted access. The required use of password protection identification features and other system protection methods also restrict access. Access is limited to those officers and authorized USAID employees who have an official need to access the records in the performance of their official duties.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with the National Archives Records Administration's General Records Disposition Schedules and the agency's approved disposition schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>USAID FOIA Public Liaison Officer, United States Agency for International Development, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division (M/MS/IRD), 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Room 2.7-C, Washington, DC 20523.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Same as Record Access Procedures.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Under the Privacy Act, individuals may request access to records about themselves. If an agency or a person, who is not the individual who is the subject of the records, requests access to records about an individual, the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records is required.</p>
<p>Requesters may submit requests for records under the Privacy Act in the following four ways: (1) By mail to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Room 2.07C—RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701; (2) via email to<i>foia@usaid.gov;</i>(3) on the USAID Web site at<i>http://www.usaid.gov/foia-requests;</i>or (4) by completing the USAID Form 508-2, Privacy Request Form, which is available: (a) By writing to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Room 2.07C—RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701; (b) via email to<i>foia@usaid.gov</i>or (c) on the USAID Web site at<i>http://www.usaid.gov/foia-requests.</i></p>
<p>Requesters must provide the information that is necessary to identify the records, including the following: Requester's full name; present mailing address; home telephone; work telephone; name of subject, if other than requester; requester relationship to subject; description of type of information or specific records; and purpose of requesting information. Requesters should provide the system of record identification name and number, if known; and, to facilitate the retrieval of records contained in those systems of records which are retrieved by Social Security Numbers, the Social Security Number of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
<p>In addition, requesters must include proof of identity information by providing copies of two (2) source documents that must be notarized by a valid (un-expired) notary public. Acceptable proof-of-identity source documents include: An unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card (both sides); unexpired driver's license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent's identification card.</p>
<p>Requesters must also provide a signed and notarized statement that they are the person named in the request; that they understand that any falsification of their statement is punishable under the provision of 18 U.S.C. 1001 by a fine, or by imprisonment of not more than five years or, if the offense involves international or domestic terrorism (as defined in section 2331), imprisonment of not more than eight years, or both; and that requesting or obtaining records under false pretenses is punishable under the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(i)(3) as a misdemeanor and by a fine of not more than $5,000. The notarized statement with an embossed notary seal must be submitted in the original paper to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Room 2.07C—RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals seeking to contest or amend records maintained on himself or herself must clearly and concisely state that information is being contested, and the proposed amendment to the information sought. Requests to amend a record must follow the Record Access Procedures above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals and organizations submitting initial requests and administrative appeals pursuant to the FOIA and Privacy Act, or other applicable executive order(s) governing classified national security information; the agency records searched in the process of responding to such requests and appeals; USAID personnel assigned to handle such requests and appeals; agency records searched in the process of responding to such requests and appeals; other agencies that refer to, search for and provide the records and related correspondence that are maintained in the case files; and submitters or subject of records or information that have provided assistance to USAID in making access or amendment determinations.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>USAID has claimed exemptions for several of its other systems of records under 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k). Additional exemptions are delineated in 22 CFR 215.13 and 215.14. During the processing of FOIA and Privacy Act requests and administrative appeals, exempt records from these other systems of records may become part of the case record in this system of records. To the extent that exempt records from other USAID systems of records are entered or become part of this system, USAID has claimed the same exemptions. In addition, any such records compiled in this system of records from any other system of records continues to be subject to any exemption(s) applicable for the records as they have in the primary systems of records of which they are a part.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="aid26" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Litigation Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p> Secret.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p> a. Active files are maintained at the Office of the General Counsel, Agency for
International Development, 320 21st Street, NW, Washington, DC 20523</p>
<p>b. Retired records are maintained at the Washington National Records Center, 4205 Suitland Road, Suitland, Maryland.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Foreign Service employees, Civil Service employees,
personal services contractors, former employees, and members of the public.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p> Correspondence and other documents relating to disputed contracts, and
tort claims against the Agency, and other claims and actions against the Agency.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p> Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended; Foreign Service Act of
1946, as amended; Tort Claims Act.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p> To law enforcement agencies, U.S. Government agencies, courts, the Department of State, foreign governments and
international agencies, and Members of Congress, for the purposes set forth in the Statement of General Routine Uses
immediately preceding these specific notices of systems of records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper copy in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p> By name of employee and calendar year.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p> Maintained in combination vault insulated against fire and located in secure premises with
access limited to those whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p> Maintained for two years following settlement of case and then retired to Washington
National Records Center for five years prior to destruction.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p> Assistant General Counsel for Management and Aministration, Office of the
General Counsel, Agency for International Development, 320 21st Street, Washington, DC 20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p> This system is exempt under 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(1), (k)
(2), and (k)(5) from the notice, access, and contest requirements of sections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H) and (I)
and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a. These exemptions are claimed to protect the materials required by Executive Order to be kept
secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy, to prevent subjects of investigation from frustrating the
investigatory process, to insure the proper functioning and integrity of law enforcement activities, to prevent
disclosure of investigative techniques, to maintain the ability to obtain candid and necessary information, to fulfill
commitments made to sources to protect the confidentiality of information, and to avoid endangering these sources. See
Agency Regulations published in this issue of the <i>Federal Register</i></p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid27" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-27</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>Partner-Vetting System, USAID – 27.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Sensitive but Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Amazon Web Services, US-EAST-1, 7600 Doane Drive, Manassas VA 20109.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Chief, Counterterrorism Vetting, Office of Security, United States Agency for International Development, Ronald Reagan Building, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., Washington, D.C.  20523.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), as amended, permits the Administrator of USAID to consider a range of foreign-policy and national-security interests in determining how to provide foreign assistance.  Sections 7034 and 7039 of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (FY 2020) contain provisions and requirements for the oversight of USAID’s programs.  Executive Order (E.O.) 9397 created and governs the use of Social Security Numbers.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>PVS supports the vetting of directors, officers, and other employees of non-governmental organizations that apply to USAID for contracts, grants, cooperative agreements or other funding.  The Agency specifically uses the information collected from the individuals to conduct screening, and to mitigate the risk that USAID’s funds and USAID-funded activities purposefully or inadvertently provide support to entities or individuals deemed a risk to national security.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Individuals who are directors, officers, or are otherwise employed by either for-profit or non-profit non-governmental organizations that apply for and receive contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or other types of instruments from USAID; individuals who apply for and receive Personal Services Contracts or other contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements; individuals or organizations that attempt to obtain other assistance or benefits from USAID (excluding for PVOs).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Full name, Social Security Number, date of birth, place of birth, passport number or permanent resident card number, tax identification number, home address, home telephone number, personal cell phone number, personal email address, work telephone number, work email address, citizenship, sex or gender, photographic biometric information, employment or salary record.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>USAID may obtain information in this system from a non-governmental organization (USAID contractor or recipient official who is responsible for completing the application package required to obtain funds or assistance from USAID as an award or as a sub-award.  In the case of applications by an individual in his/her own capacity, the Agency will collect the information directly from the individual applicant.  USAID also may obtain information in this system from public sources, Federal Departments and Agencies that conduct national-security screening, law-enforcement and intelligence-agency record systems, and other Federal Government databases.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under the Privacy Act (Section 552a (b) of Title 5 of the U.S.C.), the Agency could disclose all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system outside of USAID as a routine use, as follows:</p>
            <p>(1) To another Federal Department or Agency, to a court, magistrate, or other administrative body, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal Department or Agency, when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceedings or has a significant interest in the proceeding where the Department or Agency determines the information to be necessary and relevant.</p>
            <p>(2) To any component of the U.S. Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Department or Agency is authorized to appear, when; (a) the Department or Agency or any component thereof; or (b) any employee of the Department or Agency in her or his official capacity; or (c) any employee of the Department or Agency in his or her individual capacity where the U.S. Department of Justice or the Department or Agency has agreed to represent the employee; or (d) the United States, when the Department or Agency determines that litigation is likely to affect it or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the Department or Agency deems the use of such records by the U.S. Department of Justice or the Department or Agency is relevant and necessary to the litigation provided, however, that in each case the Department or Agency has determined that the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
            <p>(3) To the U.S. Department of Justice for the purpose of obtaining legal counsel, including whether USAID should disclose the records or information in this system of records outside the Agency.</p>
            <p>(4) To a Federal Government Department or Agency that assists USAID for the purpose of vetting, and for the purposes of ensuring accuracy of existing records and updating government records when a match between an applicant and another database is identified.</p>
            <p>(5) To disclose information to contractors (Personal Service Contractors or institutional support contractors) in furtherance of the contractor’s performance on behalf of USAID under a contract, including contracts that support the partner-vetting program.</p>
            <p>(6) To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), for the purposes of records-management inspections conducted under the authority of Sections 2904 and 2906 of Title 44 of the U.S.C. and in its role as Archivist.</p>
            <p>(7) To appropriate Federal Departments and Agencies, entities, and persons when:  (a) USAID suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (b) USAID has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, USAID (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (c) the disclosure made to such Departments and Agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with USAID’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach, or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
            <p>(8) To the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), in connection with review of private relief legislation, as set forth in OMB Circular A-19, at any stage of the legislative coordination and clearance process, as set forth in that Circular.</p>
            <p>(9) To another Federal Department or Agency or Federal entity, when USAID determines information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient Department or Agency or entity in:  (a) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach; or (b) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, that might result from a suspected or confirmed Breach.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>USAID stores records in this system in electronic format.  USAID’s staff collect paper records that contain information for counterterrorism vetting when USAID’s partners need to submit required information other than electronically.  USAID’s policy is that, following the entry of information contained in such paper copies into PVS, our staff must dispose of the paper copies properly, in accordance with the Agency’s procedures for handling information.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>USAID’s staff retrieves records in PVS by individual name, date of birth, place of birth, passport numbers, or other identifying data specified under "Categories of Records" in the system, as well as Mission/Program/Department, old awardee identification number (ID), awardee ID, alias, city, vetting status, vetting priority, vetting date, date of final determination, or date USAID created the record.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>PVS follows NARA Records Schedule Number DAA-0286-2017-0001.  USAID maintains vetting records for nine years after making an eligible or ineligible decision, regardless of award status.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>For electronic records:  USAID maintains PVS records in a secure cloud database managed by Amazon Web Services on behalf of the Agency.  The database is subject to non-disclosure agreement rules of engagement administered by AID Form 545-5.  USAID restricts access to vetting requests and results stored in the PVS database to users who are U.S. Government personnel and authorized contractors who need to know this information to perform their duties, who can include the USAID workforce hired and/or appointed by our Missions, Bureaus, and Independent Offices involved in conducting or supporting vetting.  The PVS database is housed on, and accessed from, an unclassified computer network.  USAID stores vetting results, the analysis of their content, and classified comments separately, outside of PVS, on appropriately classified networks.  Computer networks and the PVS database require a user authentication and Agency approval.  The Agency maintains and periodically reviews an audit trail to monitor access to the system.  Authorized U.S. Government personnel receive instructions in the proper use and protection of PII.</p>
            <p>For paper records:  USAID keeps paper vetting records in an approved security container at our Washington headquarters, and at the relevant locations that conduct vetting-related activities.  Access to these records is limited to those authorized U.S. Government personnel and authorized contractors who have a need for the records in the performance of their official duties.  USAID does not keep classified records within PVS.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Under the Privacy Act, individuals may request access to records about themselves.  These individuals must be limited to citizens of the United States or aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence.  If a Federal Department or Agency or a person who is not the individual who is the subject of the records, requests access to records about an individual, the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records is required.</p>
            <p>Requesters may submit requests to USAID for records under the Privacy Act in the following ways:  1) by mail to the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Office in the Information and Records Division of the Office of Management Services within USAID’s Bureau for Management, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., Room 2.07C, Ronald Reagan Building, Washington, D.C.  20523-2701; 2) via facsimile to 202-216-3070; 3) via email to foia@usaid.gov; 4) on the USAID website, at www.usaid.gov/foia-requests; or, 5) in person during regular business hours at USAID, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., Room 2.07C, Ronald Reagan Building, Washington, D.C.  20523-2701, or at USAID’s overseas Missions.</p>
            <p>Requesters who use methods 1 through 4 above may provide a written statement, or may complete and submit USAID Form 507-2, Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Record Request Form, which is available in the following ways:  a) on the USAID website, at www.usaid.gov/foia-requests; b) by email request to foia@usaid.gov; or, c) by writing to USAID’s FOIA Office in the Information and Records Division of the Office of Management Services within USAID’s Bureau for Management, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., Room 2.07C, Ronald Reagan Building, Washington, D.C.  20523-2701.  Requesters must provide information that is necessary to identify the records, including the following:  the requester’s full name; present mailing address; home telephone; work telephone; name of subject, if other than the requester; the requester’s relationship to subject; a description of the type of information or specific records; and the purpose of requesting the information.  Requesters should provide the system of record (in this case, PVS) identification name and number, if known; and, to facilitate the assembly of records retrieved by Social Security Numbers, the Social Security Number of the individual to whom the record or records pertain.</p>
            <p>In addition, requesters who use methods 1 through 4 above must include proof of their identity by providing copies of two (2) source documents notarized by a valid, unexpired notary public.  Acceptable proof-of-identity source documents include an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card (both sides); unexpired U.S. Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contains a photograph; a certificate of United States citizenship; a certificate of naturalization; a card that shows permanent residence in the United States; a United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; a United States military identification card or draft record; or a United States military dependent’s identification card.</p>
            <p>A requester who use methods 1 through 4 above also must provide a signed and notarized statement that he or she is the person named in the request; that he or she understands that any falsification of this statement is punishable under the provision of Section 1001 of Title 18 of the U.S.C. by a fine, or by imprisonment of not more than five years or, if the offense involves international or domestic terrorism (as defined in Section 2331 of the statute), imprisonment of not more than eight years, or both; and that requesting or obtaining records under false pretenses is punishable under the provisions of Section 552a(i)(3) of Title 5 of the U.S.C. as a misdemeanor, and by a fine of not more than $5,000.</p>
            <p>Requesters who use method 5 above must provide such personal identification as is reasonable under the circumstances to verify their identity, including the following:  an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card; unexpired U.S. Government employee identity card; un-expired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contains a photograph; a certificate of United States citizenship; a certificate of naturalization; a card that shows permanent residence in the United States; a United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; a United States military identification card or draft record; or a United States military dependent’s identification card.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See Record Access Procedure.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See Record Access Procedure.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Portions of USAID’s PVS are exempt from one or more provisions of the Privacy Act (74 FR 9).</p>
            <p>Exempt information in this system includes, but is not limited to, the following:</p>
            <p>●Results generated from the screening of individuals covered by this notice;</p>
            <p>●Intelligence and law-enforcement information related to national security; and</p>
            <p>●National-security vetting and counterterrorism screening information, provided to USAID by other Departments and Agencies.</p>
            <p><i>Section 215.13 of Part 215 of Title 22 of the Code of Federal Regulations</i>, General Exemptions:
            </p>
            <p>(c) The systems of records USAID is exempt under Section (j)(2) of the Act, the provisions of the Act from which the Agency is exempting them, and the justification for the exemptions, appear below:</p>
            <p>(2) Partner-Vetting System (PVS).  This system is exempt from Subsections (c)(3) and (4); (d); (e)(1), (2), and (3); (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I); (e)(5) and (8); (f), (g), and (h) of Section 552a of Title 5 of the U.S.C.  These exemptions are necessary to insure the proper functioning of the law-enforcement activity, to protect confidential sources of information, to fulfill promises of confidentiality, to maintain the integrity of law-enforcement procedures, to avoid premature disclosure of the knowledge of criminal activity and the evidentiary basis of possible enforcement actions, to prevent interference with law-enforcement proceedings, to avoid the disclosure of investigative techniques, to avoid endangering law-enforcement personnel, to maintain the ability to obtain candid and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect the confidentiality of information, to avoid endangering these sources, and to facilitate the proper selection or continuance of the best applicants or persons for a given position or contract.  Although the primary functions of USAID are not of a law-enforcement nature, the mandate to ensure USAID’s funding does not purposefully or inadvertently support entities or individuals deemed to be a risk to national security necessarily requires coordination with law-enforcement and intelligence agencies as well as use of their information.  The use of the information by these other Departments or Agencies necessitates the conveyance of these other systems exemptions to protect the information as stated. [57 FR 38277, Aug. 24, 1992, as amended at 74 FR 16, Jan. 2, 2009]</p>
            <p><i>Section 215.14 of Part 215 of Title 22 of the Code of Federal Regulation</i>, Specific Exemptions:
            </p>
            <p>(c) The systems of records to be exempted under Section (k) of the Act, the provisions of the Act from which the Agency is exempting them, and the justification for the exemptions, appear below:</p>
            <p>(6) Partner Vetting System (PVS).  This system is exempt under Subsections (k)(1), (k)(2), and (k)(5) of Section 552a of Title 5 of the U.S.C., and from the provisions of Subsections (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4)(G), (H), (I); and (f).5 of Section 552a of U.S.C. 552a.  USAID claims these exemptions to protect the materials required by Executive Order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy, to prevent subjects of investigation from frustrating the investigatory process, to ensure the proper functioning and integrity of law-enforcement activities, to prevent the disclosure of investigative techniques, to maintain the ability to obtain candid and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect the confidentiality of information, to avoid endangering these sources, and to facilitate the proper selection or continuance of the best applicants or persons for a given position or contract.  [57 FR 38277, Aug. 24, 1992, as amended at 74 FR 17, Jan. 2, 2009]</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>USAID established the PVS as a new system of records on August 27, 2007 (72FR 39042).</p>
            <p>USAID modified the PVS system of records on January 10, 2013 (77 FR 72319).</p>
            >
        </xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="aid28" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-28</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">USAID Personnel Locator System (to include Emergency Notification System, Telework, and Newsletters).</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive But Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>United States Agency for International Development, 1300 Pennsylvania Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records of current employees, contractors, consultants, and partners.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains USAID organizational information. At a solution wide level the system will collect and
display First and Last Name, title, USAID Organizational address, building name, room number, bureau, region, mission,
country, office telephone numbers, office fax numbers, contact email address, employment mechanism, home address, home
phone number, alternate phone number, emergency contact name, emergency contact phone number, emergency contact alternate
number, program areas of expertise, foreign language skills, professional affiliations, professional certifications,
photograph, region or country-based experience, operational experience and educational experience. The Personnel Locator
System is being updated as an Agency-wide system of record to cover all USAID Locator Systems, to include the Emergency
Notification System, USAID Web site Modernization to include, requests for newsletters via USAID.gov and information
collected on Agency Telework forms. This would also include electronic business card applications.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579), sec. 552a(c), (e), (f), and (p).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be used:
</p><p>(1) To develop and maintain current agency personnel locator and professional directory listings,
</p><p>(2) To identify and notify individuals employed by USAID when an emergency which occurs after hours requires that
he/she report or not report for duty,
</p><p>(3) To maintain and implement emergency plans, including continuity of operations and facility evacuation plans,
</p><p>(4) To notify, locate, and mobilize individuals as necessary during emergency or other threatening situations,





</p><p>(5) To notify the designated emergency contact in case of a medical or other emergency event involving an individual,
</p><p>(6) To identify colleagues by areas of expertise to facilitate mentoring activities with Foreign Service Officers,
</p><p>(7) To identify colleagues with specialized knowledge and/or expertise to participate in collaborative efforts,
</p><p>(8) To facilitate this information in the Emergency Notification System,
</p><p>(9) To facilitate the transmission of Agency Newsletters, and
</p><p>(10) To identify personnel that are utilizing the Governmental Telework Policy and to support the OMB mandate for
telework</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>These records are not disclosed to consumer reporting agencies.</p>
<p>Purposes of Such Uses:
</p><p>USAID may disclose relevant system records in accordance with any current and future blanket routine uses
established for its record systems. These may be for internal communications or with external partners.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>These records are not disclosed to consumer reporting agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Electronic records are maintained in user-authenticated, password-protected systems. All records are accessed
only by authorized personnel who have a need to access the records in the performance of their official duties.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by name, location or any other identifier listed in the categories of records cited
above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Additional administrative safeguards are provided through the use of internal standard operating procedures.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records will be updated periodically to reflect changes and deleted or destroyed when their use is no longer
required.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel Locator System (Emergency Notification System, Telework Program and USAID Web site Modernization),
United States Agency for International, Development, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting notification of the existence of records on them must send the request in writing to the
Chief Privacy Officer, USAID, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington, Va. 22202. The request must include the
requestor's full name, his/her current address and a return address for transmitting the information. The request shall
be signed by either notarized signature or by signature under penalty of perjury and reasonably specify the record
contents being sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to a record must submit the request in writing according to the "
Notification Procedures" above. An individual wishing to request access to records in person must provide identity
documents, such as government-issued photo identification, sufficient to satisfy the custodian of the records that the
requester is entitled to access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual requesting amendment of a record maintained on himself or herself must identify the information to
be changed and the corrective action sought. Requests must follow the "Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The records contained in this system will be provided by and updated by the individual who is the subject of the
record.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="abrev" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-29</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Deployment Tracking System [deleted]. Reason: Based upon a review of AID-29, it has been determined that this system is not needed since the program was
never activated.</subsection>
</section>
<section id="abrev" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-30</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">USAID On-Line Collaboration Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at USAID, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Ronald Reagan Building Suite 2.12, Washington, DC
20523.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system will contain records of any individual who participates in a USAID sponsored on-line collaboration
activity, for which registration is required.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Categories of records include, name, e-mail address, phone number, affiliation, title, role, company, country,
age, gender, username, password, professional biographical information, such as program areas of expertise, foreign
language skills, professional affiliations, professional certifications, photograph, regional or country-based
experience, operational experience and educational experience.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system may be used:
</p><p>(1) To perform content analysis by participant;
</p><p>(2) To perform aggregated statistical analysis of collaborative participants, such as, age, gender, country;
</p><p>(3) To create an on-line business card and identify individuals as they participate to promote collaboration;
</p><p>(4) To register participants for collaborative activities;
</p><p>(5) To perform analysis to determine if agency needs to conduct outreach or marketing to encourage participation in a
specific area, age group, region, area of expertise;
</p><p>(6) To follow up with individuals to clarify thoughts, opinions or comments provided during an on-line session</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>These records are not disclosed to consumer reporting agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to USAID's routine uses, detailed transcripts of webinars, conferences and other public forums may be
posted publicly to allow interested parties to perform analysis of the information presented. Aggregated data may also be
publicly available through Web site postings, fact sheets, brochures or other means to encourage and generate public
interest and for general informational purposes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>All records will be stored electronically in a database within USAID's firewall.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by name, location or any other identifier listed in the categories of records cited
above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>All records will be maintained within USAID's security perimeter. Physical security controls include secured
space monitored by guards. Access to the database will be authorized, set up and monitored by the information system
security officer.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual records will be destroyed when their use is no longer required.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>USAID, Chief Information Officer, 1300 Pennsylvania Ave., NW., RRB Suite 2.12, Washington, DC 20253.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting notification of the existence of records on them must send the request in writing to the
USAID Chief Privacy Officer, 1300 Pennsylvania Ave., NW, RRB Suite 2.12-003, Washington, DC 20253. The request must
include the requestor's full name, his/her current address and a return address for transmitting the information. The
request shall be signed by either notarized signature or by signature under penalty of perjury and reasonably specify the
record contents being sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting access to a record maintained on them must address the request to the USAID Chief Privacy
Officer as described in "Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting amendment of a record maintained on them must identify the information to be changed and
the corrective action sought. Requests must be sent to the USAID Chief Privacy Officer as described in "
Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The records contained in this system should be provided by the individual who is the subject of the record.
Additional sources may include a supervisor, personal assistant or other individual assigned by the individual to provide
the information.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="abrev" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-30</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Google Apps Business Edition.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive But Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>United States Agency for International Development, 2733 Crystal Drive,
11th Floor, Arlington, VA 22202.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records of current
employees, contractors, consultants, and partners.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains USAID organizational
information. At a solution wide level the system will collect and display First and Last Name,
Work Phone Number, and Work Address. This information is automatically collected from
USAID's Active Directory of user objects. Users additionally have an option to create and
maintain personal address books, accessible to only them or to users they grant access to. In
these personal address books the user may manually enter First and Last Name, Home Address,
Home Phone, and Date of Birth.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579), sec. 552a (c),
(e), (f), and (p).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be used:
</p><p>(1) The solution wide information is available to all USAID users provisioned in the Google Apps system for e-mail,
calendaring, and collaboration tools</p>
<p>(2) The personal address book information is available to the user that created the personal address book or to users
that are granted access</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>These records are not disclosed to consumer
reporting agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>USAID may disclose relevant system records in accordance with any
current and future blanket routine uses established for its record systems. These may be for
internal communications or with external partners.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Electronic records are maintained in user-authenticated, password-protected systems. All records are accessed
only by authorized personnel who have a need to access the records in the performance of their official duties.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact Sharing creates a searchable directory of the user names and e-mail
addresses in your domain, and shares this directory with everyone in your organization. By default, the directory
includes each user's primary e-mail address and any e-mail aliases or nicknames. As a Google Apps account administrator,
you can control which of these e-mail addresses appear in the directory by adjusting the Contact Sharing settings. You
can also hide users from the shared contact list</p>
<p>E-mail addresses that users saved as Personal Contacts are not included in the directory and are not affected by
changes made to the Contact Sharing setting. Suspended and deleted users also do not appear in the directory</p>
<p>All users in your domain can find contacts listed in the directory through Contacts search, Contacts details view, and
any autocomplete function in each Google App enabled for your domain</p>
<p>Contact Sharing is automatically enabled in your Google Apps account, but can be disabled (and re-enabled) at any
time.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Additional administrative safeguards are provided through the use of internal standard operating procedures.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained using the appropriate, approved National Archives Records Administration--Schedules for
the type of record being maintained.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Sukhvinder Singh, United States Agency for International Development, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington,
VA. 22202.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting notification of the existence of records on them
must send the request in writing to the Chief Privacy Officer, USAID, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington, VA
22202. The request must include the requestor's full name, his/her current address and a return address for transmitting
the information. The request shall be signed by either notarized signature or by signature under penalty of perjury and
reasonably specify the
record contents being sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to a record must submit the request in writing according to the "
Notification Procedures" above. An individual wishing to request access to records in person must provide identity
documents, such as government-issued photo identification, sufficient to satisfy the custodian of the records that the
requester is entitled to access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual requesting amendment of a record maintained on himself or herself must identify the information to
be changed and the corrective action sought</p>
<p>Requests must follow the "Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The records contained in this system will be provided by and updated by the individual who is the subject of the
record.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

</section>
<section id="aid31" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-31</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">HSPD-12 PIV Lifecycle Management.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive But Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>
United States Agency for International Development, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington, VA 22202.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records of current employees, contractors, consultants, and partners.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>
This system contains USAID organizational information. The covered record, which has already been collected by the Department of State for issuance of the current USAID PIV badge, are as follows: name; employee digital photo; two digital fingerprints; organizational affiliation; Agency; 3-4 Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) certificates; and expiration date. In order to access the data on the chip, the cardholder must create a Personal Identification Number (PIN).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579), sec. 552a(c), (e), (f), and (p).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be used:
</p><p>(1) To update current USAID Direct Hire employees' card data in order to comply with OMB M-11-11 for physical and logical access to USAID networks and facilities</p>
<p>(2) To issue PIV compliant cards to eligible contractors</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>These records are not disclosed to consumer reporting agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>USAID may disclose relevant system records in accordance with any current and future blanket routine uses established for its record systems. These may be for internal communications or with external partners.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Data records are located at the hosting environment, and maintained in user-authenticated, password-protected systems. All records are accessed only by authorized personnel who have a need to access the records in the performance of their official duties.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by name, PIN number or any other identifier listed in the categories of records cited above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Additional administrative safeguards are provided through the use of internal standard operating procedures in accordance with the FIPS-201, and NIST 800-53 standards.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained using the appropriate, approved National Archives Records Administration--Schedules for the type of record being maintained.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Jeffrey Anouilh, United States Agency for International Development, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington, VA 22202.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting notification of the existence of records on them must send the request in writing to the Chief Privacy Officer, USAID, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington, VA 22202. The request must include the requestor's full name, his/her current address and a return address for transmitting the information. The request shall be signed by either notarized signature or by signature under penalty of perjury and reasonably specify the record contents being sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to a record must submit the request in writing according to the "Notification Procedures" above. An individual wishing to request access to records in person must provide identity documents, such as government-issued photo identification, sufficient to satisfy the custodian of the records that the requester is entitled to access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual requesting amendment of a record maintained on himself or herself must identify the information to be changed and the corrective action sought. Requests must follow the "Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The records contained in this system will be provided by and updated by the individual who is the subject of the record.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
</section>

    <section id="aid32" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-32</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Reasonable Accommodation Records.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Civil Rights and Diversity, United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523-2120.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who are current or former USAID employees and applicants, and who have requested reasonable accommodation under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records contains information or documents compiled during the reasonable accommodation request process.  These records may contain names, employment status, addresses, e-mail addresses, telephone numbers, occupational series, grade level, Agency office; the details of the reasonable accommodation request or emergency assistance request, type of accommodation requested, information concerning the nature of the disability and the need for accommodation, medical documentation, sources of technical assistance consulted to identify and procure reasonable accommodations, the details of the Agency determination; and any other information related to the request.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system is established and is maintained pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 U.S.C. 791; E.O. 13164 - Requiring Federal Agencies To Establish Procedures To Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation; and E.O. 13548, Increasing Federal Employment of Individuals with Disabilities</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of this system is to allow USAID to collect and maintain records on applicants and employees with disabilities who requested or received reasonable accommodation by the Agency as required by the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the Americans with Disabilities Act Amendments Act of 2008 (ADAAA).  This system is maintained for the purpose of processing, deciding, and implementing requests for reasonable accommodation made by USAID employees and applicants.  The purpose of this system is also to track and report the processing of requests for reasonable accommodation Agency-wide to comply with applicable law and regulations and to preserve and maintain the confidentiality of medical information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), all or a portion of the records contained in this system of records may be disclosed outside USAID as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>(1) To the Department of Justice, (including United States Attorney Offices), or other appropriate Federal Government agency conducting litigation or in proceedings before any court, adjudicative or administrative body, when it is necessary to the litigation and one of the following is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation (1) USAID or any component thereof; (2) any employee of USAID in his/her official capacity; (3) any employee of USAID in his/her individual capacity where DOJ or USAID has agreed to represent the employee; or (4) the United States or any agency thereof, is a party to the litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and USAID determines that the records are both relevant and necessary to the litigation and the use of such records is compatible with the purpose for which USAID collected the records.</p>
                <p>(2) To a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                <p>(3) To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) or other federal government agencies pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>(4) To an agency, organization, or individual for the purpose of performing audit or oversight operations as authorized by law, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight function.</p>
                <p>(5) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) USAID suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by USAID or another agency or entity) or harm to the individual that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with USAID's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>(6) To contractors and their agents, grantees, experts, consultants, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for USAID, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.  Individuals provided information under this routine use is subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to USAID officers and employees.</p>
                <p>(7) To an appropriate federal, state, or local law enforcement agency or other appropriate authority charged with investigating or prosecuting a violation or enforcing or implementing a law, rule, regulation, or order, where a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law, which includes criminal, civil, or regulatory violations and such disclosure is proper and consistent with the official duties of the person making the disclosure.</p>
                <p>(8) To a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal in the course of presenting evidence, including disclosures to opposing counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations or in connection with criminal law proceedings or in response to a subpoena from a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
                <p>(9) To another federal agency or commission with responsibility for labor or employment relations or other issues, including equal employment opportunity and reasonable accommodation issues, when that agency or commission has jurisdiction over reasonable accommodation.</p>
                <p>(10) To appropriate third parties contracted by USAID to facilitate mediation or other dispute resolution procedures or programs.</p>
                <p>(11) To a Federal agency or entity that requires information relevant or related to a reasonable accommodation decision and/or its implementation.</p>
                <p>(12) To medical personnel and first responders, to meet a bona fide emergency, including medical emergencies.</p>
                <p>(13) To attorneys, union representatives, or other persons designated by USAID employees in writing to represent them in a grievance, complaint, appeal, or litigation case.</p>
                <p>(14) To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
                <p>(15) To labor organization officials when such information is relevant to personnel policies affecting employment conditions and necessary for exclusive representation by the labor organization.</p>
                 </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>Records in this system are stored on paper and/or electronic form; and are maintained in locked cabinets and/or user-authenticated, password-protected systems.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retrieved by the names of the individuals about whom they are maintained and/or the number assigned to the accommodation request.  In the case of electronic databases, information may be retrieved by other identifying search terms.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system is safeguarded in accordance with applicable laws, rules and policies, including the Agency’s automated directive system (ADS).  In general, records are maintained in buildings with restricted access.  The required use of password protection identification features and other system protection methods also restrict access.  Access to records is restricted to those authorized USAID personnel and authorized contractors who have an official need in the performance of their official duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission’s Policy Guidance on Executive Order 13164: Establishing Procedures to Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation, Directives Transmittal Number 915.003, October 20, 2000; and in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) General Records Schedule 1, Civilian Personnel Records, Item 24, Reasonable Accommodation Request Records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Reasonable Accommodation Program Manager, Office of Civil Rights and Diversity, United States Agency for International Development, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523-2120.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as Record Access Procedures.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Under the Privacy Act, individuals may request access to records about themselves.  If an agency or a person, who is not the individual who is the subject of the records, requests access to records about an individual, the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records is required.</p>
                <p> Requesters may submit requests for records under the Privacy Act: 1) by mail to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701; 2) via Facsimile to 202-216-3070; 3) via email to foia@usaid.gov;  4) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia-requests; or 5) in person during regular business hours at USAID, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523-2701, or at USAID overseas missions.</p>
                <p> Requesters using 1 through 4 may provide a written statement or may complete and submit USAID Form 507-1, Freedom of Information / Privacy Act Record Request Form, which can be obtained: a) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia -requests; b) by email request to foia@usaid.gov; or c) by writing to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701, and provide information that is necessary to identify the records, including the following:  Requester’s full name; present mailing address; home telephone; work telephone; name of subject, if other than requester; requester relationship to subject; description of type of information or specific records; and purpose of requesting information.  Requesters should provide the system of record identification name and number, if known; and, to facilitate the retrieval of records contained in those systems of records which are retrieved by Social Security Numbers, the Social Security Number of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                <p>In addition, requesters using 1 through 4 must include proof of identity information by providing copies of two (2) source documents that must be notarized by a valid (un-expired) notary public.  Acceptable proof-of-identity source documents include:  an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card (both sides); unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.</p>
                <p> Requesters using 1 through 4 must also provide a signed and notarized statement that they are the person named in the request; that they understand that any falsification of their statement is punishable under the provision of 18 USC 1001 by a fine, or by imprisonment of not more than five years or, if the offense involves international or domestic terrorism (as defined in section 2331), imprisonment of not more than eight years, or both; and that requesting or obtaining records under false pretenses is punishable under the provisions of 5 USC 552a(i)(3) as a misdemeanor and by a fine of not more than $5,000.</p>
                <p>Requesters using 5 must provide such personal identification as is reasonable under the circumstances to verify the requester’s identity, including the following: an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card; unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking to contest or amend records maintained on himself or herself must clearly and concisely state that information is being contested, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.  Requests to amend a record must follow the Record Access Procedures above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Sources of records include individuals who have requested reasonable accommodation and supporting documentation from USAID officials, employees, and agents, and/or healthcare professionals involved in the reasonable accommodation request, response, and implementation process.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    None.
                </p>

                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    </section>


    <section id="aid33" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-33</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Phoenix Financial Management System.</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Sensitive But Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Beltsville Information Management Center (BIMC), 8101 O'Dell Rd., Beltsville, MD 20705--DRP Servers</p>
<p>(2) Global Financial Service Center (GFSC--DoS), 1969 Dyess Ave., Building A, Computer Room 2A228, Charleston, SC
29405--Production Servers</p>
<p>(3) Terremark, 50 Northeast 9th Street, Miami, FL 33132--Terremark Data Center Reporting, Development and Test
Servers.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records of current employees, contractors, personal service contractors (PSCs), consultants,
partners, and those receiving foreign assistance funds.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains USAID organizational information. Phoenix imports the following data elements from NFC
Payroll
files for Personnel Services Contractors (PSC) and direct hires: Name, social security number, details of payroll
transactions and work phone numbers. Phoenix imports the following data elements from the E2 Travel system for each
traveler: Name, date of travel (month/year) and destination.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579), sec. 552a(c), (e), (f), and (p).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system will be used:
</p><p>(1) The payroll information is used to associate PSC payroll-related payments with their contracts and track direct
hire payroll payments in the system in order to produce 1099 files. If this information is not imported form NFC to
Phoenix, then USAID cannot comply with IRS regulations to maintain and produce 1099s</p>
<p>(2) The travel information is used to associate E2 travel records with Phoenix accounting information regarding travel
authorization and funding.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent> 
<p>USAID may disclose relevant system records in accordance with any current and future blanket routine uses
established
for its record systems. These may be for internal communications or with external partners</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>These records are not disclosed to consumer reporting agencies.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Electronic records are maintained in user-authenticated, password-protected systems.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>All records are accessed only by authorized personnel who have a need to access the records in the performance of
their official duties. Information is retrieved by name or by a system specific ID (Vendor ID, Traveller ID, etc.). SSN
is not employed as a key, but only present for tax reporting purposes.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Administrative, managerial and technical controls are in place. Phoenix has a current Security Assessment and
Authorization (A&amp;A) in place. Phoenix is secured through access control provided to only those individuals with a
need to know within the Agency. Further, access to the PII is limited to the staff within the CMP and CAR divisions.
Phoenix is maintained by the U.S. government, not contractors.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained in accordance with approved National Archives and Records Administration Schedules.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>David Ostermeyer, United States Agency for International Development, U.S. Department of State Annex 44, 455, 301
4th
Street SW., Washington, DC 20547.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals requesting notification of the existence of records on them must send the request in writing to the
Chief
Privacy Officer, USAID, 2733 Crystal Drive, 11th Floor, Arlington, VA 22202. The request must include the requestor's
full name, his/her current address and a return address for transmitting the information. The request shall be signed by
either notarized signature or by signature under penalty of perjury and reasonably specify the record contents being
sought.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to request access to a record must submit the request in writing according to the
"Notification Procedures" above. An individual wishing to request access to records in person must provide
identity documents, such as government-issued photo identification, sufficient to satisfy the custodian of the records
that the requester is entitled to access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual requesting amendment of a record maintained on himself or herself must identify the information to
be
changed and the corrective action sought. Requests must follow the "Notification Procedures" above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The records contained in this system will be provided by and updated by the individual who is the subject of the
record.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>


<section id="aid34" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-34</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Personal Services Contracts Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523; Terremark, 50 NE 9th Street, Miami, FL 33132; U.S. Department of State COOP Beltsville (BIMC), 8101 Odell Road, Floor/Room – 173, Beltsville, MD 20705; U.S. Department of State, Global Financial Service Center (GFSC—DoS), 1969 Dyess Ave, Building A, Computer Room 2A228, Charleston, SC 29405; and other USAID offices in the United States and throughout the world that have personal services contractor hiring authority.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system encompasses all individuals who are personal services contractors with USAID.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system consists of records created or compiled for contract actions related to personal services contractors, including personal services contractor files and contract documents.   A personal services contractor file includes name, Social Security Number, address, citizenship, resume, education, professional experience, other qualifications, Selective Service registration data, language proficiencies, licenses and certifications, clearance level, salary, direct-deposit financial information, contract number, position title, travel availability, training received, assignments, position number, applicable medical clearances, and performance evaluations.  Contract documents include applications, salary worksheet computations, statements of work, qualifications approval memoranda, final offer letters, contract, performance evaluations, correspondence, advanced leave requests, training certifications, release forms, and out-processing checklists.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system was established and is maintained pursuant to the Foreign Assistance Act, Pub. L. 87-165, as amended; 48 CFR 37.104, Personal services contracts; 48 CFR Ch. 7, App. D, Direct USAID Contracts with a U.S. Citizen or a U.S. Resident Alien for Personal Services Abroad.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The records are collected, used, maintained, and disseminated for the purposes of documenting personal services contracts processing, including personal services contracts records, pay and benefits determinations and processing, determining accountability and liability of contract parties, reports of contractor actions, and the records required in connection with the personal services contractor during the contract cycle.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b), all or a portion of the records contained in this system of records may be disclosed outside USAID as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. § 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
<p>(1)  To the Internal Revenue Service and the Social Security Administration for the purposes of reporting earnings information.</p>
<p>(2)  To a court, magistrate, or other administrative body in the course of presenting evidence, including disclosures to counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations or in connection with criminal proceedings, when USAID is a party to the proceeding or has a significant interest in the proceeding, to the extent that the information is determined to be relevant and necessary.</p>
<p>(3)  To the Department of Justice or other appropriate Federal Government agency when the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding in a court or other tribunal in which USAID or a USAID official in his or her official capacity is a party or has an interest, or when the litigation is likely to affect USAID.</p>
<p>(4)  To a Federal Government agency or entity that furnished the record or information for the purposes of permitting that agency or entity to make a decision as to access to or correction of the record or information.</p>
<p>(5)  In the event of an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by statute or particular program pursuant thereto, to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
<p>(6)  To the Department of State and its posts abroad for the purposes of transmission of information between organizational units of the Agency, or for the purposes related to the responsibilities of the Department of State in conducting United States foreign policy or protecting United States citizens, such as the assignment of employees to positions abroad, the reporting of accidents abroad, evacuation of employees and dependents, and for other purposes for which officers and employees of the Department of State have a need for the records in the performance of their duties.</p>
<p>(7)  To a foreign government or international agency in response to its request for information to facilitate the conduct of U.S. relations with that government or agency through the issuance of such documents as visas, country clearances, identification cards, drivers' licenses, diplomatic lists, licenses to import or export personal effects, and other official documents and permits routinely required in connection with the official service or travel abroad of the individual and his or her dependents.</p>
<p>(8)  To Federal agencies with which USAID has entered into an agreement to provide services to assist USAID in carrying out its functions under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended.  Such disclosures would be for the purpose of transmission of information between organizational units of USAID; of providing to the original employing agency information concerning the services of its employee while under the supervision of USAID, including performance evaluations, reports of conduct, awards and commendations, and information normally obtained in the course of personnel administration and employee supervision; or of providing other information directly related to the purposes of the inter-agency agreement as set forth therein, and necessary and relevant to its implementation.</p>
<p>(9)  To appropriate officials and employees of a Federal Government agency or entity when the information is relevant to a decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an employee; the assignment, detail or deployment of an employee; the issuance, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation; the letting of a contract; or the issuance of a grant or benefit.</p>
<p>(10)  To the National Archives and Records Administration, Information Security Oversight Office, Interagency Security Classification Appeals Panel, for the purposes of adjudicating an appeal from a USAID denial of a request for mandatory declassification review of records, made under the applicable executive order(s) governing classification.</p>
<p>(11)  To the National Archives and Records Administration for the purposes of records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
<p>(12)  To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) USAID suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) USAID has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the USAID or another agency, entity, or person) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with USAID’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
<p>(13)  To a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, or to private individuals, for the purposes of requesting information relevant to a USAID decision concerning the hiring, retention, or promotion of a personal services contractor, the issuance of a security clearance, or other decision within the purposes of this system of records.</p>
<p>(14)  To a prospective employer of a current or former USAID personal services contractor for the purposes of providing the following information to prospective employers:  Job descriptions, dates of contract, and reason for termination of contract.</p>
<p>(15) To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons for the purposes of confirming the qualifications of an applicant for the award of a personal services contract.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored on paper and/or electronic form; and are maintained in locked cabinets and/or user-authenticated, password-protected systems.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved by the name of the personal services contractor and the contract number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information in this system is safeguarded in accordance with applicable laws, rules and policies, including the agency’s automated directive system.  In general, records and technical equipment are maintained in buildings with restricted access.  The required use of password protection identification features and other system protection methods also restrict access.  Paper records and Sensitive But Unclassified records are kept in an approved security container at the USAID Washington headquarters, and at the relevant locations where USAID has a program.  The electronic records are stored in the Agency Secure Image and Storage Tracking (ASIST) or other document management systems, which are safeguarded in accordance with applicable laws, rules, and policies, including USAID’s automated systems security and access policies.  Access to the records is restricted to those authorized USAID personnel and authorized contractors who have an official need to access the records in the performance of their official duties.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with the Federal Acquisition Regulations and/or the National Archives Records Administration’s General Records Disposition Schedules, and the agency’s approved disposition schedules.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>USAID Contracting Officers or Heads of Contracting Activities, United States Agency for International Development, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC  20523; and USAID Missions throughout the world.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Same as Record Access Procedures.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Under the Privacy Act, individuals may request access to records about themselves.  If an agency or a person, who is not the individual who is the subject of the records, requests access to records about an individual, the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records is required.</p>
<p>Requesters may submit requests for records under the Privacy Act: (1) by mail to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701; (2) via Facsimile to 202-216-3070; (3) via email to foia@usaid.gov;  (4) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia-requests; or (5) in person during regular business hours at USAID, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20523-2701, or at USAID overseas missions.</p>
<p>Requesters using 1 through 4 may provide a written statement or may complete and submit USAID Form 507-1, Freedom of Information / Privacy Act Record Request Form, which can be obtained: (a) on the USAID website at www.usaid.gov/foia -requests; (b) by email request to foia@usaid.gov; or (c) by writing to the USAID FOIA Office, Bureau for Management, Office of Management Services, Information and Records Division, 1300 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Room 2.07C – RRB, Washington, DC 20523-2701, and provide information that is necessary to identify the records, including the following:  Requester’s full name; present mailing address; home telephone; work telephone; name of subject, if other than requester; requester relationship to subject; description of type of information or specific records; and purpose of requesting information.  Requesters should provide the system of record identification name and number, if known; and, to facilitate the retrieval of records contained in those systems of records which are retrieved by Social Security Numbers, the Social Security Number of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
<p>In addition, requesters using 1 through 4 must include proof of identity information by providing copies of two (2) source documents that must be notarized by a valid (un-expired) notary public.  Acceptable proof-of-identity source documents include:  an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card (both sides); unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.  </p>
<p>Requesters using 1 through 4 must also provide a signed and notarized statement that they are the person named in the request; that they understand that any falsification of their statement is punishable under the provision of 18 USC 1001 by a fine, or by imprisonment of not more than five years or, if the offense involves international or domestic terrorism (as defined in section 2331), imprisonment of not more than eight years, or both; and that requesting or obtaining records under false pretenses is punishable under the provisions of 5 USC 552a(i)(3) as a misdemeanor and by a fine of not more than $5,000.  </p>
<p>Requesters using 5 must provide such personal identification as is reasonable under the circumstances to verify the requester’s identity, including the following: an unexpired United States passport; Social Security Card; unexpired United States Government employee identity card; unexpired driver’s license or identification card issued by a state or United States possession, provided that it contain a photograph; certificate of United States citizenship; certificate of naturalization; card showing permanent residence in the United States; United States alien registration receipt card with photograph; United States military card or draft record; or United States military dependent’s identification card.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals seeking to contest or amend records maintained on himself or herself must clearly and concisely state that information is being contested, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.  Requests to amend a record must follow the Record Access Procedures above.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>     These records contain information directly from the individuals who are the subject of these records; as well as from contracting officers and contracting officers’ representatives in USAID bureaus and missions, and Office of Human Resources employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5) and as specified in 22 CFR 215.14(a)(5) and (c)(5), certain records in this system of records are exempt from the following provisions of the Privacy Act:  5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4)(G); (H); (I); and (f). 

</p></xhtmlContent>
</subsection>
</section>

<appendix id="appa" toc="yes">
<title>Agency for International Development, Address and Locations of Office Referenced in the Regulations
and Notices </title>

<xhtmlContent>

	<table width="100%" border="1" bordercolor="#333333">
        <tr>
 <th scope="col"> </th>
<th scope="col">Mailing address</th>
<th scope="col">Location</th>
</tr>
<tr><td colspan="3"><div align="center">Office</div></td>
</tr>
<tr><td colspan="3">I. In the United States:
</td></tr>
<tr><td>State Department</td><td>A.I.D., Washington, DC 20523</td><td>320 21st St. NW., Washington, DC.</td>
</tr>
<tr><td>State Department, Annex 2</td><td>-do-</td><td>515 22d St. NW, Washington, DC</td>
	</tr>
<tr><td>State Department, Annex 5</td><td>-do-</td><td>1901 Pennsylvania Ave. NW, Washington, DC</td>
		</tr>
<tr><td>State Department, Annex 11</td><td>-do-</td><td>1401 Wilson Blvd., Arlington, VA</td>
			</tr>
<tr><td>Universal North Building</td><td>-do-</td><td>1975 Florida Ave. NW, Washington, DC</td>
				</tr>
<tr><td>Pomponio Plaza Building</td><td>-do-</td><td>1735 North Lynn St., Arlington, VA
					</td></tr>
<tr><td>Rosslyn Plaza "E" Building</td><td>-do-</td><td>1621 N. Kent St., Arlington, VA</td>
						</tr>
<tr><td>Rosslyn Plaza "C" Building</td><td>-do-</td>
</tr>
<tr><td>New Cumberland</td><td>A.I.D. Excess Property Division, Building 54-5, New Cumberland Army Depot, New
Cumberland, Pa. 17070.</td><td>Building 54-5, New Cumberland Army Depot, New Cumberland, Pa. 17070</td>
	</tr>
<tr><td colspan="3"><div align="center">Mission</div></td></tr>
<tr><td colspan="3">II. Abroad:</td></tr>
<tr><td>Afghanistan</td><td>USAID to Afghanistan, c/o American Embassy, Kabul, Afghanistan</td><td>Wazir Abkar Khan Mina, Kabul,
Afghanistan
	</td></tr>
<tr><td>Bangladesh</td><td>USAID, c/o American Embassy, Dacca, Bangladesh</td><td>Adamjee Court Bldg. Montijheel, Dacca,
Bangladesh</td>
		</tr>
<tr><td>Brazil</td><td>USAID to Brazil, CAIZA Postal 14-2324, Brasilia D.F., Brazil</td><td>Ed. Bandeirantes, SCS Q. 17, Lote
2/5, Brasilia, Brazil</td>
			</tr>
<tr><td>British Honduras</td><td>American Consulate, Belize City, British Honduras</td><td>Gabourel Lane and Hutson St., Belize
City, Belize
				</td></tr>
<tr><td>Bolivia</td><td>USAID to Bolivia, c/o American Embassy, La Paz, Boliva</td><td>363 Almirante Grau St., La Paz, Bolivia
					</td></tr>
<tr><td>Chad</td><td>Country Development Officer, c/o American Embassy, N'Djamena, Chad</td><td>Rue du Lt. Col. Colonna d'Ornano,
N'Ljamena, Chad</td>
						</tr>
<tr><td>Cameroon</td><td>Area Development Office, c/o American Embassy, Yaounde, Cameroon</td><td>Rue Nachtigal, Yaounde, Cameroon</td>
							</tr>
<tr><td>Chile</td><td>USAID to Chile, c/o American Embassy, Santiago, Chile</td><td>Avenida B. O'Higgins No. 1146, Santiago, Chile</td>
								</tr>
<tr><td>Colombia</td><td>USAID to Colombia, c/o American Embassy, Bogota, Colombia</td><td>Carrera 10 Nr 28-49, Bogota,
Colombia</td></tr>
<tr><td>Costa Rica</td><td>Office of AID Affairs, c/o American Embassy, San Jose, Costa Rica</td><td>Avenida 3 Calle 1, San Jose,
Costa Rica</td></tr>
<tr><td>Dominican Republic</td><td>USAID to Domincan Republic, c/o American Embassy, Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic</td><td>
Calle Cesar Nicolas Pensen and Calle, Leopoldo Navarro, Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic</td></tr>
<tr><td>Ecuador</td><td>USAID to Ecuador, c/o American Embassy, Quito, Ecuador</td><td>120 Avenida Patria, Quito, Ecuado</td></tr>
<tr><td>Egypt</td><td>USAID, American Embassy, Cairo, Egypt</td><td>5 Sharia Latin America, Cairo, Egypt</td></tr>
<tr><td>El Salvador</td><td>USAID to El Salvador, c/o American Embassy, San Salvador, El Salvador</td><td>No. 1230, 25 Avenida
Norte, San Salvador, El Salvador</td></tr>
<tr><td>Ethiopia</td><td>USAID to Ethiopia, c/o American Embassy, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia</td><td>Crown Prince Asfaw Wossen St.,
Addis Ababa, Ethiopia</td></tr>
<tr><td>France</td><td>U.S. Mission to the OECD, c/o American Embassy, Paris, France</td><td>13 Villa Croix Nivert, Paris, France</td></tr>
<tr><td>Ghana</td><td>USAID, PO Box 1630, Accra, Ghana</td><td>Liberia and Rowe Roads, Accra, Ghana</td></tr>
<tr><td>Guatemala</td><td>USAID/ROCAP, c/o American Embassy, Guatemala City, Guatemala</td><td>USAID/ROCAP, 7-86, 8th St.,
Zone 9, Guatemala City, Guatemala</td></tr>
<tr><td>Guyana</td><td>USAID to Guyana, c/o American Embassy, Georgetown, Guyana</td><td>65 Main St., Georgetown, Guyana</td></tr>
<tr><td>Haiti</td><td>Office of AID Representative, American Embassy, Port au Prince, Haiti</td><td>American Embassy, Harry Truman
Blvd., Port au Prince, Haiti</td></tr>
<tr><td>Honduras</td><td>USAID to Honduras, c/o American Embassy, Tegucigalpa, Honduras</td><td>Avenida La Paz, Tegucigalpa,
Honduras</td></tr>
<tr><td>Iceland</td><td>American Embassy, Reykjavik, Iceland</td><td>Laufasvegur 21, Reykjavik, Iceland</td></tr>
<tr><td>India</td><td>USAID to India, c/o American Embassy, New Delhi, India 11</td><td>Shanti Path, Chanakyapuri 21, New Delhi,
India</td></tr>
<tr><td>Indonesia</td><td>USAID to Indonesia, c/o American Embassy, Jakarta, Indonesia</td><td>Medan Merdeka, Selatan 5, Jakarta,
Indonesia</td></tr>
<tr><td>Italy</td><td>American Embassy, Rome, Italy</td><td>Via Veneto 119, Rome, Italy</td></tr>
<tr><td>Ivory Coast</td><td>Regional Economic Development Services Offices/West Africa, c/o American Embassy, Abidjan, Ivory
Coast</td><td>5, Rue Jesse Owens, Abidjan, Ivory Coast</td></tr>
<tr><td>Jamaica</td><td>Office of AID Affairs, c/o American Embassy, Kingston, Jamaica</td><td>American Embassy, 43 Duke St.,
Kingston, Jamaica</td></tr>
<tr><td>Jordan</td><td>American Embassy, Amman, Jordan</td><td>Jebel Amman, Amman, Jordan</td></tr>
<tr><td>Kenya</td><td>USAID to Kenya, PO Box 30261, Nairobi, Kenya</td><td>Cotts House, Eliot St., Nairobi, Kenya</td></tr>
<tr><td>Korea</td><td>USAID to Korea, c/o American Embassy, Seoul, Korea</td><td>New Seoul Bldg. 1503 62-7, 2-KA,
Chungmu-Ro; Chung-Ku, Seoul, Korea</td></tr>
<tr><td>Lebanon</td><td>AID Regional Training Office, c/o American Embassy, Beirut, Lebanon</td><td>Corniche at Rue Aiv Mreisseh,
Beirut, Lebanon</td></tr>
<tr><td>Liberia</td><td>USAID, PO Box 1445, Monrovia, Liberia</td><td>United Nations Dr., Monrovia, Liberia</td></tr>
<tr><td>Mali</td><td>Country Development Officer, c/o American Embassy, Bamako, Mali</td><td>Rue Testard and Rue Mohamed V. Bamako,
Mali</td></tr>
<tr><td>Mauritania</td><td>Country Development Officer, c/o American Embassy, Nouakchott, Mauritania</td><td>American Embassy,
Nouakchott, Mauritania</td></tr>
<tr><td>Mexico</td><td>Office of AID Affairs, c/o American Embassy, Mexico D.F. Mexico</td><td>Cor. Danubio and Paseo de la
Reforma, 305, Colonia Cuauhtemoc, Mexico D.F. Mexico</td></tr>
<tr><td>Morocco</td><td>USAID to Morocco, c/o American Embassy, Rabat, Morocco</td><td>2 Ave. de Marrakech, Rabat, Morocco</td></tr>
<tr><td>Nepal</td><td>USAID to Nepal, c/o American Embassy, Kathmandu, Nepal</td><td>Rabi Bhawan, Kathmandu, Nepal</td></tr>
<tr><td>Nicaragua</td><td>USAID to Nicaragua, c/o American Embassy, Managua, Nicaragua</td><td>Boulevard Somoza, Managua,
Nicaragua</td></tr>
<tr><td>Niger</td><td>Area Development Office, c/o American Embassy, Niamey, Niger</td><td>Yantala Road, Niamey, Niger</td></tr>
<tr><td>Nigeria</td><td>USAID to Nigeria, c/o American Embassy, Lagos, Nigeria</td><td>1/3 Moloney St., Lagos, Nigeria</td></tr>
<tr><td>Parkistan</td><td>USAID, PO Box 1208, Islamabad, Pakistan</td><td>Diplomatic Enclave, Ramna 4, Islamabad, Pakistan</td></tr>
<tr><td>Panama</td><td>USAID to Panama, c/o American Embassy, Panama City, Panama</td><td>USAID Main Bldg., Cemento Panama Bldg.,
Manuel Espinosa Batista, Panama City, Panama</td></tr>
<tr><td>Paraguay</td><td>USAID to Paraguay, c/o American Embassy, Asuncion, Paraguay</td><td>390 Kubitschek, Asuncion, Paraguay</td></tr>
<tr><td>Peru</td><td>USAID to Peru, c/o American Embassy, Lima, Peru</td><td>Av. Espana 386, Lima, Peru</td></tr>
<tr><td>Philippines</td><td>USAID to the Republic of the Philippines, c/o American Embassy, Manila, Philippines</td><td>1680 Roxas
Blvd., Manila, Philippines</td></tr>
<tr><td>Portugal</td><td>American Embassy, Lisbon, APO New York 09678</td><td>Avenida Duque de Loule No. 39, Lisbon, Portugal</td></tr>
<tr><td>Puerto Rico</td><td>c/o Assistant Secretary, International Exchange, Department of State, Commonwealth of Puerto Rico,
San Juan, Puerto Rico</td><td>OTC, San Juan, Puerto Rico</td></tr>
<tr><td>Senegal</td><td>Area Development Office, c/o American Embassy, Dakar, Senegal</td><td>BIAO Building, Place de
I'Independance, Dakar, Senegal</td></tr>
<tr><td>Sri Lanka</td><td>Office of AID Representative c/o American Embassy, Colombo, Sri Lanka</td><td>44 Galle Road, Colpetty,
Colombo, Sri Lanka</td></tr>
<tr><td>Sudan</td><td>AID Affairs Office, c/o Embassy of the Netherlands, Khartoum, Sudan</td><td>Gambouria Ave., Khartoum, Sudan</td></tr>
<tr><td>Swaziland</td><td>Office of Southern African Regional Activities, Coordination/Mbabane, c/o American Embassy, Mbabane,
Swaziland</td><td>OSA RAC-Hdqts., 218 Gilifilan St., Mbabane, Swaziland</td></tr>
<tr><td>Switzerland</td><td>U.S. Mission to International Organization, c/o Amemb, Geneva, Switzerland</td><td>80 Rue de Lausanne,
Geneva, Switzerland</td></tr>
<tr><td>Syria</td><td>Office of AID Representative, c/o American Embassy, Damascus, Syria Arab Republic</td><td>Chare (Ave.) Al-
Mansour, Abu, Rummanih, Damascus, Syria</td></tr>
<tr><td>Taiwan</td><td>Office of AID Affairs, c/o American Embassy, Taipei, Taiwan</td><td>No. 2 Chung Hsiao West Road, Second
Sectiori, Taipei, Taiwan</td></tr>
<tr><td>Tanzania</td><td>USAID to the United Republic of Tanzania, c/o American Embassy, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania</td><td>National
Bank of Commerce Bldg. on City Drive, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania</td></tr>
<tr><td>Thailand</td><td>USOM, c/o American Embassy, Bangkok, Thailand</td><td>95 Wireless Road, Bangkok, Thailand</td></tr>
<tr><td>Togo</td><td>Area Development Officer, c/o American Embassy, Niamey, Niger</td><td>Rue Pelletier Caventor and rue Vauban,
Lome, Togo</td></tr>
<tr><td>Tunisia</td><td>USAID to Tunisia, c/o American Embassy, Tunis, Tunisia</td><td>149 Aveneue de la Liberte, Tunis, Tunisia</td></tr>
<tr><td>Turkey</td><td>USAID, PK 39, Cankaya, Ankara, Turkey</td><td>Cinnah Caddesi, No. 16, Ankara, Turkey</td></tr>
<tr><td>Upper Volta</td><td>AID Country Development Officer, c/o American Embassy, Ouagadougou, Upper Volta</td><td>Boite Postale
35, Ouagadougou, Upper Volta</td></tr>
<tr><td>Uruguay</td><td>Office of AID, Representative/Montevideo, c/o American Embassy, Montevideo, Uruguay</td><td>Lauro Muller
1776, Montevideo, Uruguay</td></tr>
<tr><td>Yemen</td><td>Office of AID Affairs, c/o American Embassy, Sana, Yemen</td><td>American Embassy, Sana, Yemen Arab Republic</td></tr>
<tr><td>Zaire</td><td>USAID to Republic of Zaire, c/o American Embassy, Kinshasa, Republic of Zaire</td><td>310 Ave. des Aviateurs,
Kinshasa, Zaire</td></tr></table>

	
</xhtmlContent></appendix>


<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="22">
<heading> Foreign Relations </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="II">
<heading>Agency for International Development </heading>
<regulationsPart number="215">
<heading>REGULATIONS FOR IMPLEMENTATION OF PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>215.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>215.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>215.3 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a system of records.
</p>
<p>215.4 Times, places, and requirements for indentification of individuals making requests.
</p>
<p>215.5 Access to requested information by individuals.
</p>
<p>215.6 Special procedures: Medical records.
</p>
<p>215.7 Request for correction or amendment of record.
</p>
<p>215.8 Agency review of request for amendment of record.
</p>
<p>215.9 Appeal of initial adverse agency determination.
</p>
<p>215.10 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</p>
<p>215.11 Fees.
</p>
<p>215.12 Penalties and remedies.
</p>
<p>215.13 General exemptions.
</p>
<p>215.14 Specific exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Public Law 93-579, 88 Stat. 1896 (5 U.S.C. 553, (b), (c), and (e))
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 57 FR 38277, Aug. 24, 1992, unless otherwise noted
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.1
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>(a) It is the purpose and objective of the International Development Cooperation Agency and the Agency for
International Development to collect information, revise personal data collection forms or processes, and maintain Agency
records in a manner that will prevent an unwarranted invasion of privacy of those individuals who are the subject of
Agency records.
</p>
<p>(b) These regulations establish the procedures by which an individual may obtain notification of the existence of
Agency records pertaining to that individual, gain access to those records, request an amendment or correction to the
records, and appeal adverse decisions to requests for amendment or correction of Agency records.
</p>
<p>(c) The Agency separately states and publishes in the <i>Federal Register</i> a public notice of the existence and
character of systems maintained by the Agency, pursuant to the provisions of sections (e)(4) and (e)(11) of the Privacy
Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a; 88 Stat. 1896)
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Act</i> means the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a; 88 Stat. 1896);
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Agency</i> means the International Development Cooperation Agency or the Agency for International Development,
its offices, bureaus, divisions, and posts abroad;
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Amend</i> shall include the amendment of a record;
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use or disseminate;
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by an
agency, including, but not limited to, his education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment
history and that contains his name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the
individual, such as a finger or voice print or a photograph;
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which
is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting
purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual, except as
provided by section 8 of title 13;
</p>
<p>(i) <i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of any agency from which information is
retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned
to the individual.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.3
 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a system of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Requests for notification of access to or amendment of Agency records contained in a system of records
pertaining to an individual may be made in person or by mail as follows: For the International Development Cooperation
Agency-Assistant Director for Administration, International Development Cooperation Agency, Room 4889 New State, 2201 C
Street, NW., Washington, DC 20523 Attention: Privacy Liaison Officer. For the Agency for International Development-
Privacy Liaison Officer, Agency for International Development, Room 4889 New State, 2201 C Street, NW., Washington, DC
20523.
</p>
<p>(b) Such request should include information necessary to identify the record, e.g., the individual's full name, date
of birth, place of birth, present mailing address, or system of record identification name and number, if known, and, to
facilitate the retrieval of records contained in those systems of records which are retrieved by social security numbers,
the social security number of the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>(c) With respect to a system of records which may be maintained by the Agency in offices outside the United States, an
individual may inquire whether he or she is the subject of an Agency record or may request access to or amendment of such
records by appearing in person or by writing to the Privacy Liaison Officer, Agency for International Development, at the
overseas missions.
</p>
<p>(d) The Assistant Director for Administration for requests to I.D.C.A. or the appropriate Privacy Liaison Officer for
request to A.I.D., or their designees shall, within ten (10) working days of receipt of the request, furnish in writing
to the requesting individual notice of the existence or nonexistence of any records described in the request.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.4
 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Individuals making personal requests for notification, access or contest may do so at the place designated in
paragraph (a) of &#167; 215.3, which is open 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. daily, except Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public
holidays.
</p>
<p>(b) Individuals making personal requests for notification, access or contest at offices outside the United States may
do so at the overseas missions during the regular business hours of those offices.
</p>
<p>(c) An individual requesting such information in person shall provide such personal identification as is reasonable
under the circumstances to verify the individual's identity; e.g. driver's license, employee identification card or
medicare card. (The identification should contain a photograph of the individual.)
</p>
<p>(d) An individual requesting such information by mail shall include in his or her request a signed notarized statement
to verify his or her identity and which stipulates that the individual understands that knowingly or willfully seeking or
obtaining access to records about another individual under false pretenses is punishable by a fine up to $5,000, as
provided in section (i)(3) of the Act.
</p>
<p>(e) Verification of identity as set forth in paragraphs (c) and (d) of this section shall not be required of
individuals seeking access to records otherwise available to members of the public under the Freedom of Information Act
(5 U.S.C. 552; 88 Stat. 1561).
</p>
<p>(f) An individual who wishes to be accompanied by another person when reviewing a record shall furnish the Agency with
a written statement authorizing discussion of his or her record in the presence of the accompanying person. Such
statement need not contain any reasons for the access or for the accompanying person's presence.</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.5
 Access to requested information by individuals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Upon receipt of a request by an individual made in accordance with the provisions of &#167; 215.3, such
individual shall be granted access to any record pertaining to him or her which is contained in a system of records
maintained by the Agency subject to exemptions discussed in &#167;&#167; 215.13 and 215.14.
</p>
<p>(b) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (a) of this section, access will not be allowed an individual to
information or records compiled by the Agency in reasonable anticipation of a civil or criminal action or proceeding.
</p>
<p>(c) Whenever possible, access to requested records will be granted;
</p>
<p>(1) Where the request is presented in person and the record is readily available, promptly upon receipt of the request
for access, determination that access to the record may be granted, verification of the identity of the individual
seeking access, and, where applicable, receipt of consent to discuss the record with a person accompanying the
individual;
</p>
<p>(2) Where the request is made by mail, the record will, whenever possible, be provided within ten (10) working days of
receipt of the request.
</p>
<p>(d) Where access to a record cannot reasonably be granted as provided in paragraphs (c)(1) and (2) of this section,
the Agency will acknowledge in writing receipt of the request for access and indicate a reasonable time within which
access to the record can be granted.
</p>
<p>(e) Where no reasonable means exist for an individual to have access to his or her record in person, a copy of the
record must be provided through the mail.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.6
 Special procedures: Medical records.
</b></p>
<p>If the Assistant Director for Administration or the Privacy Liaison Officer, determines that the release directly
to the individual of medical records maintained by the Agency could have an adverse effect upon such individual, the
Director/Officer will attempt to arrange an alternative acceptable to both the individual and Agency (such as the release
of said information to a doctor named by the individual) in granting access to such record.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.7
 Request for correction or amendment of record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) An individual may request the Agency to correct or amend a record pertaining to him or her which the
individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely or complete.
</p>
<p>(b) Such request must be in writing and must be presented, in person or by mail to the addresses listed in
&#167; 215.3(a).
</p>
<p>(c) Such requests must set forth the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) Identification of the system of records in which the particular record is maintained;
</p>
<p>(2) The portion(s) of the record to be amended or corrected;
</p>
<p>(3) The desired amendment or correction; and
</p>
<p>(4) The reasons for the amendment or correction.
</p>
<p>The request must be accompanied by evidence, documentation, or other information in support of the request.
</p>
<p>(d) Assistance in preparing a request to amend a record may be obtained from the officials listed in &#167; 
215.3(a).
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.8
 Agency review of request for amendment of record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Agency will examine the information requested to be amended to determine its accuracy, timeliness,
completeness, and its relevancy and necessity to accomplish a purpose of the Agency required to be accomplished by
statute or by executive order.
</p>
<p>(b) Within ten (10) working days after the receipt by the Assistant Director for Administration or the Privacy Liaison
Officer, of a request made in accordance with this section, the Assistant Director for Administration or the Privacy
Liaison Officer shall acknowledge in writing such receipt and shall, after examination in accordance with the provisions
of paragraph (a) of this section, promptly either:
</p>
<p>(1) Make any amendment of any portion thereof which the individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely or
complete, and notify the individual of the amendment made; or
</p>
<p>(2) Inform the individual of the Agency's refusal to amend the record in accordance with the request, the reason(s)
for the refusal, and the procedures established by the Agency for the individual to request a review of that refusal.
</p>
<p>(c) If the Agency agrees with the individual's request to amend a record, in addition to proceeding as set forth in
paragraph (b)(1) of this section, it shall promptly advise all previous recipients of the record of the fact that the
amendment was made and the substance of the amendment where an accounting of disclosures has been made.
</p>
<p>(d) If unusual circumstances prevent the completion of Agency action on the request to amend within 30 days after the
receipt thereof by the Assistant Director for Administration or the Privacy Liaison Officer, the individual will be
promptly advised of the delay, the reasons for the delay, and of the date by which the review is expected to be
completed.
</p>
<p>(e) If the Agency, after its initial examination of the record and the request for Amendment, disagrees with all or
any part of the individual's request to amend it shall:
</p>
<p>(1) To the extent the Agency agrees with any part of the individual's request to amend, proceed as described in
paragraphs (b)(1) and (c) of this section;
</p>
<p>(2) Advise the individual of its refusal and the reason(s) therefor;
</p>
<p>(3) Inform the individual that he or she may request a further review by the Director or the Administrator, or their
designees; and
</p>
<p>(4) Describe the procedures for requesting such review, including the name and address of the official to whom the
request should be directed.
</p>
<p>(f) No part of these regulations shall be construed to permit:
</p>
<p>(1) The alteration of evidence presented in the course of judicial, quasi-judicial or quasi-legislative proceedings;
</p>
<p>(2) Collateral attack upon any matter which has been the subject of judicial or quasi-judicial action; or
</p>
<p>(3) An amendment or correction which would be in violation of an existing statute, executive order or regulation.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.9
 Appeal of initial adverse agency determination.
</b></p>
<p>(a) An individual who disagrees with the denial or partial denial of his or her request to amend a record may
file a request for review of such refusal within 60 days after the date of notification of the denial or partial denial.
</p>
<p>(b) The request for review must be in writing and may be presented in person or by mail to:
</p>
<p>Director, International Development Cooperation Agency, 2201 C Street, NW., Washington, DC 20523. Attention: Privacy
Review Request.
</p>
<p>Director, Office of External Affairs, Agency for International Development, 2201 C Street, NW., Washington, DC 20523.
Attention: Privacy Review Request</p>
<p>Both the envelope and the letter should be clearly marked: Attention: Privacy Review Request. Such request should
include any documentation, information or statements advanced for the amendment of the record, and a copy of the initial
adverse determination.
</p>
<p>(c) Upon receipt of the request for review, the Director or the Assistant Administrator, or an officer of the Agency
designated in writing by the Director or Administrator, shall undertake an independent review of the initial
determination.
</p>
<p>(d) If someone other than the Director or the Assistant Administrator is designated to conduct the review, he or she
shall be an officer who is organizationally independent of or senior to the officer or employee who made the initial
determination.
</p>
<p>(e) In conducting the review, the reviewing official, may at his or her option, request such additional information as
is deemed necessary to establish that the record contains only that information which is accurate, timely, complete and
necessary to assure fairness in any determination which may be made about the individual on the basis of the record.
</p>
<p>(f) Within 30 days after receipt of the request for review, the Director, the Assistant Administrator, or the official
designated to conduct the review, shall advise the individual of the Agency's final decision. If unusual circumstances
prevent the completion of the review within the 30-day period, the Agency shall, prior to the expiration of the 30-day
period, advise the individual in writing of the circumstances preventing the completion of such review and inform him or
her of the date by which the review is expected to be completed.
</p>
<p>(g) If the reviewing official determines that the record should be amended in accordance with the individual's
request, the Agency shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Amend the record accordingly;
</p>
<p>(2) Advise the individual of the amendment; and
</p>
<p>(3) Where an accounting of disclosures has been made, advise all previous recipients of the fact that the amendment
was made and the nature of the amendment.
</p>
<p>(h) If, after conducting the review, the reviewing official refuses to amend the record, in whole or in part, in
accordance with the individual's request, Agency shall advise the individual:
</p>
<p>(1) Of its refusal and the reasons therefor;
</p>
<p>(2) Of the individual's right to file a concise statement of his or her reasons for disagreeing with the Agency's
decision;
</p>
<p>(3) Of the procedures for filing a statement of disagreement;
</p>
<p>(4) That any such statement will be sent to anyone to whom the record is subsequently disclosed, together with a brief
statement by the Agency summarizing its reasons for refusing to amend the record;
</p>
<p>(5) That to the extent an accounting of disclose was maintained, prior recipients of the disputed record will be
provided a copy of any statement of disagreement and of the Agency's statement summarizing its reasons for refusing to
amend the record; and
</p>
<p>(6) Of the individual's right to seek judicial review of the Agency's refusal to amend a record as provided for in
section (g)(1)(a) of the Act.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.10
 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Subject to the conditions of paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section, the Agency shall not disclose any record
which is contained in a system of records by any means of communication to any person or other agency who is not the
individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>(b) Upon written request or with prior written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains, the Agency may
disclose any such record to a person or to another agency as requested or authorized.
</p>
<p>(c) Notwithstanding the absence of written consent from the individual to whom the record pertains, the Agency may
disclose any such record provided such disclosure is:
</p>
<p>(1) To those officers and employees of the Agency who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties;
</p>
<p>(2) Required under the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552);
</p>
<p>(3) For a routine use as defined in &#167; 215.2;
</p>
<p>(4) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity
pursuant to the provisions of title 13 of the United States Code;
</p>
<p>(5) To a recipient who has provided the Agency with adequate advance written assurance that the record will be used
solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred in a form that is not
individually identifiable;
</p>
<p>(6) To the National Archives of the United States as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to
warrant its continued preservation by the United States Government, or for evaluation by the Administrator of General
Services or his or her designee, to determine whether the record has such value;
</p>
<p>(7) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the
United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity authorized by law: Provided, The head of the agency or
instrumentality has made a prior written request to the Assistant Administrator of Administration or the Privacy Liaison
Officer, specifying the particular record and the law enforcement activity for which it is sought;
</p>
<p>(8) To a responsible person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an
individual if upon such disclosure notification will be transmitted to the last known address of such individual;
</p>
<p>(9) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of a matter within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee,
or joint committee of Congress, or subcommittee of such joint committee;
</p>
<p>(10) To the Comptroller General, or any of his/her authorized representatives, in the course of the performance of the
duties of the General Accounting Office;
</p>
<p>(11) Pursuant to an order of a court of competent jurisdiction or;
</p>
<p>(12) To a consumer reporting agency in accordance with section 3711(f) of title 31.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.11
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The only fees to be charged to or collected from an individual under the provisions of this part are for
copying records at the request of the individual.
</p>
<p>(b) No fees shall be charged or collected for the following: Search for and retrieval of the records; review of the
records; copying at the initiative of the Agency without a request from the individual; the first 100 pages; and first-
class postage. However if special handling or other than first-class mail is requested or required, the costs shall be
added to the basic fee.
</p>
<p>(c) The copying fees prescribed in paragraph (a) of this section are:
</p>
<p>Ten (10) cents per page. Twenty (20) cents per page of computer printout</p>
<p>(d) Payment may be in the form of a check, bank draft on a bank in the United States, or postal money order payable to
the Treasurer of the United States.
</p>
<p>(e) A receipt for fees paid will be given only upon request.
</p>
<p>(f) A copying fee totaling $15.00 or less shall be waived but the copying fees for contemporaneous requests by the
same individual shall be aggregated to determine the total fee.
</p>
<p>(g) A fee may be reduced or waived by the Privacy Liaison Officer.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.12
 Penalties and remedies.
</b></p>
<p>The provisions of the Act relating to penalties and remedies are summarized below:
</p>
<p>(a) An individual may bring a civil action against the Agency when the Agency:
</p>
<p>(1) Makes a determination not to amend a record in accordance with the individual's request;
</p>
<p>(2) Refuses to comply with an individual's request pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (d)(1);
</p>
<p>(3) Fails to maintain a record concerning an individual with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness and completeness as
is necessary to assure fairness in any determination relating to the qualifications, character, rights, or opportunities
of, or benefits to the individual that may be made on the basis of such record, and as a result thereof a determination
is made which is adverse to the individual; or
</p>
<p>(4) Fails to comply with any other provision of section (d) of the Act in such a way as to have an adverse effect on
an individual.
</p>
<p>(b) The court may order the correction or amendment of the records, may enjoin the Agency from withholding the
records, may order the Agency to produce any records improperly withheld, and may assess attorney's fees and costs.
</p>
<p>(c) Where a court of competent jurisdiction makes a determination that the Agency action was willful or intentional
with respect to 5 U.S.C. 552a (g)(1) (c) or (d), the United States shall be liable for actual damages of no less than
$1,000, the costs of the action, and attorneys' fees.
</p>
<p>(d) Criminal penalties may be imposed against an officer or employee of the Agency who willfully discloses material
which he or she knows is prohibited from disclosure, or who maintains a system of records without complying with the
notice requirements.
</p>
<p>(e) Criminal penalties may be imposed against any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record
concerning an individual from an agency under false pretenses. The offenses enumerated in paragraphs (d) and (e) of this
section are misdemeanors, with fines not to exceed $5,000.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.13
 General exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2), the Director or the Administrator may, where there is a compelling reason
to do so, exempt a system of records within the Agency from any part of the Act, except subsections (b), (c) (1) and (2),
(e)(4)(A) through (F), (e) (6), (7), (9), (10), and (11), and (i) thereof, if the system of records is maintained by the
Agency or component thereof which performs as its principal function any activity pertaining to the enforcement of
criminal laws, including police efforts to prevent, control, or reduce crime or to apprehend criminals, and the
activities of prosecutors, courts, correctional, probation, pardon, or parole authorities, and which consists of:
</p>
<p>(1) Information compiled for the purpose of identifying individual criminal offenders and alleged offenders and
consisting only of identifying data and notations of arrests, the nature and disposition of criminal charges, sentencing,
confinement, release, and parole and probation status;
</p>
<p>(2) Information compiled for the purpose of a criminal investigation, including reports of informants and
investigators, and associated with an identifiable individual; or
</p>
<p>(3) Reports identifiable to an individual compiled at any stage of the process of enforcement of the criminal laws
from arrest or indictment through release from supervision.
</p>
<p>(b) Each notice of a system of records that is the subject of an exemption under this section will include a statement
that the system has been exempted, the reasons therefore, and a reference to the <i>Federal Register,</i> volume and
page, where the exemption rule can be found.
</p>
<p>(c) The systems of records to be exempted under section (j)(2) of the Act, the provisions of the Act from which they
are being exempted, and the justification for the exemptions, are set forth below:
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Criminal Law Enforcement Records.</i> This system of records is to be exempted from sections (c) (3) and (4);
(d); (e) (1), (2), and (3); (e) (4) (G), (H), and (I); (e) (5) and (8); (f), (g) and (h) of the Act. These exemptions are
necessary to insure the proper functioning of the law enforcement activity, to protect confidential sources of
information, to fulfill promises of confidentiality, to maintain the integrity of the law enforcement procedures, to
avoid premature disclosure of the knowledge of criminal activity and the evidentiary bases of possible enforcement
actions, to prevent interference with law enforcement proceeding, to avoid the disclosure of investigative techniques,
and to avoid the endangering the law enforcement personnel.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Partner Vetting System.</i> This system is exempt from sections (c)(3) and (4); (d); (e)(1), (2), and (3); (e)
(4)(G), (H), and (I); (e)(5) and (8); (f), (g), and (h) of 5 U.S.C. 552a. These exemptions are necessary to insure the
proper functioning of the law enforcement activity, to protect confidential sources of information, to fulfill promises
of confidentiality, to maintain the integrity of law enforcement procedures, to avoid premature disclosure of the
knowledge of criminal activity and the evidentiary basis of possible enforcement actions, to prevent interference with
law enforcement proceeding, to avoid the disclosure of investigative techniques, to avoid endangering law enforcement
personnel, to maintain the ability to obtain candid and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to
protect the confidentiality of information, to avoid endangering these sources, and to facilitate proper selection or
continuance of the best applicants or persons for a given position or contract. Although the primary functions of USAID
are not of a law enforcement nature, the mandate to ensure USAID funding is not purposefully or inadvertently used to
provide support to entities or individuals deemed to be a risk to national security necessarily requires coordination
with law enforcement and intelligence agencies as well as use of their information. Use of these agencies' information
necessitates the conveyance of these other systems exemptions to protect the information as stated.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 38277, Aug. 24, 1992, as amended at 74 FR 16, Jan. 2, 2009]

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 215.14
 Specific exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k), the Director or the Administrator may, where there is a compelling reason to do
so, exempt a system of records, from any of the provisions of subsections (c) (3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4) (G), (H), and (I);
and (f) of the Act if a system of records is:
</p>
<p>(1) Subject to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(1);
</p>
<p>(2) Investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of subsection
(j)(2) of the Act: Provided, however, That if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit to which he or
she would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, such material shall be provided to such
individual, except to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished
information to the Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or
prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in
confidence;
</p>
<p>(3) Maintained in connection with providing protective services to the President of the United States or other
individuals pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 3056;
</p>
<p>(4) Required by statute to be maintained and used solely as statistical records;
</p>
<p>(5) Investigatory material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications
for Federal civilian employment, military service, Federal contracts, or access to classified information, but only to
the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the
Government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or, prior to the
effective date of this section, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence;
</p>
<p>(6) Testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in
the Federal service, the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination
process; or
</p>
<p>(7) Evaluation material used to determine potential for promotion in the armed services, but only to the extent that
the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government under
an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence, or, prior to the effective date of this
section, under an implied promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.
</p>
<p>(b) Each notice of a system of records that is the subject of an exemption under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k) will include a
statement that the system has been exempted, the reasons therefore, and a reference to the <i>Federal Register,</i>
volume and page, where the exemption rule can be found.
</p>
<p>(c) The systems of records to be exempted under section (k) of the Act, the provisions of the Act from which they are
being exempted, and the justification for the exemptions, are set forth below:
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Criminal Law Enforcement Records.</i> If the 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) exemption claimed under paragraph (c) of
&#167; 215.13 and on the notice of systems of records to be published in the <i>Federal Register</i> on this same
date is held to be invalid, then this system is determined to be exempt, under 5 U.S.C. 552(a)(k) (1) and (2) of the Act,
from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4); (G); (H); (I); and (f). The reasons for asserting the
exemptions are to protect the materials required by executive order to be kept secret in the interest of the national
defense or foreign policy, to prevent subjects of investigation from frustrating the investigatory process, to insure the
proper functioning and integrity of law enforcement activities, to prevent disclosure of investigative techniques, to
maintain the ability to obtain necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect their identities
and the confidentiality of information and to avoid endangering these sources and law enforcement personnel.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Personnel Security and Suitability Investigatory Records.</i> This system is exempt under U.S.C. 552a (k)(1),
(k)(2), and (k)(5) from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4); (G); (H); (I); and (f). These
exemptions are claimed to protect the materials required by executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national
defense or foreign policy, to prevent subjects of investigation from frustrating the investigatory process, to insure the
proper functioning and integrity of law enforcement activities, to prevent disclosure of investigative techniques, to
maintain the ability to obtain candid and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect the
confidentiality of information, to avoid endangering those sources and, ultimately, to facilitate proper selection or
continuance of the best applicants or persons for a given position or contract. Special note is made of the limitation on
the extent to which this exemption may be asserted.
</p>
<p>(3) <i>Litigation Records.</i> This system is exempt under 5 U.S.C. 552(k)(1), (k)(2), and (k)(5) from the provisions
of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4) (G), (H), (I); and (f). These exemptions are claimed to protect the
materials required by executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy, to prevent
subjects of investigation from frustrating the investigatory process, to insure the proper functioning and integrity of
law enforcement activities, to prevent disclosure of investigative techniques, to maintain the ability to obtain candid
and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect the confidentiality of information.
</p>
<p>(4) <i>Employee Equal Employment Opportunity Complaint Investigatory Records.</i> This system is exempt under 5 U.S.C.
552a (k)(1) and (k)(2) from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4) (G), (H), (I); and (f). These
exemptions are claimed to protect the materials required by executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national
defense or foreign policy, to prevent subjects of investigation from frustrating the investigatory process, to insure the
proper functioning and integrity of law enforcement activities, to prevent disclosure of investigative techniques, to
maintain the ability to obtain candid and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect the
confidentiality of information, to avoid endangering these sources.
</p>
<p>(5) The following systems of records are exempt under 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(5) from the provision of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3);
(d); (e)(1); (e)(4) (G), (H), (I); and (f):
</p>
<p>(i) Employee Conduct and Discipline Records.
</p>
<p>(ii) Employee Relations Records.
</p>
<p>Note to paragraph (c)(5):</p>
<p>This exemption is claimed for these systems of records to maintain the ability to obtain
candid and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect the confidentiality of information,
to avoid endangering these sources and, ultimately, to facilitate proper selection or continuance of the best applicants
or persons for a given position or contract. Special note is made of the limitation on the extent to which this exemption
may be asserted. The existence and general character of the information exempted will be made known to the individual to
whom it pertains</p>
<p>(6) <i>Partner Vetting System.</i> This system is exempt under 5 U.S.C. 552a (k)(1), (k)(2), and (k)(5) from the
provision of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3); (d); (e)(1); (e)(4)(G), (H), (I); and (f). These exemptions are claimed to protect the
materials required by executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy, to prevent
subjects of investigation from frustrating the investigatory process, to insure the proper functioning and integrity of
law enforcement activities, to prevent disclosure of investigative techniques, to maintain the ability to obtain candid
and necessary information, to fulfill commitments made to sources to protect the confidentiality of information, to avoid
endangering these sources, and to facilitate proper selection or continuance of the best applicants or persons for a
given position or contract.
</p>
<p>[57 FR 38277, Aug. 24, 1992, as amended at 74 FR 17, Jan. 2, 2009]</p>

</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>

<regulations id="reg2" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="22">
<heading> Foreign Relations </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XII">
<heading>International Development Cooperation Agency</heading>
<regulationsPart number="1202">
<heading>REGULATIONS TO IMPLEMENT THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>

<xhtmlContent>
	
<p><b>Authority:</b> Sec. 621, 22 U.S.C. 2381, as amended; 5 U.S.C. 552a.</p>
<p><b>Cross Reference:</b> The regulations establishing procedures by which an individual may obtain notification of the
existence of agency records pertaining to that individual, gain access to those records, request an amendment to those
records, and appeal adverse decisions to requests for amendment or correction of agency records are codified as 22 CFR
215.1 through 215.14, prescribed jointly by the United States International Development Cooperation Agency and the Agency
for International Development</p>
<p>[45 FR 20791, Mar. 31, 1980]
</p>


</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>



</agency>
</pai>


