<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>
<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Federal Maritime Commission</name>
<abbrev>FMC</abbrev>

    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-11-10/pdf/2020-24923.pdf</url>
        <title>FMC-40 SERVCON; rescinded</title>
        <date year="2020" month="11" day="10" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-10-26/pdf/2021-23000.pdf</url>
        <title>FMC-2 Non-Attorney Practitioner Files.</title>
        <date year="2021" month="10 " day="26" />
    </previouslyPublished>


    <section id="fmc1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security File.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 N. Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Employees of the Federal Maritime Commission. 2. Applicants for employment with the Federal Maritime Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Results of name checks, inquiries, and investigations to determine suitability for employment with the U.S. Government, and for access to classified information, position sensitivity designation, and record of security clearance issued, if any.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Orders 10450, 12958, and 12968.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The records in this system of records are used or may be used:
</p><p>1. By Commission officials to determine suitability for employment of an applicant or retention of a current employee and to make a determination that the employment of an applicant or retention of a current employee within the Commission is clearly consistent with the interests of national security.
</p><p>2. To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil or criminal or regulatory in nature, information to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>3. To request from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information, data relevant to a Commission decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee or the issuance of a security clearance.
</p><p>4. To provide or disclose information to a Federal agency in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on that matter.
</p><p>5. By a court of law or appropriate administrative board or hearing having review or oversight authority.
</p><p>6. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a combination safe in the custody of the Information Security Officer, and access is limited to the Information Security Officer and the Personnel Security Officer and his/her duly authorized representatives.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Maintain Office of Personnel Management reports of investigation and other FMC records on file until termination of employee from agency. Destroy within 30 days after employee leaves the agency.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Information Security Officer, Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Personnel Management report, and reports from other Federal agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>All information about individuals that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), regarding suitability, eligibility or qualifications for Federal civilian employment or for access to classified information, to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Commission under a promise of confidentiality is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is required to honor promises of confidentiality.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="fmc2" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>FMC-2</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            Non-Attorney Practitioner Files.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW, Washington, DC 20573-0001.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 N. Capitol Street NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001, Secretary@fmc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 46 CFR 502.27.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of the system is to maintain a relevant verification source of information on non-attorney practitioners who are registered to practice before the Commission. The Federal Maritime Commission administers the Non-Attorneys Practicing Before the Commission program, as authorized under 46 CFR 502.27, which allows any U.S. citizen who is not an attorney at law to conduct business with the FMC on behalf of a regulated industry client. Only non-attorneys must submit a completed form FMC-12 package to be considered for and granted admission to practice before the Commission.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals, who are not attorneys, who apply for and are granted permission to practice before the Commission.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Application forms containing descriptions of educational and professional experience and qualifications, and letters of reference related to non-attorney practitioners which may include the following:</p>
                •	<p>Residence address</p>
                •	<p>Citizenship status</p>
                •	<p>Date/place of birth</p>
                •	<p>Education</p>
                •	<p>Criminal Prosecutions</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Applicants.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, the records in this system of records are used or may be used:</p>
                1.	<p>To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil or criminal or regulatory in nature, information to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.</p>
                2.	<p>To request from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information, data relevant to a Commission decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit.</p>
                3.	<p>To provide or disclose information to a Federal agency in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on that matter.</p>
                4.	<p>To disclose information to the public when disclosures are made on the record in a judicial or administrative proceeding. To disclose relevant and necessary information to any component of the Department of Justice for the purpose of representing the FMC, its officers, employees, or members in pending or potential litigation to which the record is pertinent.</p>
                5.	<p>In an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body or official, when the FMC or other Agency representing the FMC determines the records are relevant and necessary to the proceeding to which the government is a party; or in an appropriate proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                6.	<p>To contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the federal government when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this System of Records.</p>
                7.	<p>To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the FMC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the FMC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the FMC (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the FMC’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                8.	<p>To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the FMC determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                •	<p>Physical records are maintained in file folders in a limited access location.</p>
                •	<p>Electronic records are maintained within the confines of the FMC General Support System (FMC GSS).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                •	<p>Physical records are indexed alphabetically by name.</p>
                •	<p>Electronic records are retrievable by name, address, company, application date, admission date, or card number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These files will be destroyed 30 years after the applicant no longer practices before the Federal Maritime Commission.</p>
                <p>https://www.archives.gov/files/records-mgmt/rcs/schedules/independent-agencies/rg-0358/daa-0358-2017-0007_sf115.pdf</p>
                <p>See Sequence 3, Non-Attorney Practitioner files, N1-358-09-7/2 Cut off at end of calendar year in which it is established that applicant no longer practices before the Commission.  Destroy 15 years after cut-off.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                •	<p>Access to physical records in this system are limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permission.</p>
                •	<p>Electronic files are safeguarded to meet multiple National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Security Standards with password and identification protections. File access is limited to individuals who have a need to know the information for performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permission.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in out in 46 CFR 503.65.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such a request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefore and shall meet the requirements set out in of 46 CFR 503.66.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Any individual shall be informed whether or not any Commission system of records contains a record pertaining to him or her when requested in accordance with the requirements of 46 CFR 503.63(a).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>78 FR 55703 - https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2013/09/11/2013-22072/privacy-act-of-1974-systems-of-records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <section id="fmc7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-7</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Licensed Ocean Transportation Intermediaries Files (Form FMC-18).
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Bureau of Certification and Licensing, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained on individuals, including sole proprietorships, members of partnerships, and officers and owners of corporate licensees, managers and owners of limited liability companies, ex-licensees, and applicants for licenses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The System contains ocean transportation intermediaries (OTIs) names, addresses and taxpayer identification numbers (which may be the Social Security Numbers), as well as the names, addresses, and Social Security Numbers (or alternatively, driver’s license numbers, passport numbers or alien registration numbers) of the stockholders, officers, and directors of individual OTIs; descriptions of the relationships the OTI may have with other business entities; corporate organizational documents and business licenses; a record of the OTI’s past experience in providing or procuring ocean transportation services; surety bond information with respect to licensed OTIs; and any financial information and/or criminal convictions pertinent to the licensing of the OTIs. Under the Shipping Act of 1984, as amended, OTIs may be either an ocean freight forwarder, a non-vessel-operating common carrier or both.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 553; secs. 3, 8, 10, 11, 13, 15, 17 and 19, Shipping Act of 1984 (recodified October 2006 as 46 U.S.C. 305, 40102, 40104, 40501-40503, 40901-40904, 41101-41109, 41302-41303, and 41305).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records and information contained in these records may be disclosed as follows:
</p><p>1. By Commission staff for evaluation of applicants for licensing.
</p><p>2. By Commission staff for monitoring the activities of licensees to ensure they are in compliance with Commission regulations.
</p><p>3. To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, information to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rules, regulations, or orders issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>4. To request from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement information, data relevant to a Commission decision concerning the issuance of a license.
</p><p>5. To provide or disclose information to a Federal agency in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee previously employed by a licensee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on that matter.
</p><p>6. To provide or update information maintained in the U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s (CBP) Automated Commercial Environment/International Trade Data System (ACE/ITDS) to verify licensed or registered status of OTIs under Trade Act of 2002 and related CBP requirements, or any other successor agency or organization.
</p><p>7. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in file folders and in a personal computer on-site at Commission headquarters.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by name and license or organization number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in an area of restricted accessibility.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Applicant and licensee files are kept as long as the application and/or license is active. Files for withdrawn and denied applicants, and revoked licenses remain in the Record Location Center ten years after final action. After ten years the files are destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Bureau of Certification and Licensing, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Request may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Information submitted by applicants and licensees.
</p><p>2. Information submitted by Commission Area Representatives.
</p><p>3. Information submitted by the general public (e.g., through complaints).
</p><p>4. Information submitted by surety companies.
</p><p>5. Information obtained through Internet Web site searches and selected commercial and government database searches conducted by Bureau of Certification and Licensing staff in processing OTI license applications (e.g., Choicepoint and Dun &amp; Bradstreet).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-8</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Official Personnel Folder--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>This system is covered by the Office of Personnel Management’s government-wide system notice, OPM/GOVT-1.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="fmc9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-9</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Training Program Records--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 N. Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>This system is covered by the Office of Personnel Management’s government-wide system notice, OPM/GOVT-1.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-10</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Desk Audit File--FMC.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of the Federal Maritime Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Each record consists of the position classification specialist’s notes of conversations, evaluation reports, background papers, and/or research material used to support the final position classification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>44 U.S.C. 3101 <i>et seq.</i>, 5 U.S.C. 1302 and the regulations issued pursuant thereto.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records is used or may be used:
</p><p>1. By Commission officials to support decisions on the proper classification of a position.
</p><p>2. To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil or criminal or regulatory in nature, information to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>3. To request from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information, data relevant to a Commission decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit.
</p><p>4. To provide or disclose information to a Federal agency in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on that matter.
</p><p>5. By the Office of Personnel Management in the course of an investigation, or evaluating for statistical or management analysis purposes.
</p><p>6. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in locked file cabinets.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained as long as the position audited remains essential, current, and accurate, after which they are destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such a request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Human Resources Specialists of the Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-14</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Medical Examination File--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>This system is covered by the Office of Personnel Management’s government-wide system notice, OPM/GOVT-10.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-16</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Classification Appeals File-FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p><b>Note:</b></p><p>This system is covered by the Office of Personnel Management’s government-wide system notice, OPM/GOVT-9.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-18</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Travel Orders/Vouchers File--FMC.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Financial Management, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees of the Federal Maritime Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The record consists of the initial travel order for the individual and the subsequent travel voucher prepared from information supplied by the individual which includes hotel bills, subsistence breakdown, cab fares and air fares.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Travel Regulation, 41 CFR parts 301-304.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system of records are used or may be used:
</p><p>1. By the Commission for the authorization of travel performed by personnel of the Commission.
</p><p>2. By the Commission to prepare travel vouchers for submission to the Bureau of Public Debt through E-Gov and to maintain internal control of travel expenses within this agency.
</p><p>3. To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil or criminal in nature, information to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>4. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by name or bureau.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a locking file cabinet and monitored by the Director of the Office of Financial Management.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are maintained for six years and are then destroyed by shredding (in accordance with General Records Schedule 9).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Financial Management, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such a request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual to whom the record pertains, hotel bills, individual’s subsistence record, and Travel Requests (airline or train).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-19</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Ethics Program Records.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the General Counsel, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p><b>Note:</b></p><p>This system is covered by the Office of Government Ethics’ government-wide systems notices, OGE/GOVT-1 and OGE/GOVT-2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>FMC-22</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Records Tracking System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Bureau of Enforcement, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 N. Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals whose names may be found in the system include employees, officers, directors, and owners of ocean common carriers, non-vessel operating common carriers, ocean freight forwarders, passenger vessel operators, ports and terminal operators, shippers, consignees, conferences and agreements between ocean common carriers, and other entities associated with any of the foregoing. Included are individuals alleged to have violated one of the statutes or regulations administered by the Federal Maritime Commission, individuals who provided information during an investigation, and others necessary to the full development of an investigation. Not included are attorneys, government officials, Federal Maritime Commission employees, or individuals only incidentally involved in an investigation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The Records Tracking System includes records on individuals involved in official investigations conducted by the Bureau of Enforcement, fact finding and formal proceedings instituted by the Federal Maritime Commission, court proceedings, and civil and criminal investigations conducted in association with other government agencies. Investigations include investigations of alleged violations of the statutes or regulations administered by the Commission, freight forwarder application inquiries, freight forwarder application checks, freight forwarder compliance checks, service contract audits, common carrier audits, passenger vessel audits, special inquiries, undeveloped leads, intelligence activities, and other matters authorized by the Bureau of Enforcement.
</p><p>The Records Tracking System includes all files and records of the Bureau, wherever located. The system also includes reports or other information from other government agencies, shipping and commercial records, investigative work product, notes of interviews, documents obtained from any source, schedules of data, investigative plans and directives, disclosures, settlement agreements, and any other records prepared in conjunction with a case including information which tends to explain, interpret, or substantiate any of the above. The system also includes indices of these records, tracking systems, and listings of information otherwise included within the system.
</p><p>The Records Tracking System contains information in electronic and paper media. Information within the system may be stored in files or data bases by specific subject or in general groupings. The information remains within the system through analysis, research, corroboration, field investigation, reporting, and referral within the Commission or to another government agency. Information remains within the system whether a case is open or closed or the matter becomes inactive. Information also remains within the system when records are retired to storage or are otherwise purged.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Shipping Act of 1984, Intercoastal Shipping Act, 1933, and Shipping Act, 1916 (46 U.S.C. app. 1701, 843, and 801).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. In the event that a system of records maintained by the FMC to carry out its functions indicates a violation or potential violation of law or contract, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a Federal, State or local agency maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to an FMC decision concerning the assignment, hiring or retention of an individual, the issuance of a security clearance, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit.
</p><p>3. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to a Federal, State, local or international agency, in response to its request, in connection with the assignment, hiring or retention of an individual, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an individual, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on the matter.
</p><p>4. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, in the course of presenting evidence to a court magistrate or administrative tribunal, including disclosures to opposing counsel in the course of settlement negotiations.
</p><p>5. A record in this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to either House of Congress, or to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of such joint committee.
</p><p>6. A record in this system of records may be disclosed, as a routine use, to the Department of Justice in connection with determining whether disclosure thereof is required by the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552).
</p><p>7. A record in this system may be transferred, as a routine use, to the Office of Personnel Management for personnel research purposes; as a data source for management information; for the production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the records are collected and maintained; or for related manpower studies.
</p><p>8. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in paper form in filing cabinets and in a Lektriever, Series 80. Statistical data taken from record forms are maintained in a personal computer.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Information filed by case of subject file. Records pertaining to individuals are accessed by reference to the Bureau of Enforcement’s name-relationship index system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in locked metal file cabinets or in metal file cabinets in secured rooms or secured premises with access limited to those whose official duties require access. The Lektriever files are locked with a key and the key is secured in a locked file cabinet. Computer information is safeguarded with an access code. Files are maintained in buildings that have 24 hour security guards.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained for 7 years after the end of the calendar year in which the case file actions are concluded; the records are destroyed 25 years after cutoff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Bureau of Enforcement, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such a request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual shippers, carriers, freight forwarders, those authorized by the individual to furnish information, trade sources, investigative agencies, investigative personnel of the Bureau of Enforcement and other sources of information.
</p><H4>Systems exempted from certain provisions of the Act:
</H4><p>All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc24" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-24</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Informal Inquiries and Complaints Files--FMC.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Informal Inquiries and Complaints, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Consumers complaining against business entities regulated by the Commission
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Copies of complaints and correspondence developed in their resolution complaint tracking logs; and complaint tracking electronic summary database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 12160, September 26, 1979.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records is used or may be used:
</p><p>1. To determine whether a complaint can be resolved by staff in various bureaus and offices.
</p><p>2. To determine whether a complaint can be resolved by a business entity regulated by the Commission.
</p><p>3. To determine whether the complaint can be resolved by reference to another agency at the Federal, State or local level.
</p><p>4. To provide information to the Commission on developments or trends in the character of complaints which might suggest policy directions, proposed rules or programs.
</p><p>5. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Physical records are maintained in file folders; the electronic database is maintained on the Commission’s local area network.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Physical and electronic records are serially numbered and indexed by complainant and respondents.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Physical records are maintained in locked file cabinets; access to electronic records is password protected.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained by the Federal Maritime Commission for four years and then destroyed. The electronic summary database is permanently maintained.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Informal Inquiries and Complaints, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Consumers who have filed complaints.
</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc25" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-25</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Inspector General File.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Inspector General, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals and entities who are or have been the subjects of investigations conducted by the OIG, including present and former FMC employees; consultants, contractors, and subcontractors and their employees; and other individuals and entities doing business with the FMC.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. <i>Investigative Case Files</i>
</p><p>1. <i>Case Index</i>
</p><p>Selected information from each case file indexed by case file number, and case title which may include names of subjects of investigations.
</p><p>2. <i>Hard Copy Files</i>
</p><p>Case files developed during investigations of known or alleged fraud and abuse and irregularities and violations of laws and regulations. Cases relate to agency personnel and programs and operations administered by the agency, including contractors and others having a relationship with the agency. Files consist of investigative reports and related documents, such as correspondence, internal staff memoranda, copies of all subpoenas issued during the investigation, affidavits, statements from witnesses, transcripts of testimony taken in the investigation and accompanying exhibits, notes, attachments, and working papers. Files containing information or allegations which are of an investigative nature but do not relate to a specific investigation.
</p><p>B. <i>Hotline Complaints</i>
</p><p>1. <i>Hotline Index</i>
</p><p>Selected information from each hotline complaint file indexed by hotline case number and title which may include names of subject of hotline complaint.
</p><p>2. <i>Hard Copy Files</i>
</p><p>Information obtained from hotline complainants reporting indications of waste, fraud, and mismanagement. Specific information to include name and address of complainant, date complaint received, program area, nature and subject of complaint, and any additional contacts and specific information provided by the complainant. Information on OIG disposition.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App. 3), as amended by Pub. L. 100-504; 44 U.S.C. 3101 <i>et seq.</i>; Commission Order No. 113.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The records maintained in the system are used by the OIG in furtherance of the responsibilities of the Inspector General, pursuant to the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, to conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to programs and operations of the FMC; to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in the administration of such programs and operations; and to prevent and detect fraud and abuse in such programs and operations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The records in the system may be used and disseminated to further the purposes described above. The following routine uses apply to the records maintained in this system:
</p><p>1. A record may be disclosed to an individual, or to a Federal, State, local, or international agency when necessary to further the ends of a legitimate investigation or audit.
</p><p>2. A record which indicates either by itself or in combination with other information within the agency’s possession, a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, or which indicates a violation or potential violation of a contract, may be disclosed to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local or international, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation, or of enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, or of enforcing the contract.
</p><p>3. A record may be disclosed to a Federal, State, local or international agency, in response to its request, in connection with the assignment, hiring, or retention of an individual, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an individual, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on the matter.
</p><p>4. A record may be disclosed to a Member of Congress who submits an inquiry on behalf of an individual, when the Member of Congress informs the FMC that the individual to whom the record pertains has authorized the Member of Congress to have access to the record. In such cases, the Member of Congress has no more right to the record than does the individual.
</p><p>5. A record may be disclosed to the Office of Government Ethics for any purpose consistent with that Office’s mission, including the compilation of statistical data.
</p><p>6. A record may be disclosed to the U.S. Department of Justice in order to obtain that Department’s advice regarding an agency’s disclosure obligation under the Freedom of Information Act.
</p><p>7. A record may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget in order to obtain that Office’s advice regarding an agency’s obligations under the Privacy Act.
</p><p>8. A record may be disclosed to a grand jury agent pursuant either to a federal or state grand jury subpoena or to a prosecution request that such record be released for the purpose of its introduction to a grand jury.
</p><p>9. A record may be disclosed to a "consumer reporting agency" as that term is defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act and the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 in accordance with section 3711(f) of 31 U.S.C. and for the purposes of obtaining information in the course of an investigation or audit.
</p><p>10. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>The investigative case index and the hotline case index are stored on a hard disk on a personal computer. The hard copy files are stored in file folders. All records are stored under secured conditions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the investigative and hotline case index are retrieved by case title which may include the name of the subject of an investigation and by case number. Records in the hard copy files are retrieved by case numbers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Direct access is limited to authorized staff of the OIG. Additional access within FMC is limited to authorized officials on a need-to-know basis. All records, when not in a possession of an authorized individual are stored in locked cabinets or a locked, standalone, personal computer in a locked room.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Files containing information or allegations which are of an investigative nature but do not relate to a specific investigation are retained for seven years.
</p><p>2. Other investigative case files are retained for ten years.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Inspector General, Office of The Inspector General, Federal Maritime Commission, Room 1072, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001. However, see Exemption section below.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations. However, see Exemption section below.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such a request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations. However, see Exemption section below.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Agency employees, reports and contracts from other agencies, and internal and external documents.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p><p>All information about individuals that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), regarding suitability, eligibility or qualifications for Federal civilian employment or for access to classified information, to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Commission under a promise of confidentiality is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is required to honor promises of confidentiality.
</p><p>All information meeting the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a, except subsections (b), (c)(1) and (2), (e)(4)(A) through (F), (e)(6), (7), (9), (10), and (11), and (i). Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc26" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Administrative Grievance File--FMC.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any employee of the Federal Maritime Commission, including any former employee for whom a remedy can be provided.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Administrative Grievance Files contain all documents related to a particular grievance, including but not limited to any statements of witnesses, records or copies thereof, the report of the hearing when one is held, statements made by the parties to the grievance, and the decision.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 1302, 3301, 3302, 7301, E.O. 9830, 3 CFR 1943-1948 Comp., pp. 606-624; E.O. 11222, 3 CFR 2964-2969 Comp., p. 306.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records is used or may be used:
</p><p>1. By Commission officials designated as grievance examiners for the purpose of adjudication, by the Director of EEO in the event of an investigation when the EEO complaint relates to the grievance, or for information concerning the outcome of the grievance.
</p><p>2. By the Office of Personnel Management in the course of an investigation of a particular employee of the Commission, for statistical analysis purposes, or for program compliance checks.
</p><p>3. By the Merit Systems Protection Board if necessitated by an appeal.
</p><p>4. By the appropriate District Court of the United States to render a decision when the Commission has refused to release a current or former employee’s record under the Freedom of Information Act.
</p><p>5. To refer, where there is an indication of a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, information to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, or local, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rules, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>6. To request from a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information, data relevant to a Commission decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee.
</p><p>7. To provide or disclose information to a Federal agency in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on that matter.
</p><p>8. By the employee or his/her designated representative in order to gather or provide information necessary to process the grievance.
</p><p>9. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored in locked file cabinets.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with General Records Schedule 1, the Administrative Grievance File is destroyed 4 years after case is closed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is supplied by the individual to whom the record pertains and/or by his or her representative, human resource specialists, grievance examiners, and any parties providing information bearing directly on the grievance.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p><p>All information about individuals that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), regarding suitability, eligibility or qualifications for Federal civilian employment or for access to classified information, to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Commission under a promise of confidentiality is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is required to honor promises of confidentiality.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc28" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-28</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Equal Employment Opportunity Complaint Files--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of General Counsel, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 N. Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>Note:</p><p>This system of records is covered by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission’s Government-wide system notice, EEOC/GOVT-1.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc29" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-29</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Employee Performance File System Records--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>This system of records is covered by the Office of Personnel Management’s Government-wide system notice, OPM/GOVT-2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc31" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-31</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Debt Collection Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are located in the Office of Financial Management, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who are indebted to FMC.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The Debt Collection Officer’s file will contain copies of debt collection letters, bills for collection, and correspondence to and from the debtor relating to the debt. The file will include such information as the name and address of the debtor, taxpayer’s identification number (which may be the Social Security Number); amount of debt or delinquent amount; basis of debt; date debt arose; office/bureau referring debt to the Debt Collection Officer; record of each collection made; credit report; financial statement reflecting the net worth of the debtor; date by which debt must be referred to the Department of the Treasury for further collection action; and citation or basis on which debt was terminated or compromised.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>31 U.S.C. 3701 et seq., Debt Collection Act of 1982 (Pub. L. 97-365, 96 Stat. 1749) as amended by the Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996 (Pub. L. 104-134, 101 Stat. 1321-358).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is used for the purpose of collecting monies owed FMC arising out of any administrative or program activities or services administered by FMC. The Debt Collection Officer’s file represents the basis for the debt and amount of debt and actions taken by FMC to collect the monies owed under the debt. The credit report or financial statement provides an understanding of the individual’s financial condition with respect to requests for deferment of payment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. When debts are uncollectible, copies of the FMC Debt Collection Officer’s file regarding the debt and actions taken to attempt to collect the monies are forwarded to the Department of Treasury for further collection action. FMC may also provide Treasury with copies of the debt collection letter, bill for collection, and FMC correspondence to the debtor.
</p><p>2. Disclosure pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12).
</p><p>3. Disclosures may be made from this system to "consumer reporting agencies" as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).
</p><p>4. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) The Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in notebooks, file folders, on lists and forms, and in computer processible storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The system files are filed by bill for collection number, name, or taxpayer’s identification number (which may be the Social Security Number).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel screening, hardware, and software computer security measures; paper records are maintained in locked containers and/or room. All records are maintained in areas that are secured by building guards during non-business hours. Records are retained in areas accessible only to authorized personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with General Records Schedule 6, the records are maintained for 6 years and 3 months and then shredded.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Financial Management, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about themselves should contact the system manager identified above. Written requests should be clearly marked "Privacy Act Request" on the envelope and letter. Requests should include full name of the individual, some type of appropriate personal identification, and current address.
</p><p>For personal visits, the individuals should be able to provide some acceptable identification--that is, driver’s license, employing organization identification card, or other picture identification card.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification procedures above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Notification procedures above. The letter should state clearly and concisely what information is being contested, the reason for contesting it, and the proposed amendment to the information sought.
</p><p>FMC Privacy Act Regulations are promulgated in 46 CFR part 503.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Directly from the debtor, the initial application, credit report from the commercial credit bureau, administrative or program offices within FMC.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc32" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-32</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Regulated Persons Index ("RPI").
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Bureau of Certification and Licensing, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained on persons, including passenger vessel operators, vessel operating common carriers, marine terminal operators, sole proprietorships, association or agreement of persons, financial institutions, third party filers, practitioners before the Commission, ocean freight forwarders, non-vessel-operating common carriers, members of partnerships, and officers and owners of corporate licensees, managers/members and owners of limited liability companies, ex-licensees, and applicants for licenses.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The system contains names, addresses, phone/fax numbers of regulated entities and, where applicable, tax payer identification numbers (which may be Social Security Numbers), or names, addresses, and Social Security Numbers (or alternatively, driver’s license numbers, passport, visa, or alien registration numbers) of the stockholders, officers, managers/members, and directors of individual ocean transportation intermediaries (OTIs); financial responsibility information including name of financial institutions, instrument identification numbers and amount of instruments; and, internal processing and licenses information pertinent to OTIs. Under the Shipping Act of 1984, as amended, OTIs may be an ocean freight forwarder, a non-vessel-operating common carrier, or both.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 553; secs. 3, 8, 10, 11, 13, 15, 17 and 19, Shipping Act of 1984 (recodified October 2006 as 46 U.S.C. 305, 40102, 40104, 40501-40503, 40901-40904, 41101-41109, 41302-41303, and 41305), 46 App. U.S.C. 1704 (recodified as 46 U.S.C. 40302-40303), 46 App. U.S.C. 1707 (recodified as 46 U.S.C. 40501-40503), 46 App. U.S.C. 817(d) and (e) (recodified 46 U.S.C. 44101-44106), 46 CFR 502.27, 46 CFR 520.3(d).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p><i>These records and information contained in these records may be disclosed as follows:</i>
</p><p>1. By the Commission staff for monitoring the activities of regulated entities to ensure they are in compliance with Commission regulations.
</p><p>2. By Commission staff for evaluation of applicants for licensing and certificates.
</p><p>3. To provide or update information maintained in the U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s (CBP) Automated Commercial Environment/International Trade Data System (ACE/ITDS) to verify licensed or registered status of OTIs under the Trade Act of 2002 and related CBP requirements (or any other successor agency or organization) and to verify that passenger vessels with 50 or more passenger berths embarking passengers from U.S. ports have valid certificates.
</p><p>4. Selected data such as name, address, phone/fax number are available to the public at a fee.
</p><p>5. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) the Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Records are maintained in file folders and LAN environment at Commission headquarters.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by name, organization number, or license number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in an area of restricted accessibility.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Passenger vessel applicant and certificate files and OTI applicant and licensee files are kept as long as the application and/or certificate/license is active. Files for withdrawn and denied applicants, and revoked licensees as well as passenger vessel operators no longer active in the program remain in the Record Location Center ten years after final action. After ten years, the files are destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Bureau of Certification and Licensing, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Request may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefore, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Information submitted by applicants, licensees, certificants, practitioners, third party filers, vessel operating common carriers, marine terminal operators, financial entities including surety companies.
</p><p>2. OTI license status information.
</p><p>3. Information submitted by Commission Area Representatives.
</p><p>4. Information obtained through Internet web site searches and selected commercial and government database searches conducted by BCL staff in processing OTI and PVO applications (e.g., ChoicePoint and Dun &amp; Bradstreet).
</p><p>5. Information submitted by the general public.
</p><p>6. Information submitted by surety companies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes is exempted from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f). Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc33" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-33</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Payroll/Personnel System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Hard copies of personnel records and payroll transactions and reports are located at the Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001. Electronic data are located at the U.S. Department of Agriculture, National Finance Center, New Orleans, LA 70129. The electronic records are subject to the Office of Personnel Management’s government-wide system notice, OPM/GOVT-1.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of the Federal Maritime Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>All official personnel actions and/or payroll transaction information on Commission employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, 2302(b)(20)(B), 2302(b)(10), 7311, 7313; Executive Order 10450; 5 CFR 731.103.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In the event that a system of records maintained by this agency to carry out its functions indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program state, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records may be referred, as a "routine use," to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p><i>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a "routine use":</i>
</p><p>1. To a Federal, State or local agency maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary, to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of any employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract or the issuance of a license grant or other benefit.
</p><p>2. To a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision in the matter.
</p><p>3. To the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services Federal Parent Locator Service (FPLS) and Federal Tax Offset System for use in locating individuals and identifying their income sources to establish paternity, establish and modify orders of support and for enforcement action.
</p><p>4. To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Social Security Administration for verifying Social Security Numbers in connection with the operation of the FPLS by the Office of Child Support Enforcement.
</p><p>5. To the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Department of Treasury for purposes of administering the Earned Income Tax Credit Program (Section 32, Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and verifying a claim with respect to employment in a tax return.
</p><p>6. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management in accordance with the agency’s responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.
</p><p>7. To officers and employees of a Federal agency for purposes of audit.
</p><p>8. To a Member of Congress or to a congressional staff member in response to an inquiry of the congressional office made at the request of the individual about whom the record is maintained.
</p><p>9. To officers and employees of the National Finance Center in connection with administrative services provided to this agency under agreement with NFC.
</p><p>10. To GAO for audit; to the Internal Revenue Service for investigation; and to private attorneys, pursuant to a power of attorney.
</p><p>11. To the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Office of Special Counsel, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, or the Federal Labor Relations Authority, in connection with functions vested in those agencies.
</p><p>12. To the Office of Management and Budget in connection with private relief legislation.
</p><p>13. In litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency.
</p><p>14. To the National Archives and Records Administration for records management inspections.
</p><p>15. To Federal agencies as a data source for management information through the production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the functions for which the records are maintained for related studies.
</p><p>16. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) the Federal Maritime Commission suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the agency has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the agency or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p>A copy of an employee’s Department of the Treasury Form W-2, Wage and Tax Statement, also is disclosed to the state, city, or other local jurisdiction which is authorized to tax the employee’s compensation. The record will be provided in accordance with a withholding agreement between the state, city or other local jurisdiction and the Department of the Treasury pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 5516, 5517, and 5520, or, in the absence thereof, in response to a written request from an appropriate official of the taxing jurisdiction to the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001. The request must include a copy of the applicable statute or ordinance authorizing the taxation of compensation and should indicate whether the authority of the jurisdiction to tax the employee is based on place of residence, place of employment, or both. Pursuant to a withholding agreement between a city and the Department of the Treasury (5 U.S.C. 5520), copies of executed city tax withholding certificates shall be furnished to the city in response to written request from an appropriate city official to the Secretary at the above address.
</p><p>In the absence of a withholding agreement, the Social Security Number will be furnished only to a taxing jurisdiction which has furnished this agency with evidence of its independent authority to compel disclosure of the Social Security Number, in accordance with section 7 of the Privacy Act, Public Law 93-579.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p><p>Paper records are stored in Official Personnel Folders and payroll files at the FMC. Electronic records reside at the National Finance Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Hard copy records are retrievable by name. Electronic data can be retrieved by Social Security Number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Electronic records are stored at the National Finance Center, which is located in a secured Federal complex with controlled access. Access to data is limited to those individuals to whom NFC has granted access/security. Output documents from the system are maintained as hard copy documents by the FMC’s Office of Human Resources in secured cabinets located within a secured room.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Disposition of records shall be in accordance with General Records Schedule 2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Human Resources, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries regarding this system of records should be addressed to: Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record should be directed to the Secretary listed at the above address. Requests may be in person or by mail and shall meet the requirements set out in section 503.65 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>An individual desiring to amend a record shall direct such a request to the Secretary at the above listed address. Such requests shall specify the desired amendments and the reasons therefor, and shall meet the requirements of section 503.66 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The subject individual; the Commission.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc34" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-34</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">Travel Charge Card Program--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Financial Management, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>This system is covered by the General Services Administration’s government-wide system notice, GSA/GOVT-3.
 </p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc35" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-35</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Transit Benefits File--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Management Services, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>This system is covered by the Department of Transportation’s government-wide system notice, DOT/ALL-8.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fmc36" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-36</systemNumber>

<subsection type="systemName">SmartPay Purchase Charge Card Program--FMC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Management Services, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573-0001.
</p><p>This system is covered by the General Services Administration’s government-wide system notice, GSA/GOVT-6.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
	<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="46">
<heading> Shipping </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="IV">
<heading> Federal Maritime Commission </heading>
<regulationsPart number="504">
<heading> PUBLIC INFORMATION </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>&#167;Subpart G--Access to Any Record of Identifiable Personal Information
</b></p>
<p>503.60 Definitions.
</p>
<p>503.61 Conditions of disclosure.
</p>
<p>503.62 Accounting of disclosures.
</p>
<p>503.63 Request for information.
</p>
<p>503.64 Commission procedure on request for information.
</p>
<p>503.65 Request for access to records.
</p>
<p>503.66 Amendment of a record.
</p>
<p>503.67 Appeals from denial of request for amendment of a record.
</p>
<p>503.68 Exemptions.
</p>
<p>503.69 Fees.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552, 552a, 552b, 553; 31 U.S.C. 9701; E.O. 12958 of April 20, 1995 (60 FR 19825), sections 5.2(a) and (b).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984, unless otherwise noted.</p>
<p><b>Subpart G--Access to Any Record of Identifiable Personal Information
</b></p><p><b>&#167; 503.60
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For the purpose of this subpart:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Agency</i> means each authority of the government of the United States as defined in 5 U.S.C. 551(1) and shall include any executive department, military department, government corporation, government controlled corporation or other establishment in the executive branch of the government (including the Executive Office of the President), or any independent regulatory agency.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Commission</i> means the Federal Maritime Commission.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to whom a record pertains.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use, or disseminate.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Person</i> means any person not an individual and shall include, but is not limited to, corporations, associations, partnerships, trustees, receivers, personal representatives, and public or private organizations.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by the Federal Maritime Commission, including but not limited to a person’s education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history, and that contains the person’s name, or the identifying number, symbol or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print, or a photograph.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Routine use</i> means [with respect to the disclosure of a record], the use of such records for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records, maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual, but shall not include matter pertaining to the Census as defined in 13 U.S.C. 8.
</p>
<p>(i) <i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of the Commission from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p>[49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984; 49 FR 47395, Dec. 4, 1984]
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.61
 Conditions of disclosure.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Subject to the conditions of paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section, the Commission shall not disclose any record which is contained in a system of records, by any means of communication, to any person or other agency who is not an individual to whom the record pertains.
</p>
<p>(b) Upon written request or with prior written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains, the Commission may disclose any such record to any person or other agency.
</p>
<p>(c) In the absence of a written consent from the individual to whom the record pertains, the Commission may disclose any such record, provided such disclosure is:
</p>
<p>(1) To those officers and employees of the Commission who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties;
</p>
<p>(2) Required under the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C 552);
</p>
<p>(3) For a routine use;
</p>
<p>(4) To the Bureau of Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity under the provisions of title 13 U.S.C.;
</p>
<p>(5) To a recipient who has provided the Commission with adequate advance written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable;
</p>
<p>(6) To the National Archives of the United States, as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the United States government, or for evaluation by the Administrator of General Services or his designee to determine whether the record has such value;--
</p>
<p>(7) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity authorized by law, provided the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a prior written request to the Secretary of the Commission specifying the particular record and the law enforcement activity for which it is sought;
</p>
<p>(8) To either House of Congress, and to the extent of a matter within its jurisdiction, any committee, subcommittee, or joint committee of Congress;
</p>
<p>(9) To the Comptroller General, or any authorized representative, thereof, in the course of the performance of the duties of the GAO; or
</p>
<p>(10) Under an order of a court of competent jurisdiction.
</p>
<p>[49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984; 49 FR 47395, Dec. 4, 1984]
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.62
 Accounting of disclosures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Secretary shall make an accounting of each disclosure of any record contained in a system of records in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(1) and 552a(c)(2).
</p>
<p>(b) Except for a disclosure made under &#167; 503.61(c)(7), the Secretary shall make the accounting described in paragraph (a) of this section available to any individual upon written request made in accordance with &#167; 503.63(b) or &#167; 503.63(c).
</p>
<p>(c) The Secretary shall make reasonable efforts to notify the individual when any record which pertains to such individual is disclosed to any person under compulsory legal process, when such process becomes a matter of public record.
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.63
 Request for information.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Upon request, in person or by mail, made in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (b) or (c) of this section, any individual shall be informed whether or not any Commission system of records contains a record pertaining to him or her.
</p>
<p>(b) Any individual requesting such information in person shall personally appear at the Office of the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW, Washington, DC 20573 and shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Provide information sufficient, in the opinion of the Secretary, to identify the record, e.g., the individual’s own name, date of birth, place of birth, etc.;
</p>
<p>(2) Provide identification acceptable to the Secretary to verify the individual’s identity, e.g., driver’s license, employee identification card or medicare card;
</p>
<p>(3) Complete and sign the appropriate form provided by the Secretary.
</p>
<p>(c) Any individual requesting such information by mail shall address such request to the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW, Washington, DC 20573 and shall include in such request the following:
</p>
<p>(1) Information sufficient in the opinion of the Secretary to identify the record, e.g., the individual’s own name, date of birth, place of birth, etc.;
</p>
<p>(2) A signed notarized statement to verify his or her identity.
</p>
<p>[49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984; 49 FR 47395, Dec. 4, 1984, as amended at 63 FR 50535, Sept. 22, 1998]
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.64
 Commission procedure on request for information.
</b></p>
<p>Upon request for information made in accordance with &#167; 503.63, the Secretary or his or her delegate shall, within 10 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays), furnish in writing to the requesting party notice of the existence or nonexistence of any records described in such request.
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.65
 Request for access to records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>General.</i> Upon request by any individual made in accordance with the procedures set forth in paragraph (b) of this section, such individual shall be granted access to any record pertaining to him or her which is contained in a Commission system of records. However, nothing in this section shall allow an individual access to any information compiled by the Commission in reasonable anticipation of a civil or criminal action or proceeding.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Procedures for requests for access to records.</i> Any individual may request access to a record pertaining to him or her in person or by mail in accordance with paragraphs (b) (1) and (2) of this section:
</p>
<p>(1) Any individual making such request in person shall do so at the Office of the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW, Washington, DC 20573 and shall:
</p>
<p>(i) Provide identification acceptable to the Secretary to verify the individual’s identity, e.g., driver’s license, employee identification card, or medicare card; and
</p>
<p>(ii) Complete and sign the appropriate form provided by the Secretary.
</p>
<p>(2) Any individual making a request for access to records by mail shall address such request to the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW, Washington, DC 20573 and shall include therein a signed, notarized statement to verify his or her identity.
</p>
<p>(3) Any individual requesting access to records under this section in person may be accompanied by a person of his or her own choosing, while reviewing the record requested. If an individual elects to be so accompanied, he or she shall notify the Secretary of such election in the request and shall provide a written statement authorizing disclosure of the record in the presence of the accompanying person. Failure to so notify the Secretary in a request for access shall be deemed to be a decision by the individual not to be accompanied.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Commission determination of requests for access.</i> (1) Upon request made in accordance with this section, the Secretary or his or her delegate shall:
</p>
<p>(i) Determine whether or not such request shall be granted;
</p>
<p>(ii) Make such determination and provide notification within 10 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays) after receipt of such request, and, if such request is granted shall:
</p>
<p>(iii) Notify the individual that fees for reproducing copies will be made in accordance with &#167; 503.69.
</p>
<p>(2) If access to a record is denied because such information has been compiled by the Commission in reasonable anticipation of a civil or criminal action or proceeding, or for any other reason, the Secretary shall notify the individual of such determination and his or her right to judicial appeal under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Manner of providing access.</i> (1) If access is granted, the individual making such request shall notify the Secretary whether the records requested are to be copied and mailed to the individual.
</p>
<p>(2) If records are to be made available for personal inspection, the individual shall arrange with the Secretary a mutually agreeable time and place for inspection of the record.
</p>
<p>(3) Fees for reproducing and mailing copies of records will be made in accordance with &#167; 503.69.
</p>
<p>[49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984; 49 FR 47395, Dec. 4, 1984, as amended at 63 FR 50535, Sept. 22, 1998]
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.66
 Amendment of a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>General.</i> Any individual may request amendment of a record pertaining to him or her according to the procedure in paragraph (b) of this section.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Procedures for requesting amendment of a record.</i> After inspection of a record pertaining to him or her, an individual may file with the Secretary a request, in person or by mail, for amendment of a record. Such request shall specify the particular portions of the record to be amended, the desired amendments and the reasons therefor.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Commission procedures on request for amendment of a record.</i> (1) Not later than ten (10) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays) after the date of receipt of a request made in accordance with this section to amend a record in whole or in part, the Secretary or his or her delegate shall:
</p>
<p>(i) Make any correction of any portion of the record which the individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely or complete and thereafter inform the individual of such correction; or
</p>
<p>(ii) Inform the individual, by certified mail, return receipt requested, of refusal to amend the record, setting out the reasons therefor, and notify the individual of his or her right to appeal that determination to the Chairman of the Commission under &#167; 503.67.
</p>
<p>(2) The Secretary shall inform any person or other agency to whom a record has been disclosed of any correction or notation of dispute made by the Secretary with respect to such records, in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(4) referring to amendment of a record, if an accounting of such disclosure has been made.
</p>
<p>[49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984; 49 FR 47395, Dec. 4, 1984]
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.67
 Appeals from denial of request for amendment of a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>General.</i> An individual whose request for amendment of a record pertaining to him or her is denied, may further request a review of such determination in accordance with paragraph (b) of this section.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Procedure for appeal.</i> Not later than thirty (30) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays) following receipt of notification of refusal to amend, an individual may file an appeal to amend the record. Such appeal shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Be addressed to the Chairman, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW, Washington, DC 20573; and
</p>
<p>(2) Specify the reasons for which the refusal to amend is challenged.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Commission procedure on appeal.</i> (1) Upon appeal from a denial to amend a record, the Chairman of the Commission or the officer designated by the Chairman to act in his or her absence, shall make a determination whether or not to amend the record and shall notify the individual of that determination by certified mail, return receipt requested, not later than thirty (30) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal public holidays) after receipt of such appeal, unless extended pursuant to paragraph (d) of this section.
</p>
<p>(2) The Chairman shall also notify the individual of the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1)(A) regarding judicial review of the Chairman’s determination.
</p>
<p>(3) If, on appeal, the refusal to amend the record is upheld, the Commission shall permit the individual to file a statement setting forth the reasons for disagreement with the Commission’s determination.
</p>
<p>(d) The Chairman, or his or her delegate in his or her absence, may extend up to thirty (30) days the time period prescribed in paragraph (c)(1) of this section within which to make a determination on an appeal from refusal to amend a record for the reasons that a fair and equitable review cannot be completed within the prescribed time period.
</p>
<p>[49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984, as amended at 63 FR 50536, Sept. 22, 1998]
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.68
 Exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The system of records designated FMC-25 Inspector General File is exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a except subsections (b), (c) (1) and (2), (e)(4) (A) through (F), (e) (6), (7), (9), (10), and (11) and (i) to the extent it contains information meeting the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws. Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p>
<p>(b) The following systems of records are exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4) (G), (H) and (I) and (f), which otherwise require the Commission, among other things, to provide the individual named in the records an accounting of disclosures and access to and opportunity to amend the records. The scope of the exemptions and the reasons therefor are described for each particular system of records.
</p>
<p>(1) <i>FMC-1 Personnel Security File.</i> All information about individuals that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), regarding suitability, eligibility or qualifications for Federal civilian employment or for access to classified information, to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Commission under a promise of confidentiality. Exemption is required to honor promises of confidentiality.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>FMC-7 Licensed Ocean Freight Forwarders File.</i> All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory materials compiled for law enforcement purposes. Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p>
<p>(3) <i>FMC-22 Investigatory Files.</i> All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes. Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p>
<p>(4) <i>FMC-24 Informal Inquiries and Complaint Files.</i> All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes. Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasion of personal privacy of third parties.
</p>
<p>(5) <i>FMC-25 Inspector General File.</i> (i) All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes. Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p>
<p>(ii) All information about individuals that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), regarding suitability, eligibility or qualifications for Federal civilian employment or for access to classified information, to the extent the disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Commission under the promises of confidentiality. Exemption is required to honor promises of confidentiality.
</p>
<p>(6) <i>FMC-26 Administrative Grievance File.</i> (i) All information that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) regarding investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes, Exemption is appropriate to avoid compromise of ongoing investigations, disclosure of the identity of confidential sources and unwarranted invasions of personal privacy of third parties.
</p>
<p>(ii) All information about individuals that meets the criteria of 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), regarding suitability, eligibility or qualification for Federal civilian employment or for access to classified information, to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Commission under a promise of confidentiality. Exemption is required to honor promises of confidentiality.
</p>
<p>[59 FR 15636, Apr. 4, 1994]
</p><p><b>&#167; 503.69
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>General.</i> The following Commission services are available, with respect to requests made under the provisions of this subpart, for which fees will be charged as provided in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section:
</p>
<p>(1) Copying records/documents.
</p>
<p>(2) Certification of copies of documents.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Fees for services.</i> The fees set forth below provide for documents to be mailed with ordinary first-class postage prepaid. If a copy is to be transmitted by registered, certified, air, or special delivery mail, postage therefor will be added to the basic fee. Also, if special handling or packaging is required, costs thereof will be added to the basic fee.
</p>
<p>(1) The copying of records and documents will be available at the rate of five cents per page (one side), limited to size 8 1/2" x 14" or smaller.
</p>
<p>(2) The certification and validation (with Federal Maritime Commission seal) of documents filed with or issued by the Commission will be available at $94 for each certification.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Payment of fees and charges.</i> The fees charged for special services may be paid by check, draft, or postal money order, payable to the Federal Maritime Commission.
</p>
<p>[49 FR 44401, Nov. 6, 1984, as amended at 59 FR 59171, Nov. 16, 1994; 63 FR 50536, Sept. 22, 1998; 67 FR 39860, June 11, 2002; 70 FR 10330, Mar. 3, 2005]
</p>

</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency></pai>
