<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Farm Credit Administration</name>
<abbrev>FCA</abbrev>
    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-03-10/pdf/2020-04884.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-1--Employee Attendance, Leave, and Payroll Records--FCA.</title>
        <date year="2020" month="3" day="10" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-05-26/pdf/2020-11198.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-10--Farm Credit System Institution Criminal Referrals--FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="5" day="26" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-05-26/pdf/2020-11198.pdf</url>
        <title>General Statement of Routine Uses </title>
        <date year="2020" month="5" day="26" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-06-04/pdf/2020-12097.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-5--Assignments and Communication Tracking System--FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="6" day="4" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-07-31/pdf/2020-16616.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-3—Property Accountability Records—FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="7" day="31" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-07-31/pdf/2020-16602.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-4—Biographical Files—FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="7" day="31" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-07-31/pdf/2020-16617.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-15—General Training Records—FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="7" day="31" />
    </previouslyPublished>
        <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-07-31/pdf/2020-16621.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-16—Examiner Training and Education Records—FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="7" day="31" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-07-31/pdf/2020-16620.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-17—Organization Locator and Personnel Roster System—FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="7" day="31" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-03/pdf/2020-16697.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-6—Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act Requests—FCA.</title>
        <date year="2020" month="8" day="3" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-03/pdf/2020-16698.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-9—Personnel Security Files—FCA.</title>
        <date year="2020" month="8 " day="3 " />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-03/pdf/2020-16701.pdf</url>
        <title>Rescinding, FCA-12--Health and Life Insurance Records--FCA.</title>
        <date year="20" month="8 " day="3 " />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-03/pdf/2020-16702.pdf  </url>
        <title>FCA-14--Employee Travel and Relocation Records--FCA.</title>
        <date year="2020" month="8 " day="3 " />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-13/pdf/2020-17737.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-13—Correspondence Files—FCA.</title>
        <date year="2020" month="8" day="13" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-20/pdf/2020-18223.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-8—FCA Information Technology User Access and Usage Records—FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="8 " day="20 " />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-20/pdf/2020-18224.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-19—Non-Payroll Employee Administrative Records System--FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="8 " day="20 " />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-20/pdf/2020-18225.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-18—Inspector General Investigative Files—FCA,Rescinded  </title>
        <date year="2020" month="8 " day=" 20" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-08-26/pdf/2020-18706.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-11—Litigation and Administrative Adjudication Files—FCA.</title>
        <date year="2020" month="8" day="26" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-10-08/pdf/2020-22351.pdf  </url>
        <title>FCA-7—Inspector General Investigative Files—FCA</title>
        <date year="2020" month="10 " day="8" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-09-10/pdf/2020-19995.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-2—Financial Management Records—FCA.</title>
        <date year="2020" month="9" day="10" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-17/pdf/2021-25013.pdf</url>
        <title>FCA-20--Health and Safety in the Workplace Records System--FCA</title>
        <date year="2021" month="11" day="17" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-22/pdf/2021-25389.pdf</url>
        <title>Date Correction</title>
        <date year="2021" month="11" day="22" />
    </previouslyPublished>


    <routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>General Statement of Routine Uses</b></p>
    <p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), we may disclose these records or information in the record systems under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3), as provided below. The following routine uses apply to and are incorporated by reference into each system of records set forth below unless otherwise indicated.</p>
    <p>(1) We may disclose a record or information in the record system when it indicates a violation or potential violation of law. Violations may be civil, criminal, or regulatory,  arising by statute, regulation, rule, or related order. Disclosure will be made to the appropriate federal, state, local, or foreign authority responsible for investigating or prosecuting relevant violations or charged with enforcing compliance with the law.</p>
    <p>(2) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to a responsible licensing authority if the records are relevant and necessary in the particular licensing decision.</p>
    <p>(3) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to an agency, office, or establishment of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the federal or state government, in response to its request, in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, issuing a security clearance, reporting on an investigation of an employee, letting a contract, or issuing a license, grant, or other benefit to the subject of the record.</p>
    <p>(4) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to a Federal congressional office to respond to an inquiry from that office made at the request of the person who is the subject of the record.</p>
    <p>(5) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to the U.S. Department of Justice ("DOJ") for its use in providing legal advice to the FCA or in representing the FCA in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body, where the use of such information by the DOJ is deemed by the FCA to be relevant and necessary to the advice or proceeding, and in the case of a proceeding, such proceeding names as a party in interest:</p>
    <p>(a) The FCA;</p>
    <p>(b) Any employee of the FCA in his or her official capacity;</p>
    <p>(c) Any employee of the FCA in his or her individual capacity where DOJ has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
    <p>(d) The United States, where the FCA determines that litigation is likely to affect the FCA;</p>
    <p>(6) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal in presenting evidence, including disclosures to counsel or witnesses during civil discovery, litigation, administrative proceedings, settlement negotiations, or in connection with criminal proceedings, when FCA is a party to the litigation or proceeding.</p>
    <p>(7) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to a court or other adjudicative body before which FCA is authorized to appear when,</p>
    <p>(i) FCA, or</p>
    <p>(ii) Any FCA employee in his or her individual capacity, is a party or has an interest in the litigation or proceeding and FCA deems the use of such records to be relevant and necessary.</p>
    <p>(8) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to the National Archives and Records Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
    <p>(9) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to another federal agency or entity, when FCA determines that information from the record system is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (a) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (b) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the federal government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
    <p>(10) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (a) the FCA suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (b) the FCA has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the FCA (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the federal government, or national security; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with FCA’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
    <p>(11) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to entities and persons performing work on a contract, service, cooperative agreement, or other activity on behalf of the FCA or federal government and who have a need to access the record or information in the performance of their duties or activities.</p>
    <p>(12) We may disclose a record or information in the record system to another federal or state agency to (a) make a decision on the access, amendment or correction of records to be made in consultation with or by that agency, or (b) verify an individual’s identity or the accuracy of information submitted by an individual who has requested access to or amendment or correction of records.</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</routineUses>

	
	<section id="fca1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            FCA-1--Employee Attendance, Leave, and Payroll Records--FCA
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this record system is used to prepare payroll, to meet Government payroll recordkeeping and reporting requirements, prepare reports, and to retrieve and supply payroll and leave information as required for Agency needs. In addition to payroll, reporting, and related record keeping, information in the system may be used to identify and assign specific employees to specific tasks or work-related assignments, or to track activities and payroll costs associated with those tasks or assignments.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former FCA employees, individuals who have been extended and accepted formal offers of employment by the Agency, and contractor personnel.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains paper and electronic files containing payroll-related information for FCA employees, including but not limited to: employee name, title, department, supervisor, employee number, Social Security number (SSN), rate and amount of pay, hours worked, tax and retirement deductions, leave bank records, including requests and approvals for leave, life insurance and health insurance deductions, savings allotments, savings bond and charity deductions, health savings accounts, other financial deductions, mailing addresses, and home addresses. The National Finance Center provides Agency payroll services.</p>
                <p>Additionally, the system includes information used by the Office of Examination to identify and assign FCA examiners and individuals who have been extended and accepted formal offers of employment by the Agency to specific examinations of FCS institutions. Information includes, but is not limited to: employee name, supervisor, approved leave and related information pertaining to availability for a specific examination, institution to which the employee is assigned as part of the examination team, and general information about the employee’s specific area of expertise or specialty. Sensitive information, such as Social Security number, leave types, balances, and similar information is not used for scheduling purposes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system of records is obtained from the individual to whom it applies or from information supplied by Agency officials.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).  The information collected in the system will be used in a manner that is compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected and, in addition to the applicable general routine uses, may be disclosed for the following purposes:</p>
                <p>1) We may disclose information in this system of records to other Government agencies, commercial or credit organizations, or to prospective employers to verify employment.</p>
                <p>2) We may disclose information in this system of records to Federal, State, and local taxing authorities concerning compensation to employees or to contractors; to the Office of Personnel Management, Department of the Treasury, Department of Labor, and other Federal agencies concerning pay, benefits, and retirement of employees; to Federal employees’ health benefits carriers concerning health insurance of employees; to financial organizations concerning employee savings account allotments and net pay to checking accounts; to State human resource offices administering unemployment compensation programs; to educational and training organizations concerning employee qualifications and identity for specific courses; and to heirs, executors, and legal representatives of beneficiaries.</p>
                <p>3) We may disclose information in this system of records to the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services, Federal Parent Locator System (FPLS), and Federal Tax Offset System for use in locating individuals and identifying their income sources, to establish paternity, establish and modify orders of support, and for enforcement actions.</p>
                <p>4) We may disclose information in this system of records to the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Social Security Administration for verifying Social Security numbers in connection with the operation of the FPLS by the Office of Child Support Enforcement.</p>
                <p>5) We may disclose information in this system of records to the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Department of the Treasury to administer the Earned Income Tax Credit Program (section 32, Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and to verify a claim with respect to employment in a tax return.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p>We may disclose information from this system, under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), to consumer reporting agencies as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. 1681a(f), or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966, as amended, 31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3), in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(f).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in a computerized database.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by name, Social Security number, or some combination thereof.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule 2.4: Employee Compensation and Benefits Records and General Records Schedule 2.2: Employee Management Records, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875.</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621.</p>
            </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
	
<section id="fca2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>FCA-2—Financial Management Records—FCA.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
        <p>Unclassified.</p>
    </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Chief Financial Officer, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>We use information in this system of records to provide records of payments to and collections from employees for compensation and expenses, to provide payments to vendors and other Government agencies, to maintain control over the collection and disbursement of Agency funds and to limit the opportunity for fraud, to prepare reports for management and other Government agencies, to obtain necessary information for the issuance and payment of credit cards, and to assist in any audits.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Current and former FCA employees, contractors, suppliers, and persons that provide or have provided supplies or services or performed work for FCA.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Information may include: (1) individual name(s), position or title, Social Security number (SSN); employee ID number, Taxpayer Identification Number (TIN) or similar; (2) employee travel records, including advances and travel vouchers; (3) bank routing and account number, loan numbers, receivable reference numbers, and similar; and (4) purchase related records including vendor vouchers, purchase orders, requisitions, FCA administrative expenses, collections, purchase, travel, and fleet credit card records, and other pertinent written information related to financial records and purchase transactions. Also included are bids, offers, and lease agreements.</p>
            <p>This system covers general financial records not otherwise included in government wide system of records notices, including GSA/GOVT-3, GSA/GOVT-4, and GSA/GOVT-6. This system complements those systems, and in some cases, the notice incorporates by reference but does not repeat all the information contained in those systems. </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Information in this system of records comes from: (1) The individual to whom the record applies; (2) persons, corporations, or governmental entities that make bids or offers to FCA or enter into leases or other agreements with FCA; (3) credit reporting agencies; and (4) FCA employees who prepare or audit contractual actions.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
            <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained in file folders and electronically in a computerized database.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>
                Records are retrieved by (1) SF1166a (Voucher and Schedule of Payments) voucher number by year; (2) individual or vendor name; Social Security number or Tax Identification Number (as applicable) and (4) purchase order or contract number; or some combination thereof.
            </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements for financial and procurement records, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.  Only personnel with a need-to-know in support of their duties have access to the records.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
            <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fca3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>FCA-3—Property Accountability Records—FCA.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Property Management Officer, Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The Federal Property Management Reform Act of 2016, 40. U.S.C. 621; 12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>We use information in this system of records to maintain control over accountable property.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Current and former FCA employees.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>This system contains records identifying accountable property issued for official use. It includes the manufacturer’s model and serial number of the accountable property, record number, unique bar code number, acquisition document identifier (purchase order or contract number), vendor’s name, acquisition cost, in-service date, classification (by type of accountable property) number, employee to whom assigned, and employee’s location.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information in this system of records comes from the person to whom property is issued.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
                    <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are maintained electronically in a computerized database.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are retrieved by name, assigned property number, or some combination thereof.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements for storing accounting files, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.  Only personnel with a need-to-know in support of their duties have access to the records.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                    <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
                </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fca4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>FCA-4—Biographical Files—FCA.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Office of Congressional and Public Affairs, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Director, Office of Congressional and Public Affairs, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA uses information in this system of records to develop informational materials about Agency employees.  Information may also be used, with the consent of persons to whom the information pertains, in support of Agency public affairs initiatives, such as for recruitment and retention.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Current and former FCA employees and FCA Board members.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system contains biographical information and photographs for disclosure to the media and the public, which are provided voluntarily by employees and Board members. Information includes, but is not limited to: (a) name and biographical information, such as place of birth or hometown; (b)employment information, such as official title(s) or position(s), previous positions or titles held or previous employers, work history and experience; (c) photographs, video images, and voice recordings; (d) education, including degrees held, areas of study, and schools attended; (e) military experience, if applicable; (f) civic duties and previous awards; and (g) hobbies and personal interests.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA employee on whom the record is maintained.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
            <p>The information collected in the system will be used in a manner that is compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected and, in addition to the applicable general routine uses, may be disclosed for the following purposes:</p>
            1)	<p>We may disclose certain information in this system of records to the public by (a) posting copies of such records on FCA’s Web site, www.fca.gov, authorized FCA social media accounts, or by other electronic or non-electronic means; (b) to the news media; or (c) to audiences attending a particular event, conference, or meeting when the biographies of speakers are used as background in introductions or included in other informational material.  Such disclosures would be limited to those for which there is a legitimate public interest in the disclosure of the information, the disclosure would not constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, or when explicit consent is granted by the person to whom the disclosed information pertains.</p>
            <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p> <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained in file folders and electronically in a computerized database.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retrieved by name.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Physical records are safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
            <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="fca5" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Assignments and Communication Tracking System--FCA.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this record system is used to: (1) track employee assignments; (2) make appropriate portions of the records available to the public; (3) enable members of the public to review and comment on or respond to such comments; and (4) facilitate, track, and maintain records of oral and written communications between FCA staff and external parties. Information in this system is also used for reference and aids Agency management in its deliberations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who submit correspondence or have correspondence submitted on their behalf to the Agency, or who request to receive correspondence from the Agency, as well as FCA employees, contractors, and interns assigned to the management of such correspondence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains paper and electronic files, including incoming and outgoing correspondence, letters, memoranda, and other similar documents pertaining to FCA’s operations, and communication logs.  In addition to non-public correspondence, this system includes public comments and other records that an individual may submit, such as those in response to an Agency rulemaking.  Information includes, but is not limited to: (1) correspondence received and sent by the Agency; (2) mailing lists or similar lists of contact information of individuals who submit correspondence, have correspondence submitted on their behalf, or request to receive correspondence from the Agency, including name, home or work address, personal or work email address, home, work or cellular phone number, employer, and title; (3) information pertaining to the correspondence, including status or disposition, type of correspondence, associated dates, and any other information relayed in the body of the correspondence; and (4) information pertaining to the Agency employees responsible for processing the correspondence, including name, title, and other information about internal assignments.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system of records is obtained from individuals who submit correspondence or have correspondence submitted on their behalf to the Agency, FCA employees and contractors, Farm Credit System Institutions, and other external parties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64FR 8175). The information collected in the system will be used in a manner that is compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected and, in addition to the applicable general routine uses, may be disclosed for the following purposes:</p>
                <p>1) We may disclose certain information in this system of records to the public, including posting copies of public comments on FCA’s Web site, www.fca.gov, or by other electronic or non-electronic means, in accordance with the Administrative Procedures Act.  Information disclosed may include identifying information, such as names, phone numbers, and addresses, provided in public comments and other records that an individual submits in connection with Agency rulemaking and other activities.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in file folders and on a computerized database.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by name, email address, Farm Credit District, subject, or some combination thereof.</p>
                <p>POLICIES AND PROCEDURES FOR RETENTION AND DISPOSAL OF RECORDS:
                    </p>
        <p>Records are retained in accordance with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule and National Archives and Records Administration regulations.</p>
        <p>ADMINSITRATIVE, TECHNICAL, AND PHYSICAL SAFEGUARDS:</p>
        <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
    </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="fca6" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Freedom of Information and Privacy Act Requests--FCA.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Unclassified.</p> </xhtmlContent>
                
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5. U.S.C. 552, 552a; 12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>We use information in this system of records in administratively processing requests for records to ensure compliance with the Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Persons that request records under the Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act.  Freedom of Information Act requests are subject to the Privacy Act only to the extent that they concern individuals; information pertaining to corporations and other business entities and organizations is not subject to the Privacy Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains (1) paper and electronic requests for records under the Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act, including names, addresses and other contact information as provided by the requestor; and (2) copies of replies and responsive records. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Persons making Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act requests and FCA or FCSIC employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in file folders and electronically in a computerized database.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by name.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements for Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act request files, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Paper records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.  Only personnel with a need-to-know in support of their duties have access to the records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="fca7" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            Inspector General Investigative Files--FCA.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Inspector General (OIG), Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Inspector General, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>We use information in this system: to facilitate and document the conduct of investigative activities relating to programs and operations of the FCA; to report results of investigative activities to other components of the FCA and other agencies and authorities for appropriate action; and to fulfill reporting requirements.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subjects of complaints and investigations relating to FCA’s programs and operations. Subjects include, but are not limited to, current and former FCA employees; current and former agents or employees of contractors and subcontractors in their personal capacity, where applicable; and other persons whose actions affect or relate to the FCA, its programs or operations. Businesses, proprietorships, and corporations are not covered by this system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains correspondence relating to investigative activities; internal staff memoranda; copies of subpoenas issued, affidavits, witnesses’ statements, transcripts and recordings of testimony taken, and accompanying exhibits; documents and records obtained from governmental or non-governmental sources, or copies thereof; interview notes, investigative notes, staff working papers, draft materials, and other investigative documents or records; investigative plans, progress reports, and closing reports; and other documents and information relating to the investigation of alleged or suspected criminal, civil, or administrative violations or similar wrongdoing relating to FCA programs and operations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records of the FCA and other federal, state, and local agencies; current and former employees of the FCA and other federal, state, and local agencies; private individuals and entities; contractors, subcontractors, FCA-regulated institutions, and other entities having some relationship with FCA or the FCA OIG.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses."  The information collected in the system will be used in a manner that is compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected and, in addition to the general routine uses, may be disclosed for the following purposes:</p>
                1)	<p>We may disclose information in this system of records to any source when the FCA OIG is conducting an investigation, audit, inspection, or evaluation, but only to the extent necessary to get information from that source relevant to and sought in furtherance of the investigation, audit, inspection, or evaluation.</p>
                2)	<p>We may disclose the record or information in the record system to agencies, offices, or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal or State governments when we have a request and where the records or information is relevant and necessary to a decision on an employee’s discipline or other administrative action (excluding a decision on hiring). We will take reasonable steps to ensure that the records are timely, relevant, accurate, and complete enough to assure fairness to the employee affected by the disciplinary or administrative action.</p>
                3)	<p>We may disclose the record or information in the record system to an FCA contractor when a contractor-operated program has been subject to OIG investigation that has uncovered personnel problems so that the contractor can correct those problems.</p>
                4)	<p>We may disclose the record or information in the record system to debt collection contractors to collect debts owed to the Government, as authorized under the Debt Collection Act of 1982, 31 U.S.C. 3718, and subject to applicable Privacy Act safeguards.</p>
                5)	<p>We may disclose the record or information in the record system to any official charged with the responsibility to conduct qualitative assessment reviews of internal safeguards and management procedures employed in investigative operations. This disclosure category includes members of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency and officials and administrative staff within their investigative chain of command, as well as authorized officials of the Department of Justice.</p>
                6)	<p>We may disclose the record or information in the record system to members of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency for the preparation of reports to the President and Congress on the activities of the Inspectors General.</p>
                7)	<p>We may disclose the record or information in the record system to federal, state, or local agencies or to the public as required to meet statutory reporting obligations.</p>
                8)	<p>We may disclose the record or information in the record system to the news media and the public, where there exists a legitimate public interest and disclosure would not constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                1)	<p>We may disclose information from this system, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12), to consumer reporting agencies as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. 1681a(f) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966, as amended, 31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3), in accordance with section 3711(e) of title 31.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The OIG Investigative Files consist of digital records stored in network file folders, as well as paper records and data maintained on removable media, which are stored in file cabinets in OIG office space.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by the name of the subject of the investigation or complaint, a description of the subject matter of the investigation or complaint, or by a unique control number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records of investigations and complaints are destroyed 10 years after the end of the fiscal year in which the relevant investigation was closed or complaint resolved. Investigative files determined by the Inspector General to have historical significance are transferred to the National Archives for permanent retention.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to FCA OIG personnel who need to know the information to perform their official duties.  Physical records are stored in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards.  Computer and network records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), records in this system are exempt from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a, except subsections (b), (c)(1) and (2), (e)(4)(A) through (F), (e)(6), (7), (9), (10), and (11), and (i), and corresponding sections of 12 CFR 603.355, to the extent a record in the system of records was compiled for criminal law enforcement purposes.</p>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), the system is exempt from 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f), and the corresponding provisions of 12 CFR 603.355, to the extent the system of records consists of investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes. Material within the scope of the exemption at 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) is also exempt. See 12 CFR 603.355.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999, page 21875</p>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 69, No. 37/ Wednesday, February 25, 2004, page 8657</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="fca8" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            Information Technology User Access and Usage Records—FCA.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Information Technology, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Information Officer and Director, Office of Information Technology, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252, and 44 U.S.C. 3101, 3501, 3534.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system of records is used by FCA to maintain account and usage information required for approving, monitoring, facilitating, and disabling access to FCA information technology.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former FCA and FCSIC employees, contractors, and other authorized users of or persons requesting access to or use of FCA information technology.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains information including, but not limited to:  (a) contact information including name, title or positions held, business and affiliations, email and telephone numbers;  (b) system, network, or similar logs, including access and usage records, including registration numbers or identification numbers associated with FCA information technology; (c) web sites visited, dates, and times; (d) usernames, passwords, authentication credentials, and similar information associated with access to and use of FCA information technology; (e)information associated with specific user information technology requests (incident tickets), including issue and resolution notes and contact information; and (f) internet protocol (IP) addresses, Media Access Control (MAC) addresses, usage logs, and similar information associated with external users of FCA information technology.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former FCA and FCSIC employees, contractors, and other authorized users of or persons requesting access to or use of FCA information technology.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).  The information collected in the system will be used in a manner compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies: None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in hard copy and electronic form, including file folders on a computerized database.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by name of individual, user name, user ID, IP or MAC address, machine ID or name, or some combination thereof.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule and the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Paper records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="fca9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security Files--FCA.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former FCA employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains case files compiled during background investigations of employees in sensitive
positions. It may include: (a) Security forms (<i>e.g.</i>, SF 85P, Questionnaire for Public Trust
Positions); (b) investigative reports that may include a credit check, a check of police records, and
interviews with neighbors, former supervisors, and coworkers; (c) a determination of suitability for
employment or for a security clearance by FCA"s security officer; and (d) issuance of clearance statement.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252; Executive orders 10450 and 10577.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>We use information in this system of records to determine suitability for employment and to issue a
clearance.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses."
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>STORAGE:
</p><p>We maintain records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>We retrieve records by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>We maintain records in a locked safe in an area that is secured after business hours. Only the
Personnel Security Officer and Alternate Personnel Security Officer have access to the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration General
Records Schedule requirements for personnel security records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel Security Officer, Office of Management Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm
Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Address inquiries about this system of records to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration,
1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit
Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration,
1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records comes from: (a) The individual to whom the record applies;
(b) Office of Personnel Management"s investigative files maintained by the Investigations Service: (c)
employment information maintained by the FCA; and (d) external and internal investigative inquiries by
Federal law enforcement agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records about a confidential source"s identity is subject to a
specific exemption, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), to ensure accurate information on employment suitability.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="fca9" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            FCA-9—Personnel Security Files—FCA.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Personnel Security Officer, Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252; Executive orders 10577, 12968, 13467, 13488, and 13764.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>We use information in this system of records to determine suitability for employment and to issue a clearance.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former FCA employees, individuals who have been extended and accepted formal offers of employment by the Agency, interns, and contractor personnel.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains case files compiled during background investigations of employees and contractor personnel in public trust or sensitive positions. It may include: (a) Security forms (e.g., SF 85P, Questionnaire for Public Trust Positions); (b) investigative reports that may include a credit check, police records, and interviews with neighbors, former supervisors, and coworkers; (c) a determination of suitability for employment or for a security clearance by FCA’s security officer; and (d) issuance of clearance statement.  Certain records included in a case file are considered copies and are primarily owned by DCSA and are accounted for in DoD’s "Personnel Vetting Records System," DUSDI 02-DoD.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system of records comes from: (a) The individual to whom the record applies; (b) DoD and legacy OPM NBIB investigative files maintained by the DCSA; (c) employment information maintained by the FCA; and (d) external and internal investigative inquiries by Federal law enforcement agencies.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in files folders and electronically in a computerized database.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by name, Social Security number, or some combination thereof.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.  Only the Personnel Security Officer and Alternate Personnel Security Officer have access to the records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system of records about a confidential source’s identity is subject to a specific exemption, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), to ensure accurate information on employment suitability.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <section id="fca10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        FCA-10--Farm Credit System Institution Criminal Referrals--FCA
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Office of Examination, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Director, Office of Examination, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252 and 12 C.F.R. Part 612.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Information in this system of records is used to track the progress of criminal referrals through the justice system, to notify FCA examiners, the FCA Office of General Counsel, and Farm Credit System (FCS) institutions of criminal referrals, and to issue notices/orders of prohibition or take other enforcement actions.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Individuals who participate or have participated in the conduct of, or who are or were connected with, FCS institutions, such as directors, officers, employees, borrowers, shareholders, and agents, who have been named in criminal referrals, investigatory records or administrative enforcement orders or agreements.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system contains paper and electronic files consisting of:</p>
            <p>1) criminal referral forms and accompanying documents,</p>
            <p>2) inter-agency or intra-agency correspondence or memoranda;</p>
            <p>3) newspaper clippings and other similar supplementary materials;</p>
            <p>4) Federal, state, or local criminal law enforcement agency investigatory reports, indictments, and/or arrest or conviction information; and</p>
            <p>5) administrative enforcement orders or agreements.</p>
            <p>Records contain personally identifiable information including, but not limited to: name, address, Social Security number (SSN), taxpayer identification number (TIN), date of birth, relationship to an FCS institution, and employment information (for referrals involving current or former FCS institution employees, contractors, or agents), information about financial transactions or other financial information for persons suspected of a criminal violation, as well as information about the suspected criminal violation, and name, title, and contact information for identified witnesses of suspected criminal violation or FCS institution employees responsible for completing and submitting the criminal referral form.</p>
            <p>Records contained in this system (e.g., criminal investigation reports prepared by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, Secret Service, and other Federal law enforcement agencies) may be the property of other agencies. Upon receipt of a request for such records, FCA will immediately notify the proprietary agency of the request and ask how to process the request for access. FCA may forward the request to the proprietary agency for processing in accordance with that agency’s regulations.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Farm Credit System institutions; Federal financial regulatory agencies; news media outlets; and criminal law enforcement investigatory and prosecutorial authorities.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64FR 8175).  The information collected in the system will be used in a manner that is compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected and, in addition to the applicable general routine uses, may be disclosed for the following purposes:</p>
            <p>1) We may disclose information in this system of records to any financial institution, agency, authority, or other entity affected by the suspected criminal activities.</p>
            <p>
                <b>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</b>
                </p>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained in hard copy and electronic form, including in a computerized database.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retrieved by individual name, name of submitting FCS institution, date received, chronological number assigned in order of receipt, borrower type, referral type, loss amount, criminal violation, or by some combination thereof.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retained in accordance with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule and National Archives and Records Administration regulations.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with need-to-know in support of their official duties. Paper records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system is subject to a specific exemption, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), to the extent investigatory material is compiled for law enforcement purposes. Federal criminal law enforcement investigatory reports maintained as part of this system may be subject to exemptions imposed by the originating agency under 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
            <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621.</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="fca11" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Litigation and Administrative Adjudication Files--FCA.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>

        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of General Counsel, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>General Counsel, Office of General Counsel, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>We use information in this system of records to actively manage and engage in litigation and administrative matters, track litigation and administrative matters, and to draft legal opinions and litigation reports.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Parties involved in litigation or administrative adjudication with FCA or litigation in which FCA has an interest, including: (a) Administrative proceedings before the FCA (e.g., personnel actions, whistleblower cases), (b) Federal or state court cases in which FCA is a party, (c) litigation in which FCA is participating as an amicus curiae, (d) a claim and/or subsequent litigation under the Federal Tort Claims Act, (e)third-party litigation in which FCA is in some way involved, and(f) other cases involving issues of concern to FCA, including those brought by other law enforcement agencies, Federal financial regulatory agencies, and private parties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system may contain: (1) documents comprising or included in the case record, such as briefs, affidavits, reports of investigation, motions, pleadings, orders, and correspondence; and (2) other documents, memoranda, and correspondence related to the action.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Person to whom the record applies, current and former FCA employees, witnesses, participants, attorneys, others working on behalf of FCA, U.S. Attorneys, U.S. District Courts, parties to the proceedings, or other Federal, State, or local agencies.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses".</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in file folders and electronically in one or more computerized databases.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by name.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with retention schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.  Only the personnel with a need-to-know in support of their duties have access to the records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <section id="fca13" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Correspondence Files--FCA.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Unclassified.
                </p> </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Congressional and Public Affairs, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Office of Congressional and Public Affairs, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>We use information in this system of records to track incoming and outgoing correspondence and to draft correspondence and other memoranda.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who have correspondence with FCA and the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation (FCSIC) and current and former FCA and FCSIC employees assigned to process review and/or respond to the correspondence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains incoming and outgoing correspondence and internal reports and memoranda, which are part of a general correspondence file maintained by the office(s) involved. Additionally, information about the correspondence is captured, including, but not limited to: (1) the type of correspondence (letter, fax, email); (2) dates and times received or sent; (3) name and office of FCA or FCSIC employee assigned to the correspondence; and (4) basic contact information (name, address, email address, phone number) related to the correspondence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Persons corresponding with FCA and FCISC and FCA and FCSIC employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in file folders and on a computerized database.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Records are retrieved by name.
                </p>
    </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.  Only personnel with a need-to-know in support of their duties have access to the records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="fca14" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            FCA-14--Employee Travel and Relocation Records--FCA.
        </subsection>

        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Unclassified.
                </p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Financial Officer and Director, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system of records is used by the FCA to ensure the proper payment of travel and relocation claims.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA employees who travel at the expense of FCA or in support of official FCA business and individuals who relocate at FCA’s expense.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system contains information including, but not limited to:  (a) name, home and business address, telephone number, email address, and Social Security number of FCA employees traveling on FCA business or being relocated at FCA’s expense; (b) name and relationship information of spouses, children, and other family members for individuals being relocated at FCA’s expense; (c) employment information, such as grade, retirement plan, title (current and new), duty station address, salary information, and government issued credit card number (if applicable) of individuals being relocated at FCA’s expense; (d) buyer seller and similar residence transaction information of the individual being relocated at FCA’s expense, including property addresses, purchase/sale prices, information about the financing company/lender associated with a property, loan account number(s) and other loan information (principle, payments, down payment, etc.), insurance company associated with the property, and other documents provided by the individual as receipts for reimbursement; (e) travel information including authorization number, destination, itinerary, mode and purpose of travel, as well as travel and relocation authorizations, travel vouchers, receipts, dates, expenses, amounts advanced, amounts claimed, amounts reimbursed, receipts, and other records not otherwise covered as part of the government-wide system of records notices published by the General Services Administration (GSA/GOVT-3 and GSA/GOVT-4).  This system complements those systems, and in some cases, the notice incorporates by reference but does not repeat all the information contained in those systems.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA employee that is the subject of the record and service providers.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).  The information collected in the system will be used in a manner compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies: None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in hard copy and electronic form, including file folders on a computerized database.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by name of individual traveling or being relocated at FCA’s expense.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained in accordance with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule and the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule 1.1: Financial Management and Reporting Records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
                <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="fca15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>FCA-15—General Training Records—FCA.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Director, Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA uses information in this system of records to document and track (a) training provided by FCA to employees and contractors; and (b) external professional training and education provided to FCA and FCSIC employees while employed by the Agency.  The system provides FCA with a means to track the training or education provided, identify trends and needs, monitor and track the expenditure on training and education programs and related travel, schedule training classes and programs, schedule instructors, assess the effectiveness of training, identify patterns, respond to requests for information related to the training of FCA and FCSIC employees and contractors, and facilitate the compilation of statistical information about training.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Current and former FCA and FCSIC employees, interns, and contractors.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system contains training and education information for FCA and FCSIC employees and interns while employed by FCA and FCSIC and training records for FCA-provided training to contractors. Records include: (a) name, title or position, and business contact information including phone number, office location and number, email address and telephone number; (b) documentation related to training and education including registration forms, course rosters, sign-in sheets, follow-up surveys, and course and instructor critiques; (c) instructor lists and schedules; (d) payment records, including travel, per diem, and related expenditures; and (e) educational records for FCA, FCSIC , and contractor employees, including schools of attendance, courses completed or in which enrolled, dates of attendance, tuition and expenses, and related per diem and travel expenses.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA and FCSIC employee, intern, or contractor that is the subject of the record and the training and education institution(s).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64FR 8175).</p>
            <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained in files folders and electronically in a computerized database.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>We retrieve records by name, email address, or by some combination thereof.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Paper records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
            <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fca16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>FCA-16—Examiner Training and Education Records—FCA.</p>
       </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Office of Examination, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Director, Office of Examination, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA uses information in this system of records to track pre-commissioned examiners’ training and progression towards becoming commissioned examiners.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Current and former FCA examiners.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>This system contains the educational history and progression of FCA examiners toward becoming commissioned. Records include: name, skills inventory form, training program record, formal training record, and results of commissioning test. Certain records included in an examiner’s file are considered copies and are accounted for in OPM’s government-wide system of records notice, OPM/GOVT-1 – General Personnel Records.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA examiner that is the subject of the record, the examiner’s supervisor, and members of the examiner’s supervisory panel.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
            <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained in file folders and electronically in a computerized database.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retrieved by name.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
            <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fca17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        <p>FCA-17—Organization Locator and Personnel Roster System—FCA.</p>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Director, Office of Agency Services, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>To identify, contact, and recall personnel when required; locate personnel for routine and emergency matters; provide mail distribution and forwarding addresses; compile a social roster for official and non-official functions; send personal greetings and invitations; establish building security; and locate individuals during medical emergencies, facility evacuations, and similar threat situations.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Current FCA and FCSIC employees, contractors, detailees, and their identified emergency point(s) of contact.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Information in the system includes names and contact information for FCA and FCSIC employees, contractors, detailees, and their identified emergency points of contact. Information includes but is not limited to: home and work addresses; home and work telephone numbers; cell phone numbers; personal and work email addresses; official titles or positions and organizations; photographs; building security zones; and other information associated with identifying and contacting personnel.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Information in this system of records either comes from the individual to whom it applies or comes from information supplied by Agency officials.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses" (64 FR 8175).</p>
            <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are maintained in files folders as well as electronically in a computerized database.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retrieved by name, email address, phone number, or some combination thereof.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule requirements, and with the FCA Comprehensive Records Schedule.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Address inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Federal Register Vol. 64, No. 100/ Tuesday, May 25, 1999 page 21875</p>
            <p>Vol. 70, No. 183 / Thursday, September 22, 2005, page 55621</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    <section id="fca19" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>
            FCA-19—Non-Payroll Employee Administrative Records System--FCA.
        </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Office of Agency Services and Chief Human Capital Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of the Non-Payroll Employee Administrative Records System is for the Agency to collect and maintain information used for non-payroll personnel actions and for human resources administrative purposes, including administering supplemental benefits, employee assistance programs, and work life programs.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former employees, interns, and contracting personnel of the Farm Credit Administration, in addition to other individuals who may make use of FCA’s fitness facilities or services.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information may include: (a) individual name, Social Security number (SSN), employee ID number, Taxpayer Identification Number (TIN), or similar; (b) employment related information including title, position, grade, start date, supervisor’s name, performance reports, training, professional licenses, certification and memberships information, whether the employee maintains a security clearance related to his or her position, and disciplinary information; proposed and approved work schedules and alternative work locations; (c) home and work contact information, including address, telephone number, and email address; (d) information about modes of transportation to and from work; (e) information related to an employee’s participation in supplemental retirement health and benefit programs, including contribution amount(s), dependents and beneficiary  names, addresses, relationship, and Social Security number(s); (f) information about student loans related to the student loan repayment benefit, including type of loan, loan account number, loan holder name and address, total loan amount and amount outstanding; and service agreement information; and (g) receipts and similar documentation provided as evidence of expenditures for reimbursement through supplemental benefits, employee assistance and work life programs.</p>
                <p>As noted above, this system covers general personnel and administrative records not otherwise included in OPM/GOVT-1 or FCA-1. This system complements those systems, and in some cases, the notice incorporates by reference but does not repeat all the information contained in those systems.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system is obtained from current and former FCA employees, interns, and contractors, as well as from any individual who may use FCA’s fitness facilities or services, and from entities associated with benefits and work-life programs including retirement, human resources functions, accounting, and payroll systems administration.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See the "General Statement of Routine Uses."  The information collected in the system will be used in a manner compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected and, in addition to the general routine uses, may be disclosed for the following purposes:</p>
                1.	<p>To carriers, providers, and other federal agencies involved in the administration of employee benefit programs and such agencies’ contractors or plan administrators, when necessary to determine employee eligibility to participate in such programs, process employee participation in such programs, audit benefits paid under such programs, or perform any administrative function in connection with those programs; and</p>
                2.	<p>To Federal, State, and local taxation authorities concerning compensation to employees or to contractors; to the Office of Personnel Management, Department of the Treasury, Department of Labor, and other Federal agencies concerning pay, benefits, and retirement of employees; to financial organizations concerning employee allotments to accounts; to educational and training organizations concerning employee qualifications and identity for specific courses; and to heirs, executors, and legal representatives of beneficiaries.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies: None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in paper and electronic form. Paper records are maintained in file folders, with sensitive information kept under lock and key, with access limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Electronic records are maintained in secure file shares and similar systems with technical access restricted to authorized personnel with a need-to know in support of their duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrievable by a variety of fields including, but not limited to, individual name, SSN, employee ID, or some combination thereof.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Files are retained in accordance with the FCA’s Comprehensive Records Schedule, item 6, or with the applicable National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) General Records Schedules (GRS).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with need-to-know in support of their official duties. Paper records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct all inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None. This is a new System of Records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="fca20" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-20</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>FCA-20--Health and Safety in the Workplace Records System--FCA.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Office of Agency Services and Chief Human Capital Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252; Civil Rights Act of 1964 § 7, 42 U.S.C. § 2000e et seq; Workforce safety federal requirements, including 5 U.S.C. Chapters 11 and 79; 29 U.S.C. 791, Employment of Individuals with Disabilities; Executive Order 14043 on Requiring Coronavirus Disease 2019 Vaccination for Federal Employees dated September 9, 2021; Executive Order 14042 on Ensuring Adequate COVID Safety Protocols for Federal Contractors dated September 9, 2021; Executive Order 13991 on Protecting the Federal Workforce and Requiring Mask-Wearing dated January 20, 2021; and Executive Order 12196 on Occupational Safety and Health Program for Federal Employees dated February 26, 1980.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of the Health and Safety in the Workplace Records System is to capture and manage information necessary to ensure workplace health and safety in response to a public health emergency.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former FCA and FCSIC employees, interns, volunteers, job applicants, and contractors (collectively "staff"), and other visitors to FCA facilities and field offices.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information may include, without limitation: (a) individual name and employee ID number; (b) employment related information including title, position, grade, and supervisor’s name; (c) home and work contact information, including address, telephone number, and email address; (d) recent travel history; (e) health information including body temperature, confirmation of pathogen or communicable disease test, test results, dates, symptoms, potential or actual exposure to a pathogen or communicable disease, immunization or vaccination information, other medical history related to the treatment of a pathogen or communicable disease; (f) information related to requests for and approval of reasonable accommodation(s) due to the public health emergency, including type of accommodation(s) requested, date of request, reason for request, specific information regarding type of request, including but not limited to the characteristics of impairment, job function difficulties, current limitation(s), past accommodation(s), specific accommodation(s), permanent or temporary medical condition(s), or religious beliefs or practices, supporting documentation and related materials that substantiate a  request for "reasonable accommodations," case notes or similar pertaining to the request, including any notes created in evaluating the request, and status of the request, including denial or approval; (g) information necessary to support contact tracing efforts for communicable diseases such as dates, times, and locations when an individual visited an FCA facility or field office, as well as locations visited within the facility or field office, and names of other individuals with whom they may have had contact during those visits; and (h) copies of government issued identification cards.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system is obtained from the individual to whom it applies, or is derived from i) information supplied by that individual; ii) FCA or FCSIC employee’s, intern’s or contractor’s supervisor; iii) private and Federal health care providers, and medical institutions; iv) security systems monitoring access to FCA facilities and offices, such as access badge card readers; v) human resources systems; vi) emergency notification systems; and vii) federal, state, and local agencies assisting with the response to a public health emergency. Information may also be collected from property management companies responsible for managing office buildings that house FCA facilities.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Routine uses 1, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, and 11 of the FCA’s "General Statement of Routine Uses" (85 FR 31495, May 26, 2020) are applicale to this system.  The "General Statement of Routine Uses" is also available on its website, www.fca.gov/privacy.  The information collected in the system will be used in a manner compatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected and, in addition to the applicable general routine uses, may be disclosed for the following purposes:</p>
                <p>1. To a Federal, State, or local agency to the extent necessary to comply with laws governing reporting of infectious disease;</p>
                <p>2. To the emergency contact of staff for purposes of locating staff during a public health emergency or to communicate that staff may have potentially suffered exposure during a public health emergency while visiting a FCA facility or field office;</p>
                <p>3. To medical personnel to meet a bona fide medical emergency;</p>
                <p>4. To an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint or appeal filed by an employee; and</p>
                <p>5. To an actual or potential party to litigation or the party's authorized representative for the purpose of negotiation or discussion on such matters as settlement, plea bargaining, or in information discovery proceedings.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</b>
                </p>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in paper and electronic form. Paper records are maintained in file folders, with sensitive information kept under lock and key, with access limited to those with a need-to-know in support of their official duties. Electronic records are maintained in secure file shares and similar systems with technical access restricted to authorized personnel with a need-to know in support of their official duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrievable by a variety of fields including, but not limited to, individual name, employee ID, or some combination thereof.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records related to requests for and approval of a reasonable accommodation are managed in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) General Records Schedule (GRS) 2.3, item 20. Such records are considered temporary and destroyed three years after employee separation from the agency or all appeals are concluded, whichever is longer. For all other records in the system, FCA is currently awaiting further guidance from NARA on retention and destruction. Until such time, these records will be considered permanent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>FCA implements multiple layers of security to ensure access to records is limited to those with need-to-know in support of their official duties. Paper records are physically safeguarded in a secured environment using locked file rooms, file cabinets, or locked offices and other physical safeguards. Computerized records are safeguarded through use of user roles, passwords, firewalls, encryption, and other information technology security measures.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To obtain a record, contact: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct requests for amendments to a record to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090, as provided in 12 CFR part 603.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Direct all inquiries about this system of records to:  Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, VA 22102-5090.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None. This is a new System of Records. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <appendix id="appa" toc="yes">
<title> Farm Credit Administration Field Offices </title>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>McLean Field Office, 1501 Farm Credit Drive, McLean, VA 22102-5090
</p><p>Dallas Field Office, 511 East Carpenter Freeway, Suite 650, Irving, TX 75062-3930
</p><p>Denver Field Office, 3131 South Vaughn Way, Suite 250, Aurora, CO 80014-3507
</p><p>Sacramento Field Office, 2180 Harvard Street, Suite 300, Sacramento, CA 95815
</p><p>Bloomington Field Office, 2850 Metro Drive, Suite 729, Bloomington, MN 55425-1415
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>
	

<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="12">
<heading>Banks and Banking</heading>
<regulationsChapter number="VI">
<heading> Farm Credit Administration
</heading>
<regulationsPart number="603">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT REGULATIONS </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>603.300 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>603.305 Definitions.
</p>
<p>603.310 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</p>
<p>603.315 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</p>
<p>603.320 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</p>
<p>603.325 Special procedures for medical records.
</p>
<p>603.330 Request for amendment to record.
</p>
<p>603.335 Agency review of request for amendment of record.
</p>
<p>603.340 Appeal of an initial adverse determination of a request to amend a record.
</p>
<p>603.345 Fees for providing copies of records.
</p>
<p>603.350 Criminal penalties.
</p>
<p>603.355 Exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Secs. 5.9, 5.17 of the Farm Credit Act (12 U.S.C. 2243, 2252); 5 U.S.C. app. 3, 5
U.S.C. 552a (j)(2) and (k)(2).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 40 FR 40454, Sept. 2, 1975, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.300
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>(a) This part is published by the Farm Credit Administration pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974
(Pub. L. 93-579, 5 U.S.C. 552a) which requires each Federal agency to promulgate rules to establish
procedures for notification and disclosure to an individual of agency records pertaining to that person,
and for review of such records.
</p>
<p>(b) The records covered by this part include:
</p>
<p>(1) Personnel and employment records maintained by the Farm Credit Administration which are not covered
by &#167;&#167; 293.101 through 293.108 of the regulations of the Office of Personnel Management (5
CFR 293.101 through 293.108), and
</p>
<p>(2) Other records contained in record systems maintained by the Farm Credit Administration.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 40454, Sept. 2, 1975, as amended at 51 FR 41941, Nov. 20, 1986]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.305
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For the purposes of this part:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Agency</i> means the Farm Credit Administration.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent
residence;
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use, or disseminate;
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is
maintained by an agency including, but not limited to, that person"s education, financial transactions,
medical history, and criminal or employment history, and that contains that person"s name, or the
identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or
voice print or photograph;
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a
purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records maintained for statistical research
or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an
identifiable individual, except as provided by 13 U.S.C. 8;
</p>
<p>(g) <i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of any agency from which
information is retrieved by the name of an individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other
identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p>[51 FR 41941, Nov. 20, 1986]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.310
 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any present or former employee of the Farm Credit Administration seeking access to that
person"s official civil service records maintained by the Farm Credit Administration shall submit a request
in such manner as is prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management.
</p>
<p>(b) Individuals shall submit their requests in writing to the Privacy Act Officer, Office of General
Counsel, Farm Credit Administration, McLean, Virginia 22102-5090, when seeking to obtain from the
Farm Credit Administration:
</p>
<p>(1) Notification of whether the agency maintains a record pertaining to that person in a system of
records;
</p>
<p>(2) Notification of whether the agency has disclosed a record for which an accounting of disclosure is
required to be maintained and made available to that person;
</p>
<p>(3) A copy of a record pertaining to that person or the accounting of its disclosure;
</p>
<p>(4) The review of a record pertaining to that person or the accounting of its disclosure. The request
shall state the full name and address of the individual, and identify the system or systems of records
believed to contain the information or record sought.
</p>
<p>[51 FR 41941, Nov. 20, 1986, as amended at 61 FR 67185, Dec. 20, 1996]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.315
 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</b></p>
<p>The individual making written requests for information or records ordinarily will not be required
to verify that person"s identity. The signature upon such requests shall be deemed to be a certification by
the requester that he or she is the individual to whom the record pertains, or the parent of a minor, or
the duly appointed legal guardian of the individual to whom the record pertains. The Privacy Act Officer,
however, may require such additional verification of identity in any instance in which the Privacy Act
Officer deems it advisable.
</p>
<p>[51 FR 41941, Nov. 20, 1986]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.320
 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Privacy Act Officer shall, within a reasonable period of time after the date of receipt of
a request for information of records:
</p>
<p>(1) Determine whether or not such request shall be granted,
</p>
<p>(2) Notify the requester of the determination and, if the request is denied, of the reasons therefor,
and
</p>
<p>(3) Notify the requester that fees for reproducing copies of records may be charged as provided in
&#167; 603.345 of this part.
</p>
<p>(b) If access to a record is denied because the information therein has been compiled by the Farm Credit
Administration in reasonable anticipation of a civil or criminal action proceeding, the Privacy Act Officer
shall notify the requester of that person"s right to judicial appeal under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).
</p>
<p>(c)(1) If access to a record is granted, the requester shall notify the Officer whether the requested
record is to be copied and mailed to the requester or whether the record is to be made available for
personal inspection.
</p>
<p>(2) A requester who is an individual may be accompanied by an individual selected by the requester when
the record is disclosed, in which case the requester may be required to furnish a written statement
authorizing the discussion of the record in the presence of the accompanying person.
</p>
<p>(d) If the record is to be made available for personal inspection, the requester shall arrange with the
Privacy Act Officer a mutually agreeable time in the offices of the Farm Credit Administration for
inspection of the record.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 40454, Sept. 2, 1975, as amended at 51 FR 41941, Nov. 20, 1986]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.325
 Special procedures for medical records.
</b></p>
<p>Medical records in the custody of the Farm Credit Administration which are not subject to Office of
Personnel Management regulations shall be disclosed either to the individual to whom they pertain or that
person"s authorized or legal representative or to a licensed physician named by the individual.
</p>
<p>[51 FR 41942, Nov. 20, 1986]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.330
 Request for amendment to record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) If, after disclosure of the requested information, an individual believes that the record is
not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete, that person may request in writing that the record be amended.
Such a request shall be submitted to the Privacy Act Officer and shall contain identification of the system
of records and the record or information therein, a brief description of the material requested to be
changed, the requested change or changes, and the reason for such change or changes.
</p>
<p>(b) The Privacy Act Officer shall acknowledge receipt of the request within 10 days (excluding
Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) and, if a determination has not been made, advise the individual
when that person may expect to be advised of action taken on the request. The acknowledgment may contain a
request for additional information needed to make a determination.
</p>
<p>[51 FR 41942, Nov. 20, 1986]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.335
 Agency review of request for amendment of record.
</b></p>
<p>Upon receipt of a request for amendment of a record, the Privacy Act Officer shall:
</p>
<p>(a) Correct any portion of a record which the individual making the request believes is not accurate,
relevant, timely, or complete and thereafter inform the individual in writing of such correction, or
</p>
<p>(b) Inform the individual in writing of refusal to amend the record and of the reasons therefor, and
advise that the individual may appeal such determination as provided in &#167; 603.340 of this part.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 40454, Sept. 2, 1975, as amended at 51 FR 41942, Nov. 20, 1986]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.340
 Appeal of an initial adverse determination of a request to amend a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Not more than 10 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after receipt by an
individual of an adverse determination on the individual"s request to amend a record or otherwise, the
individual may appeal to the Director, Office of Management Services.
</p>
<p>(b) The appeal shall be by letter, mailed or delivered to the Director, Office of Management Services,
Farm Credit Administration, McLean, Virginia 22102-5090. The letter shall identify the records
involved in the same manner they were identified to the Privacy Act Officer, shall specify the dates of the
request and adverse determination, and shall indicate the expressed basis for that determination. Also, the
letter shall state briefly and succinctly the reasons why the adverse determination should be reversed.
</p>
<p>(c) The review shall be completed and a final determination made by the Director not later than 30 days
(excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) from receipt of the request for such review, unless the
Director extends such 30-day period for good cause. If the 30-day period is extended, the individual shall
be notified of the reasons therefor.
</p>
<p>(d) If the Director refuses to amend the record in accordance with the request, the individual shall be
notified of the right to file a concise statement setting forth that person"s disagreement with the final
determination and that person"s right under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1)(A) to a judicial review of the final
determination.
</p>
<p>(e) If an amendment of a record as requested upon review is refused, there shall be included in the
disputed portion of the record a copy of the concise statement filed by the individual together with a
concise statement of the reasons for not amending the record as requested. Such statements will be included
when disclosure of the disputed record is made to persons and agencies as authorized under 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 40454, Sept. 2, 1975, as amended at 51 FR 41942, Nov. 20, 1986; 56 FR 2673, Jan. 24, 1991; 70 FR
69645, Nov. 17, 2005]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.345
 Fees for providing copies of records.
</b></p>
<p>Fees for providing copies of records shall be charged in accordance with &#167;&#167; 602.11
and 602.12 of this chapter.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 40454, Sept. 2, 1975, as amended at 56 FR 28479, June 21, 1991; 71 FR 54900, Sept. 20, 2006]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.350
 Criminal penalties.
</b></p>
<p>Section 552a (<i>l</i>) (3) of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(i)(3)) makes it a misdemeanor,
subject to a maximum fine of $5,000, to knowingly and willfully request or obtain any record concerning any
individual from an agency under false pretenses. Sections 552a (i) (1) and (2) of the Act (5 U.S.C. 552a
(i) (1), (2)) provide penalties for violation by agency employees of the Act or regulations established
thereunder.
</p>
<p>[40 FR 40454, Sept. 2, 1975, as amended at 71 FR 54900, Sept. 20, 2006]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 603.355
 Exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Specific.</i> Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), the investigatory material compiled for law
enforcement purposes in the following systems of records is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1),
(e)(4) (G), (H), and (I) and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a and from the provisions of this part:
</p>
<p>Farm Credit Bank loans--FCA.
</p>
<p>Production Credit Association loans--FCA.
</p>
<p>Agricultural Credit Association loans--FCA.
</p>
<p>Federal Land Credit Association loans--FCA.
</p>
<p>Agricultural Credit Bank loans--FCA.
</p>
<p>Office of Inspector General Investigative Files--FCA.</p>
<p>(b) <i>General.</i> (1) In addition, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a (j)(2), investigatory materials compiled
for criminal law enforcement in the system of records described in (b)(2) are exempt from all subsections
of 5 U.S.C. 552a, except (b), (c) (1) and (2), (e)(4) (A) through (F), (e) (6), (7), (9), (10), and (11),
and (i). Exemptions from the particular subsections are justified for the following reasons:
</p>
<p>(i) From subsection (c)(3) because making available to a record subject the accounting of disclosures
from records concerning him/her would reveal investigative interest on the part of the OIG. This would
enable record subjects to impede the investigation by, for example, destroying evidence, intimidating
potential witnesses, or fleeing the area to avoid inquiries or apprehension by law enforcement personnel.
</p>
<p>(ii) From subsection (c)(4) because this system is exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d)
pursuant to subsection (j)(2) of the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(iii) From subsection (d) because the records contained in this system relate to official Federal
investigations. Individual access to those records might compromise ongoing investigations, reveal
confidential informants or constitute unwarranted invasions of the personal privacy of third parties who
are involved in a certain investigation. Amendment of the records would interfere with ongoing criminal law
enforcement proceedings and impose an impossible administrative burden by requiring criminal investigations
to be continuously reinvestigated.
</p>
<p>(iv) From subsections (e) (1) and (5) because in the course of law enforcement investigations,
information may occasionally be obtained or introduced the accuracy of which is unclear or which is not
strictly relevant or necessary to a specific investigation. In the interests of effective law enforcement,
it is appropriate to retain all information that may aid in establishing patterns of criminal activity.
Moreover, it would impede the specific investigative process if it were necessary to assure the relevance,
accuracy, timeliness and completeness of all information obtained.
</p>
<p>(v) From subsection (e)(2) because in a law enforcement investigation the requirement that information
be collected to the greatest extent possible from the subject individual would present a serious impediment
to law enforcement in that the subject of the investigation would be informed of the existence of the
investigation and would therefore be able to avoid detection, apprehension, or legal obligations or duties.
</p>
<p>(vi) From subsection (e)(3) because to comply with the requirements of this subsection during the course
of an investigation could impede the information gathering process, thus hampering the investigation.
</p>
<p>(vii) From subsections (e)(4) (G), and (H), and (I), (e)(8), (f), (g) and (h) because this system is
exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d) pursuant to subsection (j) of the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(2) Office of Inspector General Investigative Files--FCA.
</p>
<p>[56 FR 2673, Jan. 24, 1991, as amended at 57 FR 32421, July 22, 1992]

</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
