<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board</name>
<abbrev>
RATB
</abbrev>
    
    

<section id="ratb1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Telephone Directory/Locator System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current employees of the Board and vendors or other Federal employees located in the Board's office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, title, agency office address, agency mailing address, telephone number, standard administrative code, and social security number (SSN).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, 40 U.S.C. 121(c).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are used to develop and maintain current employee locator and directory listings. The locator listings are used by the Board for the purpose of locating employees and for routing mail. The directory listings are used to produce agency telephone directories on an as-needed basis.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. In the event of litigation where the defendant is (1) the Board, any component of the Board, or any employee of the Board in his or her official capacity; (2) the United States where the Board determines that the claim, if successful, is likely to directly affect the operations of the Board or any of its components; or (3) any Board employee in his or her individual capacity where the Justice Department has agreed to represent such employee, the Board may disclose such records as it deems desirable or necessary to the Justice Department to enable that Department to present an effective defense, provided such disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>B. Records may be disclosed to student volunteers, individuals working under a personal services contract, and other individuals performing functions for the Board but technically not having the status of agency employees, if they need access to the records in order to perform their assigned agency functions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
	<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Variously stored in card files, computer printouts, paper forms, magnetic tape.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Alphabetically by employee name in certain instances, also by agency and/or title.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Only authorized personnel have access to master lists.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retained as long as individual is employed by or associated with the Board, then information deleted from files by appropriate method.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Assistant, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Inquiries concerning this system should be directed to General Counsel, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as notification procedure. Requesters should also reasonably specify the record contents being sought.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above, and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested and corrective action sought with supporting justification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individual employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Credential System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current or former employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The system maintains a record for each employee issued an agency credential with badge or medallion.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is used to maintain a record of each individual issued an agency credential as well as the accountability of each badge and medallion.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. Disclosure may be made to a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry made at the request of an employee employed by the Board.
</p><p>B. Information may be disclosed to any civil or criminal law enforcement agency, whether Federal, state, or local or foreign, which requires information relevant to a civil or criminal investigation.
</p><p>C. Information may be disclosed to officials and employees of any Federal agency which requires information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring, appointment or retention of an employee; the issuance of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation or the classification of a job.
</p><p>D. Relevant information may be disclosed in a proceeding before an administrative forum, including Ad Hoc forums, which may or may not include an Administrative Law Judge, and which may or may not convene public hearings/proceedings, or to other established adjudicatory or regulatory agencies, <i>e.g.</i>, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, or other agencies with similar or related statutory responsibilities, where necessary to adjudicate decisions affecting individuals who are employed by the Board and who are covered by this system, including (but not limited to) decisions to effect any necessary remedial actions, <i>e.g.</i>, debt collection activity, disciplinary and/or other appropriate personnel actions, and/or other law enforcement related actions, where appropriate.
</p><p>E. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, foreign or other public authority responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order where the Board becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>F. Information permitted to be released to the news media and that may be made available unless it is determined that release of the specific information in the context of a particular case would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.
</p><p>G. A record may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration and the General Services Administration during a records management inspection conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The information is stored on a standalone computer system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is retrieved by the name of the employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Only authorized personnel have access to standalone computer system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are retained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 18.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Assistant, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Inquiries concerning this system should be directed to the Freedom of Information Act Office, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To locate a specific record, you must provide the name of the individual and provide at least two items of identification (date of birth, employee identification number or similar information). The address is the same as indicated in the notification procedure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is provided by employees of the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Budget System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The system maintains a record of each individual employed by the agency. Each record contains the name, SSN, position title, salary and benefits of the individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is used to make payroll projections for budget purposes and to track employees by organization within the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. To provide information to a Member of Congress in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the employee or contractor.
</p><p>B. To disclose information to another Federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.
</p><p>C. Information may be disclosed to any civil or criminal law enforcement agency, whether Federal, state, or local or foreign, which requires information relevant to a civil or criminal investigation.
</p><p>D. Information may be disclosed to officials and employees of any Federal agency which requires information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring, appointment or retention of an employee; the issuance of a security clearance, the execution of a security or suitability investigation or the classification of a job.
</p><p>E. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, foreign or other public authority responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order where the Board becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>F. A record may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration and the General Services Administration during a records management inspection conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The information is stored on a personal computer which is password protected.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The information can be retrieved by the name and/or personal identifier of the employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is maintained on a server with limited access by user-ID and password.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is retained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 5.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Director, Finance and Budget, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Inquiries concerning this system should be directed to the Freedom of Information Act Office, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To locate a specific record, you must provide the name of the individual and provide at least two items of identification (date of birth, employee identification number, dates of employment or similar information). The address is the same as indicated in the notification procedure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is provided by current and former employers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Payroll and Leave Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records contain information relating to the individual's name, SSN, age, sex, marital status, appointment, tenure, employment status and occupation series. These records also contain data as of the year to date and the most recent pay period with regard to leave earned, used and balances, withholdings and allotments to financial institutions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 CFR Part 550.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Document employee salary, tax and related information and to track and document employee leave transfers, reinstatements and other leave issues.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. To provide information to a Member of Congress from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the employee or contractor.
</p><p>B. To disclose information to another Federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.
</p><p>C. Information may be disclosed to any civil or criminal law enforcement agency, whether Federal, state, or local or foreign, which requires information relevant to a civil or criminal investigation.
</p><p>D. Information may be disclosed to officials and employees of any Federal agency which requires information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring, appointment or retention of an employee; the issuance of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation or the classification of a job.
</p><p>E. Relevant information may be disclosed in a proceeding before an administrative forum, including Ad Hoc forums, which may or may not include an Administrative Law Judge, and which may or may not convene public hearings/proceedings, or to other established adjudicatory or regulatory agencies, <i>e.g.</i>, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, or other agencies with similar or related statutory responsibilities, where necessary to adjudicate decisions affecting individuals who are employed by the Board and who are covered by this system, including (but not limited to) decisions to effect any necessary remedial actions, <i>e.g.</i>, debt collection activity, disciplinary and/or other appropriate personnel actions, and/or other law enforcement related actions, where appropriate.
</p><p>F. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, foreign or other public authority responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order where the Board becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>G. To disclose to the Office of Personnel Management in accordance with the agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.
</p><p>H. To provide a copy of an employee's Department of the Treasury Form W-2, Wage and Tax Statement, to the state, city or other local jurisdiction which is authorized to tax the employee's compensation. The record will be provided in accordance with a withholding agreement between the state, city or other jurisdiction and the Department of the Treasury pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 5516, 5517 or 5520, or in response to a written request from an appropriate official of the taxing jurisdiction. The request must include a copy of the applicable statute or ordinance authorizing the taxation of compensation and should indicate whether the authority of the jurisdiction to tax their employee is based on a place of residence, place of employment or both.
</p><p>I. To disclose information to the General Services Administration Agency Liaison Division to effect distribution of pay according to employee directions and other authorized purposes.
</p><p>J. Release information to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS). Information contained in the system may be disclosed to the IRS to obtain taxpayer mailing addresses for the purpose of locating such taxpayer to collect or compromise a Federal claim against the taxpayer.
</p><p>K. Information directly related to the identity of debtors and the history of claims contained in the system of records may be disclosed to consumer reporting agencies for the purpose of encouraging repayment of overdue debts. Such disclosures will be made only when a claim is overdue and only after due process steps have been taken to notify the debtor and give him or her a chance to meet the terms of the debt.
</p><p>L. Information may be released about debtors to the U.S. Treasury or other Federal employers in order to effect salary or administrative offsets. Information contained in the system of records may be disclosed to an employer in order to effect salary or administrative offsets to satisfy a debt owed the United States by that person. Such disclosures will be made only when all procedural steps established by the Debt Collection Act have been taken.
</p><p>M. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants or volunteers performing or working on a contract, services or job for the Board.
</p><p>N. Information may be disclosed to the General Accountability Office (GAO) during a records management audit or inspection pursuant to GAO's audit authority.
</p><p>O. A record may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration and to the General Services Administration during a records management inspection conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies under subsection (b)(12) of the Privacy Act. Disclosure may be made from this system to consumer reporting agencies as defined in the Debt Collection Act of 1982 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)) or the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Information is retrieved by the name or personal identifier of the individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>This information is maintained on either a password-protected computer or filed in a locked file cabinet in a private office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is maintained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Mission Support Services, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Inquiries concerning this system should be directed to the Freedom of Information Act Office, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To locate a specific record, you must provide the name of the individual and provide at least two items of identification (date of birth, employee identification number, dates of employment or similar information). The address is the same as indicated in the notification procedure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Individuals who are current or former employees of the agency; (2) General Services Administration Agency Liaison Division.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Time and Attendance Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Time and attendance reports, leave slips and audit reports which contain the name, SSN, grade, leave category, leave balances and organization code.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 CFR Part 630.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To provide control, reporting and accounting for employee leave.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. To provide information to a Member of Congress from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the employee or contractor.
</p><p>B. To disclose information to another Federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.
</p><p>C. Information may be disclosed to any civil or criminal law enforcement agency, whether Federal, state, or local or foreign, which requires information relevant to a civil or criminal investigation.
</p><p>D. Information may be disclosed to officials and employees of any Federal agency which requires information relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring, appointment or retention of an employee; the issuance of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation or the classification of a job.
</p><p>E. Relevant information may be disclosed in a proceeding before an administrative forum, including Ad Hoc forums, which may or may not include an Administrative Law Judge, and which may or may not convene public hearings/proceedings, or to other established adjudicatory or regulatory agencies, <i>e.g.</i>, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, or other agencies with similar or related statutory responsibilities, where necessary to adjudicate decisions affecting individuals who are employed by the Board and who are covered by this system, including (but not limited to) decisions to effect any necessary remedial actions, <i>e.g.</i>, debt collection activity, disciplinary and/or other appropriate personnel actions, and/or other law enforcement related actions where appropriate.
</p><p>F. To the appropriate Federal, state, local, foreign or other public authority responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order where the Board becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.
</p><p>G. To disclose to the Office of Personnel Management in accordance with the agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of the Federal personnel management.
</p><p>H. To disclose information to the General Services Administration Agency Liaison Division to effect maintenance of leave.
</p><p>I. A record may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration and to the General Services Administration during a records management inspection conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The information is stored manually in individual folders. Electronic access to the information is maintained on a password protected computer.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is retrieved by the name of the individual employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is either locked in a file cabinet or in offices that are locked.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is maintained and disposed of in accordance with General Record Schedule 2.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Assistant, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Inquiries concerning this system should be directed to the Freedom of Information Act Office, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To locate a specific record, you must provide the name of the individual and provide at least two items of identification (date of birth, employee identification number, or similar information). The address is the same as indicated in the notification procedure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Current and former employees; (2) current and former Time and Attendance personnel; (3) current or former employers; (4) General Services Administration Agency Liaison Division staff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Training Management System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of the agency.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records containing the type and dates of training programs for Board employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To track individual employees and their training history, class schedules, attendance and to ensure prerequisites have been met.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. Information is maintained to assist in performing the administrative functions of the Training Office and is used to prepare class directories, class rosters and statistical reports.
</p><p>B. To provide information to a Member of Congress from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the employee or contractor.
</p><p>C. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service or job for the Board.
</p><p>D. A record may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration and to the General Services Administration during a records management inspection conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Information is stored manually in individual file folders and electronically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is retrieved by the name of the individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The manual records are maintained in locked file cabinets and the automated portion is maintained on a password-protected computer.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is maintained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 1.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Administrative Officer, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Inquiries concerning this system should be directed to the Freedom of Information Act Office, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To locate a specific record, you must provide the name of the individual and provide at least two items of identification (date of birth, employee identification number, or similar information). The address is the same as indicated in the notification procedure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Current or former employees; (2) individuals from other Federal, state and local agencies; and (3) individuals from formally established training centers who may train agency employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Freedom of Information-Privacy Act System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Individuals or organizations who have requested access to information pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act; (2) individuals who have made a request to access or correct records pertaining to themselves; and (3) persons who, on behalf of another individual, have made a request to access or correct that individual's records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) Records contain Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act requests for Board records requested and any other correspondence or internal memoranda related to the processing of these requests; records will also contain such data as the name of requester, address of requester, and subject of request; (2) documents relevant to appeals and litigation under the Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552 and 552a.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To assist Board staff in carrying out their responsibilities under the Freedom of Information Act and the Privacy Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. Public information permitted to be released to the news media and the public may be made available unless it is determined that release of the specific information in the context of a particular record would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.
</p><p>B. To provide information to a Member of Congress from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that Member made at the request of the employee or contractor.
</p><p>C. Information may be disseminated to a Federal agency which furnished the record for the purpose of permitting a decision as to access or correction to be made by that agency or for the purpose of consulting with that agency as to the propriety of access or correction.
</p><p>D. Records may be disseminated to any appropriate Federal, state, local or foreign agency for the purpose of verifying the accuracy of information submitted by an individual who has requested amendment or correction of records.
</p><p>E. Release of information to the National Archives and Records Administration and the General Services Administration during a records management inspection conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Manual requests are stored in a locked file cabinet. Automated information is contained on a password-protected computer.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests are retrieved and filed under the name and/or personal identifier of the requester or subject of the request.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to records is limited to Board staff who have a need for the records to perform their official duties. Request files are stored in a locked file cabinet.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with General Records Schedule 14.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>General Counsel, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record, should make a written request to the Freedom of Information Act Office, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To locate a specific record, you must provide the name of the individual and provide at least two items of identification (date of birth, employee identification number, or similar information). The address is the same as indicated in the notification procedure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is derived from the individuals and/or companies making requests, the system of records searched in the process of responding to requests, and other agencies referring requests for access to or correction of records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None. Although no exemption has been claimed for this system of records, certain information may be duplicative of records contained in another system of records which may have an exemption. In those circumstances, the exemption will still apply.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Applicants for Employment Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons who have applied for Federal employment or are employed in the Federal service.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records contain information relating to the education and training; employment history and earnings; appraisal of past performance; convictions and offenses against the law; results from written test; appraisal of potential; honors, awards or fellowships; military service; veterans preference, birthplace; date of birth; SSN; and home address of persons who have applied for Federal employment or are employed in the Federal services and correspondence related thereto. These records may also include information concerning the date of application, qualification status, employment consideration, priority grouping, and other information relating to the consideration of the individual for employment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 1302, 3301, 3302, Executive Order 10577.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are used to determine individuals' eligibility and evaluate their qualifications for placement in positions within the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. To respond to requests for information from the Office of Personnel Management to the extent their request is compatible with the purpose for which the records are maintained.
</p><p>B. To disclose information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from a Member of Congress made at the request of that individual.
</p><p>C. In the event of litigation where the defendant is (1) the Board, or any employee of the Board in his or her official capacity; (2) the United States where the Board determines that the claim, if successful, is likely to directly affect the operations of the Board; or (3) any Board employee in his or her individual capacity where the Justice Department has agreed to represent such employee, the Board may disclose such records as it deems desirable or necessary to the Department of Justice to enable that Department to present an effective defense provided such disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>D. In the event that this system of records indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>E. Information may be disclosed as a "routine use" to a Federal, state or local agency maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement records or other pertinent records, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain a record relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit. Information may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the record is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.
</p><p>F. Where Federal agencies have the power to subpoena other Federal agencies' records, such as the Internal Revenue Service or the Civil Rights Commission, issue a subpoena to the Board for records, the Board will make such records available.
</p><p>G. Information may be disclosed to student volunteers, individuals working under a personal services contract, and other individuals performing functions for the Board but technically not having the status of agency employees, if they need access to the records in order to perform their assigned agency functions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Variously stored in card files, discs, magnetic tape, forms and lists.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by any combination of name, date of birth, SSN, and identification number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to and use of these records are limited to those persons whose official duties require such access. Personnel screening is employed to prevent unauthorized disclosure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained until the applicant is selected for a position, or for two years. After the applicant is selected for a position, the records are filed in the Official Personnel Folder which is retained until the employee leaves the Board. If the applicant is not selected for a position within two years, the records are destroyed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Mission Support Services, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Inquiries concerning this system should be directed to the Freedom of Information Act Office, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>To locate a specific record, you must provide the name of the individual and provide at least two items of identification (date of birth, employee identification number, or similar information). The address is the same as indicated in the notification procedure.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Contact the official at the address specified under notification procedure above and reasonably identify the record and specify the information to be contested.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The information is provided by current and former employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb9" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Section 1512 Data System (1512 Data System).
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>The principal location for the system, including hard copy and electronic files, is the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, located at 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006. The physical location for the <i>FederalReporting.gov</i> records is 10007 South 51st Street, Phoenix, AZ 85044.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records on recipients and subrecipients (including vendors) of Recovery Act funds, as well as recipients of any other funds that Congress mandates are subject to the accountability and transparency provisions of Title XV of the Recovery Act. Some of these recipients, subrecipients, or vendors may be individuals and/or sole proprietors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records submitted by any means to the Board in connection with the Board's mission reflected in the accountability and transparency requirements of Title XV of the Recovery Act, which may include reports submitted through <i>FederalReporting.gov,</i> and data on recipients and subrecipients (including vendors) provided by states, localities, and other public entities or on behalf of such entities. The system will also store <i>FederalReporting.gov's</i> system-generated data, such as the recipient's electronic report submission date and time, and other identifiers for internal tracking.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Recovery Act was enacted on February 17, 2009, in order to make supplemental appropriations for job preservation and creation, infrastructure investment, energy efficiency and science, assistance to the unemployed, and State and local fiscal stabilization. The Recovery Act established the Board to coordinate and conduct oversight of Recovery Act funds to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of collecting this information is to provide the public with information as to how the government spends money, and also to assist with the Board's efforts to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse of Recovery Act funds and other federal funds for which the Board has been assigned oversight responsibilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1512 Data System records will be used to collect information about recipient, subrecipient, and vendor use of Recovery Act funds and other federal funds for which the Board has been assigned oversight responsibilities, as well as to populate public-facing government Web sites where such data release has been legislated pursuant to statute. The records may also be used for auditing or other internal purpose of the Board, including but not limited to: investigation of possible fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement of Recovery Act funds; litigation purposes related to information reported to the Board; and contacting the recipient in the event of a system modification or change to <i>FederalReporting.gov,</i> including the data elements required to be reported.
</p><p>The Board may disclose information contained in a record in this system of records under the routine uses listed in this notice without the consent of the individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purposes for which the record was collected.
</p><p>The general routine uses for the Board's 1512 Data System records are listed as follows:
</p><p>A. As set forth above, 1512 Data System records may be disclosed in order to populate public-facing government Web sites when disclosure of certain data elements is consistent with applicable statutes and applicable implementing guidance from the Office of Management and Budget (OMB).
</p><p>B. Information may be disclosed to the appropriate federal, state, local, or tribal agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.
</p><p>C. Disclosure may be made to a federal, state, local, or tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit. That entity, authority or licensing organization may then make a request supported by the written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses.
</p><p>D. Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.
</p><p>E. Information may be disclosed to the Department of Justice (DOJ), or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Board is authorized to appear, when:
</p><p>1. The Board, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>2. Any employee of the Board in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>3. Any employee of the Board in his or her individual capacity where the DOJ or the Board has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>4. The United States, if the Board determines that litigation is likely to affect the Board or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ or the Board is deemed by the Board to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case it has been determined that the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>F. Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections.
</p><p>G. Information may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Board and who have a need to have access to the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The 1512 Data System records will be stored in digital format on a digital storage device. Long-term 1512 Data System records will be stored on magnetic tape format. All record storage procedures are in accordance with current applicable regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by database management systems software designed to retrieve data elements based upon role-based user access privileges.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The Board has minimized the risk of unauthorized access to the system by establishing a secure environment for exchanging electronic information. There are multiple layers of security to physical access to the system. The entire complex is patrolled by security during non-business hours. Physical access to the data system housed within the facility is controlled by a computerized badge-reading system. Multiple levels of security are maintained via dual factor authentication for access using biometrics. The computer system offers a high degree of resistance to tampering and circumvention. This system limits data access to Board and contract staff on a need-to-know basis, and controls individuals' ability to access and alter records within the system. All users of the system of records are given a unique user identification (ID) with personal identifiers. All interactions between the system and the authorized individual users are recorded.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The Board will retain and dispose of these records in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 20, Item 1.c. This schedule provides disposal authorization for electronic files and hard copy printouts created to monitor system usage, including but not limited to log-in files, audit trail files, system usage files, and cost-back files used to access charges for system use. Records will be deleted or destroyed when the Board determines they are no longer needed for administrative, legal, audit, or other program purposes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Michael Wood, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record should make a written request to the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for record access shall follow the directions described under Notification Procedure and will be addressed to the system manager at the address listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>If you wish to contest a record in the system of records, contact the system manager and identify the record to be changed, identify the corrective action sought, and provide a written justification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is obtained from recipients and subrecipients (including vendors) of Recovery Act funds or other federal funds for which the Board has been assigned oversight responsibilities; federal, state, local, and foreign agencies; and public-source materials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">FederalReporting.gov Recipient Registration System (FRRS).
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>The principal management entity for the FRRS system is the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, located at 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006. The physical location for the system will be the CGI Phoenix Data Center, located at 10007 South 51st Street, Phoenix, AZ 85044. The system will be operated at this facility.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records on all individuals that have either attempted to register or have registered to obtain an account to use FederalReporting.gov to report recipient data elements related to Recovery funds.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records including individual's name, self-assigned user name and security question, work address and related contact information (<i>e.g.</i>, phone and fax numbers, e-mail address), organizational point of contact, and related contact information. The individual registering for FederalReporting.gov will generate a self-assigned password that will be stored on the FRRS, but will only be accessible to the registering individual. The system will also store other system-generated data such as the registration date, time, and other identifiers for internal tracking. Upon assignment of the password and ID code, the user may subsequently access FederalReporting.gov by entering these data.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Recovery Act was enacted on February 17, 2009, in order to make supplemental appropriations for job preservation and creation, infrastructure investment, energy efficiency and science, assistance to the unemployed, and State and local fiscal stabilization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>FederalReporting.gov is the Board's inbound Recovery reporting solution. Recipients of Recovery funds are required to disclose certain information, which must then be posted on the public-facing Web site, Recovery.gov. The purpose of collecting this information is to provide the public with information as to how the government spends money, and also to assist with the prevention of fraud, waste, and mismanagement of Recovery funds. FRRS was developed to protect the Board and FederalReporting.gov users from individuals seeking to gain unauthorized access to user accounts on FederalReporting.gov. FederalReporting.gov is the sole source for reporting Recovery Act information.
</p><p>The information contained in records maintained in the FRRS is used for the purposes of verifying the identity of the individual, allowing individual users to establish an account on FederalReporting.gov, providing individual users access to their FederalReporting.gov account for reporting data, allowing individual users to customize, update or terminate their account with FederalReporting.gov, renewing or revoking an individual user's account on FederalReporting.gov, supporting the FederalReporting.gov help desk functions, investigating possible fraud and verifying compliance with program regulations, and initiating legal action against an individual involved in program fraud, abuse, or noncompliance. The information is also used to provide authenticated protected access to FederalReporting.gov, thereby protecting FederalReporting.gov and FederalReporting.gov users from potential harm caused by individuals with malicious intentions gaining unauthorized access to the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>FRRS records will be used to facilitate registering FederalReporting.gov system users, issuing a username and password, and subsequently, verifying an individual's identity as he/she seeks to gain routine access to his/her account. In some cases, the organizational point of contact has the ability to deny access or reporting privileges for the organization, based on the registration information provided by the user. The system has secondary uses that include: using the established username to facilitate tracking service calls or e-mails from the user in the event that there is a change in registration status or a problem the user has with FederalReporting.gov; facilitating the retrieval of user actions (<i>e.g.</i>, historical submissions and help tickets) and events while on the FederalReporting.gov system. The records may also be subsequently used for auditing or other internal purpose of the Board, including but not limited to: Instances where enforcement of the conditions of using FederalReporting.gov are necessary; investigation of possible fraud involving a registered user; litigation purposes related to information reported to the Board; contacting the individual in the event of a system modification; a change to FederalReporting.gov; or modification, revocation or termination of user's access privileges to FederalReporting.gov.
</p><p>The Board may disclose information contained in a record in this system of records under the routine uses listed in this notice without the consent of the individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purposes for which the record was collected.
</p><p>The general routine uses for the Board's FRRS are listed as follows:
</p><p>A. Information may be disclosed to the appropriate Federal, State, local, or Tribal agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.
</p><p>B. Disclosure may be made to a Federal, State, local, or Tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit. That entity, authority or licensing organization may then make a request supported by the written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses.
</p><p>C. Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.
</p><p>D. Information may be disclosed to the Department of Justice (DOJ), or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Board is authorized to appear, when:
</p><p>1. The Board, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>2. Any employee of the Board in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>3. Any employee of the Board in his or her individual capacity where the DOJ or the Board has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>4. The United States, if the Board determines that litigation is likely to affect the Board or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ or the Board is deemed by the Board to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case it has been determined that the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>E. Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections.
</p><p>F. Information may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Board and who have a need to have access to the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The FRRS records will be stored in digital format on a digital storage device. Long-term FRRS Data System records will be stored on magnetic tape format. All record storage procedures are in accordance with current applicable regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by database management systems software designed to retrieve FRRS elements based upon role-based user access privileges. Records are retrievable by the FRRS user name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The Board has minimized the risk of unauthorized access to the system by establishing a secure environment for exchanging electronic information. Physical access uses a defense in-depth approach restricting access at each layer closest to where the actual system resides. The entire complex is patrolled by security during non-business hours. Physical access to the data system housed within the facility is controlled by a computerized badge reading system. Multiple levels of security are maintained via dual factor authentication for access using biometrics. The computer system offers a high degree of resistance to tampering and circumvention. This system limits data access to Board and contract staff on a need-to-know basis, and controls individuals' ability to access and alter records within the system. All users of the system of records are given a unique user identification (ID) with personal identifiers. All interactions between the system and the authorized individual users are recorded.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The Board will retain and dispose of these records in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 20, Item 1.c. This schedule provides disposal authorization for electronic files and hard copy printouts created to monitor system usage, including but not limited to log-in files, audit trail files, system usage files, and cost-back files used to access charges for system use. Records will be deleted or destroyed when the Board determines they are no longer needed for administrative, legal, audit, or other program purposes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Michael Wood, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her, who wants access to his or her record, or who wants to contest the contents of a record should make a written request to the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for record access shall follow the directions described under Notification Procedure and will be addressed to the system manager at the address listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>If you wish to contest a record in the system of records, contact the system manager and identify the record to be changed, identify the corrective action sought, and provide a written justification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is obtained from individuals who have had or seek to have their identity authenticated except that a password and a username are explicitly self-assigned by the user registering to gain access to FederalReporting.gov.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Oversight Support.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Controlled Unclassified Information.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The principal location of the system is the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>This system contains records on individuals who relate to official Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board (Board) efforts undertaken in support of its oversight responsibilities reflected in the authorities listed in the Authority for Maintenance of the System section below.  These individuals include:</p>
<p> (a) Individuals who are or have been the subject of investigations or inquiries identified by or submitted to the Board;</p>
<p>(b) Individuals who are or have been witnesses, complainants, or informants in investigations or inquiries identified by or submitted to the Board; </p>
<p>(c) Individuals who are or have been potential subjects or parties to an investigation or inquiry identified by or submitted to the Board; and</p>
<p>(d) Individuals who are or have been related to entities or individuals that are or have been a subject of, potential subject of, or party to an investigation or inquiry identified by or submitted to the Board.</p>
<p>The system also contains records concerning individuals in their entrepreneurial capacity, corporations, and other business entities.  These records are not subject to the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a), as amended.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information relating to investigations and inquiries identified by or submitted to the Board, including:</p>
<p>(a) Letters, memoranda, and other documents describing complaints, derogatory information, or alleged criminal, civil, or administrative misconduct; and</p>
<p>(b) General intelligence and relevant data, leads for Inspectors General (or other applicable oversight and law enforcement entities), reports of investigations and related exhibits, statements and affidavits, and records obtained during an investigation or inquiry.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, §§ 1521, 1523(a)(1), Pub. L. 111-5, 123 Stat. 115, 289-90 (2009) (Recovery Act), Education Jobs Fund, Pub. L. 111-226, § 101, 124 Stat. 2389 (2010), and Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013, § 904(d), Pub. L. 113-2, 127 Stat. 4, 18 (2013), as well as in accordance with the Board’s responsibility to develop and test technology resources and oversight mechanisms to detect and remediate fraud, waste, and abuse in federal spending (see, e.g., Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015, Pub. L. 113-235, 128 Stat. 2130, 2369 (2014)).</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purpose of this system of records is to enable the Board to carry out its oversight responsibilities under applicable law, including but not necessarily limited to:  coordinating with others and conducting oversight to detect and prevent fraud, waste, and abuse of Recovery Act and Education Jobs Fund funds; developing and using information technology resources and oversight mechanisms to detect and remediate waste, fraud and abuse in the obligation and expenditure of funds appropriated for purposes related to the impact of Hurricane Sandy; and developing and testing information technology resources and oversight mechanisms to enhance transparency of and detect and remediate waste, fraud, and abuse in all federal spending for use by the Board and other federal agencies and entities.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)), the records or information contained in this system of records may specifically be disclosed outside the Board as a routine use pursuant to the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3)) as follows: </p>
<p> A.  To the appropriate federal, state, local, or tribal agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.</p>
<p> B. To any individual or entity when necessary to elicit information that will assist in a Board review or audit.</p>
<p> C.  To appropriate officials and employees of a federal agency or entity that require information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an individual; the issuance, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance; or the execution of a security or suitability investigation.</p>
<p> D.  To provide responses to queries from federal agencies and entities, including but not limited to regulatory and law enforcement agencies, regarding federal fund recipients, subrecipients, or vendors, or those seeking federal funds, when the information is relevant to a determination related to or arising out of a past, present or prospective (i) contract or (ii) grant or other benefit.  </p>
<p> E.  To a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member's behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
<p> F.  Information may be disclosed to the Department of Justice (DOJ), or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Board is authorized to appear, when:</p>
<p> 1.  The Board, or any component thereof; or</p>
<p> 2.  Any employee of the Board in his or her official capacity; or</p>
<p> 3.  Any employee of the Board in his or her individual capacity where the DOJ or the Board has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
<p> 4.  The United States, if the Board determines that litigation is likely to affect the Board or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ or the Board is deemed by the Board to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case it has been determined that the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
<p> G.  Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections.</p>
<p> H.  Information may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Board and who have a need to access the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Board.</p>
<p> I.  To appropriate federal agencies or entities that will act as successor legal and/or physical custodians of the information disclosed from the system.</p>
<p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:  </p>
<p>Not applicable.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Storage: </p>
<p>Information in this system is stored electronically on digital storage devices or as hard copy files.  All record storage procedures are in accordance with current applicable regulations. </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Records are retrievable by database management systems software designed to retrieve data elements based upon role-based user access privileges.  Records may be retrieved by personal identifiers such as, but not limited to, name, social security number, date of birth, or telephone number.  Records may also be retrieved by non-personal information such as file number, entity/institution name, subject matter, agency involved, or other information.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The Board has minimized the risk of unauthorized access to the system by establishing a secure environment for exchanging electronic information.  Physical access to the data system housed within the facility is controlled by Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) compliant access controlled systems.  The entire complex is patrolled by security during non-business hours.   The computer system offers a high degree of resistance to tampering and circumvention and limits data access to Board and contract staff on a need-to-know basis.  Individuals’ ability to access and alter records within the system is controlled.  All users of the system of records are provided a unique user identification (ID) with personal identifiers.  User IDs are consistent with the above referenced role-based access privileges to maintain proper security of law enforcement and any other sensitive information.  In concert with access controls, audit trails are used to record user and system activity within the system and its associated applications.</p>
<p> Paper records are maintained in file cabinets which may be locked or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Board personnel will review records on a periodic basis to determine whether they should be retained or modified.  Further, the Board will retain and dispose of these records in accordance with Board Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Executive Director, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Address inquiries to the System Manager listed above.  Note that the major part of this system is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2).  See "System Exempted from Certain Provisions of the Act" below.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The major part of this system is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2).  See "System Exempted from Certain Provisions of the Act" below.  To the extent that this system is not subject to exemption, it is subject to access. A determination as to exemption shall be made at the time a request for access is received.  A request for access to records contained in this system shall be made in writing, with the envelope and the letter clearly marked "Privacy Access Request." Include in the request the full name of the individual involved, his or her current address, date and place of birth, notarized signature (or submitted with date and signature under penalty of perjury), and any other identifying number or information which may be of assistance in locating the record.  The requester shall also provide a return address for transmitting the information.  Access requests shall be directed to the System Manager listed above.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Requesters shall direct their request to the System Manager listed above, stating clearly and concisely what information is being contested, the reason for contesting it, and the proposed amendment to the information.  Note that the major part of this system is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2).  See "System Exempted from Certain Provisions of the Act" below.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The subjects of investigations and inquiries; individuals and entities with which the subjects of investigations and inquiries are associated; federal, state, local, and foreign law enforcement and non-law enforcement agencies and entities; private citizens; witnesses; informants; and public and/or commercially available source materials.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The Board has exempted this system from the following provisions of the Privacy Act pursuant to the general authority in 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2):  5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) and (c)(4); (d); (e)(1), (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4)(G)-(I), (e)(5), and (e)(8); (f); and (g).  Additionally, the Board has exempted this system from the following provisions of the Privacy Act pursuant to the general authority in 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2):  5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3); (d); (e)(1) and (e)(4)(G)-(H); and (f).

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">RATB Fraud Hotline Program Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The majority of the information in the system is Sensitive but Unclassified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, located at 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons who report information to the RATB concerning the possible existence of activities constituting a violation of law, rules, or regulations, fraud, abuse, mismanagement, or gross waste of funds, and the subject of the complaints.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Letters, memoranda, other communications and documents describing complaints of alleged criminal, civil, or administrative misconduct relating to covered funds.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The RATB's enabling legislation, the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (Pub. L. 111-5) (Recovery Act), sections 1521 <i>et seq.</i>
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of this system of records is to enable the RATB to carry out its responsibilities under its enabling legislation, the Recovery Act. The RATB is statutorily directed to coordinate and conduct oversight of covered funds to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the RATB as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>A. To the appropriate federal, state, local, or tribal agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.
</p><p>B. To any individual or entity when necessary to elicit information that will assist an RATB review or audit.
</p><p>C. To appropriate officials and employees of a federal agency or entity which requires information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring, appointment, or retention of an individual; the issuance, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a security clearance; the execution of a security or suitability investigation; the letting of a contract; or the issuance or revocation of a grant or other benefit.
</p><p>D. To a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member's behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.
</p><p>E. Information may be disclosed to the Department of Justice (DOJ), or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the RATB is authorized to appear, when:
</p><p>1. The RATB, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>2. Any employee of the RATB in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>3. Any employee of the RATB in his or her individual capacity where the DOJ or the RATB has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>4. The United States, if the RATB determines that litigation is likely to affect the RATB or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ or the RATB is deemed by the RATB to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case it has been determined that the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>F. Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections.
</p><p>G. Information may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the RATB and who have a need to have access to the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the RATB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Hard copy files and a computer database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by case number or subject name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computer records are maintained in a secure, password protected computer system. Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets. All records are maintained in secure, access-controlled areas or buildings.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records will be retained and disposed of in accordance with RATB Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Director, Investigations, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Address inquiries to the System Manager listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The major part of this system is exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) and (k)(5). To the extent that this system is not subject to exemption, it is subject to access. A determination as to exemption shall be made at the time a request for access is received. A request for access to records contained in this system shall be made in writing, with the envelope and the letter clearly marked "Privacy Access Request." Include in the request the full name of the individual involved, his or her current address, date and place of birth, notarized signature (or submitted with date and signature under penalty of perjury), and any other identifying number or information which may be of assistance in locating the record. The requester shall also provide a return address for transmitting the information. Access requests shall be directed to the System Manager listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requesters shall direct their request to the System Manager listed above, stating clearly and concisely what information is being contested, the reason for contesting it, and the proposed amendment to the information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Complainants who are employees of federal, state, and local agencies, and private citizens. Records in the system come from complainants through the telephone, mail, electronic mail, facsimile, and the web site <i>http://www.recovery.gov.</i>
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ratb13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">FederalAccountability.gov System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>Controlled Unclassified Information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>The principal location for the system is the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, located at 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records on individuals acting in a personal capacity who relate to official Board efforts undertaken in support of its mission to coordinate and conduct oversight of Recovery Act funds to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse, and to develop and test technology resources and oversight mechanisms to detect and remediate fraud, waste, and abuse in Federal spending. These individuals include but are not limited to those that have applied for, sought, or received Federal funds. The system also contains records concerning individuals in their entrepreneurial capacity, corporations, and other business entities. These records are not subject to the Privacy Act.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Every possible type of information that contributes to effective oversight of fraud, waste, and abuse of Federal spending may be maintained in this system of records, including but not limited to records on Federal funding recipients and subrecipients (including vendors) and records on other individuals, corporations, sole proprietors, and other legal entities that have applied for, sought, or received Federal funds.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Recovery Act established the Board to coordinate and conduct oversight of Recovery Act funds to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse. Public Law 111-5, &#167;&#167; 1521, 1523(a)(1). The Education Jobs Fund required, among other things, that the funds it appropriated be administered under the same accountability provisions as Recovery Act funds. Public Law 111-226, &#167; 101. The Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2012 provided appropriations for the Board "to develop and test information technology resources and oversight mechanisms to * * * detect and remediate waste, fraud, and abuse in Federal spending." Public Law 112-74.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of collecting this information is to assist with the Board's efforts to detect and prevent fraud, waste, and abuse of Federal funds. By collecting data that is relevant to determinations of recipient and potential recipient responsibility and risk, the Board can create technology resources and oversight tools to be utilized by the Board and by other agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the FederalAccountability.gov System may be used:
</p><p>A. For auditing or other internal purpose of the Board, including but not limited to: review, analysis, and investigation of possible fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement of Federal funds.
</p><p>B. To provide responses to queries from Federal agencies, including but not limited to regulatory and law enforcement agencies, regarding Federal fund recipients, subrecipients, or vendors, or those seeking Federal funds.
</p><p>C. To furnish information to the appropriate Federal, state, local, or tribal agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information is relevant to a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.
</p><p>D. To disclose information to a Federal, state, local, or tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee or retention of a security clearance. That entity, authority, or licensing organization may then make a request supported by the written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses.
</p><p>E. To disclose information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.
</p><p>F. To disclose information to the Department of Justice (DOJ), or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Board is authorized to appear, when:
</p><p>1. The Board, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>2. Any employee of the Board in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>3. Any employee of the Board in his or her individual capacity where the DOJ or the Board has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>4. The United States, if the Board determines that litigation is likely to affect the Board or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ or the Board is deemed by the Board to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case it has been determined that the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>G. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections.
</p><p>H. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Board and who have a need to have access to the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Board.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The FederalAccountability.gov System records will be stored in digital format on a digital storage device. All record storage procedures are in accordance with current applicable regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrievable by database management systems software designed to retrieve data elements based upon role-based (<i>e.g.,</i> law enforcement or non-law enforcement) user access privileges.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The Board has minimized the risk of unauthorized access to the system by establishing a secure environment for exchanging electronic information. Physical access uses a defense in-depth approach restricting access at each layer closest to where the actual system resides. The entire complex is patrolled by security during non-business hours. Physical access to the data system housed within the facility is controlled by a computerized badge-reading system. Multiple levels of security are maintained via dual factor authentication for access using biometrics. The computer system offers a high degree of resistance to tampering and circumvention. This system limits data access to Board and contract staff on a need-to-know basis, and controls individuals' ability to access and alter records within the system. All users of the system of records are given a unique user identification (ID) with personal identifiers, and those user IDs are consistent with the above referenced role-based access privileges to maintain proper security of law enforcement and any other sensitive information. All interactions between the system and the authorized individual users are recorded.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Board personnel will review records on a periodic basis to determine whether they should be retained or modified. Further, the Board will retain and dispose of these records in accordance with Board Records Control Schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Michael Wood, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual who wants to know whether this system of records contains a record about him or her acting in a personal capacity, who wants access to such records, or who wants to contest the contents of such records should make a written request to the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for record access shall follow the directions described under Notification Procedure and will be addressed to the system manager at the address listed above. To the extent a portion of this system contains law enforcement records, such records are exempt from this requirement pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2) and (k)(2). To the extent that such law enforcement records are not subject to exemption, they are subject to access. A determination as to exemption shall be made at the time a request for access is received. Access requests shall be directed to the System Manager listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>If you wish to contest a record in the system of records, contact the system manager and identify the record to be changed, identify the corrective action sought, and provide a written justification.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information may be obtained from recipients and subrecipients (including vendors) of Recovery Act funds or other Federal funds for which the Board has been assigned responsibilities; Federal, state, and local agencies; public-source and/or commercially available materials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>


	<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="4">
<heading> Accounts </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="II">
<heading> Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board </heading>
<regulationsPart number="200">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>200.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>200.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>200.3 Privacy Act records maintained by the Board.
</p>
<p>200.4 Privacy Act inquiries.
</p>
<p>200.5 Requests for access to records.
</p>
<p>200.6 Processing of requests.
</p>
<p>200.7 Fees.
</p>
<p>200.8 Appealing denials of access.
</p>
<p>200.9 Requests for correction of records.
</p>
<p>200.10 Disclosure of records to third parties.
</p>
<p>200.11 Maintaining records of disclosures.
</p>
<p>200.12 Notification of systems of Privacy Act records.
</p>
<p>200.13 Privacy Act training.
</p>
<p>200.14 Responsibility for maintaining adequate safeguards.
</p>
<p>200.15 Systems of records covered by exemptions.
</p>
<p>200.16 Mailing lists.
</p>
<p>200.17 Exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a(f).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 74 FR 60127, Nov. 20, 2009, unless otherwise noted.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.1
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>This part sets forth the policies and procedures of the Board regarding access to systems of records maintained by the Board under the Privacy Act, Public Law 93-579, 5 U.S.C. 552a. The provisions in the Act shall take precedence over any part of the Board’s regulations in conflict with the Act. These regulations establish procedures by which an individual may exercise the rights granted by the Privacy Act to determine whether a Board system of records contains a record pertaining to him or her; to gain access to such records; and to request correction or amendment of such records. These regulations also set identification requirements and prescribe fees to be charged for copying records.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>As used in this part:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Agency</i> means any executive department, military department, government corporation, or other establishment in the executive branch of the federal government, including the Executive Office of the President or any independent regulatory agency;
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Individual</i> means any citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Maintain</i> means to collect, use, store, or disseminate records as well as any combination of these recordkeeping functions. The term also includes exercise of control over, and therefore responsibility and accountability for, systems of records;
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by the Board and contains the individual’s name or other identifying information, such as a number or symbol assigned to the individual or his or her fingerprint, voice print, or photograph. The term includes, but is not limited to, information regarding an individual’s education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history;
</p>
<p>(e) <i>System of records</i> means a group of records under the control of the Board from which information is retrievable by use of the name of the individual or by some number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual;
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of a record for a purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Designated Privacy Act Officer</i> means the person named by the Board to administer the Board’s activities in regard to the regulations in this part;
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Executive Director</i> means the chief operating officer of the Board;
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Days</i> means standard working days, excluding weekends and federal holidays.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.3
 Privacy Act records maintained by the Board.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Board shall maintain only such information about an individual as is relevant and necessary to accomplish a purpose of the agency required by statute or by Executive Order of the President. In addition, the Board shall maintain all records that are used in making determinations about any individual with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to ensure fairness to that individual in the making of any determination about him or her. However, the Board shall not be required to update retired records.
</p>
<p>(b) The Board shall not maintain any record about any individual with respect to or describing how such individual exercises rights guaranteed by the First Amendment of the Constitution of the United States, unless expressly authorized by statute or by the subject individual, or unless pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized law enforcement activity.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.4
 Privacy Act inquiries.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Inquiries regarding the contents of record systems.</i> Any person wanting to know whether the Board’s systems of records contain a record pertaining to him or her may file an inquiry in person, by mail or by telephone.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Inquiries in person</i> may be submitted at the Board’s headquarters located at 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006. Inquiries should be marked "Privacy Act Inquiry" on each page of the inquiry and on the front of the envelope and directed to the Privacy Act Officer.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Inquiries by mail</i> may be sent to: Privacy Act Officer, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006. "Privacy Act Inquiry" should be written on the envelope and each page of the inquiry.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Telephone inquiries</i> may be made by calling the Board’s Privacy Act Officer at (202) 254-7900.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.5
 Requests for access to records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) All requests for records should include the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) Full name, address, and telephone number of requester.
</p>
<p>(2) The system of records containing the desired information.
</p>
<p>(3) Any other information that the requester believes would help locate the record.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Requests in writing.</i> A person may request access to his or her own records in writing by addressing a letter to: Privacy Act Officer, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Requests by fax.</i> A person may request access to his or her records by facsimile at (202) 254-7970.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Requests by phone.</i> A person may request access to his or her records by calling the Privacy Act Officer at (202) 254-7900.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Requests in person.</i> Any person may examine and request copies of his or her own records on the Board’s premises. The requester should contact the Board’s office at least one week before the desired appointment date. This request may be made to the Privacy Act Officer in writing or by calling (202) 254-7900. Before viewing the records, proof of identification must be provided. The identification should be a valid copy of one of the following:
</p>
<p>(1) A government ID;
</p>
<p>(2) A driver’s license;
</p>
<p>(3) A passport; or
</p>
<p>(4) Other current identification that contains both an address and a picture of the requester.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.6
 Processing of requests.
</b></p>
<p>Upon receipt of a request for information, the Privacy Act Officer will ascertain whether the records identified by the requester exist, and whether they are subject to any exemption under &#167; 200.15. If the records exist and are not subject to exemption, the Privacy Act Officer will provide the information.
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Requests in writing, including those sent by fax.</i> Within five working days of receiving the request, the Privacy Act Officer will acknowledge its receipt and will advise the requester of any additional information that may be needed. Within 15 working days of receiving the request, the Privacy Act Officer will send the requested information or will explain to the requester why additional time is needed for a response.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Requests in person or by telephone.</i> Within 15 days of the initial request, the Privacy Act Officer will contact the requester and arrange an appointment at a mutually agreeable time when the record can be examined. The requester may be accompanied by no more than one person. In such case, the requestor must inform the Privacy Act Officer that a second individual will be present and must sign a statement authorizing disclosure of the records to that person. The statement will be kept with the requester’s records. At the appointment, the requester will be asked to present identification as stated in &#167; 200.5(e).
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Excluded information.</i> If a request is received for information compiled in reasonable anticipation of litigation, the Privacy Act Officer will inform the requester that the information is not subject to release under the Privacy Act (see 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(5)).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.7
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>A fee will not be charged for searching, reviewing, or making corrections to records. A fee for copying will be assessed at the same rate established for the Freedom of Information Act requests. Duplication fees for paper copies of a record will be 10 cents per page for black and white and 20 cents per page for color. For all other forms of duplication, the Board will charge the direct costs of producing the copy. However, the first 100 pages of black-and-white copying or its equivalent will be free of charge.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.8
 Appealing denials of access.
</b></p>
<p>(a) If access to records is denied by the Privacy Act Officer, the requester may file an appeal in writing. The appeal should be directed to Executive Director, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006.
</p>
<p>(b) The appeal letter must specify the denied records that are still sought, and state why denial by the Privacy Act Officer is erroneous.
</p>
<p>(c) The Executive Director or his or her designee will respond to appeals within 20 working days of the receipt of the appeal letter. The appeal determination will explain the basis of the decision to deny or grant the appeal.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.9
 Requests for correction of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Correction requests.</i> Any person is entitled to request correction of his or her record(s) covered under the Act. The request must be made in writing and should be addressed to Privacy Act Officer, Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, 1717 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20006. The letter should clearly identify the corrections desired. In most circumstances, an edited copy of the record will be acceptable for this purpose.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Initial response.</i> Receipt of a correction request will be acknowledged by the Privacy Act Officer in writing within five working days. The Privacy Act Officer will provide a letter to the requester within 20 working days stating whether the request for correction has been granted or denied. If the Privacy Act Officer denies any part of the correction request, the reasons for the denial will be provided to the requester.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.10
 Disclosure of records to third parties.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Board will not disclose any record that is contained in a system of records to any person or agency, except with a written request by or with the prior written consent of the individual whose record is requested, unless disclosure of the record is:
</p>
<p>(1) Required by an employee or agent of the Board in the performance of his/her official duties.
</p>
<p>(2) Required under the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552). Records required to be made available by the Freedom of Information Act will be released in response to a request in accordance with the Board’s regulation published at 4 CFR Part 201.
</p>
<p>(3) For a routine use as published in the annual notice in the <i>Federal Register.</i>
</p>
<p>(4) To the Census Bureau for planning or carrying out a census, survey, or related activities pursuant to the provisions of Title 13 of the United States Code.
</p>
<p>(5) To a recipient who has provided the Board with adequate advance written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record and that the record is to be transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable.
</p>
<p>(6) To the National Archives and Records Administration as a record that has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the United States government, or for evaluation by the Archivist of the United States, or his or her designee, to determine whether the record has such value.
</p>
<p>(7) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity, if the activity is authorized by law, and if the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a written request to the Board for such records specifying the particular part desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought. The Board also may disclose such a record to a law enforcement agency on its own initiative in situations in which criminal conduct is suspected, provided that such disclosure has been established as a routine use, or in situations in which the misconduct is directly related to the purpose for which the record is maintained.
</p>
<p>(8) To a person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual if, upon such disclosure, notification is transmitted to the last known address of such individual.
</p>
<p>(9) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of matters within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee.
</p>
<p>(10) To the Comptroller General, or any of his or her authorized representatives, in the course of the performance of official duties of the Government Accountability Office.
</p>
<p>(11) Pursuant to an order of a court of competent jurisdiction. In the event that any record is disclosed under such compulsory legal process, the Board shall make reasonable efforts to notify the subject individual after the process becomes a matter of public record.
</p>
<p>(12) To a consumer reporting agency in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).
</p>
<p>(b) Before disseminating any record about any individual to any person other than a Board employee, the Board shall make reasonable efforts to ensure that the records are, or at the time they were collected, accurate, complete, timely, and relevant. This paragraph (b) does not apply to disseminations made pursuant to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552) and paragraph (a)(2) of this section.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.11
 Maintaining records of disclosure.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Board shall maintain a log containing the date, nature, and purposes of each disclosure of a record to any person or agency. Such accounting also shall contain the name and address of the person or agency to whom or to which each disclosure was made. This log will not include disclosures made to Board employees or agents in the course of their official duties or pursuant to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552).
</p>
<p>(b) An accounting of each disclosure shall be retained for at least five years after the accounting is made or for the life of the record that was disclosed, whichever is longer.
</p>
<p>(c) The Board shall make the accounting of disclosure of a record pertaining to an individual available to that individual at his or her request. Such a request should be made in accordance with the procedures set forth in &#167; 200.5. This paragraph (c) does not apply to disclosure made for law enforcement purposes under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(7) and &#167; 200.10(a)(7).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.12
 Notification of systems of Privacy Act records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Public notice.</i> The Board periodically reviews its systems of records and will publish information about any significant additions or changes to those systems in the <i>Federal Register.</i> Information about systems of records maintained by other agencies that are in the temporary custody of the Board will not be published. In addition, the Office of the Federal Register biennially compiles and publishes all systems of records maintained by all federal agencies, including the Board.
</p>
<p>(b) At least 30 days before publishing additions or changes to the Board’s systems of records, the Board will publish a notice of intent to amend, providing the public with an opportunity to comment on the proposed amendments to its systems of records in the <i>Federal Register.</i>

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.13
 Privacy Act training.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Board shall ensure that all persons involved in the design, development, operation, or maintenance of any Board systems of records are informed of all requirements necessary to protect the privacy of individuals. The Board shall ensure that all employees having access to records receive adequate training in their protection and that records have adequate and proper storage with sufficient security to ensure their privacy.
</p>
<p>(b) All employees shall be informed of the civil remedies provided under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1) and other implications of the Privacy Act and of the fact that the Board may be subject to civil remedies for failure to comply with the provisions of the Privacy Act and the regulations in this part.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.14
 Responsibility for maintaining adequate safeguards.
</b></p>
<p>The Board has the responsibility for maintaining adequate technical, physical, and security safeguards to prevent unauthorized disclosure or destruction of manual and automated records systems. These security safeguards shall apply to all systems of records in which identifiable personal data are processed or maintained, including all reports and output from such systems of records that contain identifiable personal information. Such safeguards must be sufficient to prevent negligent, accidental, or unintentional disclosure, modification, or destruction of any personal records or data; must minimize, to the extent practicable, the risk that skilled technicians or knowledgeable persons could improperly obtain access to modify or destroy such records or data; and shall further ensure against such casual entry by unskilled persons without official reasons for access to such records or data.
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Manual systems.</i> (1) Records contained in a system of records as defined in this part may be used, held, or stored only where facilities are adequate to prevent unauthorized access by persons within or outside the Board.
</p>
<p>(2) Access to and use of a system of records shall be permitted only to persons whose duties require such access to the information for routine uses or for such other uses as may be provided in this part.
</p>
<p>(3) Other than for access by employees or agents of the Board, access to records within a system of records shall be permitted only to the individual to whom the record pertains or upon his or her written request.
</p>
<p>(4) The Board shall ensure that all persons whose duties require access to and use of records contained in a system of records are adequately trained to protect the security and privacy of such records.
</p>
<p>(5) The disposal and destruction of identifiable personal data records shall be done by shredding and in accordance with rules promulgated by the Archivist of the United States.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Automated systems.</i> (1) Identifiable personal information may be processed, stored, or maintained by automated data systems only where facilities or conditions are adequate to prevent unauthorized access to such systems in any form.
</p>
<p>(2) Access to and use of identifiable personal data associated with automated data systems shall be limited to those persons whose duties require such access. Proper control of personal data in any form associated with automated data systems shall be maintained at all times, including maintenance of accountability records showing disposition of input and output documents.
</p>
<p>(3) All persons whose duties require access to processing and maintenance of identifiable personal data and automated systems shall be adequately trained in the security and privacy of personal data.
</p>
<p>(4) The disposal and disposition of identifiable personal data and automated systems shall be done by shredding, burning, or, in the case of electronic records, by degaussing or by overwriting with the appropriate security software, in accordance with regulations of the Archivist of the United States or other appropriate authority.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.15
 Systems of records covered by exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>The Board currently has no exempt systems of records.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.16
 Mailing lists.
</b></p>
<p>The Board shall not sell or rent an individual’s name and/or address unless such action is specifically authorized by law. This section shall not be construed to require the withholding of names and addresses otherwise permitted to be made public.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 200.17
 Exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>General policy.</i> The Privacy Act permits an agency to exempt certain types of systems of records from some of the Privacy Act’s requirements. It is the policy of the Board to exercise authority to exempt systems of records only in compelling cases.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Specific systems of records exempted under (j)(2) and (k)(2).</i> The Board exempts the RATB Investigative Files (RATB-11) system of records from the following provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a:
</p>
<p>(1) From subsection (c)(3) because the release of accounting of disclosure would inform a subject that he or she is under investigation. This information would provide considerable advantage to the subject in providing him or her with knowledge concerning the nature of the investigation and the coordinated investigative efforts and techniques employed by the cooperating agencies. This would greatly impede the Board’s criminal law enforcement duties.
</p>
<p>(2) From subsection (c)(4) and (d) because notification would alert a subject to the fact that an open investigation on that individual is taking place, and might weaken the ongoing investigation, reveal investigatory techniques, and place confidential informants in jeopardy.
</p>
<p>(3) From subsection (e)(1) because the nature of the criminal and/or civil investigative function creates unique problems in prescribing a specific parameter in a particular case with respect to what information is relevant or necessary. Also, due to the Board’s close working relationship with other Federal, state and local law enforcement agencies, information may be received which may relate to a case under the investigative jurisdiction of another agency. The maintenance of this information may be necessary to provide leads for appropriate law enforcement purposes and to establish patterns of activity which may relate to the jurisdiction of other cooperating agencies.
</p>
<p>(4) From subsection (e)(2) because collecting information to the fullest extent possible directly from the subject individual may or may not be practical in a criminal and/or civil investigation.
</p>
<p>(5) From subsection (e)(3) because supplying an individual with a form containing a Privacy Act Statement would tend to inhibit cooperation by many individuals involved in a criminal and/or civil investigation. The effect would be somewhat adverse to established investigative methods and techniques.
</p>
<p>(6) From subsection (e)(4)(G)-(I) because this system of records is exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d).
</p>
<p>(7) From subsection (e)(5) because the requirement that records be maintained with attention to accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness would unfairly hamper the investigative process. It is the nature of law enforcement for investigations to uncover the commission of illegal acts at diverse stages. It is frequently impossible to determine initially what information is accurate, relevant, timely, and least of all complete. With the passage of time, seemingly irrelevant or untimely information may acquire new significance as further investigation brings new details to light.
</p>
<p>(8) From subsection (e)(8) because the notice requirements of this provision could present a serious impediment to law enforcement by revealing investigative techniques, procedures, and existence of confidential investigations.
</p>
<p>(9) From subsection (f) because the agency’s rules are inapplicable to those portions of the system that are exempt and would place the burden on the agency of either confirming or denying the existence of a record pertaining to a requesting individual, which might in itself provide an answer to that individual relating to an ongoing investigation. The conduct of a successful investigation leading to the indictment of a criminal offender precludes the applicability of established agency rules relating to verification of record, disclosure of the record to that individual, and record amendment procedures for this record system.
</p>
<p>(10) For comparability with the exemption claimed from subsection (f), the civil remedies provisions of subsection (g) must be suspended for this record system. Because of the nature of criminal investigations, standards of accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness cannot apply to this record system. Information gathered in an investigation is often fragmentary, and leads relating to an individual in the context of one investigation may instead pertain to a second investigation.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Specific systems of records exempted under (k)(2) and (k)(5).</i> The Board exempts the RATB Fraud Hotline Program Files (RATB-12) system of records from the following provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a:
</p>
<p>(1) From subsection (c)(3) because disclosures from this system could interfere with the just, thorough and timely resolution of the complaint or inquiry, and possibly enable individuals to conceal their wrongdoing or mislead the course of the investigation by concealing, destroying or fabricating evidence or documents.
</p>
<p>(2) From subsection (d) because disclosures from this system could interfere with the just, thorough and timely resolution of the complaint or inquiry, and possibly enable individuals to conceal their wrongdoing or mislead the course of the investigation by concealing, destroying or fabricating evidence or documents. Disclosures could also subject sources and witnesses to harassment or intimidation which jeopardize the safety and well-being of themselves and their families.
</p>
<p>(3) From subsection (e)(1) because the nature of the investigatory function creates unique problems in prescribing specific parameters in a particular case as to what information is relevant or necessary. Due to close working relationships with other Federal, state and local law enforcement agencies, information may be received which may relate to a case under the investigative jurisdiction of another government agency. It is necessary to maintain this information in order to provide leads for appropriate law enforcement purposes and to establish patterns of activity which may relate to the jurisdiction of other cooperating agencies.
</p>
<p>(4) From subsection (e)(4)(G)-(H) because this system of records is exempt from the access provisions of subsection (d).
</p>
<p>(5) From subsection (f) because the agency’s rules are inapplicable to those portions of the system that are exempt and would place the burden on the agency of either confirming or denying the existence of a record pertaining to a requesting individual might in itself provide an answer to that individual relating to an on-going investigation. The conduct of a successful investigation leading to the indictment of a criminal offender precludes the applicability of established agency rules relating to verification of record, disclosure of the record to that individual, and record amendment procedures for this record system.
</p>
<p>[75 FR 37287, June 29, 2010]
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
