<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai >
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</name>
<abbrev>
EEOC
</abbrev>
        
    
    
    <section id="eeoc1" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
       

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Age Discrimination in Employment Act, Equal Pay Act, and Section 304 of the Government Employee Rights Act Discrimination Case Files.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Field Office where the charge or complaint of discrimination was filed (see Appendix A).  Records of complaints filed under section 321 of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991 are located in the Office of Federal Operations 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507, after a hearing has been requested.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Persons other than federal employees and applicants who file charges or complaints with EEOC alleging that an employer, employment agency or labor organization has violated the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 or the Equal Pay Act of 1963, or who file complaints under section 304 of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains the records compiled during the investigation of age and equal pay discrimination cases and during the investigation and hearing of complaints filed under section 304 of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991.  These records include:</p>
                <p> a.  Documents submitted by charging party or complainant such as charge of discrimination, personal interview statement, and correspondence.</p>
                <p> b.  Documents submitted by employer such as statement of position, correspondence, statements of witnesses, documentary evidence such as personnel files, records of earnings, employee benefit plans, seniority list, job titles and descriptions, applicant data, organizational charts, collective bargaining agreements, and petitions to revoke or modify subpoenas.</p>
                <p> c.  Records gathered and generated by EEOC in the course of its investigation and, in complaints filed under section 304 of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991, during the hearing, such as letters of referral to state fair employment practices agencies, correspondence with state fair employment practices agencies, witness statements, investigator's notes, investigative plan, report of initial and exit interview, investigator's analyses of evidence and charge, subpoenas, decisions and letters of determination, conciliation agreements, correspondence and any additional evidence gathered during the course of the investigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 301; 29 U.S.C. 209, 211, 623, 626; 42 U.S.C. 2000e-16c; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 2 U.S.C. 1220.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of enforcing the prohibitions against employment discrimination contained in the Age Discrimination in Employment Act, the Equal Pay Act and section 304 of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose pertinent information to a federal, state, or local agency or third party as may be appropriate or necessary to perform the Commission's functions under the Age Discrimination in Employment Act, Equal Pay Act, or section 304 of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991.</p>
                <p>b.  To disclose information contained in these records to state and local agencies administering state or local fair employment practices laws.</p>
                <p>c.  To disclose non-confidential and non-privileged information from closed ADEA/EPA case files (a file is closed when the Commission has terminated its investigation and has decided not to sue) to the employer where a lawsuit has been filed against the employer involving that information, to other employees of the same employer who have been notified by the Commission of their right under 29 U.S.C. 216 to file a lawsuit on their own behalf, and their representatives.</p>
                <p> d.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of a party to the charge.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where the EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> g.  To disclose information to officials of state or local bar associations or disciplinary boards or committees when they are investigating complaints against attorneys in connection with their representation of a party before EEOC.</p>
                <p> h.  To disclose to a Federal agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of government, in response to its request for information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision.</p>
                <p> i.  To disclose information to other federal agencies in accordance with Memoranda of Understanding or similar agreements between EEOC and other agencies that provide for coordination, cooperation, and confidentiality of documents in EEOC’s employment discrimination enforcement efforts.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retrievable by charging party name, employer name, and charge number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>

        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records are maintained in a secured area to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.  The premises are locked when authorized personnel are not on duty.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of usernames and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>All private sector charge files not designated for permanent retention will be retained for three years following the fiscal year in which they were closed. (For example, if a charge was closed on March 31, 2014, in FY 2014, the three-year retention period would begin on October 1, 2014, which is the first day of FY 2015.)  These non-permanent files will be retained for one year in the EEOC field office where the charge of discrimination was filed.  Afterwards, the non-permanent files will be transferred to the Federal Records Center (FRC).  The FRC will destroy the files after the three-year retention period is met.  Permanent files will be retained in the field office for three years and then transferred to FRC.  FRC will transfer the files to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for permanent retention when eligible.</p>
                <p>Closed non-permanent private sector charge files that are the subject of Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests are retained for six years after the FOIA response is provided.  The files will be transferred to FRC one year after completion of all actions taken under FOIA/Privacy Act.  Alternatively, the files may be included as part of the permanent files retained by the EEOC field office.</p>
                <p>Closed private sector charge files that are the subject of a Section 83 request are retained for six years after the Section 83 response is provided.  The files will be transferred to FRC one year after completion of all actions taken under FOIA.  Alternatively, the files may be included as part of the permanent files retained by the EEOC field office.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director of the office in the field where the charge was filed (see Appendix A).  Director of the Office of Field Programs, 131 M  Street NE, Washington, D.C.  20507.  Director of the Office of Federal Operations, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C.  20507 (only for complaints filed under section 321 of the Government Employees Right Act of 1991).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is exempt under 5 U.S.C. § 552a(k)(2) from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I) and (f) of the Act.</p> </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc2" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
           
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Attorney Referral List.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> All District Offices (see Appendix A).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Attorneys who represent plaintiffs in employment discrimination litigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains attorneys' names, business addresses and telephone numbers, the nature and amount of their civil rights litigation experience; their state and federal bar admissions; whether the attorneys have the capacity and desire to handle class actions; whether the attorneys charge consultation fees (and how much); whether the attorneys will waive the consultation fee; the types of fee arrangements the attorneys will accept; and whether the attorney speaks a foreign language fluently.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 42 U.S.C. 2000e-4(g); 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of providing charging parties, upon their request, with information about local attorneys who represent plaintiffs in employment discrimination litigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To refer charging parties to attorneys who handle litigation of employment discrimination lawsuits.</p>
                <p> b.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> Stored on prepared forms, on index cards and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Indexed alphabetically by names of the attorneys.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Access to this system of records is restricted to EEOC personnel who have a legitimate use for the information.  This system is stored in filing cabinets.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of access codes and entry logs, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Files are reviewed and updated annually.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Regional Attorney at each District Office (see Appendix A).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the appropriate system manager.  It is necessary to furnish the following information: (1) full name of the individual whose records are requested; (2) mailing address to which the reply should be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The individual on whom the record is maintained.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc3" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
             
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Title VII, Americans with Disabilities Act, and Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act Discrimination Case Files.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Field Office where the charge of discrimination was filed (see Appendix A).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Persons, other than federal employees and applicants, who file charges alleging that an employer, employment agency, labor organization or joint labor-management apprenticeship committee has violated Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, Title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (GINA), or any combination of the three.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains records compiled during the investigation of race, color, religion, sex, national origin, disability, and genetic information discrimination cases.  These records include:</p>
                <p> a.  Documents submitted by charging party, such as a charge of discrimination, a personal interview statement, medical records, and correspondence.</p>
                <p> b.  Documents submitted by employer such as position statement, correspondence, statements of witnesses, documentary evidence such as personnel files, records of earnings, EEO data, employee benefit plans, seniority lists, job titles and descriptions, applicant data, organizational charts, collective bargaining agreements, and petition to revoke or modify subpoenas.</p>
                <p> c.  Records gathered and generated by EEOC in the course of its investigation such as letters to state or local fair employment practice agencies, correspondence with state fair employment practice agencies, witness statements, investigator's notes, investigative plan, investigator's analysis of the evidence and charge, report of initial and exit interviews, copy of deferral to state, subpoenas, decisions and letters of determination, analysis of deferral agency action, conciliation agreements, correspondence, and any additional evidence gathered during the course of the investigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 301; 42 U.S.C. 2000e-5, -8 and -9; 42 U.S.C. 12117; 44 U.S.C. 3101, 42 U.S.C. 2000ff-10.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of enforcing the prohibitions against employment discrimination contained in Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, and Title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose pertinent information to a federal, state, or local agency or third party as may be appropriate or necessary to perform the Commission's functions under Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, or Title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose information contained in these records to state and local agencies administering state or local fair employment practices laws.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose non-confidential or non-privileged information contained in these records to the following persons after a notice of right to sue has been issued:</p>
                <p>  1.  Aggrieved persons and their attorneys in case files involving Commissioner Charges provided that such persons have been notified of their status as aggrieved persons;</p>
                <p>  2.  Persons or organizations filing on behalf of an aggrieved person provided that the aggrieved person has given written authorization to the person who filed on his or her behalf to act as the aggrieved person's agent for this purpose, and their attorneys;</p>
                <p>  3.  Employers and their attorneys, provided that the charging party or aggrieved person has filed suit under Title VII, the Americans with Disabilities Act, Title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008, or any combination of the three.</p>
                <p> d.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of a party to the charge.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agencies responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> g.  To disclose information to officials of disciplinary boards or committees under the control of a state or local government when they are investigating complaints against attorneys in connection with their representation of a party before EEOC.</p>
                <p> h.  To disclose to a Federal agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of government, in response to its request for information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision.</p>
                <p> i.  To disclose information to other federal agencies in accordance with Memoranda of Understanding or similar agreements between EEOC and other agencies that provide for coordination, cooperation, and confidentiality of documents in EEOC’s employment discrimination enforcement efforts.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retrievable by charging party name, employer name, and charge number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records are maintained in a secured area to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.  The premises are locked when authorized personnel are not on duty.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of usernames and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> All private sector charge files not designated for permanent retention will be retained for three years following the fiscal year in which they were closed. (For example, if a charge was closed on March 31, 2014, in FY 2014, the three-year retention period would begin on October 1, 2014, which is the first day of FY 2015.)  These non-permanent files will be retained for one year in the EEOC field office where the charge of discrimination was filed.  Afterwards, the non-permanent files will be transferred to the Federal Records Center (FRC).  The FRC will destroy the files after the three-year retention period is met.  Permanent files will be retained in the field office for three years and then transferred to FRC.  FRC will transfer the files to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for permanent retention when eligible.</p>
                <p>Closed non-permanent private sector charge files that are the subject of Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests are retained for six years after the FOIA response is provided.  The files will be transferred to FRC one year after completion of all actions taken under FOIA/Privacy Act.   Alternatively, the files may be included as part of the permanent files retained by the EEOC field office.</p>
                <p>Closed private sector charge files that are the subject of a Section 83 request are retained for six years after the Section 83 response is provided.  The files will be transferred to FRC one year after completion of all actions taken under FOIA/Privacy Act.  Alternatively, the files may be included as part of the permanent files retained by the EEOC field office.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director of the office in the field where the charge was filed (see Appendix A).  Director of the Office of Field Programs, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is exempt under 5 U.S.C. § 552a(k)(2) from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), and (f) of the Act.</p> </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc4" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
             
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Biographical Files.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of Communications and Legislative Affairs, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current and former Commissioners, General Counsels and Commission officials.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Includes for each the name, date and place of birth, education, employment history, and other biographical information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 44 U.S.C. 3101, 42 U.S.C. 2000e-4.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of providing information about EEOC officials to members of the Congress and the public.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used</p>
                <p> a.  To answer public and congressional inquiries regarding EEOC Commissioners, General Counsels and Commission officials.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> Stored electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Indexed by last name of the Commissioner, General Counsel or Commission official.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Files are kept in the Office of Communications and Legislative Affairs, which is locked evenings, weekends, and holidays.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Maintained permanently.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director, Office of Communications and Legislative Affairs, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  All inquiries should furnish the full name of the individual and the mailing address to which the reply should be mailed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The individual to whom the record pertains.</p></xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc5" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
            
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Correspondence and Communications.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> All locations listed in appendix A and all headquarters offices, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Charging parties, members of the general public, members of Congress and current and former federal employees who seek information or assistance from EEOC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> a.  Inquiries from members of Congress, the White House and members of the general public, including current and former federal employees.</p>
                <p> b.  EEOC responses to the above inquiries.</p>
                <p> c.  Computer tracking system indicating the dates inquiries are received, to whom and when they are assigned for response and the dates they are answered.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 44 U.S.C. 3101; 42 U.S.C. 2000e-4.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of responding to inquiries from members of Congress and the public seeking information or assistance.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file cabinets and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Computer entries are retrievable by name of author of a letter, by subject, by key word, by reference number, by name of person to whom assigned, and by dates assigned, due, and answered.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are kept in a secured area to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.  The premises are locked when authorized personnel are not on duty.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of usernames and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are maintained for three years from the date of the last communication and then destroyed.  Tracking system information is maintained in the computer for four years.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director of each Commission office in the field and Headquarters office.  (See Appendix A.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  All inquiries should furnish the full name of the individual and the mailing address to which the reply should be mailed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Members of Congress, their staffs, the White House, charging parties, members of the general public, current and former federal employees.</p>  </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc6" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
          
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Field Office where Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act request was submitted (see Appendix A); Office of Legal Counsel, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Persons who submit Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) and Privacy Act requests and administrative appeals to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC); and persons whose requests and /or records have been submitted to EEOC by other agencies.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system consists of records created or compiled in response to FOIA or Privacy Act requests and administrative appeals, including the original requests and administrative appeals, responses to such requests and administrative appeals, all related memoranda, correspondence, notes and other related or supporting documentation, and, in some instances, copies of requested records and records under administrative appeal.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C 552; and 5 U.S.C. 552a.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of processing requests and administrative appeals under the FOIA, and access and amendment requests and administrative appeals under the Privacy Act; for the purpose of participating in litigation regarding agency action on such requests and appeals; and for the purpose of assisting EEOC in carrying out any other responsibilities under the FOIA and the Privacy Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To provide information to a federal, state, local, or foreign agency or entity for the purpose of consulting with that agency or entity to enable the EEOC to make a determination as to the propriety of access to, or correction of, information, or for the purpose of verifying the identity of an individual or the accuracy of information submitted by an individual who has requested access to or amendment of information.</p>
                <p> b.  To provide information to a federal agency or entity that furnished the record or information for the purpose of permitting that agency or entity to make a decision as to access to, or correction of, the record or information.</p>
                <p> c.  To provide information to a submitter or subject of a record or information in order to obtain assistance to EEOC in making a determination as to access or amendment.</p>
                <p> d.  To provide information to the National Archives and Records Administration, Office of Government Information Services (OGIS), to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities under 5 U.S.C. 552(h) to review federal agency policies, procedures, and compliance with the FOIA, and to facilitate OGIS’s offering of mediation services to resolve disputes between persons making FOIA requests and federal agencies.</p>
                <p> e.  To provide information to contractors, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the federal government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                <p>f.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of the individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p>g.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> h.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p>i. To disclose in response to a request for discovery or for appearance of a witness, information that is relevant to the subject matter involved in the pending judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p> None.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> Records in this system are stored on paper and/or in electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are retrieved by the name of the requester or appellant; the number assigned to the request or appeal; and, in some instances, the name of the attorney representing the requester or appellant or the name of the EEOC personnel assigned to handle such requests and appeals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>

        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information in this system is safeguarded in accordance with applicable laws, rules, and policies, including EEOC’s automated systems security and access policies.  Records and electronic equipment are maintained in buildings with restricted access.  The required use of password protection identification features and other system protection methods also restrict access.  Access is limited to those EEOC officers and employees who have an official need for access to perform their duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are retained and disposed of in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule 14.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director of the field office where the Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act request was submitted (see Appendix A) or the Legal Counsel, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  All inquiries should furnish the full name of the individual and the mailing address or email address to which the reply should be mailed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals who submit initial requests and administrative appeals pursuant to the FOIA and the Privacy Act; the agency records searched in the process of responding to such requests and appeals; EEOC personnel assigned to handle such requests and appeals; and other agencies or entities that have referred to EEOC requests concerning EEOC records.</p>  </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc7" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
          
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Employee Pay and Leave Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> All locations listed in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current and former employees of EEOC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Time and attendance records; leave records (includes employee name, branch or office, pay period ending, leave and overtime used during the pay period); requests for leave (earned or advance) or leave of absence; requests for an authorization of overtime; annual attendance record (indicates name, social security number, service computation date, hours and dates worked and taken as leave, pay plan, salary and occupation code, grade, leave earned and used); thrift savings plan participation, deductions for Medicare, FICA, taxes, life, health, and long term care insurance, union contributions, charitable contributions, savings allotments and bond issuance and bond balance.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records in this system are maintained in accordance with the requirements set forth by statutes, regulations and guidance from the Office of Personnel Management, the General Services Administration, and the Thrift Savings Board.  They are maintained for the purpose of providing salaries and other benefits to EEOC employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a. To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p> b. To provide a copy of an employee's Department of the Treasury Form W-2, Wage and Tax Statement, to the state, city or other local jurisdiction which is authorized to tax the employee's compensation.  The record will be provided in accordance with a withholding agreement between the state, city, or other jurisdiction and the Department of Treasury pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 5516, 5517 or 5520, or in response to a written request from an appropriate official of the taxing jurisdiction.  The request must include a copy of the applicable statute or ordinance authorizing the taxation of compensation and should indicate whether the authority of the jurisdiction to tax the employee is based on place of residence, place of employment, or both.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose copies of executed city tax withholding certificates to a city pursuant to a withholding agreement between the city and the Department of the Treasury (5 U.S.C. 5520) in response to a written request from an appropriate city official.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose the social security number only, in the absence of a withholding agreement, to a taxing jurisdiction that has furnished this agency with evidence of its independent authority to compel disclosure of the social security number, in accordance with section 7 of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a note.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose to an agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch or the District of Columbia's Government information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, the letting of a contract, the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefits by the requesting agency, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision.</p>
                <p> g. To disclose to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
                <p> h. To disclose to the Office of Personnel Management in accordance with the agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
                <p> i. To disclose to officers and employees of the Department of the Interior in connection with administrative services provided to this agency under agreement with DOI.</p>
                <p> j. To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> k.  To disclose information to the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services Federal Parent Locator system (FPLS) and Federal Tax Offset system for use in locating individuals and identifying their income sources to establish paternity, establish and modify orders of support and for enforcement action.</p>
                <p> l. To disclose information to the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Social Security Administration for verifying social security numbers in connection with the operation of the FPLS by the Office of Child Support Enforcement.</p>
                <p>
                    m.  To disclose information to the Office of Child Support Enforcement for release to the Department of Treasury for purposes of administering the Earned Income Tax Credit Program (Section 32, Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and verifying a claim with respect to employment in a tax return.
                </p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p> Disclosures may be made from this system to consumer reporting agencies as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> Stored electronically and in file folders.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Indexed by an assigned employee code.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Access to these records is limited to employees whose official duties require such access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records are destroyed after three years.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director of each Commission Office (See Appendix A).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  It is necessary to furnish the following information:  (1) name and (2) mailing address to which the response is to be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Official personnel folder, data submitted by employees and data submitted by the offices where the individuals are or were employed.</p>  </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc8" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
          
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Employee Travel and Reimbursement Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> All locations listed in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current and former employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Includes travel orders, travel vouchers, records of travel advances, amounts owed the agency by employees for travel and other purposes, amounts payable to the employee for travel and other purposes, payments made to the employees for travel and other reimbursable transactions, and a record of the difference between the cost of official travel as estimated in the travel order and the amount actually expended by the employee.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 31 U.S.C. 3512, 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained in accordance with the General Service Administration’s regulations for the purpose of allowing EEOC employees to travel for official business and reimbursing travel expenses.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose to an agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch or the District of Columbia's Government, information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, the letting of a contract, the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefits by the requesting agency, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose to the Office of Personnel Management in accordance with the agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose to officers and employees of the Department of the Interior in connection with administrative services provided to this agency under agreement with DOI.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p>
                    g.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.
                </p>
                <p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:</p>
                <p> Disclosures may be made from this system to consumer reporting agencies as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)) or the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 (31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(3)).</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> Stored on prepared forms and  electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Indexed alphabetically by name and/or chronologically by event and name.  Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.  Personnel screening is employed to prevent unauthorized disclosure.  Files are stored electronically and in standard cabinets, safes, and secured rooms.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of user names and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are destroyed in accordance with GSA General Records Schedule 2.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director, Finance and Systems Services Division, Office of the Chief Financial Officer, EEOC, 131  M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Employees of the Commission wishing to know whether information about them is maintained in this system of records should address inquiries to the Director of the Office where employed (see Appendix A).  The individual should provide his or her full name, date of birth, and mailing address.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Bills, receipts, and claims presented by employees and original data generated by the Commission.</p>  </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc9" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
          
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Claims Collection Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are located in the Finance and Systems Services Division, Office of Chief Financial Officer, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Any individual who is indebted to the United States as a result of his or her interaction or financial activities with the Commission or another federal agency including, but not limited to, any current or former Commission employee.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains:</p>
                <p> Debtor Files.  These files contain information and evidence on the identity and location of the individual who is subject to a claim, the origin and amount of the indebtedness, decisions and determinations regarding a claim, actions taken to collect a claim, and the results of those actions.  Depending on the status of a claim, a case file may include such records as documents evidencing indebtedness, written demands for payment, required notices, financial statements, medical disability statements, agency investigative reports, credit reports, written agreements for payment, intra-agency and inter-agency memoranda of consultation and opinion on the collection action, documentation resulting from a hearing, requests for waiver, requests for reconsideration, written determinations and decisions, certifications of indebtedness by this or another agency, counterclaims, judgments, and documents evidencing payment or compromise of the debt. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 301, 5514, 5522, 5584, 5705, 5724(f); 15 U.S.C. 1692; 26 U.S.C. 6331; 31 U.S.C. 3701, 3702, 3711, 3716, 3717, 3718, 3719; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 4 CFR Parts 91-93, 101-105.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of collecting debts owed the United States by individuals as a result of their interaction with the Commission or another federal agency.  The debts are collected in accordance with the Commission’s regulatory debt collection procedures, which include salary offset, administrative offset, Federal income tax refund offset, and wage garnishment.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose information to appropriate officials and employees of the Department of Justice for the purposes of litigation and forced collection on administratively uncollected debts.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose information to appropriate officials of the Department of the Treasury and the Office of Management and Budget to provide reports on debt collection activities.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to another federal agency for the purpose of collecting a debt owed to the Commission by an individual through EEOC’s debt collection procedures undertaken by the other agency upon proper certification or evidence of the debt owed from the Commission.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose information to another federal agency for the purpose of collecting a debt owed to that agency by an individual through EEOC’s debt collection procedures undertaken by the Commission upon proper certification or evidence of the debt owed from the other agency.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose a debtor's name and identification number to the Secretary of the Treasury or his or her designee for the purpose of obtaining the debtor's mailing address from the IRS.</p>
                <p> f.    To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p> g.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> h.  To disclose to an agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch or the District of Columbia's government in response to its request, or at the initiation of the agency maintaining the records, information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, the letting of a contract, the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision.</p>
                <p> i.  To disclose to officers and employees of the Department of the Interior Business Center, in connection with administrative services provided to this agency under agreement with DOI.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are indexed by the name of the individual.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individual case files are usually retained for two years after the claim is collected.  Case records on individuals whose delinquent debts are reported to consumer reporting agencies are retained indefinitely.  Other case files may be maintained for a period up to ten years.  IRS Mailing Address Index on any individual is not maintained beyond six years.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director, Finance and Systems Services Division, Office of Chief Financial Officer  Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Under the Debt Collection Act, individuals are notified if claims collection records are maintained on them in accordance with statutory procedures for debt collection.   Individuals may also contact the System Manager in order to obtain notification of claims collection records on themselves.</p>
                <p> Individuals must provide their full names under which records may be maintained, and a mailing address to which a reply should be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information in this system of records is provided by or from:</p>
                <p> a.  The individual on whom the record is maintained;</p>
                <p> b.  Other Federal agencies;</p>
                <p> c.  Personnel, payroll, travel records, contract records, or other records;</p>
                <p> d.  Administrative hearings;</p>
                <p> e.  Court records.</p> </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc10" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
           
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Grievance Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are located in the Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507, and in other headquarter offices and offices in the field where the grievances were filed (see Appendix A).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current or former EEOC employees who have submitted grievances to the EEOC, or pursuant to a negotiated procedure.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The system contains all documents related to the grievance, including statements of witnesses, reports of interviews and hearings, examiners' findings and recommendations, a copy of the original and final decision, and related correspondence and exhibits.  This system includes files and records of internal grievance and arbitration systems that EEOC has or may establish through negotiations with recognized labor organizations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 7121.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records result from EEOC employees’ grievances, filed under the Commission’s administrative grievance procedures or the formal grievance procedures contained in section 7121 of the Civil Service Reform Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose information to any source from which additional information is requested in the course of processing a grievance, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose to an agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch or the District of Columbia's government, information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, the letting of a contract, the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefits by the requesting agency, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> e.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
                <p> g.  To disclose in response to a request for discovery or for appearance of a witness, information that is relevant to the subject matter involved in a pending judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> h.  To provide information to officials of labor organizations recognized under the Civil Service Reform Act when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retrieved by grievance numbers and the names of the individuals on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained in lockable metal filing cabinets to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of usernames and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are shredded or burned 3 years after closing the case.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> If the grievance is pending at or was never raised beyond the Step 1or Step 2 level, the system manager is the office director, administrative officer, or district resource manager.  (See Appendix A.)  For grievances that were raised beyond Step 2, the system manager is the Chief Human Capital Officer, EEOC, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> It is required that individuals submitting grievances be provided a copy of the record under the grievance process.  They may, however, contact the agency personnel or designated office where the action was processed regarding the existence of such records regarding them.  They must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:  (a) name; (b) approximate date of closing of the case and kind of action taken; (c) organizational component involved.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information in this system of records is provided:</p>
                <p> a.  By the individual on whom the record is maintained;</p>
                <p> b.  By testimony of witnesses;</p>
                <p> c.  By agency officials;</p>
                <p> d.  From related correspondence from organizations or persons.</p></xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc11" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
           
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Records of Adverse Actions Against Nonpreference Eligibles in the Excepted Service.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are located in Office of Chief Human Capital Officer, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507 or in the headquarters and offices in the field in which the actions have been taken.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current or former nonpreference-eligible, excepted service Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) employees against whom an adverse action has been proposed or taken and who have not completed two years of current and continuous service in the same or similar positions.  [This system covers only those adverse action files not covered by OPM/GOVT-3.]</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains records and documents on the processing of adverse actions for employees who are nonpreference eligible in the excepted service and who do not have two years of continuous service in their positions.  The records include copies of the notice of proposed action, materials relied on by the agency to support the reasons in the notice, replies by the employee, statements of witnesses, reports, and agency decisions.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records result from the proposal, processing, and documentation of adverse actions taken by the Commission against nonpreference-eligible, excepted service EEOC employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To provide information to officials of labor organizations recognized under 5 U.S.C. Chapter 71 when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to any source from which additional information is requested for processing any of the covered actions or in regard to any appeal or administrative review procedure, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose information to a federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, or the classifying of jobs, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p> e.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> g.  To disclose, in response to a request for discovery or for appearance of a witness, information that is relevant to the subject matter involved in a pending judicial, or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> h.  To disclose to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints  examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in the investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retrieved by the names of the individuals on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained in locked metal filing cabinets to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of usernames and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records documenting an adverse action are disposed of 4 years after the closing of the case.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Chief Human Capital Officer, and Directors of offices in the field (see Appendix A).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals receiving notice of a proposed action are provided access to all documents supporting the notice.  They may also contact the personnel office where the action was processed regarding the existence of such records on them.  They must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                <p> a.  Name</p>
                <p> b.  Approximate date of closing of case and kind of action taken</p>
                <p> c.  Organizational component involved.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information in this system of records is provided:</p>
                <p> a.  By the individual on whom the record is maintained</p>
                <p> b.  By witnesses</p>
                <p> c.  By agency officials.</p> </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc12" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
            
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Telephone Call Detail Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Telecommunications Manager, Customer Services Management Division, Office of Information Technology, EEOC, 131 MM Street NE, Washington D.C. 20507, and each office in the field listed in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals (generally EEOC employees) who made telephone calls from EEOC telephones, individuals who received  telephone calls  from, or charged to, EEOC telephones., and individuals who are assigned U.S. government phone cards by EEOC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records relating to the use of EEOC telephones and government phone cards to make calls; records indicating the assignment of telephone numbers to employees; records relating to the location of telephones.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained for the purpose of keeping an account of telephone calls made from EEOC telephones and ensuring that phone calls and card charges are made for official business only.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information from these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose to representatives of the General Services Administration or the National Archives and Records Administration who are conducting records management inspections under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose to an agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch or the District of Columbia's government in response to its request, or at the initiation of the EEOC, information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, the letting of a contract, the issuance of a license, grant or other benefits by the requesting agency, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose to a telecommunications company providing telecommunications support to permit servicing the account.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are retrieved by employee name or identification number and by name of recipient of telephone call or telephone number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are maintained and stored in file cabinets in a secured area to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of usernames and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are disposed of as provided in the National Archives and Records Administration's General Records Schedule 12.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Telecommunications Manager, Customer Services Management Division, Office of Information Technology, EEOC, 131M Street NE, Washington D.C., 20507 and the Directors of the field offices listed in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  It is necessary to provide the following information: (1) name; (2) telephone number (office number if Commission employee); (3) mailing address to which response is to be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Telephone assignment records; call detail listings; results of administrative inquiries relating to assignment of responsibilities for placement of specific local and long distance calls. on government phone card bills</p>  </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>
                <section id="eeoc13" toc="yes">
                    <systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
          
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Employee Identification Cards.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Operations Services Division, Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, EEOC, 131 M Street NE, Washington D.C. 20507, and each of the field offices in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current EEOC employees, and other individuals who require regular, ongoing access to EEOC facilities or information technology systems including, but not limited to, federal employees, contractors, interns, volunteers, and individuals formerly in any of these positions.  This system does not apply to occasional or short-term .visitors.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records maintained on individuals issued identification cards, including Personal Identification Verification (PIV) cards, by EEOC include the following information:  full name; signature; social security number; date of birth; photograph; fingerprints; hair color; eye color; height; weight; office of assignment; telephone number; copy of background investigation form; card issue and expiration dates; personal identification number; results of background investigation; PIV request form; PIV registrar approval signature; PIV card serial number; and a list of all persons who possess current identification cards.  In addition, for office locations permitting access by proximity cards, numbered proximity cards and a list of all persons with their assigned proximity card numbers, all doors controlled by the proximity cards, and all persons permitted access to each door.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 44 U.S.C. 3101; 41 C.F.R. 101-20.3.  5 U.S.C. § 301; Federal Information Security Act (Pub. L. 104-106, § 5113); Electronic Government Act (Pub. L. 104-347, § 203); Homeland Security Presidential Directive (HSPD) 12, Policy for Common Identification Standard for Federal Employees and Contractors, August 27, 2004;   and Office of Personnel Management Memorandum, Final Credentialing Standards for Issuing Personal Identity Verification Cards under HSPD-12, July 31, 2008.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained for the purpose of ensuring that EEOC offices and information systems are secure and that only authorized individuals have access to those offices and systems.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information from these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose to other government agencies and to the public whether an individual is a current employee of the EEOC.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose information to agency contractors who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract or other activity related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform their activity.</p>
                <p> f.  To notify another federal agency when, or verify whether, a PIV card is no longer valid.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in paper files and in electronic media.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are retrieved by name, social security number, other ID number, PIV card serial number, photograph, or fingerprint.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are maintained and stored in file cabinets in a secured area to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of usernames and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are destroyed not later than five years after the separation or transfer of the employee.  In accordance with HSPD-12, PIV cards are deactivated within 18 hours of cardholder separation, loss of card, or expiration.  The information on PIV cards is maintained in accordance with General Records Schedule 11, Item 4.  PIV cards are destroyed by cross-cut shredding no later than 90 days after deactivation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director, Operations Services Division,  Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, EEOC, 131 M Street, NE., Washington D.C., 20507, and the Directors of the field offices listed in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  It is necessary to provide the following information: (1) name; (2) date of birth; and (3) mailing address to which the response is to be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information contained in this system is obtained from the employee or contractor; other federal agencies; contract employer; or former employer.</p>   </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection></section>

    <section id="eeoc14" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>
                Reserved
            </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
   </subsection>
    </section>

         

    <section id="eeoc15" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Internal Harassment Inquiries.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current or former EEOC employees, contractors, applicants, interns, and volunteers who have submitted complaints or reports of harassment under EEOC Order 560.005, Prevention and Elimination of Harassment in the Workplace, and current and former EEOC employees, contractors, applicants, interns, and volunteers who have been accused of harassment under that Order.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The system contains all documents related to a complaint or report of harassment, including statements of witnesses, reports of interviews, investigator’s and Coordinator’s findings and recommendations, final decisions and corrective action taken, and related correspondence and exhibits.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 29 U.S.C. 633a; 29 U.S.C. 791; 42 U.S.C. 2000e-16; 44 U.S.C. 3101; Exec. Order No. 11478, 34 FR 12985; Exec. Order No. 13087, 63 FR 30097.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained for the purpose of conducting internal investigations into allegations of harassment brought by current or former EEOC employees, contractors, applicants, interns, and volunteers and taking appropriate action in accordance with EEOC Order 560.005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose information as necessary to any source from which additional information is requested in the course of processing a complaint or report of harassment made pursuant to EEOC Order 560.005.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in ligation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> d.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
                <p> f.   To disclose to the individual who filed the complaint or report of harassment and to the alleged harasser the outcome of any inquiry that may have been conducted and of disciplinary and corrective steps taken.</p>
                <p> g.  To provide to officials of labor organizations recognized under the Civil Service Reform Act information to which they are statutorily entitled when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions.</p>
                <p> h.  To provide to the alleged harasser information in the event of a disciplinary hearing.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are cross-indexed by the name of the individual who files a complaint or report of harassment, the name of the alleged victim of harassment, if any, and the name of the alleged harasser.  The records may be retrieved by any of the above three indexes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records are maintained in locked metal filing cabinets to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to electronic records is limited, through use of logins and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained for one year after the complaint or report of harassment is closed and then transferred to the Federal Records Center where they are destroyed after three years.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Harassment Coordinator, Office of Chief Human Capital Officer, EEOC, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is exempt under 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I) and (f) of the Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="eeoc16" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Office of Inspector General Investigative Files.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of Inspector General (OIG), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, DC 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals who are subjects of investigations by the Office of Inspector General relating to the programs and operations of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission.  Subject individuals include, but are not limited to, current and former employees; current and former agents or employees of contractors and subcontractors in their personal capacity, where applicable; and other individuals whose actions affect the EEOC, its programs or operations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Correspondence relating to the investigation; internal staff memoranda; copies of subpoenas issued during the investigation, affidavits, statements from witnesses, transcripts of testimony taken during the investigation, and accompanying exhibits; documents, notes, investigative notes, staff working papers, draft materials, and other documents and records relating to the investigation; opening reports, progress reports, and closing reports; video and audio recordings; and other investigatory information or data relating to the alleged or suspected criminal, civil, or administrative violations or similar wrongdoing by subject individuals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, 5 U.S.C. App.3.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Pursuant to the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, this system of records is maintained for the purpose of : (1) documenting the conduct and outcome of investigations by the OIG and other investigative agencies regarding EEOC programs and operations; (2) reporting the results of investigations to other Federal agencies, other public authorities or professional organizations which have the authority to bring criminal prosecutions, or civil or administrative actions, or to impose other disciplinary sanctions; (3) maintaining a record of the activities which were the subject of investigations; (4) reporting investigative findings to other components of EEOC for their use in operating and evaluating their programs or operations, and in the imposition of civil or administrative sanctions; (5) coordinating relationships with other Federal agencies, state and local governmental agencies and nongovernmental entities in matters relating to the statutory responsibilities of the OIG; and (6) acting as a repository and source for information necessary to fulfill the reporting requirements of the Inspector General Act, 5 U.S.C. App.3.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> a.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation or order, where the EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose information to any source, private or governmental, to the extent necessary to secure from such source information relevant to and in furtherance of a legitimate OIG investigation, audit, evaluation, or other inquiry.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to agencies, offices or establishments of the executive, legislative, or judicial branches of the Federal or state governments:</p>
                <p> (1) Where such agency, office, or establishment has an interest in an individual for employment purposes, including a security clearance or determination as to access to classified information, and needs to evaluate the individual’s qualifications, suitability, or loyalty to the United States Government, or access to classified information or restricted areas, or</p>
                <p> (2) Where such agency, office, or establishment conducts an investigation of the individual for purposes of granting a security clearance, or for making a determination of qualifications, suitability or loyalty to the United States Government, or access to classified information or restricted areas, or</p>
                <p> (3) Where the records or information in those records is relevant and necessary to a decision with regard to the hiring or retention of an employee or disciplinary or other administrative action concerning an employee.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose information to a Congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the Congressional office made at the written request of that individual.</p>
                <p> f.  To private contractors who have been retained by OIG to perform any functions or analyses that facilitate or are relevant to an OIG investigation, audit, inspection, or inquiry.</p>
                <p>g.  To disclose information to authorized officials of the Council of Inspectors General for Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE), the Department of Justice, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the purpose of conducting qualitative assessment reviews of the Office of Inspector General’s investigative operations.</p>
                <p>h.  To disclose information to authorized officials of the CIGIE for their preparation of reports to the President and Congress on the activities of the Inspectors General.</p>
                <p>i.  To disclose to an agency, organization or individual for the purpose of performing audit or oversight operations as authorized by law, including peer reviews, but only such information as is necessary and relevant to such audit or oversight operation."</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> Information in this system is stored manually in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records are retrieved by the name of the subject of the investigation or by a unique control number assigned to each investigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information is stored in locked file cabinets in a secured space. Access to electronic records is limited through the use of logins and passwords to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are held for five (5) years and then retired to the Federal Records Center.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inspector General, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, P. O. Box 18858, Washington, DC 20036-8858.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Specific: Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2) the Office of Inspector General Investigative Files are exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d)(1), (d)(2) and (e)(1) of the Privacy Act.</p>
                <p> General: Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), investigatory materials compiled for criminal law enforcement in the Office of Inspector General Investigative Files are exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d)(1), (d)(2), (e)(1), (e)(2), and (e)(3) of the Privacy Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="eeoc17" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Defensive Litigation Files.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> External Defensive Litigation Files are located in the Office of Legal Counsel, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.  Internal Defensive Litigation Files are located in the Office of General Counsel, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals who have filed civil or administrative litigation against EEOC and individuals who have given sworn testimony, affidavits, or declarations under penalty of perjury in such actions.  External cases are brought by members of the public; internal cases are brought by applicants, current, and former EEOC employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains all documents related to external and internal litigation brought against the Commission.  These records include:</p>
                <p> a.  Documents submitted or filed by plaintiffs, grievants, and EEO complainants to prosecute civil or administrative litigation against the EEOC, such as complaints, grievances, unfair labor practice claims, motions, and briefs.</p>
                <p> b.  Documents submitted by the EEOC to defend the action against it such as an answer to a civil complaint or a motion to dismiss or for summary judgment, and a reply to an administrative EEO complaint, grievance, or unfair labor practice.</p>
                <p> c.  Administrative determinations at issue in the litigation such as final agency EEO decisions, final grievance decisions, final decisions on personnel actions, final agency administrative dispositions of tort claims, and agency determinations under the Freedom of Information Act.</p>
                <p> d.  Discovery and investigatory materials such as witness statements, affidavits, declarations under penalty of perjury, correspondence, records, exhibits, and other documentary evidence.</p>
                <p> e.  Litigation materials, such as attorney work product, attorney notes, hearing transcripts,  legal memoranda, and related correspondence and exhibits.</p>
                <p> f.  Final judgments, orders, decisions, decrees, and settlement agreements.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained for the purpose of defending EEOC in litigation brought against it by current and former employees (internal files), charging parties, respondents and members of the public (external files).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose pertinent information as may be appropriate or necessary for the Commission to defend itself in a civil action or administrative proceeding, or to seek enforcement of a settlement, order, or final decision involving the same or a similar matter.</p>
                <p> b.  To provide information to a congressional office in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of a party to the administrative or civil proceeding to which the record pertains.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose pertinent information to an appropriate federal court, agency, or administrative body responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where the EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation, or in order to seek enforcement or clarification of an order or decision for or against the EEOC to which the record pertains.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose information to another federal agency or to a court when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose, in response to an order, information that is relevant to a pending judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> External defensive litigation files are maintained in a locked filing system in the Office of Legal Counsel.  Internal defensive litigation files are maintained in a locked filing system in the Office of General Counsel.  Information identifying existing external and internal defensive litigation files is maintained electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> External Defensive Litigation records are cross-indexed by name of the plaintiff, and Office of Legal Counsel reference number.    Internal Defensive Litigation records are maintained by name of plaintiff, complainant, grievant, or aggrieved individual, and by Office of General Counsel reference number.  The records may be retrieved by either index.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>            External Defensive Litigation paper records maintained at EEOC headquarters are kept in locked cabinets in the Office of Legal Counsel.  Internal Defensive Litigation paper records maintained at EEOC headquarters are kept in locked cabinets in the Office of General Counsel.  Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.  The premises are locked evenings, weekends, and holidays.  Paper records which have been retired are maintained at the Federal Records Center.  Access to electronic External and Internal Defensive Litigation records is limited through use of passwords to those whose official duties require access, input, and retrieval of information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Two years after the date of closure of the underlying civil or administrative action (e.g., final order, decision on appeal), records pertaining to that action are retired to the Federal Records Center.  Thereafter, non-permanent files are destroyed six years after the date of closure of the underlying action.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The System Manager for External Defensive Litigation files is the Assistant Legal Counsel, Advice &amp;  Litigation Division, Office of Legal Counsel, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.  The System Manager for Internal Defensive Litigation files is the Assistant General Counsel for Internal Litigation Services, Office of General Counsel, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Any person wanting to know whether this system of records contains information about him or her should contact the System Manager.  Such person should provide his or her full name and mailing address to which a response is to be sent, and forum, filing date, and docket number of the action involved, if available.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records described herein are compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.  Pursuant to section (d)(5) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. § 552a(d)(5), an individual is precluded from access to such records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as the Notification Procedures above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Plaintiffs, grievants, complainants, aggrieved individuals, current and former EEOC employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="eeoc18" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-18</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Reasonable Accommodation Records
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C.  20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current and former EEOC employees and applicants who have requested reasonable accommodations under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Requests for reasonable accommodations; medical records; notes or records made during consideration of requests; decisions on requests; records made to implement or track decisions on requests.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 U.S.C. 791; E.O. 13164.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system is maintained for the purpose of considering, deciding, and implementing requests for reasonable accommodation made by EEOC employees and applicants.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> a.  To disclose information to medical personnel to meet a bona fide medical emergency.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose information to another Federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>Maintained in locked file cabinets and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Indexed by name of employee or applicant and office location.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Files are maintained in locked cabinets.  Access is restricted to EEOC personnel whose official duties require such access.  Access to computerized records is limited, through use of logins and passwords, to those whose official duties require access. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records will be maintained in the Office of the Human Capital Officer for the longer of an employee’s tenure with EEOC or  5 years.  Thereafter, they will be destroyed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Disability Program Manager, Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M  Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Any person wanting to know whether this system of records contains information about him or her should contact the System Manager.  Such person should provide his or her full name, position title and office location at the time the accommodation was requested, and mailing address to which a response is to be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as the Notification Procedures above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as the Notification Procedures above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information contained in this system is obtained from the current or former employee,  the Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, and management officials.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="eeoc19" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Revolving Fund Registrations.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Revolving Fund Division, Office of Field Programs, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C.  20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who register for or attend EEOC Revolving Fund programs, courses and conferences and who purchase publications and products.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains the names, job titles, company, organization or agency names, business addresses and phone numbers, email addresses, any reasonable accommodation requested, and attendance or purchase dates.  Some of the records may contain payment information, the industry of the company, and the size of the establishment.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>42 U.S.C. 2000e-4(k).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are maintained for the purpose of administering Revolving Fund programs and publicizing future programs.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p>a.  To send mailings to registrants and attendees advertising future Revolving Fund programs.</p>
                <p>b.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of the individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p>c.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>These records are maintained electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are indexed by the names of the registrants or attendees, by company, organization, or agency name.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Access to and use of these records is limited, through use of access codes and entry logs, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are kept indefinitely.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Revolving Fund Division, Office of Field Programs, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  All inquiries should furnish the full name of the individual and the mailing address to which the reply should be mailed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information contained in this system is obtained from the registrant or attendee. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="eeoc20" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-20</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    RESOLVE Program Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>RESOLVE Program, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C.  20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former EEOC employees who request alternative dispute resolution during the counseling or investigative process of their EEO complaints against EEOC, as well as EEOC employees who contact the RESOLVE program for alternative dispute resolution of disputes occurring in their EEOC employment.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains the records generated in the course of receiving and attempting to resolve disputes brought to the RESOLVE program, including, as appropriate, intake interview notes, mediation scheduling notices, the mediator’s outcome form, and settlement agreements.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. §§ 571-574; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 29 C.F.R. Part 1614.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are maintained for the purpose of administering EEOC’s RESOLVE Program, which provides a forum for the informal resolution of a variety of workplace disputes as an alternative to the formal procedures that employees traditionally use to resolve disputes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p>a.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p>b.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of the individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p>These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are indexed by the names of the employee.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records are maintained in locked metal filing cabinets to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to and use of electronic records is limited, through use of logins and passwords, to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are maintained for one year after the complaint or dispute matter brought to RESOLVE is closed and then transferred to the Federal Records Center where they are destroyed after three years.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Mediation Officer, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  All inquiries should furnish the full name of the individual and the mailing address to which the reply should be mailed.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information contained in this system is obtained from the current or former employee, the Office of Equal Opportunity, the Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, management officials, union officials, and the mediator.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="eeoc21" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-21</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Emergency Management Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Headquarters, District, Field, Area, and Local Offices may maintain emergency contact files.   The Office of the Chief Financial Officer maintains emergency management and continuity of operations (COOP) files.  The Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer maintains the orders of succession, which are part of the COOP files.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> EEOC employees, contractors, and other governmental and non-governmental persons essential to carrying out emergency activities.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records, composed of emergency notification rosters and files, emergency contact information, and COOP files, may contain the following personal information: name; office, cellular and home telephone numbers; home address; email address; primary contact name, relationship, address, cellular, work and home telephone numbers; alternate contact’s name, relationship, address, cellular, work and home telephone numbers.  Each office may collect a different set of information.  System records may include special needs information such as medical, mobility, and transportation requirements for individuals.  Additional information may include official titles and emergency assignments.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; Executive Order 12565, Assignment of Emergency Preparedness Responsibilities, (Nov. 18, 1989); Presidential Decision Directive 67, Ensuring Constitutional Government and Continuity of Government Operations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> To maintain current information on EEOC employees and other persons covered by this system to allow persons with emergency management responsibilities to notify or contact them about conditions that require their urgent assistance or attention during an emergency.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to an expert, consultant or contractor in the performance of a federal government duty involving EEOC emergency management.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose information about an individual during an emergency in order to locate or contact that individual.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in paper files and in electronic media.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are retrieved by name, organization, or location.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are maintained and stored in file cabinets in a secured area to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to electronic records is limited through use of logins and passwords for those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are destroyed one year after termination of the employment relationship or contract termination.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Headquarters, District, Field, Area, and Local Office Directors.   Addresses listed in Appendix A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be made to the system manager.  It is necessary to provide the name of the individual and the mailing address to which the response should be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information in this system is obtained from the individuals themselves, their supervisors or office.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="eeoc22" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    EEOC Personnel Security Files.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, Operations Services Division, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C.  20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> EEOC employees, applicants, former employees, interns, volunteers, and contractors.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Name, former names, birth date, birth place, social security number, home address, telephone numbers, employment history, residential history, education and degrees earned, names of associates and references and their contact information, citizenship, names of relatives, citizenship of relatives, names of relatives who work for the federal government, criminal history, drug use, financial information, fingerprints, summary report of investigation, results of suitability decisions, requests for appeal, witness statements, investigator’s notes, tax return information, credit reports, security violations (including circumstances of violation and agency action taken).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>             5 U.S.C. 3101; 5 C.F.R. Parts 731, 732, and 736; Executive Orders 10450, 10865, 12333, 12356, and 13467;Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12 (HSPD 12), Policy for a Common Identification Standard for Federal Employees and Contractors, August 27, 2004; and Office of Personnel Management Memorandum, Final Credentialing Standards for Issuing Personal Identity Verification Cards under HSPD-12, July 31, 2008.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The records in this system are used to document and support decisions regarding the suitability, eligibility, and fitness for service of applicants for EEOC employment and contract positions, including criminal background screening for interns, or volunteers, to the extent their duties require access to federal facilities, information, systems, or applications. The records may be used to document security violations and supervisory actions taken.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> a.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
                <p> b.  Except as noted on Standard Forms 85, 85P, and 86, to disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where EEOC becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> c.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose information to any source or potential source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation concerning the retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose information to employees of  contractors who have been engaged by EEOC to perform an activity related to suitability, eligibility, and fitness for service of EEOC applicants and employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in paper files and in electronic media.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Background investigation files are retrieved by name, social security number, or fingerprint.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are maintained and stored in file cabinets in a secured area to which only authorized personnel have access.  Access to electronic records is limited through use of logins and passwords to those whose official duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are destroyed upon notification of death or not later than five years after separation or transfer of employee to another agency or department.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Director, Operations Services Division, Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer, EEOC, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C.  20507.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Inquiries concerning this system of records should be addressed to the system manager.  It is necessary to provide the following information: (1) name; (2) date of birth; and (3) mailing address to which response is to be sent.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information is obtained from a variety of sources, including the employee, contractor or applicant via use of the SF-85, SF-85P, or SF-86 and personal interviews; employers’ and former employers’ records; FBI criminal history records and other databases; financial institutions and credit reports; interviews of witnesses, such as neighbors, friends, co-workers, business associates, teachers, landlords, or family members; tax records; and other public records.  Security violation information is obtained from a variety of sources, such as guard reports, security inspections, witnesses, supervisor’s reports, audit reports.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system of records is exempt in accordance with 5 U.S.C. § 552a(k)(5) from subsection (c)(3) and (d)(1) of the Privacy Act, but only to the extent that the information identifies witnesses promised confidentiality as a condition of providing information during the course of the background investigation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="govt1" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>
            /GOVT-1
        </systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    Equal Employment Opportunity in the Federal Government Complaint and Appeal Records.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Equal employment opportunity complaint files are maintained in an Office of Equal Employment Opportunity or other designated office of the agency or department where the complaint was filed.  EEO hearing records are maintained in the EEOC office in the field that handles the hearing request (See Appendix A).  EEO Appeal files (including appeals from final negotiated grievance decisions involving allegations of discrimination) and petitions for review of decisions of the Merit Systems Protection Board are maintained in the Office of Federal Operations, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 131 M St. NE, Washington, D.C. 20507.  Applicants for federal employment and current and former federal employees who contact an EEO counselor, file complaints of discrimination or reprisal with their agency, file requests for hearings, or file appeals of EEO complaints, petitions for review of decisions of the Merit Systems Protection Board, or appeals of final decisions in negotiated grievance actions involving allegations of discrimination.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system of records contains information or documents compiled during the pre-complaint counseling, investigation, hearing, and appeal of complaints filed under section 717 of Title VII, section 15 of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act, section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act, and the Equal Pay Act and all appeals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 42 U.S.C. 2000e-16(b) and (c); 29 U.S.C. 204(f) and 206(d); 29 U.S.C. 633(a); 29 U.S.C. 791; Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1978, 43 Fed. Reg. 19607 (May 9, 1978); Exec. Order No. 12106, 44 Fed. Reg. 1053 (Jan. 3, 1979).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained for the purpose of counseling, investigating, and adjudicating complaints of employment discrimination brought by applicants and current and former federal employees against federal employers.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                <p> a.  To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate federal, state, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p> b.  To disclose information to another federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a federal agency when the government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> c.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from that congressional office made at the request of that individual.</p>
                <p> d.  To disclose to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, administrative judge, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator, or other duly authorized official engaged in investigation or settlement of a grievance, complaint, or appeal filed by an employee.</p>
                <p> e.  To disclose, in response to a request for discovery or for appearance of a witness, information that is relevant to the subject matter involved in a pending judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p> f.  To disclose information to officials of state or local bar associations or disciplinary boards or committees when they are investigating complaints against attorneys in connection with their representation of a party before EEOC.</p>
                <p> g.  To disclose to a Federal agency in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of government, in response to its request for information in connection with the hiring of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, or the lawful statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision.</p>
                <p> h.  To disclose information to employees of contractors engaged by an agency to carry out the agency’s responsibilities under 29 C.F.R. Part 1614.</p>
                <p> i.  To disclose information to potential witnesses as appropriate and necessary to perform the agency’s functions under 29 C.F.R. Part 1614.</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Storage:</p>
                <p> These records are maintained in file folders and electronically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are indexed by the names of the individuals on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Access to and use of these records are limited to those persons whose official duties require such access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained for one year after resolution of the case and then transferred to the Federal Records Center where they are destroyed after three years.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Within the agency or department where the complaint of discrimination was filed, the system manager is the Director of the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity or other official designated as responsible for the administration and enforcement of equal employment opportunity laws and regulations within the agency or department.</p>
                <p>Where an individual has requested a hearing, the system manager of hearing records is the Director of the Office of Field Programs, 131 M StreetNE, Washington, D.C.  20507.</p>
                <p>Where an EEO complaint or final negotiated grievance decision has been appealed to EEOC or an individual has petitioned EEOC for review of a decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board, the system manager of the appeal or petition file is the Director, Office of Federal Operations, 131 M Street NE, Washington, D.C.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Pursuant to subsection (k)(2) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), this system of records is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I) and (f) of the Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
            <appendix id="app" toc="yes">
            <xhtmlContent>

                <p>Appendix A. </p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC ALBUQUERQUE AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>505 MARQUETTE AVENUE, N.W.</p>
                    <p>SUITE 900 – 9th FLOOR</p>
                    <p>ALBUQUERQUE, NEW MEXICO  87102-2158</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC ATLANTA DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>
                        SAM NUNN ATLANTA FEDERAL CENTER
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        100 ALABAMA STREET, S.W.
                    </p>
                    <p>SUITE 4R30</p>
                    <p>ATLANTA, GEORGIA  30303</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC BALTIMORE FIELD OFFICE</p>
                    <p>CITY CRESCENT BUILDING</p>
                    <p>10 SOUTH HOWARD STREET</p>
                    <p>3RD FLOOR</p>
                    <p>BALTIMORE, MARYLAND  21201-2526</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC BIRMINGHAM DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>RIDGE PARK PLACE</p>
                    <p>1130 22ND STREET, SUITE 2000</p>
                    <p>BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA  35205</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC BOSTON AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>JOHN F. KENNEDY FED BLDG.</p>
                    <p>475 GOVERNMENT CENTER</p>
                    <p>BOSTON, MASSACHUSETTS 02203</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC BUFFALO LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>6 FOUNTAIN PLAZA</p>
                    <p>SUITE 350</p>
                    <p>BUFFALO, NEW YORK 14202</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC CHARLOTTE DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>129 WEST TRADE STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 400</p>
                    <p>CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA 28202</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC CHICAGO DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>500 WEST MADISON STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 2000</p>
                    <p>CHICAGO, ILLINOIS  60661</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC CINCINNATI AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>JOHN W. PECK FED. OFFICE BLDG.</p>
                    <p>550 MAIN STREET, 10TH FLOOR</p>
                    <p>CINCINNATI, OHIO  45202</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC CLEVELAND FIELD OFFICE</p>
                    <p>ANTHONY J. CELEBREZZE FED. BLDG.</p>
                    <p>1240 E. 9TH STREET, SUITE 3001</p>
                    <p>CLEVELAND, OHIO  44199</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC DALLAS DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>207 SOUTH HOUSTON STREET</p>
                    <p>3RD FLOOR</p>
                    <p>DALLAS, TEXAS  75202-4726</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC DENVER FIELD OFFICE</p>
                    <p>303 EAST 17TH AVENUE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 510</p>
                    <p>DENVER, COLORADO  80203</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC DETROIT FIELD OFFICE</p>
                    <p>PATRICK V. MCNAMARA BLDG.</p>
                    <p>477 MICHIGAN AVENUE</p>
                    <p>ROOM 865</p>
                    <p>DETROIT, MICHIGAN  48226-9704</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC EL PASO AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>300 E. MAIN DR.</p>
                    <p>SUITE 500</p>
                    <p>EL PASO, TEXAS  79901</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC FRESNO LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>2300 TULARE STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 215</p>
                    <p>FRESNO, CALIFORNIA  93727</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC GREENSBORO LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>2303 W. MEADOWVIEW ROAD</p>
                    <p>SUITE 201</p>
                    <p>GREENSBORO, NORTH CAROLINA 27407</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC GREENVILE LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>301 NORTH MAIN STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1402</p>
                    <p>GREENVILLE, SOUTH CAROLINA 29601</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC HONOLULU LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>300 ALA MOANA BOULEVARD</p>
                    <p>ROOM 7-127</p>
                    <p>P.O. BOX 50082</p>
                    <p>HONOLULU, HAWAII  96850-0051</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC HOUSTON DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>MICKEY LELAND BLDG.</p>
                    <p>1919 SMITH STREET</p>
                    <p>6TH FLOOR</p>
                    <p>HOUSTON, TEXAS  77002</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC INDIANAPOLIS DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>101 WEST OHIO STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1900</p>
                    <p>INDIANAPOLIS, INDIANA  46204-4203</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC JACKSON AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>DR. A. H. MCCOY FED. BLDG.</p>
                    <p>100 WEST CAPITOL STREET, SUITE 338</p>
                    <p>JACKSON, MISSISSIPPI  39269</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC KANSAS CITY AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>GATEWAY TOWER II</p>
                    <p>400 STATE AVENUE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 905</p>
                    <p>KANSAS CITY, KANSAS  66101</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC LITTLE ROCK AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>820 LOUIAINA STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 200</p>
                    <p>LITTLE ROCK, ARKANSAS  72201</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC LOS ANGELES DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>ROYBAL FED. BLDG.</p>
                    <p>255 EAST TEMPLE STREET</p>
                    <p>4TH FLOOR</p>
                    <p>LOS ANGELES, CALIFORNIA  90012</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC LAS VEGAS LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>333 LAS VEGAS BOULEVARD SOUTH</p>
                    <p>SUITE 8112</p>
                    <p>LAS VEGAS, NEVADA 89101</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC LOUISVILLE AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>600 DR. MARTIN LUTHER KING JR., PLACE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 268</p>
                    <p>LOUISVILLE, KENTUCKY  40202</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC MEMPHIS DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>1407 UNION AVENUE</p>
                    <p>9TH FLOOR</p>
                    <p>MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE  38104</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC MIAMI DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>100 SE 2ND STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1500</p>
                    <p> MIAMI, FLORIDA  33131</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC MILWAUKEE DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>REUSS FED. PLAZA</p>
                    <p>310 WEST WISCONSIN AVENUE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 500</p>
                    <p>MILWAUKEE, WISCONSIN  53203-2292</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC MINNEAPOLIS AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>TOWLE BLDG.</p>
                    <p>330 SOUTH SECOND AVENUE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 720</p>
                    <p>MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA  55401-2224</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC MOBILE LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>63 SOUTH ROYAL STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 504</p>
                    <p>MOBILE, ALABAMA 36602</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC NASHVILLE AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>220 ATHENS WAY</p>
                    <p>SUITE 350</p>
                    <p>NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE  37228-9940</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC NEWARK AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>TWO GATEWAY CENTER</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1703</p>
                    <p>283-299 MARKET STREET</p>
                    <p>NEWARK, NEW JERSEY 07102</p>
                    <p>EEOC NEW ORLEANS DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>HALE BOGGS FED. BLDG.</p>
                    <p>500 POYDRAS STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 809</p>
                    <p>NEW ORLEANS, LOUISIANA  70130</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC NEW YORK DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>33 WHITEHALL STREET</p>
                    <p>5TH FLOOR</p>
                    <p>NEW YORK, NEW YORK 10004</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC NORFOLK LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>FEDERAL BUILDING</p>
                    <p>SUITE 739</p>
                    <p>200 GRANBY STREET</p>
                    <p>NORFOLK, VIRGINIA  23510</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC OAKLAND LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>1301 CLAY STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1170-N</p>
                    <p>OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA  94612-5217</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC OKLAHOMA CITY AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>215 DEAN A MCGEE AVENUE</p>
                    <p>OKLAHOMA CITY, OKLAHOMA  73102</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC PHILADELPHIA DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>801 MARKET STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1300</p>
                    <p>PHILADELPHIA, PENNSYLVANIA  19107</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC PHOENIX DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>3300 NORTH CENTRAL AVENUE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 690</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX, ARIZONA  85012-2504</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC PITTSBURGH AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>WILLIAM S. MOORHEAD FED. BLDG.</p>
                    <p>1001 LIBERTY AVENUE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1112</p>
                    <p>PITTSBURGH, PENNSYLVANIA  15222-4187</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC RALEIGH AREA OFFICE</p>
                    <p>434 FAYETTEVILLE STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 700</p>
                    <p>RALEIGH, NORTH CAROLINA 27601-1701</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC RICHMOND LOCAL  OFFICE</p>
                    <p>400 N. EIGHT STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 350</p>
                    <p>RICHMOND, VIRGINIA  23219</p>
                    <p>EEOC SAN ANTONIO FIELD OFFICE</p>
                    <p>LEGACY OAKS, BLDG. A</p>
                    <p>5410 FREDERICKSBURG ROAD</p>
                    <p>SUITE 200</p>
                    <p>SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS  78229-3555</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC SAN DIEGO LOCAL  OFFICE</p>
                    <p>555 WEST BEECH STREET, SUITE 504</p>
                    <p>SAN DIEGO, CALIFORNIA  92101</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC SAN FRANCISCO DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>450 GOLDEN GATE AVENUE</p>
                    <p>5 WEST, P.O. BOX 36025</p>
                    <p>SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA  94102</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC SAN JOSE LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>96 NORTH 3RD STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 250</p>
                    <p>SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA  95112</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC SAN JUAN LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>525 F.D. ROOSEVELT AVENUE</p>
                    <p>PLAZA LAS AMERICAS, SUITE 1202</p>
                    <p>SAN JUAN, PUERTO RICO 00918-8001</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC SAVANNAH LOCAL OFFICE</p>
                    <p>7391 HODGSON MEMORIAL DRIVE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 200</p>
                    <p>SAVANNAH, GEORGIA 31406-2579</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC SEATTLE FIELD OFFICE</p>
                    <p>FEDERAL OFFICE BUILDING</p>
                    <p>909 FIRST AVENUE</p>
                    <p>SUITE 400</p>
                    <p>SEATTLE, WASHINGTON  98104-1061</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC ST. LOUIS DISTRICT OFFICE</p>
                    <p>ROBERT A. YOUNG BUILDING</p>
                    <p>1222 SPRUCE STREET</p>
                    <p> ROOM 8.100</p>
                    <p>ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI  63103</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC TAMPA FIELD  OFFICE</p>
                    <p>501 EAST POLK STREET</p>
                    <p>SUITE 1000</p>
                    <p>TAMPA, FLORIDA  33602</p>
                    <p>U.S. EEOC WASHINGTON FIELD OFFICE</p>
                    <p>131 M STREET NE</p>
                    <p>FOURTH FLOOR</p>
                    <p>SUITE 4NWO2F</p>
                    <p>WASHINGTON, DC 20507-0100</p>

                </xhtmlContent>
</appendix>


           
            <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
                <regulationsTitle number="29">
                    <heading>Labor </heading>
                    <regulationsChapter number="XIV">
                        <heading> Equal Employment Opportunity Commission </heading>
                        <regulationsPart number="1611">
                            <heading> PRIVACY ACT REGULATIONS </heading>
                            <xhtmlContent>
                                <p>
                                    1611.1 Purpose and scope.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.2 Definitions.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.3 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.4 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.5 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.6 Special procedures: Medical records.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.7 Request for correction or amendment to record.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.8 Agency review of request for correction or amendment to record.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.9 Appeal of initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.10 Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.11 Fees.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.12 Penalties.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.13 Specific Exemptions--Charge and complaint files.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.14 Exemptions--Office of Inspector General Files.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    1611.15 Exemption--EEOC Personnel Security Files.
                                </p>
                                <p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a.
                                </p>
                                <p><b>Source:</b> 42 FR 7949, January 2, 2017 and December 31, 2018.

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.1
                                        Purpose and scope.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    This part contains the regulations of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (the Commission) implementing the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a. It sets forth the basic responsibilities of the Commission under the Privacy Act (the Act) and offers guidance to members of the public who wish to exercise any of the rights established by the Act with regard to records maintained by the Commission. All records contained in system EEOC/GOVT-1, including those maintained by other agencies, are subject to the Commission's Privacy Act regulations. Requests for access to, an accounting of disclosures for, or amendment of records in EEOC/GOVT-1 must be processed by agency personnel in accordance with this part. Commission records that are contained in a government-wide system of records established by the U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM), the General Services Administration (GSA), the Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB), the Office of Government Ethics (OGE) or the Department of Labor (DOL) for which those agencies have published systems notices are subject to the publishing agency's Privacy Act regulations. Where the government-wide systems notices permit access to these records through the employing agency, an individual should submit requests for access to, for amendment of or for an accounting of disclosures to the Commission offices as indicated in &#167; 1611.3(b).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [56 FR 29580, June 28, 1991]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.2
                                        Definitions.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    For purposes of this part, the terms <i>individual, maintain, record,</i> and <i>system of records</i> shall have the meanings set forth in 5 U.S.C. 552a.

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.3
                                        Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) Any person who wishes to be notified if a system of records maintained by the Commission contains any record pertaining to him or her, or to request access to such record or to request an accounting of disclosures made of such record, shall submit a written request, either in person or by mail, in accordance with the instructions set forth in the system notice published in the <i>Federal Register.</i> The request shall include:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) The name of the individual making the request;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) The name of the system of records (as set forth in the system notice to which the request relates);
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) Any other information specified in the system notice; and
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) When the request is for access to records, a statement indicating whether the requester desires to make a personal inspection of the records or be supplied with copies by mail.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) Requests pertaining to records contained in a system of records established by the Commission and for which the Commission has published a system notice should be submitted to the person or office indicated in the system notice. Requests pertaining to Commission records contained in the government-wide systems of records listed below should be submitted as follows:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) For systems OPM/GOVT-1 (General Personnel Records), OPM/GOVT-2 (Employee Performance File System Records), OPM/GOVT-3 (Records of Adverse Actions and Actions Based on Unacceptable Performance), OPM/GOVT-5 (Recruiting, Examining and Placement Records), OPM/GOVT-6 (Personnel Research and Test Validation Records), OPM/GOVT-9 (Files on Position Classification Appeals, Job Grading Appeals and Retained Grade or Pay Appeals), OPM/GOVT-10 (Employee Medical File System Records) and DOL/ESA-13 (Office of Workers' Compensation Programs, Federal Employees' Compensation File), to the Director of Personnel Management Services, EEOC, 131 M Street, NE., Washington, DC 20507;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) For systems OGE/GOVT-1 (Executive Branch Public Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Ethics Program Records), OGE/GOVT-2 (Confidential Statements of Employment and Financial Interests) and MSPB/GOVT-1 (Appeal and Case Records), to the Legal Counsel, EEOC, 131 M Street, NE., Washington, DC 20507;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) For system OPM/GOVT-7 (Applicant Race, Sex, National Origin, and Disability Status Records), to the Director of the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, EEOC, 1801 L Street, NW., Washington, DC 20507;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) For systems GSA/GOVT-3 (Travel Charge Card Program) and GSA/GOVT-4 (Contracted Travel Services Program) to the Director of Financial and Resource Management Services, EEOC, 131 M Street, NE., Washington, DC 20507.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (c) Any person whose request for access under paragraph (a) of this section is denied, may appeal that denial in accordance with &#167; 1611.5(c).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [42 FR 7949, Feb. 8, 1977, as amended at 56 FR 29581, June 28, 1991; 74 FR 3430, Jan. 21, 2009]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.4
                                        Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) If a person submitting a request for access under &#167; 1611.3 has asked that the Commission authorize a personal inspection of records pertaining to that person, and the appropriate Commission official has granted that request the requester shall present himself or herself at the time and place specified in the Commission's response or arrange another, mutually convenient time with the appropriate Commission official.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) Prior to inspection of the records, the requester shall present sufficient personal identification (e.g., driver's license, employee identification card, social security card, credit cards). If the requester is unable to provide such identification, the requester shall complete and sign in the presence of a Commission official a signed statement asserting his or her identity and stipulating that he or she understands that knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another individual under false pretenses is a misdemeanor punishable by fine up to $5,000.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (c) Any person who has requested access under &#167; 1611.3 to records through personal inspection, and who wishes to be accompanied by another person or persons during this inspection, shall submit a written statement authorizing disclosure of the record in such person's or person's presence.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (d) If an individual submitting a request by mail under &#167; 1611.3 wishes to have copies furnished by mail, he or she must include with the request a signed and notarized statement asserting his or her identity and stipulating that he or she understands that knowlingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another individual under false pretenses is a misdemeanor punishable by fine up to $5,000.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (e) A request filed by the parent of any minor or the legal guardian of any incompetent person shall: state the relationship of the requester to the individual to whom the record pertains; present sufficient identification; and, if not evident from information already available to the Commission, present appropriate proof of the relationship or guardianship.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (f) A person making a request pursuant to a power of attorney must possess a specific power of attorney to make that request.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (g) No verification of identity will be required where the records sought are publicly available under the Freedom of Information Act.

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.5
                                        Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) Upon receipt of request for notification as to whether the Commission maintains a record about an individual and/or request for access to such record:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) The appropriate Commission official shall acknowledge such request in writing within 10 working days of receipt of the request. Wherever practicable, the acknowledgement should contain the notification and/or determination required in paragraph (a) (2) of this section.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) The appropriate Commission official shall provide, within 30 working days of receipt of the request, written notification to the requester as to the existence of the records and/or a determination as to whether or not access will be granted. In some cases, such as where records have to be recalled from the Federal Records Center, notification and/or a determination of access may be delayed. In the event of such a delay, the Commission official shall inform the requester of this fact, the reasons for the delay, and an estimate of the date on which notification and/or a determination will be forthcoming.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) If access to a record is granted, the determination shall indicate when and where the record will be available for personal inspection. If a copy of the record has been requested, the Commission official shall mail that copy or retain it at the Commission to present to the individual, upon receipt of a check or money order in an amount computed pursuant to &#167; 1611.11.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) When access to a record is to be granted, the appropriate Commission official will normally provide access within 30 working days of receipt of the request unless, for good cause shown, he or she is unable to do so, in which case the requester shall be informed within 30 working days of receipt of the request as to those reasons and when it is anticipated that access will be granted.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (5) The Commission shall not deny any request under &#167; 1611.3 concerning the existence of records about the requester in any system of records it maintains, or any request for access to such records, unless that system is exempted from the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a in &#167;&#167; 1611.13, 1611.14, or 1611.15.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (6) If the Commission receives a request pursuant to &#167; 1611.3 for access to records in a system of records it maintains which is so exempt, the appropriate Commission official shall deny the request.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) Upon request, the appropriate Commission official shall make available an accounting of disclosures pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), unless that system is exempted from the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a in &#167;&#167; 1611.13, 1611.14, or 1611.15.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (c) If a request for access to records is denied pursuant to paragraph (a) or (b) of this section, the determination shall specify the reasons for the denial and advise the individual how to appeal the denial. If the request pertains to a system of records for which the Commission has published a system notice, any appeal must be submitted in writing to the Legal Counsel, EEOC, 131 M Street, NE., Washington, DC 20507. If the request pertains to a government-wide system of records any appeal should be in writing, identified as a Privacy Act appeal and submitted as follows:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) For systems established by OPM and for which OPM has published a system notice, to the Assistant Director for Workforce Information, Personnel Systems and Oversight Group, OPM, 1900 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20415. The OPM Privacy Act regulations, 5 CFR 297.207, shall govern such appeals.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) For systems established by OGE and for which OGE has published a system notice, to the Privacy Act Officer, Office of Government Ethics, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Suite 500, Washington, DC 20005-3917. The OGE Privacy Act regulations, 5 CFR part 2606, shall govern such appeals.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) For the system established by MSPB and for which MSPB has published a system notice, to the Deputy Executive Director for Management, U.S. Merit Systems Protection Board, 1120 Vermont Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20419. The MSPB Privacy Act regulations, 5 CFR part 1205, shall govern such appeals.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) For systems established by GSA and for which GSA has published a system notice, to GSA Privacy Act Officer, General Services Administration (ATRAI), Washington, DC 20405. The GSA Privacy Act regulations, 41 CFR 105-64.301-5, shall govern such appeals.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (5) For the system established by DOL and for which DOL has published a system notice, to the Solicitor of Labor, Department of Labor, 200 Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20210. The DOL Privacy Act regulations, 29 CFR 70a.9, shall govern such appeals.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (d) In the event that access to a record is denied on appeal by the Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee, the requestor shall be advised of his or her right to bring a civil action in Federal district court for review of the denial in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (e) Nothing in 5 U.S.C. 552a or this part allows an individual access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [42 FR 7949, Feb. 8, 1977, as amended at 56 FR 29581, June 28, 1991; 74 FR 3430, Jan. 21, 2009; 74 FR 6831, Feb. 11, 2009]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.6
                                        Special procedures: Medical records.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    In the event the Commission receives a request pursuant to &#167; 1611.3 for access to medical records (including psychological records) whose disclosure of which the appropriate Commission official determines could be harmful to the individual to whom they relate, he or she may refuse to disclose the records directly to the requester but shall transmit them to a physician designated by that individual.

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.7
                                        Request for correction or amendment to record.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) Any person who wishes to request correction or amendment of any record pertaining to him or her which is contained in a system of records maintained by the Commission, shall submit that request in writing in accordance with the instructions set forth in the system notice for that system of records. If the request is submitted by mail, the envelope should be clearly labeled "Personal Information Amendment." The request shall include:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) The name of the individual making the request;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) The name of the system of records as set forth in the system notice to which the request relates;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) A description of the nature (e.g., modification, addition or deletion) and substance of the correction or amendment requested; and
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) Any other information specified in the system notice.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) Any person submitting a request pursuant to paragraph (a) of this section shall include sufficient information in support of that request to allow the Commission to apply the standards set forth in 5 U.S.C. 552a (e).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (c) All requests to amend pertaining to personnel records described in &#167; 1611.3(b) shall conform to the requirements of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section and may be directed to the appropriate officials as indicated in &#167; 1611.3(b). Such requests may also be directed to the system manager specified in the OPM's systems notices.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (d) Any person whose request under paragraph (a) of this section is denied may appeal that denial in accordance with &#167; 1611.9(a).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [42 FR 7949, Feb. 8, 1977, as amended at 56 FR 29581, June 28, 1991]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.8
                                        Agency review of request for correction or amendment to record.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) When the Commission receives a request for amendment or correction under &#167; 1611.7(a), the appropriate Commission official shall acknowledge that request in writing within 10 working days of receipt. He or she shall promptly either:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) Determine to grant all or any portion of a request for correction or amendment; and:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (i) Advise the individual of that determination;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (ii) Make the requested correction or amendment; and
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (iii) Inform any person or agency outside the Commission to whom the record has been disclosed, and where an accounting of that disclosure is maintained in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(c), of the occurrence and substance of the correction or amendments, or;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) Inform the requester of the refusal to amend the record in accordance with the request; the reason for the refusal; and the procedures whereby the requester can appeal the refusal to the Legal Counsel of the Commission.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) If the Commission official informs the requester of the determination within the 10-day deadline, a separate acknowledgement is not required.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (c) In conducting the review of a request for correction or amendment, the Commission official shall be guided by the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(e).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (d) In the event that the Commission receives a notice of correction or amendment from another agency that pertains to records maintained by the Commission, the Commission shall make the appropriate correction or amendment to its records and comply with paragraph (a)(1)(iii) of this section.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (e) Requests for amendment or correction of records maintained in the government-wide systems of records listed in &#167; 1611.5(c) shall be governed by the appropriate agency's regulations cited in that paragraph. Requests for amendment or correction of records maintained by other agencies in system EEOC/GOVT-1 shall be governed by the Commission's regulations in this part.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [42 FR 7949, Feb. 8, 1977, as amended at 56 FR 29581, June 28, 1991]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.9
                                        Appeal of initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) If a request for correction or amendment of a record in a system of records established by EEOC is denied, the requester may appeal the determination in writing to the Legal Counsel, EEOC, 131 M Street, NE., Washington, DC 20507. If the request pertains to a record that is contained in the government-wide systems of records listed in &#167; 1611.5(c), an appeal must be made in accordance with the appropriate agency's regulations cited in that paragraph.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) The Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee shall make a final determination with regard to an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section not later than 30 working days from the date on which the individual requests a review, unless for good cause shown, this 30-day period is extended and the requester is notified of the reasons for the extension and of the estimated date on which a final determination will be made. Such extensions will be used only in exceptional circumstances and will not normally exceed 30 working days.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (c) In conducting the review of an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section, the Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee shall be guided by the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(e).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (d) If the Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee determines to grant all or any portion of a request on an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section, he or she shall so inform the requester, and the appropriate Commission official shall comply with the procedures set forth in &#167; 1611.8(a)(1)(ii) and (iii).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (e) If the Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee determines in accordance with paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section not to grant all or any portion of a request on an appeal submitted under paragraph (a) of this section, he or she shall inform the requester:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) Of this determination and the reasons for it;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) Of the requester's right to file a concise statement of reasons for disagreement with the determination of the Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) That such statements of disagreement will be made available to anyone to whom the record is subsequently disclosed, together with (if the Legal Counsel or Legal Counsel's designee deems it appropriate) a brief statement summarizing the Legal Counsel or Legal Counsel's designee's reasons for refusing to amend the record;
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) That prior recipients of the disputed record will be provided with a copy of the statement of disagreement together with (if the Legal Counsel or Legal Counsel's designee deems it appropriate) a brief statement of the Legal Counsel or Legal Counsel's designee's reasons for refusing to amend the record, to the extent that an accounting of disclosure is maintained under 5 U.S.C. 552a(c); and
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (5) Of the requester's right to file a civil action in Federal district court to seek a review of the determination of the Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (f) The Legal Counsel or the Legal Counsel's designee shall ensure that any statements of disagreement submitted by a requestor are made available or distributed in accordance with paragraphs (e) (3) and (4) of this section.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [56 FR 29582, June 28, 1991, as amended by; 74 FR 3430, Jan. 21, 2009]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.10
                                        Disclosure of record to person other than the individual to whom it pertains.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    The Commission shall not disclose any record which is contained in a system of records it maintains, by any means of communication to any person or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains, unless the disclosure is authorized by one or more provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(b).

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.11
                                        Fees.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) No fee shall be charged for searches necessary to locate records. No charge shall be made if the total fees authorized are less than $1.00. Fees shall be charged for services rendered under this part as follows:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) For copies made by photocopy--$0.15 per page (maximum of 10 copies). For copies prepared by computer, such as tapes or printouts, EEOC will charge the direct cost incurred by the agency, including operator time. For other forms of duplication, EEOC will charge the actual costs of that duplication.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) For attestation of documents--$25.00 per authenticating affidavit or declaration.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) For certification of documents--$50.00 per authenticating affidavit or declaration.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) All required fees shall be paid in full prior to issuance of requested copies of records. Fees are payable to "Treasurer of the United States."
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [71 FR 11309, Mar. 7, 2006]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.12
                                        Penalties.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    The criminal penalties which have been established for violations of the Privacy Act of 1974 are set forth in 5 U.S.C. 552a(i). Penalties are applicable to any officer or employee of the Commission; to contractors and employees of such contractors who enter into contracts with the Commission on or after September 27, 1975, and who are considered to be employees of the Commission within the meaning of 5 U.S.C. 552a(m); and to any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual from the Commission under false pretenses.

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.13
                                        Specific Exemptions--Charge and complaint files
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    Pursuant to subsection (k)(2) of the Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), systems EEOC-1 (Age and Equal Pay Act Discrimination Case Files), EEOC-3 (Title VII and Americans with Disabilities Act Discrimination Case Files), EEOC-15 (Internal Harassment Inquiries) and EEOC/GOVT-1 (Equal Employment Opportunity Complaint Records and Appeal Records) are exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I), and (f) of the Privacy Act. The Commission has determined to exempt these systems from the above named provisions of the Privacy Act for the following reasons:
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) The files in these systems contain information obtained by the Commission and other Federal agencies in the course of harassment inquiries, and investigations of charges and complaints that violations of Title VII of the Civil Rights Act, the Age Discrimination in Employment Act, the Equal Pay Act, the Americans With Disabilities Act and the Rehabilitation Act have occurred. In some instances, EEOC and agencies obtain information regarding unlawful employment practices other than those complained of by the individual who is the subject of the file. It would impede the law enforcement activities of the Commission and other agencies if these provisions of the Act applied to such records.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) The subject individuals of the files in these systems know that the Commission or their employing agencies are maintaining a file on their charge, complaint, or inquiry, and the general nature of the information contained in it.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (c) Subject individuals of the files in EEOC-1 (Age and Equal Pay Act Discrimination Case Files), EEOC-3 (Title VII and Americans with Disabilities Act Discrimination Case Files, and EEOC/GOVT-1 (Equal Employment Opportunity Complaint Records and Appeal Records) have been provided a means of access to their records by the Freedom of Information Act. Subject individuals of the charge files in system EEOC-3 have also been provided a means of access to their records by section 83 of the Commission's Compliance Manual. Subject individuals of the case files in system EEOC/GOVT-1 have also been provided a means of access to their records by the Commission's Equal Employment Opportunity in the Federal Government regulation, 29 CFR 1614.108(f).
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (d) Many of the records contained in system EEOC/GOVT-1 are obtained from other systems of records. If such records are incorrect, it would be more appropriate for an individual to seek to amend or correct those records in their primary filing location so that notice of the correction can be given to all recipients of that information.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (e) Subject individuals of the files in each of these systems have access to relevant information provided by the allegedly discriminating employer, accuser or harasser as part of the investigatory process and are given the opportunity to explain or contradict such information and to submit any responsive evidence of their own. To allow such individuals the additional right to amend or correct the records submitted by the allegedly discriminatory employer, accuser or harasser would undermine the investigative process and destroy the integrity of the administrative record.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (f) The Commission has determined that the exemption of these four systems of records from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (e)(4)(H), (e)(4)(I) and (f) of the Privacy Act is necessary for the agency's law enforcement efforts.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [67 FR 72373, Dec. 5, 2002]

                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.14
                                        Exemptions--Office of Inspector General Files.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (a) <i>General.</i> The system of records entitled Office of Inspector General Investigative Files consists, in part, of information compiled by the OIG for the purpose of criminal law enforcement investigations. Therefore, to the extent that information in this system falls within the scope of Exemption (j)(2) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), this system of records is exempt from the requirements of the following subsections of the Privacy Act, for the reasons stated below.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) From subsection (c)(3), because release of an accounting of disclosures to an individual who is the subject of an investigation could reveal the nature and scope of the investigation and could result in the altering or destruction of evidence, improper influencing of witnesses, and other evasive actions that could impede or compromise the investigation.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) From subsection (d)(1), because release of investigative records to an individual who is the subject of an investigation could interfere with pending or prospective law enforcement proceedings, constitute an unwarranted invasion of the personal privacy of third parties, reveal the identity of confidential sources, or reveal sensitive investigative techniques and procedures.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) From subsection (d)(2), because amendment or correction of investigative records could interfere with pending or prospective law enforcement proceedings, or could impose an impossible administrative and investigative burden by requiring the OIG to continuously retrograde its investigations attempting to resolve questions of accuracy, relevance, timeliness and completeness.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) From subsection (e)(1), because it is often impossible to determine relevance or necessity of information in the early stages of an investigation. The value of such information is a question of judgment and timing; what appears relevant and necessary when collected may ultimately be evaluated and viewed as irrelevant and unnecessary to an investigation. In addition, the OIG may obtain information concerning the violation of laws other than those within the scope of its jurisdiction. In the interest of effective law enforcement, the OIG should retain this information because it may aid in establishing patterns of unlawful activity and provide leads for other law enforcement agencies. Further, in obtaining evidence during an investigation, information may be provided to the OIG which relates to matters incidental to the main purpose of the investigation but which may be pertinent to the investigative jurisdiction of another agency. Such information cannot readily be identified.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (5) From subsection (e)(2), because in a law enforcement investigation it is usually counterproductive to collect information to the greatest extent practicable from the subject thereof. It is not always feasible to rely upon the subject of an investigation as a source for information which may implicate him or her in illegal activities. In addition, collecting information directly from the subject could seriously compromise an investigation by prematurely revealing its nature and scope, or could provide the subject with an opportunity to conceal criminal activities, or intimidate potential sources, in order to avoid apprehension.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (6) From subsection (e)(3), because providing such notice to the subject of an investigation, or to other individual sources, could seriously compromise the investigation by prematurely revealing its nature and scope, or could inhibit cooperation, permit the subject to evade apprehension, or cause interference with undercover activities.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (b) <i>Specific.</i> The system of records entitled Office of Inspector General Investigative Files consists, in part, of investigatory material compiled by the OIG for law enforcement purposes. Therefore, to the extent that information in this system falls within the coverage of exemption (k)(2) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), this system of records is exempt from the requirements of the following subsections of the Privacy Act, for the reasons stated below.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (1) From subsection (c)(3), because release of an accounting of disclosures to an individual who is the subject of an investigation could reveal the nature and scope of the investigation and could result in the altering or destruction of evidence, improper influencing of witnesses, and other evasive actions that could impede or compromise the investigation.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (2) From subsection (d)(1), because release of investigative records to an individual who is the subject of an investigation could interfere with pending or prospective law enforcement proceedings, constitute an unwarranted invasion of the personal privacy of third parties, reveal the identity of confidential sources, or reveal sensitive investigative techniques and procedures.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (3) From subsection (d)(2), because amendment or correction of investigative records could interfere with pending or prospective law enforcement proceedings, or could impose an impossible administrative and investigative burden by requiring the OIG to continuously retrograde its investigations attempting to resolve questions of accuracy, relevance, timeliness and completeness.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    (4) From subsection (e)(1), because it is often impossible to determine relevance or necessity of information in the early stages of an investigation. The value of such information is a question of judgment and timing; what appears relevant and necessary when collected may ultimately be evaluated and viewed as irrelevant and unnecessary to investigation. In addition, the OIG may obtain information concerning the violation of laws other than those within the scope of its jurisdiction. In the interest of effective law enforcement, the OIG could retain this information because it may aid in establishing patterns of unlawful activity and provide leads for other law enforcement agencies. Further, in obtaining evidence during an investigation, information may be provided to the OIG which relates to matters incidental to the main purpose of the investigation but which may be pertinent to the investigative jurisdiction of another agency. Such information cannot readily be identified.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [67 FR 72374, Dec. 5, 2002]
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    <b>
                                        &#167; 1611.15
                                        Exemption--EEOC Personnel Security Files.
                                    </b>
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    EEOC's system of records entitled EEOC Personnel Security Files contains records that document and support decisions regarding suitability, eligibility and fitness for service of applicants for EEOC employment and contract positions. The records include background investigation records. Pursuant to section (k)(5) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), this system of records is exempt from the provisions of sections (c)(3) and (d)(1) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3) and (d)(1), but only to the extent that the accounting of disclosures or the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the government under an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.
                                </p>
                                <p>
                                    [74 FR 6832, Feb. 11, 2009]
                               </p>

                            </xhtmlContent>
    </regulationsPart>
    </regulationsChapter>
    </regulationsTitle>
    </regulations>
    </agency>
    </pai>

