<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation</name>
<abbrev>
PBGC
</abbrev>
    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs> 
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-10-08/pdf/2020-19950.pdf</url>
        <title>Privacy Act Regulation; Exemption for Insider Threat Program Records</title>
        <date year="20" month="10 " day="8" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-09-01/pdf/2021-18918.pdf</url>
        <title>PBGC-19: Office of Negotiations and Restructuring/Office of General Counsel Case Management System — PBGC </title>
        <date year="21" month="9 " day="1" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-16/pdf/2021-24905.pdf</url>
        <title>PBGC – 21: Reasonable Accommodation Records</title>
        <date year="21" month="11 " day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses
</b></p>
    <p>G1. Routine Use—Law Enforcement: A record from this system may be disclosed to law enforcement in the event the record is connected to a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute, regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto.  Such disclosure may be made to the appropriate agency, whether federal, state, local, or tribal, or other public authority responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, if PBGC determines that the records are both relevant and necessary to any enforcement, regulatory, investigative or prospective responsibility of the receiving entity.</p>
    <p>G2. Routine Use—Disclosure When Requesting Information: A record from this system of records may be disclosed to a federal, state, tribal or local agency or to another public or private source maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information if, and to the extent necessary, to obtain information relevant to a PBGC decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, or the letting of a contract.</p>
    <p>G3. Routine Use—Disclosure of Existence of Record Information: With the approval of the Director, Human Resources Department (or his or her designee), the fact that this system of records includes information relevant to a federal agency’s decision in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit may be disclosed to that federal agency.</p>
    <p>G4. Routine Use—Disclosure in Litigation: A record from this system of records may be disclosed in a proceeding before a court or other adjudicative body in which PBGC, an employee of PBGC in his or her official capacity, an employee of PBGC in his or her individual capacity whom PBGC (or the Department of Justice (DOJ)) has agreed to represent is a party, or the United States or any other federal agency is a party and PBGC determines that it has an interest in the proceeding, and if PBGC determines that the record is relevant to the proceeding and that the use is compatible with the purpose for which PBGC collected the information.</p>
    <p>G5. Routine Use—Disclosure to DOJ in Litigation: When PBGC, an employee of PBGC in his or her official capacity, or an employee of PBGC in his or her individual capacity whom PBGC (or DOJ) has agreed to represent is a party to a proceeding before a court or other adjudicative body, or the United States or any other federal agency is a party and PBGC determines that it has an interest in the proceeding, a record from this system of records may be disclosed to DOJ if PBGC is consulting with DOJ regarding the proceeding or has decided that DOJ will represent PBGC, or its interest, in the proceeding and PBGC determines that the record is relevant to the proceeding and that the use is compatible with the purpose for which PBGC collected the information.</p>
    <p>G6. Routine Use—Disclosure to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB): A record from this system of records may be disclosed to OMB in connection with the review of private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A–19 at any stage of the legislative coordination and clearance process as set forth in that Circular.</p>
    <p>G7. Routine Use—Congressional Inquiries: A record from this system of records may be disclosed to a congressional office in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.</p>
    <p>G8. Routine Use—Disclosure to Labor Organizations: A record from this system of records may be disclosed to an official of a labor organization recognized under 5 U.S.C. ch. 71 when necessary for the labor organization to properly perform its duties as the collective bargaining representative of PBGC employees in the bargaining unit.</p>
    <p>G9. Routine Use—Disclosure in Response to a Breach: A record from this system of records may be disclosed to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) PBGC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) PBGC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with PBGC’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
    <p>G10. Routine Use—Contractors, Experts, and Consultants: To contractors, experts, consultants, and the agents thereof, and others performing or working on a contract, service, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for PBGC when necessary to accomplish an agency function. Individuals provided information under this routine use are subject to the same Privacy Act requirements and limitations on disclosure as are applicable to PBGC employees.</p>
    <p>G11. Routine Use—Records Management: To the National Archives and Records Administration or to the General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
    <p>G12. Routine Use—Gathering Information: To any source from which information is requested in the course of processing a grievance, investigation, arbitration, or other litigation, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested.</p>
    <p>G13. Routine Use—Disclosure to a Federal Agency: To disclose information to a federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, issuing a security clearance, conducting a security or suitability investigation of an individual, or classifying jobs, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on the matter.</p>
    <p>G14. Routine Use—Disclosure to Another Federal Agency or Federal Entity in Response to a Breach: To another federal agency or federal entity, when information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security. </p>

</xhtmlContent></routineUses>

    <section id="pbgc1" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-1: Congressional Correspondence — PBGC
               </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Communications Outreach and Legislative Affairs, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; and 5 U.S.C. 301</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained to catalog and respond to correspondence received from members of Congress and their staff on behalf of their constituents, and to respond to correspondence directed to the Office of the Director of the PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Members of the United States Congress and staff, Congressional constituents and individuals who have corresponded with PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Names of members of Congress, congressional staff and constituents; addresses; phone numbers; social security numbers; customer identification numbers; email addresses; copies of correspondence received; replies to such correspondence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Members of Congress and their staff; correspondents; agency employees preparing responses to incoming correspondence or who generate original correspondence in their official capacities.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S. C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G11, G13 and G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Name.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 1, Congressional Correspondence (last published at 81 FR 63300 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc2" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-2: Disbursements — PBGC
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005, PBGC Field Offices (Field Benefit Administration), and/or paying agent worksites. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Financial Operations Department, PBGC, K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 31 U.S.C. 6101; 31 U.S.C. 9101, et seq.; 31 U.S.C. 3716.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained for use in determining amounts to be paid and in effecting payments by the Department of the Treasury on behalf of PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC Employees; consultants; contractors; vendors; and any other individuals who receive payments from PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Acquisition data for the procurement of goods and services; invoices; payment vouchers; financial information of commercial vendors and government contractors; Electronic Funds Transfer (EFT) information; IP information; cookies (session and persistent); name; address; taxpayer identification number; financial information; bank information; Social Security number; and other information related to the disbursement of funds.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals and PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses Gl through G7 and G9 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system of records may be transmitted to the United States Department of the Treasury and/or financial institutions, including entities contracted by PBGC, to effect payments to consultants and vendors, to verify consultants' and vendors' eligibility to receive payments, or to fulfill PBGC's requirement pursuant to the Digital Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014.</p>
                <p>3.  To the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), or the Government Accountability Office (GAO) when the information is required for program evaluation purposes.</p>
                <p>4. A record from this system may be disclosed to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name, social security number, and tax payer identification number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
                <p>Records existing on paper are destroyed beyond recognition.  Transactional records may be temporary in nature and deleted once payment has been accepted, any action has been completed, superseded, obsolete, or no longer needed. The retention of other records may be discontinued at the completion of the contract, a requisition requiring payment, or upon receipt of the payment itself.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    PBGC – 2, Disbursements (last published at 81 FR 63301 (September 14,

                    2016)).
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc3" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-3: Employee Payroll, Leave, and Attendance Records — PBGC
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Financial Operations Division, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
                <p>Director, Human Resources Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 5 U.S.C. 5501-5584.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained to perform agency functions involving employee, student, and intern leave, attendance, and payments, including determinations relating to the amounts to be paid to employees, the distribution of pay according to employee, student, and intern directions (for allotments to financial institutions, and for other authorized purposes), tax withholdings and other authorized deductions, and for statistical purposes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former PBGC employees, students and interns.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Personnel information, such as: names, addresses, phone numbers, social security numbers, employee numbers, dates of birth, notifications of personnel actions; payroll information, such as: allotments and requests, marital status and number of dependents, beneficiary data, child support enforcement order information (which may include the social security numbers of custodian and minor children), debts owed to PBGC, debts owed to the federal government, garnishments, personal bank account information, direct deposit information, union dues, tax information, other deductions, time and attendance records; emergency contact information; co-owner and/or beneficiary of bonds; Thrift Savings Plan information; Flexible Spending Account information; Long Term Care Insurance; awards; retirement information; salary data including pay rate, grade, length of service; health information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; subject individuals’ supervisors; timekeepers; Department of the Interior, Interior Business Center; and, the Office of Personnel Management.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system may be disclosed to the United States Department of the Interior, the United States Department of Labor, Social Security Administration, and the United States Department of the Treasury in order to effect payments to current or former PBGC employees, students, and interns.</p>
                <p>3. Information regarding current payments due or delinquent repayments owed to PBGC through current and former employees, students, and interns may be shared with the Department of the Treasury for the purposes of offset.</p>
                <p>4. Information from this system of records may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to that agency’s responsibility for the evaluation and oversight of federal personnel management.</p>
                <p>5.  A record from this system may be disclosed to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
               
                </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; employee number; or social security number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 3, Employee Payroll, Leave, and Attendance Records (last published at 81 FR 63301 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc6" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-6: Plan Participant and Beneficiary Data — PBGC
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, and/or PBGC Field Offices (Field Benefit Administration), plan administrator worksites, and paying agent worksites. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief of Benefits Administration, Office of Benefits Administration, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1055, 1056(d)(3), 1302, 1321, 1341, 1342, and 1350; 26 U.S.C. 6103; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained for use in determining whether participants, alternate payees, beneficiaries, spouses and domestic partners are eligible for benefits under plans covered by ERISA, determining supplemental payments to be paid to those persons by a party other than PBGC, determining the amounts of benefits to be paid, making benefit payments, collecting benefit overpayments, and complying with statutory and regulatory mandates.</p>
                <p>Names, addresses, and telephone numbers are used to survey customers to measure their satisfaction with PBGC’s benefit payment services and to track (for follow-up) those who do not respond to surveys.</p>
                <p>Information from this system may be used for research into, and statistical information about, benefit determinations for actuaries and publications.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Participants, alternate payees, beneficiaries, spouses and domestic partners in terminated and non-terminated retirement plans covered by the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA), and other individuals who contact PBGC regarding benefits they may be owed from PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Names; addresses; telephone numbers; e-mail addresses; gender; social security numbers and other Social Security Administration information; dates of birth and death; dates of hire, termination, and retirement; salary; employment history; marital status; domestic relations orders; time of plan participation; eligibility status; pay status; benefit data, including records of benefit payments made to participants, alternate payees, and beneficiaries in terminating and terminated retirement plans; powers of attorney; insurance information where plan benefits are provided by private insurers; medical records; disability information; retirement plan names and numbers; correspondence; initial and final PBGC determinations (see, 29 CFR 4003.21 and 4003.59); and, other records relating to debts owed to PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Plan administrators; participants, spouses, alternate payees, beneficiaries, and other individuals who contact PBGC regarding benefits they may be owed from PBGC; agents listed on power of attorneys; agents listed on release forms, PBGC field office; the SSA; the FAA; and the IRS.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1, G2, G4 through G7, G9 through and G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to third parties, such as banks, insurance companies, or trustees:</p>
                <p>a. To enable these third parties to make or determine benefit payments, or</p>
                <p>b. To report to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) the amounts of benefits paid (or required to be paid) and taxes withheld.</p>
                <p>3. A record from this system may be disclosed, in furtherance of proceedings under Title IV of ERISA, to a contributing sponsor (or other employer who maintained the plan), including any predecessor or successor, and any member of the same control group.</p>
                <p>4. A record from this system may be disclosed, upon request, for a purpose authorized under ERISA, to an official of a labor organization recognized as the current or former collective bargaining representative of the individual about whom a request is made.</p>
                <p>5. Payees' names, addresses, telephone numbers, and information related to how PBGC determined that a debt was owed by such payees to PBGC may be disclosed to the Department of the Treasury or a debt collection agency or to collect a claim. Disclosure to a debt collection agency shall be made only under a contract issued by the federal government that binds any such contractor or employee of such contractor to the penalties of the Privacy Act. The information so disclosed shall be used exclusively pursuant to the terms and conditions of such contract and shall be used solely for the purposes prescribed therein. The contract shall provide that the information so disclosed shall be returned at the conclusion of the debt collection effort.</p>
                <p>6. The name and social security number of a participant employed or formerly employed as a pilot by a commercial airline may be disclosed to the Federal Aviation Administration to obtain information relevant to the participant's eligibility or continued eligibility for disability benefits.</p>
                <p>7. The name of a participant's plan, the actual or estimated amount of a participant's benefit under ERISA, the form(s) in which the benefit is payable, and whether the participant is currently receiving benefit payments under the plan or (if not) the earliest date(s) such payments could commence may be disclosed to the participant's spouse, domestic partner, former spouse, former domestic partner, child, or other dependent solely to obtain a qualified domestic relations order under 29 U.S.C. 1056(d) and 26 U.S.C. 414(p).  PBGC will disclose the information only upon the receipt of a written request by a prospective alternate payee, or the alternate payee's representative, that describes the requester's relationship to the participant and states that the information will be used solely to obtain a qualified domestic relations order under state domestic relations law. PBGC will notify the participant of any information disclosed to a prospective alternate payee or their representative under this routine use.</p>
                <p>8. Information from an initial benefit determination under 29 CFR 4003 (excluding the participant's address, telephone number, social security number, and any sensitive medical information) may be disclosed to an alternate payee, or their representative, under a qualified domestic relations order issued pursuant to 29 U.S.C. 1056(d) and 26 U.S.C. 414, et seq., to explain how PBGC determined the benefit due the alternate payee so that the alternate payee can pursue an administrative appeal of the benefit determination under 29 CFR 4003, et seq. PBGC shall notify the participant of the information disclosed to an alternate payee or their representative under this routine use.</p>
                <p>9. Information from an alternate payee’s initial benefit determination under 29 CFR 4003.1 (excluding the alternate payee's address, telephone number, social security number, and any sensitive medical information) may be disclosed to a participant, or their representative, under a qualified domestic relations order issued pursuant to 29 U.S.C. 1056(d) and 26 U.S.C. 414(p) to explain how PBGC determined the benefit due to the alternate payee so that the participant may pursue an administrative appeal of the benefit determination under 29 CFR 4003, et seq. PBGC shall notify the alternate payee of the information disclosed to a participant or their representative under this routine use.</p>
                <p>10. Information used in calculating the benefit, or share of the benefit, of a participant or alternate payee (excluding the participant's or alternate payee's address, telephone number, social security number, and any sensitive medical information) may be disclosed to a participant or an alternate payee, or their representative, when (a) a qualified domestic relations order issued pursuant to 29 U.S.C. and 26 U.S.C. affects the calculation of the benefit, or share of the benefit, of the participant or alternate payee; and (b) the information is needed to explain to the participant or alternate payee how PBGC calculated the benefit, or share of the benefit, of the participant or alternate payee. PBGC shall notify the participant or the alternate payee, or their representative, as appropriate, of the information disclosed to the participant or the alternate payee, or their representative, under this routine use.</p>
                <p>11. The names, addresses, social security numbers, dates of birth, and the pension plan name and number of eligible PBGC pension recipients may be disclosed to the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Labor to implement the income tax credit for health insurance costs under 26 U.S.C. 35 and the program for advance payment of the tax credit under 26 U.S.C. 7527.</p>
                <p>12. Names, addresses, social security numbers, and dates of birth of eligible PBGC pension recipients residing in a particular state may be disclosed to the state's workforce agency if the agency received a National Dislocated Worker Grant from the Department of Labor under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act of 2014 to provide assistance and support services for state residents under 29 U.S.C. ch. 32.</p>
                <p>13. Payees' names, social security numbers, and dates of birth may be provided to the Department of the Treasury's Bureau of the Fiscal Service, the Social Security Administration, the Internal Revenue Service, or a third party with whom PBGC has a contractual relationship, to verify payees' eligibility to receive payments.</p>
                <p>14. Names and social security numbers of participants and beneficiaries may be provided to the Department of the Treasury, the Department of the Treasury's financial agent, and the Federal Reserve Bank for the purpose of learning which of PBGC's check payees have electronic debit card accounts used for the electronic deposit of federal benefit payments, for establishing electronic debit card accounts for eligible participants and beneficiaries, and for administering payments to participants and beneficiaries who have selected this method of payment.</p>
                <p>15. Information relating to revocation of a power of attorney may be disclosed to the former agent that was named in the revoked power of attorney.</p>
                <p>16. With the exception of third party social security numbers, all beneficiary information contained in the participant file (such as: names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses and dates of birth) provided by the subject of the record may be disclosed to the subject of the record, upon written request to the Disclosure Officer in accordance with the Record Access Procedure outlined below.</p>
                <p>17. Names, social security numbers, last known addresses, dates of birth and death, amount of benefit, plan name, plan EIN/PIN number, name of plan sponsor, and the city and state of the plan sponsor of plan participants and beneficiaries may be disclosed to third parties, with whom PBGC has a contractual relationship, that provide locator services (including credit reporting agencies and debt collection firms or agencies) to locate participants and beneficiaries. Such information will be disclosed only if PBGC has no address for an individual, if mail sent to the individual at the last known address is returned as undeliverable, or if PBGC has been otherwise unsuccessful at contacting the individual. Disclosure shall be made only under a contract that subjects the firm or agency providing the service and its employees to the criminal penalties of the Privacy Act. The information so disclosed shall be used exclusively pursuant to the terms and conditions of such contract and shall be used solely for the purposes prescribed therein. The contract shall provide that the information so disclosed shall be returned or destroyed at the conclusion of the locating effort.</p>
                <p>18. Names, social security numbers, last known addresses, dates of birth and death, employment history, and pay status of individuals covered by legal settlement agreements involving PBGC may be disclosed to entities covered by or created under those agreements.</p>
                <p>19.  A record from this system may be disclosed to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
                <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).   Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retrievability">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; social security number; customer identification number; address; date of birth; or, date of death.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="safeguards">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                        <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
                        <p>Paper and electronic records that contain federal tax information are stored under procedures that meet IRS safeguarding standards, as reflected in IRS Publication 1075. Other records that do not contain federal tax information are kept in file folders in areas of restricted access that are locked after office hours.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4 or to amend records pertaining to themselves in accordance with 29 CRF 4902.5, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>None.</p>
                           </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 6, Plan Participant and Beneficiary Data (last published at 81 FR 63303 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc8" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-8: Employee Relations Files — PBGC
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
            <p>Unclassified.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Human Resources Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 5 U.S.C.7101; 42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of this system is to catalog, investigate, and appropriately and timely respond to administrative and union grievances and appeals filed by PBGC employees or the Union on behalf of an employee pursuant to PBGC's Administrative Grievance Procedure and the Collective Bargaining Agreement.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former PBGC employees who have initiated grievances under an administrative grievance procedure or under an applicable collective bargaining agreement.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Administrative and union grievances submitted by PBGC employees or the Union; agency responses to employees and Union grievances; employees' appeals of responses to grievances; agency responses to such appeals and related correspondence; investigative notes; records of proceedings; appeal decisions; last chance, last rights, and settlement agreements, and related information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; subject individuals’ supervisors, managers, representatives or colleagues; PBGC Office of the General Counsel; PBGC Human Resources Department staff; Department of Labor; Office of Personnel Management; United States Office of Special Counsel; Federal Labor Relations Authority; the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; the Merit Systems Protection Board; and, other individuals with relevant information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G11, G13, and G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, Office of Special Counsel, or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to carry out their authorized functions (under 5 U.S.C. 1103, 1204, 7105, and 42 U.S.C. 2000e-4, in that order).</p>
                <p>3. A record from this system may be disclosed to a union representative, Hearing Examiner or Arbitrator for the purpose of representation or in order to conduct a hearing in connection with an employee’s grievance or appeal.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by employee name or social security number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, following the requirements of Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), records in this system are exempt from the requirements of subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4) (G), (H), (I), and of 5 U.S.C. 552a, provided, however, that if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that he or she would otherwise be entitled to by federal law, or for which he or she would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of these records, such material shall be provided to the individual, except to the extent that the disclosure of the material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government with an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.</p>
                
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 8, Employee Relations Files (last published at 81 FR 63305 (September 14, 2016)).</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc9" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-9</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-9: Unclaimed Pensions — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 and/or PBGC Field Offices (Field Benefit Administration), and paying agent worksites. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director - Participant Services Department, Office of Benefits Administration, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1055, 1056(d)(3), 1302, 1321, 1322, 1322a, 1341, 1342, and 1350; 29 U.S.C. 1203; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained to locate participants, alternate payees, and beneficiaries of defined benefit and defined contribution plan funds who may be owed benefits as the result of a terminated plan or defined contribution plan whose funds are held under the control or authority of the PBGC, and to provide information on insurance companies to individuals who may have had annuities purchased for them by a terminated plan.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Participants, alternate payees, and beneficiaries in defined benefit plans, and defined contribution plans covered by the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Names; dates of birth and death; social security numbers; addresses; e-mail addresses; telephone numbers; names of plan sponsor; names of defined benefit and defined contribution plans; plan numbers for defined benefit and defined contribution plans; employment history; pay status; amount of benefit owed; last known address of the plan sponsor and plan sponsor EIN/PN.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC-6; the SSA; the IRS; labor organization officials; firms or agencies providing locator services; USPS licensees; and, PBGC Field Offices (Field Benefit Administration) and any other individual that provides PBGC with information regarding a missing participant, beneficiary, or alternate payee.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1, G4 through G7, G9 through G11, G13 and G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. Names and social security numbers of plan participants, beneficiaries, and alternate payees may be disclosed to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to obtain current addresses from tax return information and to the Social Security Administration (SSA) to obtain current addresses. Such information will be disclosed only if PBGC has no address for an individual or if mail sent to the individual at the last known address is returned as undeliverable.</p>
                <p>3. Names and last known addresses may be disclosed to an official of a labor organization recognized as the collective bargaining representative of participants for posting in union halls or for other means of publication to obtain current addresses of participants and beneficiaries. Such information will be disclosed only if PBGC has no address for an individual or if mail sent to the individual at the last known address is returned as undeliverable.</p>
                <p>4. Names, social security numbers, last known addresses, dates of birth and death, amount of benefit, retirement plan name, plan EIN/PN number, name of plan sponsor, and the city and state of the plan sponsor may be disclosed to private firms and agencies that provide locator services, including credit reporting agencies and debt collection firms or agencies, to locate participants, beneficiaries, and alternate payees. Such information will be disclosed only if PBGC has no address for an individual, if mail sent to the individual at the last known address is returned as undeliverable or if PBGC has been otherwise unsuccessful at contacting the individual. Disclosure shall be made only under a contract that subjects the firm or agency providing the service and its employees and contractors to the criminal penalties of the Privacy Act. The information so disclosed shall be used exclusively pursuant to the terms and conditions of such contract and shall be used solely for the purposes prescribed therein. The contract shall provide that the information so disclosed shall be returned or destroyed at the conclusion of the locating effort.</p>
                <p>5. Names and addresses may be disclosed to licensees of the United States Postal Service (USPS) to obtain current addresses under the USPS's National Change of Address Linkage System (NCOA). Disclosure shall be made only under a contract that binds the licensee of the Postal Service and its employees to the criminal penalties of the Privacy Act. The contract shall provide that the records disclosed by PBGC shall be used exclusively for updating addresses under NCOA and must be returned to PBGC or destroyed when the process is completed. The records will be exchanged electronically in an encrypted format.</p>
                <p>6. Names and last known addresses may be disclosed to other participants in, and beneficiaries under, a retirement plan to obtain the current addresses of individuals. Such information will be disclosed only if PBGC has no address for an individual or if mail sent to the individual at the last known address is returned as undeliverable.</p>
                <p>7. Names of participants and beneficiaries, names and addresses of participants' former employers, and the plan name may be disclosed to the public to obtain the current addresses for participants, beneficiaries, and alternate payees. Such information will be disclosed to the public when PBGC is unable to make benefit payments to those participants, beneficiaries, and alternate payees because the address on file is unable to be confirmed as current or correct.</p>
                <p>8. Names, social security numbers, last known addresses, dates of birth and death, employment history, and pay status of individuals covered by legal settlement agreements involving PBGC may be disclosed to entities covered by or created under those agreements.</p>
                <p>9. Names, social security numbers, last known addresses, dates of birth, and benefit amounts owed may be disclosed to other government agencies under a Memorandum of Understanding or an Interagency Agreement in order to locate missing participants.</p>
                <p>10. Names, social security numbers, dates of birth and death, name of plan sponsors, plan sponsor EIN/PN may be periodically disclosed to insurance companies where annuities have been purchased by a terminated plan.</p>
              
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by employee name, social security number and/or date of birth.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 9, Unclaimed Pensions (amended to Unclaimed Retirement Funds) (last published at 81 FR 63306 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc10" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-10: Administrative Appeals Files — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Manager of the Appeals Division, Office of the General Counsel, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 29 U.S.C. ch. 18; 29 CFR 4003.1; 29 CFR 4003.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of this system is to catalog, review, and respond to administrative appeals by plan participants, beneficiaries and employers of PBGC determinations (such as plan, benefit, qualified domestic relations order, payment, and liability determinations).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who file administrative appeals with PBGC' s Appeals Board.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Personal information (such as names, addresses, social security numbers, gender, dates of birth, dates of hire and termination, salary, marital status, marriage certificates, birth certificates, domestic relations orders, medical records); employment and pension plan information (such as the name of the pension plan, plan number, dates of commencement of plan participation or employment, statements regarding employment, dates of termination of plan participation or retirement, benefit payment data, benefit election forms and data on beneficiaries, pay status, calculations of benefit amounts, calculations of amounts subject to recoupment and/or recovery, and worker’s compensation awards); Social Security Administration (SSA) information; insurance claims and awards; correspondence; and, other information relating to appeals and initial and final PBGC determinations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; participants, beneficiaries, or alternate payees; plan administrators, plan actuaries, paying agents, purchased annuity providers, contributing sponsors (or other employer who maintained the plan, which may include any predecessor, successor, or member of the same control group); the labor organization recognized as the collective bargaining representative of a participant; SSA; and, any third party affected by the decision.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 and G4 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system may be disclosed to third parties who may be aggrieved by the decision of the Appeals Board under 29 CFR 4003.57.</p>
                <p>3. A record from this system may be disclosed, upon request, to an attorney representative or a non-attorney representative who has a power of attorney for the subject individuals, under 29 CFR 4003.6.</p>
                <p>4. A record from this system may be disclosed to third parties, such as banks, insurance companies, and trustees, to effectuate benefit payments to plan participants, beneficiaries, and/or alternate payees.</p>
                <p>5. A record from this system may be disclosed to third parties, such as contractors and expert witnesses, to obtain expert analysis of an issue necessary to resolve an appeal.</p>
                <p>6. A record from this system, specifically, the name and social security number of a participant, may be disclosed to an official of a labor organization recognized as the collective bargaining representative of the participant to obtain information relevant to the resolution of an appeal.</p>
                <p>7. A record from this system may be disclosed to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
                               </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: participant, beneficiary, and/or alternate payee’s name, social security number, or PBGC customer identification number; plan name; appeal number; or extension request number.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 10, Administrative Appeals File (last published at 81 FR 63307 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc11" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-11: Call Detail Records — PBGC
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Information Officer, Office of Information Technology, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is used for Office of the Inspector General investigations and other special investigation requests.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC employees, contractors, students and interns</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records relating to the use of PBGC telephones and PBGC-issued portable electronic devices to place calls outside of PBGC and receive calls from outside of PBGC, and records indicating the assignment of telephone extension numbers and PBGC-issued portable electronic devices to PBGC employees.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1, G3, G4, G5, and G7 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                               </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name of employee or contractor; telephone extension number; PBGC-issued portable electronic device number; or telephone number called.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Telephone and PBGC-issued portable electronic device assignment records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 11, Call Detail Records (last published at 81 FR 63308 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc12" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-12: Personnel Security Investigation Records — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent> </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Human Resources Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 5 U.S.C. 3301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; Executive Order 10450; Executive Order 10577; Executive Order 12968; Executive Order 13467; Executive Order 13488; 5 CFR 5.2; 5 CFR 731, 732 and 736; 5 CFR 1400; OMB Circular No. A-130 Revised, Appendix III, 61 FR 6428; Federal Information Processing Standard 201; Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records in this system of records are used to document and support decisions as to the suitability, eligibility, and fitness for service of applicants for federal employment and contract positions, and may include students, interns, or vendors to the extent their duties require access to federal facilities, information, information systems, or applications.</p>
                <p>The records may also be used to help streamline and make the background suitability investigations and adjudications processes more efficient.</p>
                <p>The records additionally may be used to document security violations and supervisory actions taken in response to such violations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former applicants, employees, students, interns, government contractors, experts, instructors, vendors, and consultants to federal programs who undergo a personnel background investigation to determining suitability for employment, contractor employee fitness, credentialing for Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12, and/or access to PBGG facilities or information technology system. Individuals who have corresponded with PBGC regarding personnel security investigations. This system also includes individuals accused of or found in violation of PBGC’s security rules and regulations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Name; former names; date and place of birth; home address; email address; phone numbers; employment history; residential history; education and degrees citizenship; passport information; name, date and place of birth, social security number, and citizenship information for spouse or cohabitant; the name and marriage information for current and former spouse(s) or domestic partner, names of associates and references and their contact information; names, dates and places of birth, citizenship, and addresses of relatives; names of relatives who work for the federal government; information on foreign contacts and activities; association records; information on loyalty to the United States; criminal history; mental health history; drug use; financial information; photographs; personal identity verification (PIV) card information; information from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) pertaining to income tax returns; credit reports; information pertaining to security clearances; other agency reports furnished to PBGC in connection with the background investigation process; summaries of personal and third party interviews conducted during the background investigation; results of suitability decisions; and additional records developed from above.</p>
                <p>Records pertaining to security violations may contain information pertaining to circumstances of the violation; witness statements; investigator's notes; and documentation of agency action taken in response to security violations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Applications and other personnel and security forms, including, but not limited to, SF-85, SF-85P, SF-86, SF-87; information from personal interviews with the applicant and various individuals, such as former employers, references, neighbors, and other associates who may have information about the subject of the investigation; investigative records and notices of personnel actions furnished by other federal agencies; public records such as court filings; publications such as newspapers, magazines, and periodicals; tax records; educational institutions; police departments; credit bureaus; probation officials; prison officials; and, medical professionals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record, from which information is requested during an investigation from this system, may be disclosed to an authorized source (i.e., someone who has the legal authority to request such information, such as an investigator from the Office of Personnel Management National Background Investigations Bureau (NBIB), or the Office of the Inspector General) to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, or identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p>3. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to carry out its respective authorized functions (under 5 U.S.C. 1204, and 7105, and 42 U.S.C. 2000e-4).</p>
                <p>4. To designated officers and employees of agencies, offices, and other establishments in the executive, legislative, and judicial branches of the Federal Government, having a need to evaluate qualifications, suitability, and loyalty to the United States Government and/or a security clearance or access determination.</p>
                <p>5. To designated officers and employees of agencies, offices, and other establishments in the executive, legislative, and judicial branches of the Federal Government, when such agency, office, or establishment investigates an individual for purposes of granting a security clearance, or for the purpose of making a determination of qualifications, suitability, or loyalty to the United States Government, or access to classified information or restricted areas.</p>
                <p>6.  To designated officers and employees of agencies, offices, and other establishments in the executive, judicial, or legislative branches of the Federal Government, having the responsibility to grant clearances to make a determination regarding access to classified information or restricted areas, or to evaluate qualifications, suitability, or loyalty to the United States Government, in connection with performance of a service to the Federal Government under a contract or other agreement.</p>
                <p>7.  To U.S. intelligence agencies for use in intelligence activities.</p>
                <p>8.  To the appropriate federal, state, tribal, local, or other public authority responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order where OPM becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p>9.  To an agency, office, or other establishment in the executive, legislative, or judicial branches of the Federal Government, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>10.  To provide information to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual. However, to the extent these records may reveal the identity of an individual who has provided information pertaining to the investigation, the investigative file, or the parts thereof, are exempt from release.  Further, requests for OPM records contained in this system will be referred to OPM.</p>
                <p>11.  To disclose information to contractors, experts, consultants, or students performing or working on a contract, service, or job for the PBGC.</p>
                <p>12.  To disclose results of investigations or individuals records to agencies, such as the Department of Labor, providing adjudicative support services to PBGC.</p>
                <p>13.  To provide criminal history record information to the FBI, to help ensure the accuracy and completeness of FBI and PBGC records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; social security number; unique case serial number; or other unique identifier.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), records in this system are exempt from the requirements of subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4) (G), (H), (I), and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a, provided, however, that if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that he or she would otherwise be entitled to by federal law, or for which he or she would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of these records, such material shall be provided to the individual, except to the extent that the disclosure of the material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government with an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 12, Personnel Security Investigation Records (last published at 81 FR 63309 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc13" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-13: Debt Collection — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 and/or PBGC Field Offices (Field Benefit Administration), plan administrator, and paying agents worksites. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Financial Operations Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
                <p>Chief of Benefits Administration, Office of Benefits Administration, PBGC, 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 31 U.S.C. 3711(a); 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; Executive Order 13019.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained for the purpose of collecting debts owed to PBGC by various individuals, including, but not limited to, pension plans and/or sponsors owing insurance premiums, interest and penalties; PBGC employees and former employees; consultants and vendors; participants, alternate payees, and beneficiaries in retirement plans coming under the control or authority of the PBGC; and individuals who received payments from PBGC to which they are not entitled. This system facilitates PBGC's compliance with the Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Any individual who may owe a debt to PBGC, including but not limited to: pension plans and/or sponsors owing insurance premiums, interest, and penalties; employees and former employees of PBGC; individuals who are consultants and vendors to PBGC; participants, alternate payees, and beneficiaries in terminating and terminated defined benefit or defined contribution plans coming under the control or authority of the PBGC; and any individual who received payments to which they are not entitled.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Plan filings; names; addresses; social security numbers; taxpayer identification numbers; employee numbers; pay records; travel vouchers and related documents filed by PBGC employees; invoices filed by consultants and vendors to PBGC; records of benefit payments made to participants, alternate payees, and beneficiaries in plans covered by ERISA; and other relevant records relating to a debt including financial information, bank account numbers, the amount, status, and history of the debt, and the program under which the debt arose.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; plan administrators; labor organization officials; debt collection agencies or firms; firms or agencies providing locator services; PBGC Field Offices (Field Benefit Administration); and, other federal agencies.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the United States Department of the Treasury for cross-servicing to effect debt collection in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
                <p>3. Names, addresses, and telephone numbers of employees, participants, beneficiaries, alternate payees and any other individual owing a debt to PBGC, and information pertaining to debts owed by such individuals to PBGC may be disclosed to a debt collection agency to collect a claim. Disclosure to a debt collection agency or firm shall be made only under a contract that binds any such contractor or employee of such contractor to the criminal penalties of the Privacy Act. The information so disclosed shall be used exclusively pursuant to the terms and conditions of such contract and shall be used solely for the purposes prescribed therein. The contract shall provide that the information so disclosed shall be returned at the conclusion of the debt collection effort.</p>
                <p>4. These records may be used to disclose information to any federal agency, state or local agency, tribal governments, U.S. territory or commonwealth, or the District of Columbia, or their agents or contractors, including private collection agencies (consumer and commercial):</p>
                <p>a. To facilitate the collection of debts through the use of any combination of various debt collection methods required or authorized by law, including, but not limited to:</p>
                <p>i. Request for repayment by telephone or in writing;</p>
                <p>ii. Negotiation of voluntary repayment or compromise agreements;</p>
                <p>iii. Offset of federal payments, which may include the disclosure of information contained in the records for the purpose of providing the debtor with appropriate pre-offset notice and to otherwise comply with offset prerequisites, to facilitate voluntary repayment in lieu of offset, and to otherwise effectuate the offset process;</p>
                <p>iv. Referral of debts to private collection agencies, to Treasury designated debt collection centers, or for litigation;</p>
                <p>v. Administrative and court-ordered wage garnishment;</p>
                <p>vi. Debt sales;</p>
                <p>vii. Publication of names and identities of delinquent debtors in the media or other appropriate news or websites; and</p>
                <p>viii. Any other debt collection method authorized by law;</p>
                <p>b. To collect a debt owed to the United States through the offset of payments made by states, territories, commonwealths, tribal governments, or the District of Columbia;</p>
                <p>c. To account or report on the status of debts for which such entity has a financial or other legitimate need for the information in the performance of official duties; or,</p>
                <p>d. For any other appropriate debt collection purpose.</p>
                <p>5.  A record from this system may be disclosed to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: employer identification number; social security number; customer identification number; plan number; recovery tracking number; name of debtor, plan, plan sponsor, plan administrator, participant, alternate payee, or beneficiary.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 13, Debt Collection (last published at 81 FR 63311 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc14" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-14: My Plan Administration Account Records — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                         <p>Unclassified.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Financial Operations Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302, 1306, and 1343; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3601, et seq.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained for use in verifying the identity of individuals who register to use the My PAA application to make PBGC filings, and receiving, authenticating, processing, and keeping a history of filings and premium payments submitted to PBGC by registered users. Information from this system is used to provide the public with contact information for plan sponsors, plan administrators, pension practitioners, actuaries and pension benefit professionals who submit plan information through My PAA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who use the My Plan Administration Account (My PAA) application to make PBGC filings and payments electronically via PBGC's website (www.pbgc.gov), including individuals acting for plan sponsors, plan administrators, pension practitioners, actuaries, pension benefit professionals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>User name; work telephone number; work e-mail address; other contact information; a temporary PBGC-issued user ID and password; a user-selected user ID and password; a secret question/secret answer combination for authentication; IP addresses; cookies (session and persistent); financial information; taxpayer identification number; bank information; for each pension plan for which the user intends to participate in making filings with PBGC: the plan name; employer identification number; plan number; the plan administrator's name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and other contact information; and the role that the user will play in the filing process, e.g., creating and editing filings, signing filings electronically as the plan administrator, signing filings electronically as the enrolled actuary, or authorizing payments to PBGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Registered users.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1, G4 through G7, G9, G10, and G12 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. Names, addresses and phone numbers of plan sponsors, plan administrators, pension practitioners, actuaries and pension benefit professionals who submit plan information to My PAA may be disclosed to the public in order to ensure the public has access to contact information for those individuals submitting information regarding pension plans and those responsible for the administration of pension plans covered by the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; user ID; email address; telephone number; plan name; EIN; or plan number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC-14, My Plan Administration Account Records (last published at 81 FR 63312 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc15" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-15: Emergency Notification Records — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                                    <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Workplace Solutions Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; Executive Order 12656.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained for notifying PBGC employees, students, interns, and contractors of PBGC's operating status in the event of an emergency, natural disaster or other event affecting PBGC operations; and for contacting employees, students, interns, and contractors who are out of the office on leave or after regular duty hours to obtain information necessary for official business.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC employees, students, interns, and individuals who work for PBGC as contractors or as employees of contractors.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Name; title; organizational component; employer; PBGC and personal telephone numbers; PBGC and personal e-mail addresses; other contact information; user ID; a temporary PBGC-issued password; and a user-selected password.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1, G4, G5, G7, G9 through G11, G13, and G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record in this system of records may be disclosed to family members, emergency medical personnel, or to law enforcement officials in case of a medical or other emergency involving the subject individual (without the subsequent notification prescribed in 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(8)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; organizational component; or user ID and password.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 15, Emergency Notification Records (last published at 81 FR 63313 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc16" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-16: PBGC Connect Search Center — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Division Manager, Information Technology Customer and Operations Service Division, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is used by PBGC employees, interns and contractors to identify other PBGC employees, interns and contractors; and, to access contact information for PBGC employees, interns and contractors.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC employees and contractors with PBGC network access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Name; photograph; personal description; skills; interests; schools; birthday; mobile phone number; home phone number; organizational component and title; supervisor's name; PBGC street address; room or workstation number; PBGC network ID; work email address; and work telephone number and extension.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals and PBGC personnel records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; username; organizational component; job title; work phone number; office number; supervisor; work email; skills; interests; birth date; education; peers; and employee type (federal or contractor).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 16, Employee Online Directory (last published at 81 FR 63314 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc17" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-17: Office of Inspector General Investigative File System — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of Inspector General, Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of the Inspector General, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. App. 3.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is used to supervise and conduct investigations relating to programs and operations of PBGC by the Inspector General.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals named in investigations conducted by the Office of Inspector General (OIG); complainants and subjects of complaints collected through the operation of the OIG Hotline; other individuals, including witnesses, sources, and members of the general public who are named individuals in connection with investigations conducted by OIG.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information within this system relates to OIG investigations carried out under applicable statutes, regulations, policies, and procedures. The investigations may relate to criminal, civil, or administrative matters. These OIG files may contain investigative reports; transcripts; internal staff memoranda; working drafts of papers to PBGC employees; investigative plans; litigation strategies; copies of personnel, financial, contractual, and property management records maintained by PBGC; information submitted by or about pension plan sponsors or plan participants; background data including arrest records, statements of informants and witnesses, and laboratory reports of evidence analysis; information and documentation received from other government agencies; search warrants, summonses and subpoenas; and other information related to investigations. Personal data in the system may consist of names, social security numbers, addresses, dates of birth and death, fingerprints, handwriting samples, reports of confidential informants, physical identifying data, voiceprints, polygraph tests, photographs, and individual personnel and payroll information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; individual complainants; witnesses; interviews conducted during investigations; federal, state, tribal, and local government records; individual or company records; claim and payment files; employer medical records; insurance records; court records; articles from publications; financial data; bank information; telephone data; service providers; other law enforcement organizations; grantees and sub-grantees; contractors and subcontractors; pension plan sponsors and participants; and other sources.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1, G2, G4, G5, G7, and G9 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record relating to a person held in custody pending or during arraignment, trial, sentence, or extradition proceedings or after conviction may be disclosed to a federal, state, local, tribal or foreign prison; probation, parole, or pardon authority; or any other agency or individual involved with the maintenance, transportation, or release of such a person.</p>
                <p>3. A record relating to a case or matter may be disclosed to an actual or potential party or his or her attorney for the purpose of negotiation or discussion on such matters as settlement of the case or matter, plea bargaining, or informal discovery proceedings.</p>
                <p>4. A record may be disclosed to any source, either private or governmental, when reasonably necessary to elicit information or obtain the cooperation of a witness or informant when conducting any official investigation or during a trial or hearing or when preparing for a trial or hearing.</p>
                <p>5. A record relating to a case or matter may be disclosed to a foreign country, through the United States Department of State or directly to the representative of such country, under an international treaty, convention, or executive agreement; or to the extent necessary to assist such country in apprehending or returning a fugitive to a jurisdiction that seeks that individual's return.</p>
                <p>6. A record originating exclusively within this system of records may be disclosed to other federal offices of inspectors general and councils comprising officials from other federal offices of inspectors general, as required by the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended. The purpose is to ensure that OIG investigative operations can be subject to integrity and efficiency peer reviews, and to permit other offices of inspectors general to investigate and report on allegations of misconduct by senior OIG officials as directed by a council, the President, or Congress. Records originating from any other PBGC systems of records, which may be duplicated in or incorporated into this system, also may be disclosed with all identifiable information redacted.</p>
                <p>7. A record may be disclosed to the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Justice when the OIG seeks an ex parte court order to obtain taxpayer information from the Internal Revenue Service.</p>
                <p>8. A record may be disclosed to any governmental, professional or licensing authority when such record reflects on qualifications, either moral, educational or vocational, of an individual seeking to be licensed or to maintain a license.</p>
                <p>9. A record may be disclosed to any direct or indirect recipient of federal funds, e.g., a contractor, where such record reflects problems with the personnel working for a recipient, and disclosure of the record is made to permit a recipient to take corrective action beneficial to the Government.</p>
                <p>10. A record may be disclosed where there is an indication of a violation or a potential violation of law, rule, regulation or order whether civil, criminal, administrative or regulatory in nature, to the appropriate agency, whether federal,  state, tribal or local, or to a securities self-regulatory organization, charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation or order.</p>
                <p>11. A record may be disclosed to federal,  state, tribal or local authorities in order to obtain information or records relevant to an Office of Inspector General investigation or inquiry.</p>
                <p>12. A record may be disclosed to a bar association, state accountancy board, or other federal, state, tribal, local, or foreign licensing or oversight authority; or professional association or self-regulatory authority to the extent that it performs similar functions (including the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board) for investigations or possible disciplinary action.</p>
                <p>13. A record may be disclosed to inform complainants, victims, and witnesses of the results of an investigation or inquiry.</p>
                <p>14.  To the Department of Justice for the purpose of obtaining advice on investigatory matters or in order to refer information for the purpose of prosecution.</p>
                <p>15. To contractors, interns and experts who have been engaged to assist in an OIG investigation or in the performance of a service related to this system of records and require access to these records for the purpose of assisting the OIG in the efficient administration of its duties.  All recipients of these records shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended.</p>
                <p>16.  To the public when the matter under investigation has become public knowledge, or when the Inspector General determines that such disclosure is necessary to preserve confidence in the integrity of the OIG investigative process, to demonstrate the accountability of PBGC employees, or other individuals covered by this system, or when there exists a legitimate public interest, unless the Inspector General has determined that disclosure of specific information would constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records may be retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; social security number; subject category; or assigned case number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system is exempt from the notification and record access requirements. However, consideration will be given to requests made in compliance with 29 CFR 4902.3 and 4902.4.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system is exempt from amendment requirements. However, consideration will be given requests made in compliance with 29 CFR 4902.3 and 4902.5.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system is exempt from the notification requirements. However, consideration will be given to inquiries made in compliance with 29 CFR 4902.3.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(j) and (k), PBGC has established regulations at 29 CFR 4902.11 that exempt records in this system depending on their purpose.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 17, Inspector General Investigative File System (last published at 81 FR 63315 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc19" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>PBGC-19: Office of Negotiations and Restructuring/Office of General Counsel Case Management System — PBGC</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 and 1275 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Office of the General Counsel (OGC), PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
                <p>Office of Negotiations and Restructuring (ONR), PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1055, 1056(d)(3), 1302, 1303, 1310, 1321, 1322a, 1341, 1342, 1343, 1350; 1431, and 1432; 5 U.S.C. app. 105; 5 U.S.C. 301, 552(a), 552a(d), 7101; 42 U.S.C. 2000e, et seq.; 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of this system of records is to catalog, litigate, review or otherwise resolve any case or matter handled by the ONR or the OGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals who are participants, beneficiaries, and alternate payees in pension plans covered by the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), 29 U.S.C. 1301, et seq.; pension plan sponsors, administrators, control group members and third parties, who are responsible for, manage, or have control over ERISA pension plans; other individuals who are identified in connection with investigations conducted pursuant to 29 U.S.C. 1303 or litigation conducted with regard to ERISA pension plans; individuals (including PBGC employees) who are parties or witnesses in civil litigation or administrative proceedings involving or concerning PBGC or its officers or employees; individuals who are the subject of a breach of personally identifiable information; individuals who are potential contractors or contractors with PBGC or are otherwise personally associated with a contract or procurement matter; individuals who receive legal advice from OGC; and other individuals (including current, former, and potential PBGC employees, contract employees, interns, and externs) who are the subject of or are otherwise connected to an inquiry, investigation, other matter handled by the OGC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Draft and final versions of notes, reports, memoranda; settlements; legal opinions; agreements; correspondence; contracts; contract proposals and other procurement documents; plan documents; participant, alternate payee, and beneficiary files; initial and final PBGC determinations of ERISA matters; Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) and the Privacy Act of 1974 disclosures, determinations, appeals and decisions of those appeals; records and information obtained from other Federal, state, tribal, and local agencies and departments, including, but not limited to: Office of Personnel Management, Social Security Administration, Department of Treasury and Department of Justice; drafts and legal reviews of proposed personnel actions; ethics inquiries; personnel records; financial records; individual tax returns; litigation files; labor relations files; information provided by labor unions or other organizations; witness statements; summonses, subpoenas, discovery requests and responses; and breach reports and supporting documentation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; pension plan participants, sponsors, administrators and third parties; Federal government records; current and former employees, contractors, interns, and externs; PBGC debt and disbursement records; insurers; the Social Security Administration; labor organizations; court records; articles from publications; and other individuals, organizations, and corporate entities with relevant knowledge/information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G15 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system of records may be disclosed, in furtherance of proceedings under Title IV of ERISA, to a contributing sponsor (or other employer who maintained the plan), including any predecessor or successor, and any member of the same control group.</p>
                <p>3. Names, addresses, and telephone numbers of employees, former employees, participants, and beneficiaries and information pertaining to debts to PBGC may be disclosed to the Department of Treasury, the Department of Justice, a credit agency, and a debt collection to collect the debt. Disclosure to a debt collection may be made only under a contract that binds any such contractor or employee of such contractor to criminal penalties of the Privacy Act.</p>
                <p>4. Information may be disclosed to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal in the course of presenting evidence, including disclosures to opposing counsel or witnesses in the course of civil discovery, litigation, or settlement negotiations in response to a court order or in connection with criminal law proceedings.</p>
                <p>5. Information may be provided to a congressional office in response to an inquiry made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                <p>6. Information may be provided to third parties during the course of an investigation to the extent necessary to obtain information pertinent to the investigation.</p>
                <p>7. Relevant and necessary information may be disclosed to a former employee of PBGC for the purposes of: (1) responding to an official inquiry by Federal, state, tribal or local government entity or professional licensing authority; or (2) facilitating communications with a former employee that may be necessary for personnel-related or other official purposes where PBGC requires information and/or consultation assistance from the former employee regarding a matter within that person's former area of responsibility.</p>
                <p>8. A record relating to a case or matter may be disseminated to a foreign country pursuant to an international treaty or convention entered into and ratified by the United States or to an executive agreement.</p>
                <p>9. A record may be disseminated to a foreign country, through the United States Department of State or directly to the representative of such country, to the extent necessary to assist such country in civil or criminal proceedings in which the United States or one of its officers or agencies has an interest.</p>
                <p>10. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), Office of Government Information Services (OGIS), to the extent necessary to fulfill its responsibilities in 5 U.S.C. 552(h), to review administrative agency policies, procedures and compliance with the FOIA, and to facilitate use of OGIS’ mediation services.</p>
                <p>11. A record from this system may be disclosed to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711(e).</p>
                <p>12. A record from this system of records may be disclosed under a Memorandum of Understanding or an Interagency Agreement to: (1) the Department of Treasury (USDT) or (2) the Department of Labor’s Employee Benefits Security Administration (EBSA) to facilitate an investigation or inquiry relating to a multiemployer plan’s compliance with appliable provisions under ERISA or the Internal Revenue Code, including the special financial assistance program created by the American Rescue Plan (ARP) Act of 2021 (P.L. 117-2).</p>
           
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are indexed by assigned case number and sequential record identifier.  Records are full-text indexed and information from this system may be retrieved using any free-form key, which may include names, social security number, address, representative or any other personal identifiers.  For certain systems, only individuals assigned to the particular matter may retrieve associated records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST).  Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.  Paper records are kept in file folders in areas of restricted access that are locked after office hours.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.  Further, for certain systems covered by this notice, heightened security access is required.  Such access is granted by the specific permissions group assigned to monitor that particular system and only authorized employees of the agency may retrieve, review or modify those records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request, in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.5, identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), records in this system are exempt from the requirements of subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4) (G), (H), (I), and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a, provided, however, that if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that he or she would otherwise be entitled to by Federal law, or for which he or she would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of these records, such material will be provided to the individual, except to the extent that the disclosure of the material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government with an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 19, Office of General Counsel Case Management System (last published at 83 FR 6270 (February 13, 2018)).</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="pbgc21" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-21</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
<p>PBGC – 21: Reasonable Accommodation Records</p>
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Unclassified</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Reasonable Accommodations Coordinator, Human Resources Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.; 29 U.S.C. 791; 42 U.S.C.</p>
<p>12101 et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 2000bb; 42 U.S.C. Ch. 21, 126; 29 CFR Parts 1605, 1614, 1630; Executive Order 13164 (July 26, 2000); and Executive Order 13548 (July 26, 2010).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The purposes of this system are: (1) to allow PBGC to collect and maintain records on prospective, current, and former employees with disabilities or sincerely held religious beliefs, practices, or observances who requested or received reasonable accommodation by PBGC; (2) to track and report the processing of requests for reasonable accommodation PBGC-wide to comply with applicable law and regulations; and (3)  to maintain the confidentiality of medical or religious information submitted by or on behalf of applicants or employees requesting reasonable accommodation.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Prospective, current, and former employees of PBGC who request and/or receive a reasonable accommodation for a disability or religious belief, practice, or observance authorized individuals or representatives (e.g., family members, union representatives, or attorneys) who submit a request for a reasonable accommodation on behalf of a prospective, current, or former employee.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Name and employment information of current or prospective employee needing an accommodation; requester's name and contact information (if different than the employee who needs an accommodation); date request was initiated; information concerning the nature of the disability or religious belief, practice, or observance and the need for accommodation, including appropriate medical or other documentation; occupational series; pay grade; essential duties of the position; details of the accommodation request, such as: type of accommodation requested, how the requested accommodation would assist in job or allow job performance while accommodating the disability or religious belief, practice, or observance, the sources of technical assistance consulted in trying to identify alternative reasonable accommodation, any additional information provided by the requester relating to the processing of the request, whether the request was approved or denied, whether the accommodation was approved for a trial period; and, documentation between the employee and his/her supervisor(s) regarding the accommodation.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Subject individuals; individual making the request (if different than the subject individuals); medical and equal employment opportunity professionals; and the subject individuals' supervisor(s).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), and:</p>
<p>1.  General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory                 Statement of General Routine Uses at 83 FR 6247 (Feb. 13, 2018)).</p>
<p> 2. A record from this system may be disclosed to physicians or other medical professionals to provide them with or obtain from them the necessary medical documentation and/or certification for reasonable accommodation.</p>
<p>3. A record from this system may be disclosed to another federal agency or commission with responsibility for labor or employment relations or other issues, including equal employment opportunity and reasonable accommodation issues, when that agency or commission has jurisdiction over reasonable accommodation issues.</p>
<p> 4. A record from this system may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB),   Department of Labor (DOL), Office of Personnel Management (OPM), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), or Office of Special Counsel (OSC) to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements related to reasonable accommodation.</p>
<p>5. A record from this system may be disclosed to appropriate third-parties contracted by the Agency to facilitate mediation or other dispute resolution procedures or programs.</p>
<p>6.  A record from this system may be disclosed to the Department of Defense (DOD) for purposes of procuring assistive technologies and services through the Computer/Electronic Accommodation Program in response to a request for reasonable accommodation.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs). Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor- hosted network.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: employee name or assigned case number.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA. Records existing on paper are destroyed beyond recognition.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
<p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4 or to amend records pertaining to themselves in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.5, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend, in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.5, their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent>
<p>None.</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="history"><xhtmlContent>
<p>PBGC – 21, Reasonable Accommodation Records (last published at 83 FR 6271 (February 13, 2018)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc22" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-22: Telework and Alternative Worksite Records — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Telework Managing Officer, Human Resources Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 5 U.S.C. 6120.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of this system of records is to collect and maintain records on current and former employees who have participated in, presently participate in, or have sought to participate in PBGC's Telework Program.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former employees of PBGC who have requested to participate in PBGC's Telework Program in order to work at an alternative worksite other than their official PBGC duty station.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Name, position title, grade, series, and department name; official PBGC duty station address and telephone number; alternative worksite address and telephone number(s); date telework agreement received and approved/denied; telework request and approval form; telework agreement, self-certification home safety checklist, and supervisor-employee checklist; type of telework requested (e.g., episodic or regular); regular work schedule; telework schedule; approvals/disapprovals; description and list of government-owned equipment and software provided to the teleworker; mass transit benefits received through PBGC's mass transit subsidy program; parking subsidies received through PBGC's subsidized parking program; license plate information; driver’s license; and any other miscellaneous documents supporting telework.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; subject individuals' supervisors.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. A record from this system may be disclosed to federal, state, tribal or local governments during actual emergencies, exercises, or continuity of operations tests for the purposes of emergency preparedness and responding to emergency situations.</p>
                <p>3. A record from this system may be disclosed to the Department of Labor when an employee is injured when working at home while in the performance of normal duties.</p>
                <p>4. A record from this system may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) for use in its Telework Survey to provide consolidated data on participation in PBGC's Telework Program.</p>
                <p>5. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to appropriate third-parties contracted by the Agency to facilitate mediation or other dispute resolution procedures or programs.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.   Also, each of PBGC’s departments has a Telework Liaison who may maintain copies of the records pertaining to employees working in his or her department.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records may be retrieved by any one or more of the following: employee name, and the department in which the employee works, will work, or previously worked.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.  </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC – 22, Telework and Alternative Worksite Records (last published at 81 FR 63319 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc23" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-23</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-23: Internal Investigations of Allegations of Harassing Conduct — PBGC.
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Human Resources Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 5 U.S.C. 301; 42 U.S.C. 2000e, et seq.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records is maintained for the purpose of upholding PBGC's policy to prevent and eradicate harassing conduct in the workplace, including conducting and resolving internal investigations of allegations of harassing conduct brought by or against PBGC employees, contractors or interns.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current or former PBGC employees, contractors, and interns who have filed a complaint, made a report of harassment, or have been accused of harassing conduct.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The system contains all documents related to a complaint or report of harassment, which may include the name, position, grade, and supervisor(s) of the complainant and the accused; the complaint; statements of witnesses; reports of interviews; medical records; final decisions and corrective actions taken; and related correspondence and exhibits.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Subject individuals; PBGC supervisors, employees, contractors, and others with knowledge; outside counsel retained by subject individuals; and medical professionals.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. Disclosure of information from this system of records regarding the status of any investigation that may have been conducted may be made to the complaining party and to the individual against whom the complaint was made when the purpose of the disclosure is both relevant and necessary and is compatible with the purpose for which the information was collected.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained manually in paper and/or electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by any one or more of the following: name; department; or unique identifier assigned to each incident reported.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Paper records are kept in cabinets in areas of restricted access that are locked after office hours.  Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), records in this system are exempt from the requirements of subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), (I), and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a, provided, however, that if any individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit that he or she would otherwise be entitled to by federal law, or for which he or she would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of these records, such material shall be provided to the individual, except to the extent that the disclosure of the material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the Government with an express promise that the identity of the source would be held in confidence.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC –23, Internal Investigations of Allegations of Harassing Conduct (last published at 81 FR 63320 (September 14, 2016)).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc24" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-24</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC-24: Participant Debt Collection — PBGC; [Rescinded]
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="pbgc25" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-25</systemNumber>
            <subsection type="systemName">
                PBGC-25: PBGC.GOV Comment Management System — PBGC
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="securityClassification">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Unclassified</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Division Manager, Communications Outreach and Legislative Affairs Department, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>29 U.S.C. 1302; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 44 U.S.C. Ch 36; 5 U.S.C. 301; 40 U.S.C. Subchapter II.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>The information in this system is maintained to: provide a central location to search, view, download and comment on federal rulemaking documents; respond to the public’s comments; track regulatory feedback; and, retain commenter information in order to respond to the public.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Any individual commenting on PBGC’s rulemaking activities or submitting supporting materials; any individual initiating contact with the PBGC through use of the agency website.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Comments and supporting documentation from the public (may include name, email address, physical address, phone numbers, PBGC customer identification numbers, Social Security numbers, dates of birth, dates of hire, dates of termination, marital status, pay status); agency rulemaking materials; Federal Register publications; scientific and financial studies; IP information; cookies (session and persistent); and, internet protocol (IP) addresses.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals commenting on agency rulemaking; individuals contacting PBGC via the agency website.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                    <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                    <p>2. Information, including personally identifiable information (PII), contained in comments about agency rulemaking, whether submitted through pbgc.gov or regulations.gov, may be published to the PBGC website.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are maintained in electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Information from this system may be retrieved by numerous data elements and key word searches, including, but not limited to name, dates, subject, and other information retrievable with full-text searching capability.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Records are maintained and destroyed in accordance with the National Archives and Record Administration’s (NARA) Basic Laws and Authorities (44 U.S.C. 3301, et seq.) or a PBGC records disposition schedule approved by NARA.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                    <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>None.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                    </subsection>
        </section>
    <section id="pbgc26" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            PBGC – 26: PBGC Insider Threat and Data Loss Prevention — PBGC
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
               
                    <p>Unclassified</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), 1200 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. (Records may be kept at an additional location as backup for continuity of operations.)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Information Officer, Office of Information Technology, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>29 U.S.C. 1302(b)(3); 5 U.S.C. 301; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 44 U.S.C. 3554; Executive Order 13587, Structural Reforms To Improve the Security of Classified Networks and the Responsible Sharing and Safeguarding of Classified Information (Oct. 7, 2011); Presidential Memorandum – National Insider Threat Policy and Minimum Standards for Executive Branch Insider Threat Programs (Nov. 21, 2012); Executive Orders 13488 and 13467, as amended by 13764, To Modernize the Executive Branch-Wide Governance Structure and Processes for Security Clearances, Suitability and Fitness for Employment, and Credentialing, and Related Matters; Executive Order 3356, Controlled Unclassified Information (Nov. 4, 2010); 5 CFR part 731; 5 CFR part 302; OMB Circular A-130 (July 28, 2016); National Institute of Standards and Technology Special Publication 800-53.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The purpose of the system is to detect anomalous behavior by PBGC insiders and, as warranted, gather information from sources or existing PBGC systems of records to support an investigation of the incident.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The categories of individuals covered by this system are PBGC insiders, defined as any person with authorized access to any PBGC resource including facilities, information, equipment, networks, or systems.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>A. The system will contain these categories of records:</p>
                <p>Information collected through user activity monitoring, including keystrokes, screen captures, and content transmitted via email, chat, or data import or export.</p>
                <p>Reports of investigation regarding security violations and privacy breaches, including incident reports; usernames and aliases, levels of network access, audit data, information regarding misuse of PBGC devices, information regarding unauthorized use of removable media, and logs of printer, copier, and facsimile machine use.</p>
                <p>Records relating to the management and operation of PBGC personnel and physical security, including information relating to continued eligibility for access to PBGC facilities, information, and information systems.</p>
                <p>Information identifying threats to PBGC personnel, property, facilities, and information; information obtained from the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or from other agencies or organizations about individuals known or suspected of being engaged in conduct constituting, preparing for, aiding, or relating to an insider threat, including espionage or unauthorized disclosure of personally identifiable information (PII).</p>
                <p>B. The system may include these categories of records:</p>
                <p>Publicly available information, such as information regarding: Arrests and detentions; real property; bankruptcy; liens or holds on property; vehicles; licensure (including professional and pilot’s licenses, firearms and explosive permits); business licenses and filings; and from social media.</p>
                <p>Reports furnished to the PBGC, or collected by PBGC, in connection with personnel security investigations and Insider Threat Detection Program operated by PBGC pursuant to Federal laws and Executive Orders, rules, regulations, guidance, and PBGC policies.</p>
                <p>Documentation pertaining to investigative or analytical efforts by PBGC Insider Threat Program Personnel to identify threats to PBGC personnel, property, facilities, and information.</p>
                <p>Intelligence reports and database query results relating to individuals covered by this system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To monitor for, identify, and respond to potential insider threats, information in the system will be received on an as needed basis from PBGC employees, contractors, vendors, interns, and detailees; officials from other foreign, federal, tribal, state, and local government agencies and organizations; non-government, commercial, public, and private agencies and organizations; complainants, informants, suspects, and witnesses; and from relevant records, including counterintelligence and security databases and files; personnel security databases and files; PBGC human resources databases and files; PBGC contractor files; PBGC’s Office of Information Technology; information collected through user activity monitoring; PBGC telephone usage records; federal, state, tribal, territorial, and local law enforcement and investigatory records; Inspector General records; available U.S. Government intelligence and counterintelligence reporting information and analytic products pertaining to adversarial threats; other Federal agencies; and publicly available information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information about covered individuals may be disclosed without consent as permitted by the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 522a(b), and:</p>
                <p>1. General Routine Uses G1 through G14 apply to this system of records (see Prefatory Statement of General Routine Uses).</p>
                <p>2. Records may be disclosed to any person, organization, or governmental entity in order to notify them of a serious threat for the purpose of guarding against or responding to the threat.</p>
                <p>3. Records may be disclosed to a federal, state, or local agency, or other appropriate entities or individuals, or through established liaison channels to selected foreign governments, in order to enable the intelligence agency with the relevant authority and responsibility for the matter to carry out its responsibilities under the National Security Act of 1947 as amended, the CIA act of 1949 as emended, Executive Order 12333 or any successor order, applicable national security directives, or classified implementing procedures approved by the Attorney General and promulgated pursuant to such statutes, orders or directives.</p>
                <p>4.  Records may be disclosed to the U.S. Department of Homeland Security (DHS) if captured in an intrusion detection system used by PBGC and DHS pursuant to a DHS cybersecurity program that monitors internet traffic to and from federal government computer networks to prevent a variety of types of cybersecurity incidents.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in electronic form (including computer databases or discs).  Records may also be maintained on back-up tapes, or on a PBGC or a contractor-hosted network.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information from this system may be retrieved by numerous data elements and key word searches, including, but not limited to name, dates, subject, and other information retrievable with full text searching capability.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PBGC has established security and privacy protocols that meet the required security and privacy standards issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Records are maintained in a secure, password protected electronic system that utilizes security hardware and software to include multiple firewalls, active intruder detection, and role-based access controls. PBGC has adopted appropriate administrative, technical, and physical controls in accordance with PBGC’s security program to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information, and to ensure that records are not disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized individuals.</p>
                <p>Electronic records are stored on computer networks, which may include cloud-based systems, and protected by controlled access with Personal Identity Verification (PIV) cards, assigning user accounts to individuals needing access to the records and by passwords set by authorized users that must be changed periodically.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records in this system of records are covered by National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 5.6, items 210, 220, 230, and 240.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to request access to their records in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.4, should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to amend their records must submit a written request identifying the information they wish to correct in their file, in addition to following the requirements of the Record Access Procedure above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals, or third parties with written authorization from the individual, wishing to learn whether this system of records contains information about them should submit a written request to the Disclosure Officer, PBGC, 1200 K Street, NW, Washington, DC 20005, providing their name, address, date of birth, and verification of their identity in accordance with 29 CFR 4902.3(c).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), PBGC has established regulations at 29 CFR 4902.12 that exempt records in this system depending on their purpose.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>





    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="29">
<heading> Labor </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XL">
<heading> Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation </heading>
<regulationsPart number="4902">
<heading> DISCLOSURE AND AMENDMENT OF RECORDS PERTAINING TO INDIVIDUALS UNDER THE PRIVACY ACT </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>4902.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>4902.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>4902.3 Procedures for determining existence of and requesting access to records.
</p>
<p>4902.4 Disclosure of record to an individual.
</p>
<p>4902.5 Procedures for requesting amendment of a record.
</p>
<p>4902.6 Action on request for amendment of a record.
</p>
<p>4902.7 Appeal of a denial of a request for amendment of a record.
</p>
<p>4902.8 Fees.
</p>
<p>4902.9 Privacy Act provisions for which PBGC claims an exemption.
</p>
<p>4902.10 Specific exemption: Personnel security investigation records.
</p>
<p>4902.11 Specific exemptions: Office of Inspector General investigative file system.
</p>
<p>4902.12 Filing rules; computation of time.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a, 29 U.S.C. 1302(b)(3). 
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 61 FR 34128, July 1, 1996, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.1
 Purpose and Scope.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Procedures.</i> Sections 4902.3 through 4902.7 establish procedures under which--
</p>
<p>(1) An individual may--
</p>
<p>(i) Determine whether PBGC maintains any system of records that contains a record pertaining to the individual;
</p>
<p>(ii) Obtain access to the individual"s record upon request;
</p>
<p>(iii) Make a request to amend the individual"s record; and
</p>
<p>(iv) Appeal a denial of a request to amend the individual"s record; and
</p>
<p>(2) PBGC will make an initial determination of a request to amend an individual"s record.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Fees.</i> Section 4902.8 prescribes the fees for making copies of an individual"s record.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Privacy Act provisions.</i> Section 4902.9 summarizes the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) provisions for which PBGC claims an exemption for certain systems of records.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Exemptions.</i> Sections 4902.10 through 4902.12 set forth those systems of records that are exempted from certain disclosure and other provisions of the Privacy Act, and the reasons for the exemptions.
</p>
<p>[74 FR 27081, June 8, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>In addition to terminology in part 4001 of this chapter, as used in this part:
</p>
<p><i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by an agency, including, but not limited to, his or her education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history and that contains his or her name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print or a photograph.
</p>
<p><i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of any agency from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p><i>Working day</i> means any weekday excepting Federal holidays.
</p>
<p>[61 FR 34128, July 1, 1996, as amended at 74 FR 27081, June 8, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.3
 Procedures for determining existence of and requesting access to records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual may submit a request to the Disclosure Officer, Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, for the purpose of learning whether a system of records maintained by the PBGC contains any record pertaining to the requestor or obtaining access to such a record. Such a request may be sent to the Disclosure Officer or made in person between the hours of 9 a.m. and 4 p.m. on any working day. Current information on how to make a request, including the Disclosure Officer"s mailing address and location, can be obtained on PBGC"s Web site, <i>http://www.pbgc.gov.</i>.
</p>
<p>(b) Each request submitted pursuant to paragraph (a) of this section shall include the name of the system of records to which the request pertains and the requester"s full name, home address and date of birth, and shall prominently state the words, "Privacy Act Request." If this information is insufficient to enable the PBGC to identify the record in question, or to determine the identity of the requester (to ensure the privacy of the subject of the record), the disclosure officer shall request such further identifying data as the disclosure officer deems necessary to locate the record or to determine the identity of the requester.
</p>
<p>(c) Unless the request is only for notification of the existence of a record and such notification is required under the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552), the requester shall be required to provide verification of his or her identity to the PBGC as set forth in paragraph (c)(1) or (2) of this section, as appropriate.
</p>
<p>(1) If the request is made by mail, the requester shall submit a notarized statement establishing his or her identity.
</p>
<p>(2) If the request is made in person, the requester shall show identification satisfactory to the disclosure officer, such as a driver"s license, employee identification, annuitant identification or Medicare card.
</p>
<p>(d) The disclosure officer shall respond to the request in writing within 10 working days after receipt of the request or of such additional information as may be required under paragraph (b) of this section. If a request for access to a record is granted, the response shall state when the record will be made available.
</p>
<p>[61 FR 34128, July 1, 1996, as amended at 68 FR 61358, Oct. 28, 2003; 74 FR 27081, June 8, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.4
 Disclosure of record to an individual.
</b></p>
<p>(a) When the disclosure officer grants a request for access to records under &#167; 4902.3, such records shall be made available when the requester is advised of the determination or as promptly thereafter as possible. At the requester"s option, the record will be made available for the requester"s inspection and copying at the PBGC, between the hours of 9 a.m. and 4 p.m. on any working day, or a copy of the record will be mailed to the requester. Current information on where the records may be inspected and copied can be obtained on PBGC"s Web site, <i>http://www.pbgc.gov.</i>
</p>
<p>(b) If the requester desires to be accompanied by another individual during the inspection and/or copying of the record, the requester shall, either when the record is made available or at any earlier time, submit to the disclosure officer a signed statement identifying such other individual and authorizing such other individual to be present during the inspection and/or copying of the record.
</p>
<p>[61 FR 34128, July 1, 1996, as amended at 74 FR 27082, June 8, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.5
 Procedures for requesting amendment of a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any individual about whom the PBGC maintains a record contained in a system of records may request that the record be amended. Such a request shall be submitted in the same manner described in &#167; 4902.3(a).
</p>
<p>(b) Each request submitted under paragraph (a) of this section shall include the information described in &#167; 4902.3(b) and a statement specifying the changes to be made in the record and the justification therefor. The disclosure officer may request further identifying data as described in &#167; 4902.3(b).
</p>
<p>(c) An individual who desires assistance in the preparation of a request for amendment of a record shall submit such request for assistance in writing to the Deputy General Counsel, Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation. The Deputy General Counsel shall respond to such request as promptly as possible.
</p>
<p>[61 FR 34128, July 1, 1996, as amended at 68 FR 61358, Oct. 28, 2003]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.6
 Action on request for amendment of a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Within 20 working days after receipt by the PBGC of a request for amendment of a record under &#167; 4902.5, unless for good cause shown the  Director of the PBGC extends such 20-day period, the disclosure officer shall notify the requester in writing whether and to what extent the request shall be granted. To the extent that the request is granted, the disclosure officer shall cause the requested amendment to be made promptly.
</p>
<p>(b) When a request for amendment of a record is denied in whole or in part, the denial shall include a statement of the reasons therefor, the procedures for appealing such denial, and a notice that the requester has a right to assistance in preparing an appeal of the denial.
</p>
<p>(c) An individual who desires assistance in preparing an appeal of a denial under this section shall submit a request to the Deputy General Counsel, Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation. The Deputy General Counsel shall respond to the request as promptly as possible, but in no event more than 30 days after receipt.
</p>
<p>[61 FR 34128, July 1, 1996, as amended at 68 FR 61359, Oct. 28, 2003; 74 FR 27082, June 8, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.7
 Appeal of a denial of a request for amendment of a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) An appeal from a denial of a request for amendment of a record under &#167; 4902.6 shall be submitted, within 45 days of receipt of the denial, to the General Counsel, Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, unless the record subject to such request is one maintained by the Office of the General Counsel, in which event the appeal shall be submitted to the Director or Director"s designee, Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation. The appeal shall state in detail the basis on which it is made and shall clearly state "Privacy Act Request" on the first page. In addition, the submission shall clearly state "Privacy Act Request" on the envelope (for mail, hand delivery, or commercial delivery), in the subject line (for e-mail), or on the cover sheet (for fax).
</p>
<p>(b) Within 30 working days after the receipt of the appeal, unless for good cause shown the Director of the PBGC extends such 30-day period, the General Counsel or, where appropriate, the Director or Director"s designee, shall issue a decision in writing granting or denying the appeal in whole or in part. To the extent that the appeal is granted, the General Counsel or, where appropriate, the Director or Director"s designee, shall cause the requested amendment to be made promptly. To the extent that the appeal is denied, the decision shall include the reasons for the denial and a notice of the requester"s right to submit a brief statement setting forth reasons for disputing the denial of appeal, to seek judicial review of the denial pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1)(A), and to obtain further information concerning the provisions for judicial review under that section.
</p>
<p>(c) An individual whose appeal has been denied in whole or in part may submit a brief summary statement setting forth reasons for disputing such denial. Such statement shall be submitted within 30 days of receipt of the denial of the appeal to the Disclosure Officer. Any such statement shall be made available by the PBGC to anyone to whom the record is subsequently furnished and may also be accompanied, at the discretion of the PBGC, by a brief statement summarizing the PBGC"s reasons for refusing to amend the record. The PBGC shall also provide copies of the individual"s statement of dispute to all prior recipients of the record with respect to whom an accounting of the disclosure of the record was maintained pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(1).
</p>
<p>(d) To request further information concerning the provisions for judicial review, an individual shall submit such request in writing to the Deputy General Counsel, who shall respond to such request as promptly as possible.
</p>
<p>[61 FR 34128, July 1, 1996, as amended at 68 FR 61359, Oct. 28, 2003; 74 FR 27082, June 8, 2009; 74 FR 30212, June 25, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.8
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>When an individual requests a copy of his or her record under &#167; 4902.4, charges for the copying shall be made according to the following fee schedule:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Standard copying fee.</i> There shall be a charge of $0.15 per page of record copies furnished. Where the copying fee is less than $1.50, it shall not be assessed.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Voluminous material.</i> If the volume of page copy desired by the requester is such that the reproduction charge at the standard page rate would be in excess of $50, the individual desiring reproduction may request a special rate quotation from the PBGC.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Manual copying by requester.</i> No charge will be made for manual copying by the requester of any document made available for inspection under &#167; 4902.4. The PBGC shall provide facilities for such copying without charge between the hours of 9 a.m. and 4 p.m. on any working day.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.9
 Privacy Act provisions for which PBGC claims an exemption.
</b></p>
<p>Subsections 552a(j) and (k) of title 5, U.S.C., authorize PBGC to exempt systems of records meeting certain criteria from various other subsections of section 552a. This section contains a summary of the Privacy Act provisions for which PBGC claims an exemption for the systems of records discussed in this part pursuant to, and to the extent permitted by, subsections 552a(j) and (k):
</p>
<p>(a) Subsection (c)(3) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to make available to the individual named in the records an accounting of each disclosure of records.
</p>
<p>(b) Subsection (c)(4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to inform any person or other agency to which a record has been disclosed of any correction or notation of dispute the agency has made to the record in accordance with subsection (d) of the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(c) Subsections (d)(1) through (4) of 5 U.S.C. 552a require an agency to permit an individual to gain access to records about the individual, to request amendment of such records, to request a review of an agency decision not to amend such records, and to provide a statement of disagreement about a disputed record to be filed and disclosed with the disputed record.
</p>
<p>(d) Subsection (e)(1) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to maintain in its records only such information about an individual that is relevant and necessary to accomplish a purpose required by statute or executive order of the President.
</p>
<p>(e) Subsection (e)(2) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to collect information to the greatest extent practicable directly from the subject individual when the information may result in adverse determinations about an individual"s rights, benefits, and privileges under federal programs.
</p>
<p>(f) Subsection (e)(3) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to inform each person whom it asks to supply information of the authority under which the information is sought, whether disclosure is mandatory or voluntary, the principal purpose(s) for which the information will be used, the routine uses that may be made of the information, and the effects of not providing the information.
</p>
<p>(g) Subsection (e)(4)(G) and (H) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to publish a <i>Federal Register</i> notice of its procedures whereby an individual can be notified upon request whether the system of records contains information about the individual, how to gain access to any record about the individual contained in the system, and how to contest its content.
</p>
<p>(h) Subsection (e)(5) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to maintain its records with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to ensure fairness to the individual in making any determination about the individual.
</p>
<p>(i) Subsection (e)(8) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to make reasonable efforts to serve notice on an individual when any record on such individual is made available to any person under compulsory legal process when such process becomes a matter of public record.
</p>
<p>(j) Subsection (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a requires an agency to establish procedures whereby an individual can be notified upon request if any system of records named by the individual contains a record pertaining to the individual, obtain access to the record, and request amendment.
</p>
<p>(k) Subsection (g) of 5 U.S.C. 552a provides for civil remedies if an agency fails to comply with the access and amendment provisions of subsections (d)(1) and (d)(3), and with other provisions of the Privacy Act, or any rule promulgated thereunder, in such a way as to have an adverse effect on an individual.
</p>
<p>[74 FR 27082, June 8, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.10
 Specific exemption: Personnel Security Investigation Records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Exemption.</i> Under the authority granted by 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), PBGC hereby exempts the system of records entitled "PBGC-12, Personnel Security Investigation Records--PBGC" from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I), and (f), to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to PBGC under an express promise of confidentiality or, before September 27, 1975, under an implied promise of confidentiality.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Reasons for Exemption.</i> The reasons for asserting this exemption are to insure the gaining of information essential to determining suitability and fitness for PBGC employment or for work for PBGC as a contractor or as an employee of a contractor, access to information, and security clearances, to insure that full and candid disclosures are obtained in making such determinations, to prevent subjects of such determinations from thwarting the completion of such determinations, and to avoid revealing the identities of persons who furnish information to PBGC in confidence.
</p>
<p>[74 FR 27082, June 8, 2009]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 4902.11
 Specific exemptions: Office of Inspector General Investigative File System.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Criminal Law Enforcement.</i> (1) <i>Exemption.</i> Under the authority granted by 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), PBGC hereby exempts the system of records entitled "PBGC-17, Office of Inspector General Investigative File System--PBGC" from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a (c)(3), (c)(4), (d)(1) through (4), (e)(1) through (3), (e)(4)(G) and (H), (e)(5), (e)(8), (f), and (g) because the system contains information pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Reasons for exemption.</i> The reasons for asserting this exemption are:
</p>
<p>(i) Disclosure to the individual named in the record pursuant to subsections (c)(3), (c)(4), or (d)(1) through (4) could seriously impede or compromise the investigation by alerting the target(s), subjecting a potential witness or witnesses to intimidation or improper influence, and leading to destruction of evidence.
</p>
<p>(ii) Application of subsection (e)(1) is impractical because the relevance of specific information might be established only after considerable analysis and as the investigation progresses. Effective law enforcement requires the Office of Inspector General to keep information that may not be relevant to a specific Office of Inspector General investigation, but which may provide leads for appropriate law enforcement and to establish patterns of activity that might relate to the jurisdiction of the Office of Inspector General and/or other agencies.
</p>
<p>(iii) Application of subsection (e)(2) would be counterproductive to performance of a criminal investigation because it would alert the individual to the existence of an investigation.
</p>
<p>(iv) Application of subsection (e)(3) could discourage the free flow of information in a criminal law enforcement inquiry.
</p>
<p>(v) The requirements of subsections (e)(4)(G) and (H), and (f) do not apply because this system is exempt from the provisions of subsection (d). Nevertheless, PBGC has published notice of its notification, access, and contest procedures because access is appropriate in some cases.
</p>
<p>(vi) Although the Office of Inspector General endeavors to maintain accurate records, application of subsection (e)(5) is impractical because maintaining only those records that are accurate, relevant, timely, and complete and that assure fairness in determination is contrary to established investigative techniques. Information that may initially appear inaccurate, irrelevant, untimely, or incomplete may, when collated and analyzed with other available information, become more pertinent as an investigation progresses.
</p>
<p>(vii) Application of subsection (e)(8) could prematurely reveal an ongoing criminal investigation to the subject of the investigation.
</p>
<p>(viii) The provisions of subsection (g) do not apply to this system if an exemption otherwise applies.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Other Law Enforcement.</i> (1) <i>Exemption.</i> Under the authority granted by 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), PBGC hereby exempts the system of records entitled "PBGC-17, Office of Inspector General Investigative File System--PBGC" from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d)(1) through (4), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G) and (H), and (f) for the same reasons as stated in paragraph (a)(2) of this section, that is, because the system contains investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes other than material within the scope of subsection 552a(j)(2).
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Reasons for exemption.</i> The reasons for asserting this exemption are because the disclosure and other requirements of the Privacy Act could substantially compromise the efficacy and integrity of the Office of Inspector General operations. Disclosure could invade the privacy of other individuals and disclose their identity when they were expressly promised confidentiality. Disclosure could interfere with the integrity of information which would otherwise be subject to privileges (see, e.g., 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(5)), and which could interfere with other important law enforcement concerns (see, e.g., 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(7)).
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Federal Civilian or Contract Employment.</i> (1) Exemption. Under the authority granted by 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), PBGC hereby exempts the system of records entitled "PBGC-17, Office of Inspector General Investigative File System--PBGC" from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d)(1) through (4), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G) and (H), and (f) because the system contains investigatory material compiled for the purpose of determining eligibility or qualifications for federal civilian or contract employment.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Reason for exemption.</i> The reason for asserting this exemption is to protect from disclosure the identity of a confidential source when an express promise of confidentiality has been given to obtain information from sources who would otherwise be unwilling to provide necessary information.
</p>
<p>[74 FR 27082, June 8, 2009]
</p>

    <p>
        <b>
            &#167; 4902.12
           Specific exemptions: Insider Threat and Data Loss Prevention.
        </b>
    </p>

    <p>
        (a) <i>Exemption.</i>  Under the authority granted by 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), PBGC hereby exempts the system of records entitled "PBGC-26, PBGC Insider Threat and Data Loss Prevention – PBGC" from the provisions of  5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4)(G), (H), and (I) and (f).
    </p>
    <p>
        (b) <i>Reasons for exemption.  </i>The reasons for asserting the exemption in this section are because the disclosure and other requirements of the Privacy Act could substantially compromise the efficacy and integrity of PBGC’s ability to investigate insider threat activities and the improper exfiltration of personally identifiable information.  Disclosure could invade the privacy of other individuals and disclose their identity when they were expressly promised confidentiality.  Disclosure could interfere with the integrity of information which would otherwise be subject to privileges, see, e.g., 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(5), and which could interfere with other important law enforcement concerns, see, e.g., 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(7).
    </p>
    <p> [Reserved]</p>

    <p>[84 FR 32619, July 9, 2019]</p>

    <p><b>&#167; 4902.13
 Filing rules; computation of time.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Filing rules</i>--(1) <i>Where to file.</i> See &#167; 4000.4 of this chapter for information on where to file a submission under this part with the PBGC.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Method of filing.</i> The PBGC applies the rules in subpart A of part 4000 of this chapter to determine permissible methods of filing with the PBGC under this part.
</p>
<p>(3) <i>Date of filing.</i> The PBGC applies the rules in subpart C of part 4000 of this chapter to determine the date that a submission under this part was filed with the PBGC.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Computation of time.</i> The PBGC applies the rules in subpart D of part 4000 of this chapter to compute any time period for filing under this part.
</p>
<p>[68 FR 61359, Oct. 28, 2003. Redesignated at 74 FR 27082, June 8, 2009. Redesignated at 84 FR 32619, July 9, 2019]
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
