<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">

    <name>Department of Defense, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency</name>
    <abbrev>NGA</abbrev>

    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>

    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-01-16/pdf/2020-00567.pdf</url>
        <title>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Maritime Safety Office Metrics Database, NGA-005--Rescindment</title>
        <date year="2020" month="1" day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-01-16/pdf/2020-00571.pdf</url>
        <title>Record of Accounts Receivable, B0302-13--Rescindment</title>
        <date year="2020" month="1" day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-01-16/pdf/2020-00582.pdf</url>
        <title>Classified Material Access Files, B0502-03-2--Rescindment</title>
        <date year="2020" month="1" day="16" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-03-18/pdf/2020-05665.pdf</url>
        <title>Centralized Disbursing System, T7320b</title>
        <date year="2020" month="3" day="18" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-07-06/pdf/2020-13114.pdf</url>
        <title>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Privacy Program;2 CFR part 320 removed</title>
        <date year="2020" month="7" day="18" />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Editorial Note:</b> The National Imagery and Mapping Agency changed its name to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency on November 23, 2003 (Pub. L. 108-136).</p>
<p><b>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency
</b></p>
<p><i>How Systems of Records Are Arranged</i></p>
<p>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency records are grouped by subject series. Each series has records about a specific activity or function to which a subject title and number is given. Systems or records are grouped in the same way. For example, a system of records on personnel security clearances may be found in Personnel Security Files--B0504-01 and one about military personnel assignments may be found in Military Services Administrative Record Files--B0614-02. These numbers are part of the system identification. The letter B means National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency. The first four digits (0504 and 0614) show that the records pertain to Personnel Security and Military Personnel respectively, and the last two are a further breakdown of the series. Other systems of records which differ from these examples but have similar documents may also be found in the same series.
</p><p><i>How To Use the Index Guide
</i></p><p>The systems of records maintained by the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency are contained within the subject series that are listed below. This list identifies each series in the order in which it appears in this issuance. Use the list to identify subject areas of interest. Having done so, use the series number (for example 0504 for Personnel Security) to locate the systems of records grouping in which you are interested.
</p>
<table>
<tr>
<th scope="col">Subject series</th>
<th scope="col">System identification series</th></tr>
<tr><td>Inspection</td>
<td>0210</td></tr>
<tr><td>Historical</td>
<td>0228</td></tr>
<tr><td>Finance and Accounting</td>
<td>0302</td></tr>
<tr><td>Civilian Personnel Pay and Accounting</td>
<td>0303</td></tr>
<tr><td>General Legal</td>
<td>0401</td></tr>
<tr><td>Claims Investigating and Processing Documents</td>
<td>0402</td></tr>
<tr><td>Informational Services</td>
<td>0408</td></tr>
<tr><td>Information Security</td>
<td>0502</td></tr>
<tr><td>Guard Protective Services</td>
<td>0503</td></tr>
<tr><td>Personnel Security</td>
<td>0504</td></tr>
<tr><td>Military Personnel Files</td>
<td>0614</td></tr>
<tr><td>Safety Management Program</td>
<td>0615</td></tr>
<tr><td>Medical and Health Program</td>
<td>0901</td></tr>
<tr><td>Individual Procurement Transactions</td>
<td>1202</td></tr>
<tr><td>General Supply Accounting</td>
<td>1205</td></tr>
<tr><td>Self Service Supply</td>
<td>1206</td></tr>
<tr><td>Maintenance</td>
<td>1208</td></tr>
<tr><td>Personnel Travel and Transportation</td>
<td>1211</td></tr>
</table>
<p><i>Requesting Records
</i></p><p>Records are retrieved by name or by some other personal identifier. It is therefore especially important for expeditious service when requesting a record that particular attention be provided to the Notification and/or Access Procedures of the particular record system involved so as to furnish the required personal identifiers, or any other pertinent personal information as may be required to locate and retrieve the record.
</p><p><i>Blanket Routine Uses
</i></p><p>Certain "blanket routine uses" of the records have been established that are applicable to every record system maintained within the Department of Defense unless specifically stated otherwise within a particular record system. These additional blanket routine uses of the records are published below only once in the interest of simplicity, economy and to avoid redundancy.
</p><p><i>Law enforcement routine use:</i> In the event that a system of records maintained by this component to carry out its functions indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, state, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p><i>Disclosure when requesting information routine use
</i></p><p>A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, state, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a component decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit.
</p><p><i>Disclosure of requested information routine use
</i></p><p>A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.
</p><p><i>Congressional inquiries routine use:</i> Disclosure from a system of records maintained by this component may be made to a Congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the Congressional office made at the request of that individual.
</p><p><i>Private relief legislation routine use:</i> Relevant information contained in all systems of records of the Department of Defense published on or before August 22, 1975, may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget in connection with the review of private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular A-19 at any stage of the legislative coordination and clearance process as set forth in that Circular.</p>
<p><i>Disclosures required by international agreements routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed to foreign law enforcement, security, investigatory, or administrative authorities in order to comply with requirements imposed by, or to claim rights conferred in, international agreements and arrangements including those regulating the stationing and status in foreign countries of Department of Defense military and civilian personnel.
</p><p><i>Disclosure to state and local taxing authorities routine use:</i> Any information normally contained in IRS Form W-2 which is maintained in a record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed to state and local taxing authorities with which the Secretary of the Treasury has entered into agreements pursuant to Title 5, U.S. Code, Sections 5516, 5517, 5520, and only to those state and local taxing authorities for which an employee or military member is or was subject to tax regardless of whether tax is or was withheld. This routine use is in accordance with Treasury Fiscal Requirements Manual Bulletin Number 76-07.
</p><p><i>Disclosure to the office of personnel management routine use:</i> A record from a system of records subject to the Privacy Act and maintained by this component may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management concerning information on pay and leave, benefits, retirement deductions, and any other information necessary for the Office of Personnel Management to carry out its legally authorized Government-wide personnel management functions and studies.
</p><p><i>Disclosure to the department of justice for litigation routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to any component of the Department of Justice for the purpose of representing the Department of Defense, or any officer, employee or member of the Department in pending or potential litigation to which the record is pertinent.
</p><p><i>Disclosure to military banking facilities overseas routine use:</i> Information as to current military addresses and assignments may be provided to military banking facilities who provide banking services overseas and who are reimbursed by the Government for certain checking and loan losses. For personnel separated, discharged, or retired from the Armed Forces, information as to last known residential or home of record address may be provided to the military banking facility upon certification by a banking facility officer that the facility has a returned or dishonored check negotiated by the individual or the individual has defaulted on a loan and that if restitution is not made by the individual, the U.S. Government will be liable for the losses the facility may incur.
</p><p><i>Disclosure of information to the general services administration routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to the General Services Administration for the purpose of records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p><i>Disclosure of information to the national archives and records administration routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to the National Archives and Records Administration for the purpose of records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p><i>Disclosure to the merit systems protection board routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to the Merit Systems Protection Board, including the Office of the Special Counsel for the purpose of litigation, including administrative proceedings, appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of OPM or component rules and regulations, investigation of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices; including administrative proceedings involving any individual subject of a DoD investigation, and such other functions, promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, or as may be authorized by law.
</p><p><i>Counterintelligence purposes routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use outside the DoD or the U.S. Government for the purpose of counterintelligence activities authorized by U.S. Law or Executive Order or for the purpose of enforcing laws which protect the national security of the United States.
</p><p><i>Data breach remediation purposes routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by a Component may be disclosed to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) The Component suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of the information in the system of records has been compromised; (2) the Component has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise there is a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system or other systems or programs (whether maintained by the Component or another agency or entity) that rely upon the compromised information; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the Components efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p><p><i>Information sharing environment routine use:</i> A record from a system of records maintained by a Component consisting of, or relating to, terrorism information (6 U.S.C. 485(a)(4)), homeland security information (6 U.S.C. 482(f)(1)), or Law enforcement information (Guideline 2 Report attached to White House Memorandum, "Information Sharing Environment, November 22, 2006) may be disclosed to a Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, foreign governmental and/or multinational agency, either in response to its request or upon the initiative of the Component, for purposes of sharing such information as is necessary and relevant for the agencies to the detection, prevention, disruption, preemption, and mitigation of the effects of terrorist activities against the territory, people, and interests of the United States of America as contemplated by the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Protection Act of 2004 (Public Law 108-458) and Executive Order 13388 (October 25, 2005).
</p><p><i>NOTE:</i> Information relating to, but not in and of itself constituting, terrorism, homeland security, or law enforcement information, as defined above, may only be disclosed upon a showing by the requester that the information is pertinent to the conduct of investigations of, or the development of analyses regarding, terrorism.
</p></xhtmlContent></routineUses>


<section id="003" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-003</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise Workforce System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) headquarters in
Washington, DC metro facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NGA employees, military personnel, independent industry advisors,
contractors, and foreign visitors employed by or assigned to NGA facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Identifying information, such as name, date of birth, place of birth, address, telephone
numbers, email addresses, employee identification number, job title and band, emergency contact information, supervisor's contact
information, photographs, passport and/or drivers' license information, citizenship, polygraph, security clearance, access control
passes, payroll information, Social Security Number (SSN), time and attendance, performance, awards and bonuses, duty location,
education and training data, military and veterans status, gender, ethnicity/race indicator, disability data, drug, vision and
medical test results for deployment readiness.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>50 U.S.C. &#167; 402a; Coordination of counterintelligence activities; Executive Order
10450, Security requirements for Government employment; Executive Order 12968 Access to classified information; 5 CFR part 732,
National security positions; 5 CFR part 736, Personnel Investigations; 32 CFR part 147, Adjudicative Guidelines for Determining
Eligibility for Intelligence Directive (DCID) 6/4, Personnel Security Standards and Procedures Governing Eligibility for Access to
Sensitive Compartmented Information; 5 U.S.C. 301 Departmental Regulations; DoDD 5105.60, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency
(NGA); 5 U.S.C. 7532, Suspension and Removal; Employees; E.O. 12958, Classified National Security Information; DoD 5200.2-R,
DoD Personnel Security Program; Director of Central Intelligence Directive No. 1/14, Personnel Security Standards and Procedures
Governing Eligibility for Access to Sensitive Compartmented Information (SCI); and E.O. 9397 (SSN), as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA collects, uses, maintains, and disseminates employee information to facilitate a variety
of NGA's mission-related duties, including activities related to administrative matters, account creation, operations support, access
controls, workforce security, training records, expertise, competency management, polygraph information, drug, vision and medical
test results, Federal reporting requirements, and international counterintelligence. NGA Enterprise Workforce System data, which
includes personally identifiable information (PII), is necessary for NGA to effectively and efficiently conduct its mission on
multiple levels by using PII provided by employees and contingent workers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974 and the DoD Blanket Routine Uses, these records contained therein may be specifically disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>Relevant records from this system may be provided regularly to the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) for the Intelligence Community to provide aggregate workforce planning, analysis, and reporting purposes. Records provided to the ODNI through this routine use for the Personnel Data Repository (PDR) and Intelligence Community Capabilities Catalog (IC3) initiatives will not include any individual's name or Social Security Number (SSN).
</p><p>The DoD 'Blanket Routine Uses' set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy
Act of 1974, as amended, these records may be specifically disclosed outside of the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. a(b)(3)
as follows:
</p><p>The DoD Blanket Routine Uses set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation or systems of records notices apply to this
system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored electronically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name or other personal identifier listed above in the Categories
of Records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies,
including all applicable NGA automated systems security and access policies. Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk
of compromising the information that is being stored. Access to the computer system containing the records in this system is limited
to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate
clearances or permissions. Some of the technical controls include, limited, role based access as well as profiles based access to
limit users to only data that is needed for the performance of their official duties. The system is located in a secure data center
and operated by Federal personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA will delete or destroy these records three years after the end date of employment with
NGA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>;Human Development Directorate, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether this system of records contains information about
themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy
Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked 'Privacy Act Inquiry.'
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C.
1746, in the following format:
</p><p>If executed outside the United States:
</p><p>'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the
foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)'.
</p><p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths:
</p><p>'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).
Signature)'."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Delete entry and replace with "Individuals seeking access to this system of records contains information about themselves
should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office,
7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked 'Privacy Act Inquiry.'
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C.
1746, in the following format:
</p><p>If executed outside the United States:
</p><p>'I declare (or certify, verify, or state).under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the
foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)'.
</p><p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths:
</p><p>'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).
Signature)'.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Office of the General Counsel, Mail Stop D-10, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address, and telephone number.
</p><p>Contesting records procedure:
</p><p>Individuals contesting the accuracy of records in this system of records contains information
about themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information
Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked 'Privacy Act Inquiry.'
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C.
1746, in the following format:
</p><p>If executed outside the United States:
</p><p>'I declare (or certify, verify, or state).under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the
foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)'.
</p><p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths:
</p><p>'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).
Signature)'.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information originates from the individual and from sources contacted during personnel and
background investigations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Information specifically authorized to be classified under E.O. 12958, as implemented by DoD 5200.1-R, may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1).
</p><p>Investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of subsection 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). However, if an individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit for which he would otherwise be entitled by Federal law or for which he would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of the information, the individual will be provided access to the information exempt to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a confidential source. <i>Note:</i> When claimed, this exemption allows limited protection of investigative reports maintained in a system of records used in personnel or administrative actions.
</p><p>An exemption rule for this system has been promulgated in accordance with requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1), (2), and (3), (c) and (e) published in 32 CFR part 320. For additional information, contact the system manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
	<section id="nga4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-004</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">NGA Threat Mitigation Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at NGA headquarters in Washington, DC metro facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals known or appropriately suspected to be or have been engaged in conduct constituting, in preparation for, in aid of, or
related to terrorism ("known or suspected terrorists"), individuals who were officially detained during military
operations, but not as Enemy Prisoners of War, and who have been identified to pose an actual or possible threat to national security
(hereinafter military detainees).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Identifying information, such as name, date of birth, place of birth, biometrics, photographs, passport and/or drivers' license
information, and other available identifying particulars used to compare the identity of an individual being screened with a known or
suspected terrorist, including audit records containing this information.
</p><p>For known or suspected terrorists, in addition to the categories of records listed above, references to and/or information from
other government law enforcement and intelligence databases, or other relevant databases that may contain terrorism information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 10 U.S.C. Chapter 22, The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; 50 U.S.C. 402a,
Coordination of Counterintelligence Activities; and HSPD-24, Biometrics for Identification and Screening to Enhance National
Security.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA collects, uses, maintains, and disseminates information to facilitate NGA's counterintelligence activities, including
activities related to international counterterrorism. Threat Mitigation data, which includes personally identifiable information
(PII), is necessary for NGA to effectively and efficiently conduct its mission by assessing the risk and/or threat to NGA personnel,
property, information and facilities posed by persons who have been deemed known or suspected terrorists or have a nexus to criminal
activity.
</p><p>NGA is receiving information relevant for use in authorized screening processes to assist in detecting and mitigating domestic and
international threats to the United States (U.S.) and U.S. interests worldwide.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, these records
may be specifically disclosed outside of the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD Blanket Routine Uses set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices may apply to this
system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored electronically in secure facilities behind a locked door with strict physical access controls in
place. The records are stored on magnetic disc, tape, digital media, and CD-ROM.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name or other personal identifier listed in the Categories of records section.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>TThe records are stored on a secure enclave system and are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies, including all applicable NGA automated systems security and access policies.  Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is being stored.  Access to the computer system containing the records in this system is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions. Usage of physical access controls, encryption, monitoring and auditing mechanisms protect the information stored on the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Retain locally and review annually.  Destroy/delete 2 years after completion of final action.  If still needed for Agency business, records
may be retained for up to 10 years.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Security and Installation Counterespionage Division, Fusion Branch (SICCC), National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA  22150.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether this system of records contains information about themselves should address written
inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive,
Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>A request for notification must meet the requirements of 32 CFR 320.4. The request envelope and letter should both be clearly
marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits
statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to records about themselves contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the
National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA
22150.
</p><p>A request for access must meet the requirements of 32 CFR 320.4. The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked
"Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits
statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals contesting the accuracy of records in this system of records containing information about themselves should address
written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT
Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>A request for contesting records must meet the requirements of 32 CFR 320.4. The request envelope and letter should both be
clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits
statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are received from the JUSTICE/FBI-019 Terrorist Screening Records System, system of records notice published in the Federal Register (76 FR 77846, December 14, 2011).  In addition, information contained in this system is obtained from subject individuals; other Federal, State, local and foreign agencies and organizations; hard-copy media, including periodicals, newspapers, and broadcast transcripts, and commercial and public record databases and Web sites; public and classified reporting, intelligence source documents, investigative reports, and correspondence.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Exempt materials from JUSTICE/FBI—019 Terrorist Screening Records System and/or other sources listed above may become part of the case records in this system of records. To the extent that copies of exempt records from JUSTICE/FBI—019, Terrorist Screening Records System, and/or other sources listed above are entered into these Threat Mitigation case records, NGA hereby claims the same exemptions, (j)(2) and (k)(2) for the records as claimed in JUSTICE/FBI—019, Terrorist Screening Records system of records of which they are a part as reflected in the final rule published on May 31, 2013, 78 FR 32554.</p>

<p>Information specifically authorized to be classified under E.O. 12958, as implemented by DoD 5200.1-R, may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1).
</p>
<p>Investigative material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for federal civilian employment, military service, federal contracts, or access to classified information may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), but only to the extent that such material would reveal the identity of a confidential source.</p>

<p>An exemption rule for this system has been promulgated in accordance with the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 553(b)(1), (2) and (3) (c) and (e) and it published at 32 CFR part 320.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="nga7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-007</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Management and Execution Tracker (MET)
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at NGA headquarters in Washington, DC metro facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Government employees and military personnel at the National Geospatial Intelligence Agency.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, current address, date and place of birth, employee ID number, program element code, department ID, job code, supervisor, email address, occupation, official title, subproject code, work address, home address, work phone, home phone, Social Security Number (SSN), travel information, contact information, discretionary training information and supply information. In addition, dates of employee and military personnel activities, budget allocations and assignments, and classified justifications are also included in the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA collects, uses, maintains, and disseminates information to account for government employees and military members' activities for the purpose of providing operational metrics, tracking budgets, and presenting work products to senior leadership regarding travel, training, and supply. Data is used by leadership to effectively and efficiently make decisions for fiscal and resource planning.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, these records may be specifically disclosed outside of the DoD as a routine pursuant to 5 U.S.C. a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD Blanket Routine Uses set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation or systems of records notices may apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records and electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name or any of the personal identifiers listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies, including all applicable NGA automated systems security and access policies. Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the stored information. Access to the computer system containing the records in this system is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances and permissions. Usage of physical access controls, encryption, monitoring and auditing mechanisms protect the information stored on the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA will maintain travel related records in electronic form for six years, and training, budget, and supply related records for two years, after which, hardcopies are filed with the supervisor and archived with Record Services for six years.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Resource and Programming Office, Execution Division, Operations Branch Chief (ABREO), Analysis Directorate, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), 7500 GEOINT Dr., Springfield, VA 22150.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether this system of records contains information about themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>A request for notification must meet the requirements of 32 CFR 320.4. The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to records about themselves contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>A request for access must meet the requirements of 32 CFR 320.4. The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals contesting the accuracy of records in this system of records containing information about themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>A request for contesting records must meet the requirements of 32 CFR 320.4. The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information originates from the individual and the NGA PeopleSoft Directory.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>An exemption rule for this system has been promulgated in accordance with requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(d) pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1) and published in 32 CFR Part 320. For additional information, contact the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="nga8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-008</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Polygraph Records System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) Headquarters in Washington, DC metro facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NGA employees, military personnel, contractors, employed by or assigned to NGA facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Polygraph reports, polygraph charts, polygraph tapes, and notes from polygraph interviews or activities related to polygraph interviews. Identifying information such as, name, date of birth, place of birth, Social Security Number (SSN), company name, contract number, disability data, medical information, gender, grade/rank, employee identification number, and foreign contacts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>50 U.S.C. 402a; Coordination of counterintelligence activities; E.O. 10450, Security requirements for Government employment; E.O. 12968, as amended, Access to classified information; 5 CFR part 732, National security positions; 5 CFR part 736, Personnel investigations; 32 CFR part 147, Adjudicative Guidelines for Determining Eligibility for Classified Information; Director of Central Intelligence Directive (DCID) 6/4, Personnel Security Standards and Procedures Governing Eligibility for Access to Sensitive Compartmented Information; 5 U.S.C. 301 Departmental Regulations; DoDD 5105.60, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA); 5 U.S.C. 7532, Suspension and Removal; E.O. 12958, Classified National Security Information; DoD 5200.2-R, DoD Personnel Security Program; Director of Central Intelligence Directive No. 1/14, Personnel Security Standards and Procedures Governing Eligibility for Access to Sensitive Compartmented Information (SCI); E.O. 13467, Reforming Processes Related to Suitability for Government Employment, Fitness for Contractor Employees, and Eligibility for Access to Classified National Security Information; and E.O. 9397 (SSN), as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To ensure the integrity in the polygraph examination process, document polygraph results, assist with security eligibility determinations and employment or assignment suitability decisions in accordance with applicable laws, regulations and guidance. To assist with investigations into possible violations of NGA rules and regulations, including the possible loss or compromise of classified or protected NGA information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, these records may be specifically disclosed outside of the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD Blanket Routine Uses set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation or systems of records notices may apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name, employee identification number or SSN.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies, including all applicable NGA automated systems security and access policies. Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is being stored. Access to the computer system containing the records in this system is strictly limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions. Some of the technical controls include, limited, role based access as well as profiles based access to limit users to only data that is needed for the performance of their official duties. The system is located in a secure data center and operated by Federal personnel and contractors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA will transfer the records to the National Archives and Records Administration when no longer needed and destroyed/deleted when 10 years old.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Polygraph Branch Chief, Security and Installations Division, Personnel Security, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150-7500.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:
</p><p>If executed outside the United States: 'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)'.
</p><p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: 'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). Signature)'.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150-7500.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:
</p><p>If executed outside the United States: 'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)'.
</p><p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: 'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). Signature)'.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals contesting the accuracy of records contained in this system of records about themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 Geoint Drive, Springfield, VA 22150-7500.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry."
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:
</p><p>If executed outside the United States: 'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). (Signature)'.
</p><p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: 'I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date). Signature)'.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information originates from the individual prior to and during the examination.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of subsection 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). However, if an individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit for which he would otherwise be entitled by Federal law or for which he would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of the information, the individual will be provided access to the information exempt to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a confidential source. </p><p><i>Note:</i>  When claimed, this exemption allows limited protection of investigative reports maintained in a system of records used in personnel or administrative actions.
</p><p>An exemption rule for this system has been promulgated in accordance with requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1), (2), and (3), (c) and (e) published in 32 CFR Part 320. For additional information, contact the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="nga10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-010</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Security Financial Disclosure Reporting Records System.  </subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records are maintained at National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) Headquarters in Washington, DC metro facilities.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Current and former NGA employees, military personnel, contractors, and external applicants who have been extended a conditional offer of employment employed by or assigned to NGA facilities.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>
<p>The system also contains any records of the analysts" examination of the form and related materials, including any notations, memoranda, investigative notes and summaries or other observations.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent>
<p>50 U.S.C. 402a, Coordination of counterintelligence activities; </p>
<p>E.O. 13467, Reforming Processes Related to Suitability for Government Employment, Fitness for Contractor Employees, and Eligibility for Access to Classified National Security Information; Public Law 103-359, Title VIII, Counterintelligence and Security Enhancements Act of 1994; E.O. 10865, Safeguarding Classified Information Within Industry; E.O. 12333, United States Intelligence Activities; 5 CFR part 732; 5 CFR part 736; 32 CFR part 147; DCID 6/4; 5 U.S.C. 301 Departmental Regulations; DoDD 5105.60, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA); 5 U.S.C. 7532 Suspension and Removal; E.O. 10450, Security Requirements for Government Employees; E.O. 12958, Classified National Security Information; E.O. 12968, Access to Classified Information; Section 1.350 U.S.C 401-413, National Security Act of 1947, as amended; DoD 5200.2-R, DoD Personnel Security Program; DCID 1/14, Personnel Security Standards and Procedures Governing Eligibility for Access to Sensitive Compartmented Information (SCI); and E.O. 9397 (SSN), as amended. </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent>
<p>NGA collects and uses employee financial disclosure information to facilitate a variety of NGA"s mission-related duties, including activities related to personnel security, access controls, security clearances, and counterintelligence activities.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent>

<p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, these records may be specifically disclosed outside of the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. a(b)(3) as follows:  </p>

<p>The DoD Blanket Routine Uses set forth at the beginning of NGA"s compilation of systems of records notices may apply to this system.  The complete list of DoD Blanket Routine Uses can be found online at:  http://dpcld.defense.gov/Privacy/SORNsIndex/BlanketRoutineUses.aspx</p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent>

<p>Storage:  </p>
<p>Paper records and electronic storage media.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records may be retrieved by name, employee identification number or SSN.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Records in this system are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies, including all applicable NGA automated systems security and access policies.  Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is being stored.  Access to the computer system containing the records in this system is strictly limited to those individuals who have a need to know for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances or permissions.  Some of the technical controls include limited, role based access as well as profiles based access to limit users to only data that is needed for the performance of their official duties.  The system is located in a secure data center and operated by Federal personnel and contractors. </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Disposition pending (until the National Archives and Records Administration approve the retention and disposition of these records, treat as permanent).  </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Security and Installations Directorate, Personnel Security Division, Security Financial Disclosure Branch, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA  22150-7500.</p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150-7500.  </p>

<p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry." </p>

<p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth.  Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.</p>

<p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:</p>

<p>If executed outside the United States:</p>
<p>"I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct.  Executed on (date).  (Signature)".</p>

<p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct.  Executed on (date).  Signature)". </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150-7500.  </p>

<p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry." </p>

<p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth.  Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.</p>

<p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:</p>

<p>If executed outside the United States:</p>
<p>"I declare (or certify, verify, or state).under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct.  Executed on (date).  (Signature)".</p>

<p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct.  Executed on (date).  Signature)". </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Individuals contesting the accuracy of records contained in this system of records about themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 Geoint Drive, Springfield, VA 22150-7500.  </p>

<p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked "Privacy Act Inquiry." </p>

<p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth.  Also include an explanation of why you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.</p>

<p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:</p>

<p>If executed outside the United States:</p>
<p>"I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct.  Executed on (date).  (Signature)".</p>

<p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct.  Executed on (date).  Signature)". </p>

</xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent>
<p>Information originates from the individual completing the security disclosure form.  The system also contains records originating from the security specialist reviewing the financial submission, including any notations, memoranda, investigative notes and summaries or other observations made by the NGA specialist who reviews the file for trend analysis and/or anomalies.  </p>
</xhtmlContent></subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
        <p>
            Investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of subsection 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2).  However, if an individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit for which he would otherwise be entitled by Federal law or for which he would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of the information, the individual will be provided access only to the information they submitted however exemption applies to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a confidential source. The NGA specialist case notes will be kept separate from the individual"s data submission.  Those case notes will contain investigative case leads and summaries, sensitive processes, evidence gathered from external sources and potential referrals to law enforcement agencies. NOTE:  When claimed, this exemption allows limited protection of investigative reports maintained in a system of records used in personnel or administrative actions.
        </p>
        <p>Investigative material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for federal civilian employment, military service, federal contracts, or access to classified information may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), but only to the extent that such material would reveal the identity of a confidential source.</p>

        <p>An exemption rule for this system has been promulgated in accordance with requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1), (2), and (3), (c) and (e) published in 32 CFR Part 320. For additional information, contact the system manager.</p>
    </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
</section>


<section id="nga13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-013</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) Inspector General Investigative and Complaint
Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained at NGA headquarters in Washington, DC metro facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NGA employees, military personnel, contractors, members of the public who
make an inquiry or file a complaint or allegation involving NGA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Identifying information, such as name, address, telephone numbers, email addresses, employee
identification number, job title and band, supervisor's contact information, company name, witness information and statements,
military branch, rank, financial information, adverse information, technical reports, record of interviews, exhibits and photographs,
Social Security Number (SSN), and sworn testimonies.
</p><p>Investigative/complaint files, inquiries or investigative reports pertaining to complaints, allegations of fraud, waste, abuse,
mismanagement, malfeasance, or reprisal as procedures pertaining to NGA personnel, procedures, policies or programs. Files may
contain Reports of Investigation, sworn testimony, letters, memorandums and working papers regarding developed or obtained as a
result of investigation or complaint wherein someone has made allegations of violations involving fraud, waste, abuse, mismanagement,
reprisal, denial of due process pertaining to NGA personnel, programs, policies and/or procedures developed or obtained as a result
of the investigation or complaint.
</p><p>Letters/transcriptions of complaints, allegations and queries; letters of appointment; reports of reviews, inquiries and
investigations with supporting attachments, exhibits and photographs; record of interviews; witness statements; reports of legal
review of case files, congressional responses; memoranda; letters and reports of findings and actions taken; letters to complainants
and subjects of investigations; letters of rebuttal from subjects of investigations; finance; personnel; administration; adverse
information, and technical reports.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations, 5 U.S.C. App., Inspector General Act of 1978, 10
U.S.C. 1612 citing 5 U.S.C. 2301, 44 U.S.C. 3545(c)(1), E.O. 12333, United States Intelligence Activities, as amended; and E.O. 9397
(SSN), as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To analyze and evaluate the effectiveness and efficiency of NGA policies, programs,
procedures, activities, and operations for the purpose of detecting and preventing fraud, waste and abuse. Additionally, the system
is used to resolve complaints and inquiries, and to initiate proper corrective action if the allegation is proven to be true in fact
as well as to be used for corrective action.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy
Act of 1974, as amended, these records may be specifically disclosed outside of the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. a(b)(3)
as follows:
</p><p>The DoD Blanket Routine Uses that appear at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices may apply to this
system.
</p><p>NGA may share information contained in this system with U.S. intelligence agencies related to investigations, criminal activity or
evidence of waste, fraud and abuse.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records in this system are stored electronically.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name or SSN.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are stRecords in this system are safeguarded in accordance with applicable rules and policies,
including all applicable NGA automated systems security and access policies. Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk
of compromising the information that is being stored. Access to the computer system containing the records in this system is limited
to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate
clearances or permissions. Some of the technical controls include, limited, role based access as well as profiles based access to
limit users to only data that is needed for the performance of their official duties. The system is located in a secure data center
and operated by Federal personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Investigative records are cutoff and retired when 15 years old, then destroyed/deleted 10
years after cutoff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant Inspector General for Plans and Programs, Office of the Inspector General, National
Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether this system of records contains information about
themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy
Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked 'Privacy Act Inquiry.'
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits
statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization. A request for notification must meet the
requirements of 32 CFR 320.4.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system of
records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Act
Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked 'Privacy Act Inquiry.'
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits
statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization. A request for notification must meet the
requirements of 32 CFR 320.4.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals contesting the accuracy of records in this system of records contains information
about themselves should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Freedom of Information
Act/Privacy Act Office, 7500 GEOINT Drive, Springfield, VA 22150.
</p><p>The request envelope and letter should both be clearly marked 'Privacy Act Inquiry.'
</p><p>The written request must contain your full name, current address, and date and place of birth. Also include an explanation of why
you believe NGA would have information on you and specify when you believe the records would have been created.
</p><p>You must sign your request and your signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits
statements to be made under penalty of perjury, as a substitute for notarization. A request for notification must meet the
requirements of 32 CFR 320.4.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information originates from the individual and from sources contacted during personnel and
background investigations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of subsection 5 U.S.C. 552a(j)(2), may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2). However, if an individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit for which he would otherwise be entitled by Federal law or for which he would otherwise be eligible, as a result of the maintenance of the information, the individual will be provided access to the information exempt to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a confidential source. (<i>Note:</i> When claimed, this exemption allows limited protection of investigative reports maintained in a system of records used in personnel or administrative actions.)
</p><p>Investigative material compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for federal civilian employment, military service, federal contracts, or access to classified information may be exempt pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), but only to the extent that such material would reveal the identity of a confidential source.
</p><p>An exemption rule for this system has been promulgated in accordance with requirements of 5 U.S.C. 553(b)(1), (2), and (3), (c) and (e) published in 32 CFR part 320. For additional information contact the system manager.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0228-04" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0228-04</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Historical Photographic Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Affairs Office, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, GC (D-39), 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any individual or VIP visitor photographed at NGA functions or activities, i.e., award ceremonies, sporting events, retirement ceremonies, etc., that is of historical interest to NGA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Photographs and negatives taken at any NGA function or activity, i.e., award ceremonies, sporting events, retirement ceremonies, etc., that is of historical interest to NGA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To furnish copies of photographs to organizations that requested photographs to be taken, to obtain the background information regarding events, ceremonies, awards, sports, retirements at NGA for input to newspapers and magazine articles to recognize accomplishments and publications.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>To News Media for Public Relations and Community Affairs Matters and to organizers of testimonials, banquets and parties for the purpose of obtaining background information regarding events, ceremonies, awards, sports, and retirements at NGA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Prints and negatives filed in cabinets, and on electronic storage devices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Retrieved by name and/or event.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secured area/locked file cabinets with access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are Permanent. Records will be retired to Washington National Records Center on discontinuance of the installation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA Historian, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mail Stop D-54, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA's rules for accessing records, and for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in NIMA Instruction 5500.7R1; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Photographs taken at awards ceremonies; sporting events; retirement parties.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0228-10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0228-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Installation Historical Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Affairs Office - DMA Hydrographic/Topographic Center. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DMA's compilation of systems of records notices.
</p><p>Decentralized Segments - Records Holding Area, Information Management Support Division. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DMA's compilation of systems of records notices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who have given speeches or written an article for a magazine or newspaper.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Copies of speeches and articles for magazine or newspapers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To furnish background information on the history of installations to obtain up-to-date information on all speeches, articles for magazines and newspapers published or given by an individual of DMA; to recognize accomplishments and publications.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>To News for Public Relations and Community Affairs Matters and to organizers of testimonials and banquets for the purpose of obtaining background information on the history of installations, up-to-date information on all speeches, articles for magazines and newspapers published or given by an individual of DMA, and recognizing accomplishments and publications.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Files retrieved alphabetically by name of individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secured area/locked file cabinets with access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>This is a permanent record. Retired from Records Holding Area.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Affairs Office, ST A-11, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to Public Affairs Office, ST A-11, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to Public Affairs Office, ST A-11, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, Social Security Number.
</p><p>For personal visits the individual should be able to provide some acceptable identification, such as, drivers license, employing office's identification card, and give some verbal information that could be verified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>DMA's rules for accessing records and contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DMA Instruction 5400.11; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee copies of speeches; newspapers; magazines, photographs and related publications.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="b0303-05" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0303-05</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Leave Record Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the Comptroller, Finance and Accounting Division. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DMA's compilation of systems of records notices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All civilian employees of DMA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Record of official annual accumulation and use of employee's leave.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>21 U.S.C. 1175
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record official annual accumulation and use of employee's leave.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The 'Blanket Routine Uses' set forth at the beginning of DMA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Magnetic tapes and printouts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are by payroll block number, organization, and name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secured area/locked file cabinets with access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Applications for leave - Destroy on receipt of audit completion letter.
</p><p>Remaining Files: Destroy after 6 years, 3 months old, or 90 days after receipt of audit completion letter.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Finance and Accounting Division, ST L-5, Defense Mapping Agency, 3200 South Second Street, St. Louis, IL 63118-3399.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to Finance and Accounting Division, ST L-5, Defense Mapping Agency, 3200 South Second Street, St. Louis, IL 63118-3399.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to Finance and Accounting Division, ST L-5, Defense Mapping Agency, 3200 South Second Street, St. Louis, IL 63118-3399.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, and Social Security Number. Visits are limited to normal working hours.
</p><p>For personal visits, the individual should be able to provide some acceptable identification, such as, drivers license, employing office's identification card, and give some verbal information that could be verified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>DMA's rules for accessing records and contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DMA Instruction 5400.11; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Time and attendance cards initialed by employee. Accumulation and use of leave.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    
            <section id="b0402-05" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0402-05</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Legal Claims File.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Primary System--Office of the General Counsel, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mail Stop L-32, 3200 S. Second Street, St. Louis, MO 63118-3399.
</p><p>Decentralized Segments--Staff Judge Advocate, ATTN: ATZT-JA-CO, 125 East 8th Street, Fort Leonard Wood, MO 65473-8942.
</p><p>Military District of Washington, ATTN: PAWJA-LA, 204 Lee Avenue, Fort Myer, VA 22211-1199.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA personnel and other individuals having a claim against the Government for loss, damage, or destruction of personal property or for NGA personnel who are claiming reimbursement of their real estate expenses for either the sale or purchase of their residence associated with a permanent change of station (PCS). Any individual filing a tort claim against NGA for damages, loss or destruction of property, personal injury or death resulting from negligence or wrongful act, or omission of acts by NGA personnel and individuals against whom the Agency has legal claim.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>File contains individual's claims, related correspondence and processing papers, investigative reports, recommendations and opinions of the General Counsel's Office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 28 U.S.C. 2671-2680, Federal Torts Claims Act and II JTR, Chapter 14 (Joint Travel Regulations).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To document claims against the U.S. Government, involving NGA personnel or property, for damage, loss, or destruction of personal property. To document claims of NGA employees concerning real estate reimbursement claims adjudicated by the Office of the General Counsel.
</p><p>Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purposes of such uses:
</p><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD "Blanket Routine Uses"  set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper record in file folders and electronic records are maintained on computer server accessible only by authorized user name and password.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed alphabetically by last name of employee or by case name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secured/locked file cabinets with access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access. Automated files are protected by user name and password and are stored in a database that requires additional access permissions
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Disapproved claims and claims involving a minor are destroyed 10 years after final action on the case. Approved claims are destroyed 5 years after final action on the case. PCS records that are reviewed by the Office of General Counsel are retained for 5 years and disposed of after 5 years by shredding. No records are transferred to the records center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>General Counsel, ST L-32, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, 3200 S. Second Street, St. Louis, MO 63118-3399.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail Stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail Stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, and Social Security Number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA's rules for accessing records, and for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in NIMA Instruction 5500.7R1; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Related forms, correspondence, investigative reports and information gathered in anticipation of litigation, and opinions of Counsel and the NGA individual's claim form and accompanying documents and records from the NGA Travel Office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0408-11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0408-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Biography Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Affairs Offices-Defense Mapping Agency Headquarters, DMA Hydrographic/Topographic Center, DMA Aerospace Center, Defense Mapping School, and DMA Combat Support Center. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DMA's compilation of systems of records notices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All top management and other key personnel of DMA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographies; photographs; newspaper clippings and related documents pertaining to leading military and civilian personalities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>44 U.S.C. 3101, Records Management by Federal Agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To document biographies, photographs, newspaper clippings, and related materials pertaining to leading DMA military and civilian personalities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The 'Blanket Routine Uses' set forth at the beginning of DMA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper record in file folders and/or Kardex book.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed alphabetically by last name of employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secured area/locked file cabinets with access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Destroy two years after transfer, separation or death of the individual concerned.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Public Affairs Office, ST A-11, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Public Affairs Office, ST A-11, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Public Affairs Office, ST A-11, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, and the case control number that appears with the office symbol, on all correspondence received from this office.
</p><p>For personal visits, the individual should be able to provide some acceptable identification, such as, drivers license, employing office's identification card, and give some verbal information that could be verified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>DMA's rules for accessing records and contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DMA Instruction 5400.11; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Biographical data furnished by individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0502-01" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0502-01</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) Public Key Enabled NIPRnet.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Primary location: National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) Arnold Facility, 3838 Vogel Road, Arnold, MO 63010-6238.
</p><p><i>Secondary location:
</i> National Gospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) Bethesda Facility, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>U.S. Government civilian employees, military personnel, and contractors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, phone number, e-mail address, county of origin, citizen status, and contract name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 10 U.S.C. 455, Maps, charts, and geodetic data: Public availability; exceptions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of the system is to manage user access to web applications and other resources.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD "Blanket Routine Uses"  set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained on magnetic disks.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retrieved by an algorithm which uses last name, first name, e-mail address and duty location as possible inputs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Record are maintained in controlled areas accessible only to authorized personnel. Access to personal information is further restricted by the use of passwords. Physical entry is restricted by the use of locks, guards, and administrative procedures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Data is destroyed when superseded or when no longer needed or operational purposes, whichever is later.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Security and Installation Operations, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, Maryland 20816-5003.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether this system of records contains information about themselves should adderss written inquries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Customer Help Desk/L-89, 3833 Vogel Road, Arnold, MO 63010.
</p><p>The request should contain the full name, address, and telephone number.
</p><p>Individuals can also access the "My Account"  link <i>(https://www.extranet.nga.mil/servlet/RegistrtionForm</i>) on the NGA PKE NIPRNet.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to records about themselves contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Customer Help Desk/L-89, 3838 Vogel road, Ranold, MO 63010.
</p><p>The request should contain the full name, address, and telephone number.
</p><p>Individuals can also access the "My Account"  link (<i>https://www.extranet.nga.mil/servlet/RegistrationForm</i>) on the NGA PKE NIPRNet.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>The NGA rules for accessing records, for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are contained in NGA Instruction 5500.7R1; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals and other Department of Defense Records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0502-03" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0502-03</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Master Billet/Access Records (March 19, 2002, 67 FR 12532).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: This system was originally established to identify and verify personnel authorized access to SCI in order to control access to
secure areas for use of classified information, for periodic re-indoctrination (re-briefing) of employees for SCI access, for
periodic security education and training, and for control and reissue of identification badges. Because the stand-alone system no
longer exists, records in that system are now covered under NGA-003, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise
Workforce System (May 24, 2013, 78 FR 31526); therefore, B0502-03, Master Billet/Access Records can be deleted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="b0502-15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0502-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Security Compromise Case Files (March 19, 2002, 67 FR 12532).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: This system was originally established to protect records relating to investigations conducted into alleged and/or actual security
violations by Security Office personnel and appointed investigating officials. Because the stand-alone system no longer exists,
records in that system are now covered under NGA-003, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise Workforce System (May
24, 2013, 78 FR 31526); therefore, B0502-15, Security Compromise Case Files can be deleted.
</p><p>This system was originally established to record official annual accumulation and use of employees' leave. Because the stand-alone
system no longer exists, the records are now covered under NGA-003, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise
Workforce System (May 24, 2013, 78 FR 31526); therefore, B0303-5, Leave Record Files can be deleted.
</p><p>B0303-5, Leave Record Files (February 22, 1993, 58 FR 10189)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0503-02" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0503-02</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Security Identification Accountability Files (March 19, 2002, 67 FR 12532).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: This system was originally established to maintain accountability for various identification cards/badges issues and identify to
whom issued. Because the stand-alone system no longer exists, records in that system are now covered under NGA-003, National
Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise Workforce System (May 24, 2013, 78 FR 31526); therefore, B0503-02, Security
Identification Accountability Files can be deleted.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="b0503-03" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0503-03</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Firearms Authorization Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Chief, Security Branch, Mission Support, ATTN: MSRS P-12, 12310 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, VA 20191-3449;
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Chief, Security Branch, Mission Support, ATTN: MSBS D-60, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003;
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Chief, Security Branch, Mission Support, ATTN: MSNS N-55, Building 213, 1200 First Street, SE., Washington, DC 20505-0001; and
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Chief, Security Branch, Mission Support, ATTN: MSWS L-59, 3200 S. Second Street, St. Louis, MO 63118-3399.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Security guards that have been issued firearms and ammunition.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Documents authorizing NGA civilian guards to carry firearms. Included are firearms authorization cards and related papers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental regulations; DoD Directive 5210.56, Use of deadly force and the carrying of firearms by DoD personnel engaged in law enforcement and security duties; NIMA Policy Directive 5200R2, Operational Security; NIMA Instruction 5210.2R2, Use of force.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain required firearms annual qualifications records, weapons serial numbers and firearms authorization cards issued to each assigned Security Police.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD 'Blanket Routine Uses' set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Retrieved by last name of employee.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Buildings or facilities employ security guards. Records are maintained in areas accessible only to authorized personnel that are properly screened, cleared, and trained.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Destroy upon expiration of authorization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Security Branch, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, ATTN: MSRS P-12, 12310 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, VA 20191-3449;
</p><p>Chief, Security Branch, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, ATTN: MSBS D-60, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003;
</p><p>Chief, Security Branch, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, ATTN: MSNS N-55, Building 213, 1200 First Street, SE., Washington, DC 20505-0001; and Chief, Security Branch, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, ATTN: MSWS L-59, 3200 S. Second Street, St. Louis, MO 63118-3399.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA's rules for accessing records, and for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in NIMA Instruction 5500.7R1; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Subject individual to whom the firearm is issued, home address and telephone number, weapon serial number, and authorization card issued.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0503-05" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0503-05</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Vehicle Registration and Driver Record File.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Security Specialist, Mission Support, MSRS P-12, 12310 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, VA 20191-3449;
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Security Specialist, Mission Support, MSBS D-60, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003;
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Security Specialist Mission Support, MSNS N-55, Building 213, 1200 First Street, SE, Washington, DC 20505-0001; and
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, ATTN: Security Specialist, Mission Support, MSWS L-59, 3200 S. Second Street, St. Louis, MO 63118-3399.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any person privileged to operate a motor vehicle on a military installation or NGA leased properties and who has been involved in a chargeable traffic accident or whose commission of a moving traffic violation has been verified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>File contains a record of issuance of decal and of all traffic offenses/incidents and actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations; 50 U.S.C. 797, Security Regulations and Orders; Penalty for Violation; and NIMA Instruction 4540.1R3, Parking and Vehicular Traffic.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To record traffic offenses, incidents and actions taken, and to track parking permits issued to agency personnel and contractors.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD 'Blanket Routine Uses' set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records and on electronic storage media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Retrieved by last name of individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to electronic file or locked filing cabinet is limited to authorized individuals or with valid user name and password.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Destroy one year after revocation or expiration.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Security Specialist, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, MSRS P-12, 12310 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, VA 20191-3449;
</p><p>Security Specialist, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, MSBS D-60, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003;
</p><p>Security Specialist, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, MSNS N-55, Building 213, 1200 First Street, SE., Washington, DC 20505-0001; and
</p><p>Security Specialist, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Mission Support, MSWS L-59, 3200 S. Second Street, St. Louis, MO 63118-3399.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA's rules for accessing records, and for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in NIMA Instruction 5500.7R1; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Report of traffic violation from Security police.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0503-09" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0503-09</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Key Accountability Files (67 FR 12532, March 19, 2002).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: This system was originally established to maintain documentation on periodic inspections, key accountability, reference checks and
daily use records and investigations into lost or destruction of secure areas. The system no longer exists, the records have met their
retention, and therefore B0503-09, Key Accountability Files can be deleted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0504-01-2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0504-01-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security and Suitability Files (December 2, 1994, 59 FR 61885).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: This system was originally established to maintain up-to-date personnel security and suitability information for civilians,
military and applicant personnel who require access to classified information, to determine and ensure continued eligibility for
access to classified information. Because the overall purpose of the system has changed, records in that system are now covered under
NGA-003, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise Workforce System (May 24, 2013, 78 FR 31526); therefore,
B0504-01-2, Personnel Security and Suitability Files can be deleted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

<section id="b0614-01" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0614-01</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Military Personnel Information Files (March 19, 2002, 67 FR 12532).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: This system was originally established to determine the acceptability of an individual nominated by the parent service for an
agency position, to be used in the preparation of efficiency/fitness/effectiveness reports, award recommendations, and other
personnel actions. Because the stand-alone system no longer exists, records in that system are now covered under NGA-003,
National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise Workforce System (May 24, 2013, 78 FR 31526); therefore, B0614-01, Military
Personnel Information Files can be deleted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b0901-07" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B0901-07</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Primary location: DMA Fairfax.
</p><p>Decentralized locations: DMA Bethesda, DMA Reston, and DMA St. Louis. Records Holding Area, Administrative Operations Division. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DMA's compilation of systems of records notices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All civilian employees who have contacted program counselor requesting assistance.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>File contains counseling interview notes, medical documents, therapy/treatment referral notes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>21 U.S.C 1175; 5 U.S.C. 7301; 42 U.S.C. 290dd-3 and 290ee-3; Pub. L. 100-71; E.O. 12564, Drug-Free Federal Workplace; and E.O. 9397.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain documents relating to alcohol and narcotic control, treatment, assistance, and advice provided to DMA personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>In order to comply with provisions of 5 U.S.C. 7301 and 42 U.S.C. 290dd-3 and 290ee-3, the Defense Mapping Agency 'Blanket Routine Uses' do not apply to this system of records.
</p><p>Records in this system may not be disclosed without the prior written consent of such patient, unless the disclosure would be:
</p><p>To medical personnel to the extent necessary to meet a bona fide medical emergency;
</p><p>To qualified personnel for the purpose of conducting scientific research, management audits, financial audits, or program evaluation, but such personnel may not identify, directly or indirectly, any individual patient in any report of such research, audit, or evaluation, or otherwise disclose patient identities in any manner; and
</p><p>If authorized by an appropriate order of a court of competent jurisdiction granted after application showing good cause therefor.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Filed chronologically by number; names deleted, but are known by counselor.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secured area/locked file cabinets with access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Destroy when 3 years old.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Human Resources, Work Force Management Division, ST A-8, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137..
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to Human Resources Work Force Management Division, ST B-5, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to Human Resources Work Force Management Division, ST B-5, Defense Mapping Agency, 8613 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA 22031-2137.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, and Social Security Number. Visits are limited to normal working hours. For personal visits the individual should be able to provide some acceptable identification, such as, drivers license, employing office's identification card, and give some verbal information that could be verified.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>DMA's rules for accessing records and contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DMA Instruction 5400.11; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee interviews and medical reports. Employee or relatives.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b1202-17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B1202-17</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Contracting Officer Designation Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA Contracting Officers are located at NGA Headquarters in Bethesda, MD; Reston, VA; Washington Navy Yard, Washington, DC; and NGA St. Louis, MO. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to NGA's compilation of systems of records notices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee designated Contracting Officer and Contracting Officer Representative.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Documents reflecting the designation and rescission of Contracting Officers and Contracting Officers representative which includes the specific procurement authorities delegated.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301, Departmental Regulations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>To maintain documents showing individual designated as Contracting Officers; to include data reflecting limitations, restrictions on authority, and background information for use in other contracts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD "Blanket Routine Uses"  set forth at the beginning of NGA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Paper records in file folders and on electronic medium.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is retrieved by name of contracting officer.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a secured area with access limited to authorized personnel whose duties require access. The database can only be accessed via a correct user ID and password.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are temporary. NGA destroys these records upon the transfer, reassignment or termination of the contracting officer.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Procurement Technician, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, PCP (D-15), 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system of records should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Office of General Counsel, 4600 Sangamore Road, Mail stop D-10, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA's rules for accessing records, and for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in NIMA Instruction 5500.7R1; 32 CFR part 320; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Certificate of Appointment and background information on education, training, experience, Standard Form 1402, and specific information on procurement authorities delegated.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b1211-03" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B1211-03</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Passport and Visa Files (January 18, 2002, 67 FR 2639).
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Deletion: This system was originally established to issue passports and visas to agency personnel and their dependents for official
government travel and to obtain necessary visas from appropriate embassies. Because the stand-alone system no longer exists, records
in that system are now covered under NGA-003, National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Enterprise Workforce System (May 24,
2013, 78 FR 31526); therefore, B1211-03, Passport and Visa Files can be deleted.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="b1211-04" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>B1211-04</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">TravelNet.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), 12310 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, VA 20191-3449.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA employees and contactors who maintain travel activities or interests outside the Continental United States (OCONUS) or maintain a relationship with a foreign contact.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name, address, date of birth, Social Security Number (SSN), business phone number and e-mail address, personal phone number and e-mail address, medical clearance status, military status, employment status, passport information, foreign activities and interests, and family personal contact information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>National Security Act of 1947, Section 102, Director of Intelligence; Executive Order 12333, United States Intelligence Activities; DoD 4500.54G, DoD Foreign Clearance Guide; DoD 5105.21-M-1, DoD Sensitive Compartmental Information Administrative Security Manual; DoD Instruction 5240.6, Counterintelligence Awareness and Briefing Program; DoD 2000.16, DoD Antiterrorism Standards; Director of Central Intelligence Directive (DCID) 1/20, Security Policy Concerning Travel and Assignment of Personnel with Access to Sensitive Compartmented Information; DCID 1/19P, Security Policy for Sensitive Compartmented Information and Security Policy Manual; and E.O. 9397 (SSN), as amended.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>TravelNet manages employee and contractor travel activities, related to personal and business interests outside the Continental United States (OCONUS), and relationships with foreign contacts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act of 1974, these records contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:
</p><p>The DoD 'Blanket Routine Uses' set forth at the beginning of the Army's compilation of systems of records notices also apply to this system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained on electronic storage media and paper.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>By Social Security Number (SSN) and name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a controlled facility. Physical access is restricted by the use of locks, guards, and is accessible only to authorized personnel. Access to records is limited to individuals responsible for servicing the record in performance of their official duties and who are properly screened and cleared for need-to-know. Access to computerized data is restricted by password protection, firewalls, and encryption.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>TravelNet records are destroyed or deleted six years after the user account is terminated or if the password is altered when no longer needed for investigative, or for security purposes, whichever is later. Paper records are destroyed by shredding.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), ATTN: Branch Chief, Mission Support, MSRS P-12, 12310 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, VA 20191-3449.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Office of the General Counsel, Mail Stop D-10, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests should contain the full name of the individual, current address, and telephone number. While the requestor's Social Security Number (SSN) is not required, providing it will expedite the authentication of the requestor's identity and clearance levels.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA), Office of the General Counsel, Mail Stop D-10, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>Written requests should contain the full name of the individual, current address, and telephone number. While the requestor's Social Security Number (SSN) is not required, providing it will expedite the authentication of the requestor's identity and clearance levels.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>NGA's rules for accessing records, and for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations, are published in NGA Instruction 5500.7R10; 32 CFR part 320.6; or may be obtained from the system manager.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>From the individual.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    <section id="t3720b" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>T7320b</systemNumber>

        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Centralized Disbursing System, T7320b.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Defense Finance and Accounting Service, Disbursing Operations, 8899 East 56th Street, Indianapolis, IN  46249-3300.  DISA DECC Ogden, Ogden, UT.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>System Manager, 1240 East 9th Street, Cleveland, OH  44199.  Telephone:  216-204-2447.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Department of Defense Financial Management Regulation (DoDFMR) 7000.14-R, Vol.4:  31 U.S.C. Sections 3511 and 3513; and E.O. 9397 (SSN) as amended.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The CDS performs general activities common for disbursing, collecting, payment processing, electronic funds transfer, check issue, printing for legal retention of records and accountability reporting processes.  The CDS contains a file control module, which automates manual interfaces with a number of entitlement systems, electronically uploads or rejects data from a single source on a daily basis, and automates the control of daily incoming files.  The file control module guarantees data upload into the CDS, ensuring complete and valid voucher data, and returns advice of status to users.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Active Duty and Retired Military Personnel, Air Force National Guard Personnel, DoD Civilian Employees and Federal Contractors.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individual name, Social Security Numbers (SSN), Mailing/Home Address and Financial Information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Automated Disbursing System, Departmental Cash Management System, Department of Defense Debt Management System, Defense Enterprise Accounting and Management System, Junior Reserve Officers Training Corps Payroll Maintenance and Certification Division, General Accounting and Finance System, Defense Travel System, General Accounting and Finance System, DFAS Transactional Interface Module, Integrated Accounts Payable System, Military Sealift Command Financial Management System, Reserve Travel System, Standard Material Accounting System, Transportation Financial Management System, Defense Corporate Database / Defense Corporate Warehouse.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                <p>a.  To contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, students, and others performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, or other assignment for the federal government when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this System of Records.</p>
                <p>b.  To the appropriate Federal, State, local, territorial, tribal, foreign, or international law enforcement authority or other appropriate entity where a record, either alone or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature.</p>
                <p>c.  To any component of the Department of Justice for the purpose of representing the DoD, or its components, officers, employees, or members in pending or potential litigation to which the record is pertinent.</p>
                <p>d.  In an appropriate proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body or official, when the DoD or other Agency representing the DoD determines that the records are relevant and necessary to the proceeding; or in an appropriate proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>e.  To the National Archives and Records Administration for the purpose of records management inspections conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. §§ 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>f.  To a member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member’s behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                <p>g.  To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the DoD suspects or confirms the security or confidentiality of the information in the System of Records; (2) the DoD determined as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the DoD (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the DoD’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>h.  To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the DoD determines that information from this System of Records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in paper and electronic storage media, in accordance with the safeguards mentioned below.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records are retrieved primarily by Individual Name, SSN, Mailing/Home Address, and Financial Information. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>System records will be destroyed when 10 years old.  After the retention period, records will be destroyed by degaussing, burning, or shredding.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in secure, limited access, and monitored areas.  The database is monitored, its access is password protected, and it is Common Access Card (CAC) enabled.  Firewalls, Virtual Private Network (VPN) and role based access controls are used.  Physical entry by unauthorized persons is restricted through the use of cipher locks, key cards, security guards, closed circuit tv, and identification badges.  Archived data is stored on compact discs, or magnetic tapes, which are kept in a locked and controlled access area.  Access to personal information is limited to those individuals who require a need to know to perform their official assigned duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>If executed outside the United States:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).  (Signature)."</p>
                <p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).  (Signature)."</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The DoD rules for accessing records, contesting contents, and appealing initial agency determinations are contained in 32 CFR Part 310, or may be obtained from the system manager.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this System of Records should address requests to the Freedom of Information/Privacy Act Program Manager, Defense Finance and Accounting Service, Corporate Communications Office, 8899 East 56th Street, Indianapolis, IN  46249-0150.  Signed, written requests should contain the individual’s full name, telephone number, street address, email address, and name and number of this SORN.  In addition, the requester must provide either a notarized statement or an unsworn declaration made in accordance with 28 U.S.C. 1746, in the following format:</p>
                <p>If executed outside the United States:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).  (Signature)."</p>
                <p>If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths:  "I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).  (Signature)."</p>

            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> N/A.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

<appendix id="appa" toc="yes">
<title> National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency Official Mailing Addresses </title>
<xhtmlContent>

<p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, 4600 Sangamore Road, Bethesda, MD 20816-5003.
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, 3200 South Second Street, St. Louis, MO 63118-3399.
</p><p>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, 1210 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, VA 22091-3414.
</p><p>NGA College, 5825 21st Street, Suite 106, Ft. Belvoir, VA 22060-5921.
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>

    

</agency>
</pai>
