<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>National Counterintelligence Center</name>
<abbrev>
NACIC</abbrev>
    
    

<routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Statement of General Routine Uses
</b></p><p>The following routine uses apply to, and are incorporated by reference into each system of records maintained by NACIC. It should be noted that, before the individual record system notices begin, the blanket routine uses of the records are published below only once in the interest of simplicity, economy and to avoid redundancy.
</p><p>1. Routine Use-Law Enforcement: In the event that a system of records maintained by NACIC to carry out its functions indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records in the system of records maybe referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency whether Federal, state, local or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation or order issued pursuant thereto.
</p><p>2. Routine Use-Disclosure When Requesting Information: A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, state, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a component decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contact, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit.
</p><p>3. Routine Use-Disclosure of Requested Information: A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency?s decision on the matter.
</p><p>4. Routine Use-Congressional: Inquiries from a system of records maintained by this component maybe made to a Congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the Congressional office made at the request of that individual.
</p><p>5. Routine Use-Disclosures Required by International Agreements: A record from  a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed to foreign law enforcement, security, investigatory, or administrative authorities in order to comply with requirements imposed by, or to claim rights conferred in, international agreements and arrangements including those regulating the stationing and status in foreign countries of Department of Defense military and civilian personnel.
</p><p>6. Routine Use-disclosure to the Department of Justice for Litigation: A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as  routine use to any component of the Department of Justice for the purpose of representing any officer, employee or member of this component in pending or potential litigation to which the record is pertinent.
</p><p>7. Routine Use-Disclosure of Information to the Information Security Oversight Office (ISOO): A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to the Information Security Oversight Office (ISOO) or any other executive branch entity authorized to conduct inspections or develop security classification policy for the purpose of records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>8. Routine Use-Disclosure of Information to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA): A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for the purpose of records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.
</p><p>9. Routine Use-Disclosure to the Merit Systems Protection Board: A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use to the Merit Systems Protection Board, including the Office of the Special Counsel for the purpose of litigation, including administrative proceedings, appeals special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of OPM or component rules and regulations, investigation of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices; including administrative proceedings involving any individual subject of investigation, and such other functions, promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, or as may be authorized by law.
</p><p>10. Routine Use-Counterintelligence Purposes: A record from a system of records maintained by this component may be disclosed as a routine use outside the U.S. Government for the purpose of counterintelligence activities authorized by U.S. Law or Executive Order or for the purpose of enforcing laws which protect the national security of the United States.
</p></xhtmlContent></routineUses>

<section id="nacic1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">National Counterintelligence Center System of Records (NACIC-1).
</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>The classification of individual records in the system range from UNCLASSIFIED to TOP SECRET Codeword.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Counterintelligence Center, 3W01 NHB, Washington, DC 20505
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Individuals who are of foreign intelligence or foreign counterintelligence interest and relate in any manner to foreign intelligence threats to U.S. national and economic security;
</p><p>2. Applicants for, and current and former personnel of NACIC who are federal employees;
</p><p>3. Individuals associated with NACIC administrative operations or services including independent contractors, industrial contractor employees, or individuals otherwise associated with such operations and services;
</p><p>4. And, any other individuals authorized access to NACIC information and facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. Counterintelligence Damage Assessments and Incident Files: Maintained by the NACIC Threat Assessment Office (TAO); records include copies of the finished assessments of the damage to U.S. intelligence sources and methods resulting from significant and particular espionage cases as well as summaries of significant counterintelligence incidents including the circumstances and characteristics of the target, the circumstances of the event, and the particular threat presented;
</p><p>2. Compromised Names Database: Maintained by the NACIC Threat Assessment Office (TAO); the database is utilized to notify U.S. intelligence community personnel whose names were potentially compromised as a result of espionage or other foreign intelligence collection activity; the database contains the names of persons potentially compromised, date of the memo sent to the person or their employer informing them, and documentary reference(s) to the compromised information;
</p><p>3. Computer and Physical Security Files: Maintained by the NACIC Executive Secretariat Office (ESO); records include the names, passwords, accesses, and special accesses to both physical locations and computer systems, relevant audit trails for such accesses, and particular clearances and certifications of clearances;
</p><p>4. Publication, Training and Seminar Files: Maintained by NACIC?s Program Integration Office (PIO) Community Training Branch; records include letters of acceptance, enrollment forms, thank you letters, lists of attendees, lists of speakers, notes, case studies, syllabi, training packets, magazine or newspaper articles, and other records used either for course development purposes or to facilitate the presentation of seminars;
</p><p>5. Personnel Files:
</p><p>a. Specific types of personnel records are maintained by the NACIC Front Office (FO); these  records are maintained in individual official personnel folders and include, inter alia, papers documenting personnel actions, performance appraisals, correspondence, travel documents, contracts, justifications, memorandums, and administrative material;
</p><p>b. A second type of personnel records is maintained by the NACIC Executive Secretariat Office (ESO); these records are Memorandums of Agreement between the detailee?s parent organization and NACIC;
</p><p>c. The third type of personnel records is maintained by the NACIC Program Integration Office/Community Training Branch (PIO/CTB); these records include the training documents;
</p><p>6. Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)/Privacy Act (PA) Requests and Legal Files: Files created in response to public requests for information and/or amendment of records under the FOIA/PA, consisting of the original request, a copy of the reply thereto, and all related supporting files which may include the official file copy of requested record or copy thereof; also, all similar records created in response to administrative appeals and litigations predicated on such initial requests;
</p><p>7. Special Search Files: Files created in response to official United States or foreign government requests for information which may include requests from executive, congressional, judicial, or diplomatic sectors consisting of the original tasking or request, a copy of the reply thereto, and all related supporting files which may include the official file copy of the requested record or copy thereof.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Section 506(a) of the Federal Records Act of 1950, codified at 44 U.S.C. 3101, and Title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, Chapter XII, which require Federal agencies to insure that adequate and proper records are made and preserved to document the organization, functions, polices,  decisions, procedures and transactions and to protect the legal and financial rights of the Federal Government.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>NACIC was established by Presidential directive for the purpose of coordinating national level counterintelligence activities of the United States. The purposes for the maintenance of these records include: Coordinating national strategic CI planning efforts, providing strategic guidance and assessing the effectiveness of CI operations, facilitating the development of and implementing training for the CI community, producing national-level foreign intelligence threat  assessments, and coordinating assessments of damage to U.S. interests resulting from espionage cases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>See Statement of General Routine Uses.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:
</p><p>Files are maintained in computerized form and hard copy form; computerized form may be stored in memory, on disk storage, on computer tape, and/or on a computer printed listing.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Names and related information are retrievable by automated or hand search based on extant indices and automated capabilities utilized in the normal course of business. Under applicable law and regulations, NACIC may not permit any organization, public or private, outside the NACIC to have direct access to NACIC files; accordingly, all searchers of NACIC databases and paper files will be performed on site, within NACIC space, by NACIC personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records and databases are maintained in a restricted area within NACIC and are accessed only by NACIC personnel. All employees are checked to ensure that they hold currently valid security clearances, are cautioned about divulging classified or other privileged information contained in NACIC files, and are advised that failure to abide by these provisions may constitute a violation of federal criminal law and/or give rise to civil liability. Employees who resign or retire are also cautioned about divulging information acquired in their jobs. Registered mail is used to transmit routine hard copy records while highly classified records are hand carried by individuals holding appropriate security clearances. Highly classified or sensitive privacy information, which is electronically transmitted between NACIC and other offices, is transmitted in encrypted form to prevent interception.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records evaluated as historical and permanent will be transferred to the National Archives after established retention periods and administrative needs of the NACIC have elapsed.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Information and privacy Coordinator, Executive Secretariat Office, National Counterintelligence Center, 3W01 NHB, Washington, DC 20505.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See record access procedures, infra.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>A request for access to a record from the system shall be made in writing with the envelope and the letter clearly marked "Privacy Act Request." Your request should include your full name, complete address, date of birth, place of birth, notarized signature (or declaration under penalty of perjury), and other identifying data you may wish to furnish to assist in making a proper search of NACIC records. A request for access to records must describe the records sought in sufficient detail to enable NACIC personnel to locate the system of records containing the record with a reasonable amount of effort. Whenever possible, a request for access should describe the nature of the record sought, and the data of the record or the period in which the record was compiled. The requester must also provide a return address for transmitting the information. Requests for access must be addressed to the System Manager as noted above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals desiring to contest or amend information maintained in the system should also direct their request to the System Manager as noted above. Such requests should delineate the information believed to be incorrect and should include the information requested to be substituted or added to the record.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Record source categories include subject individuals pursuant to notice, official records and information disseminated to NACIC by other federal government entities, and official records and information provided to NACIC by other entities including foreign, state and local governments as well as individuals and business entities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>Notice is hereby given that NACIC intends to exempt from certain provisions of the Privacy Act the following information pursuant to the following specified authority:
</p><p>(a) Records or portions of records in the physical possession of NACIC which were originated by other federal agencies or which contain information originated by such agencies shall be deemed to be in the joint legal custody of and mutually maintained by both agencies. Accordingly, NACIC shall apply any applicable exemptive provisions when so informed by those agencies;
</p><p>(b) Records or portions of records in the physical custody of NACIC which would reveal intelligence sources and methods in contravention of the National Security Act of 1947 are, pursuant to the exemptions previously authorized by the Director of Central Intelligence under the authority of section (j)(1), exempt from disclosure of accounting (section (c)(3)), disclosure (section (d)), notification of collection authority (section (e)(3) (A-D)), and notification of existence of records (sections (e)(4)(G) and (f)(1)); in such instances where confirmation of the existence of a record may itself jeopardize intelligence sources and methods, the Coordinator must neither confirm nor deny the existence of the record and shall advise the requester that there is no record which is available pursuant to the Privacy Act;
</p><p>(c) Records or portions of records in the physical custody of NACIC which are currently and properly classified pursuant to Executive Order 12958 (or predecessor or subsequent Order) are, under the authority of section (k)(1), exempt from disclosure of accounting (section (c)(3)), disclosure (section (d)), and notification of existence of records (sections (e)(4)(G) and (f)(1));
</p><p>(d) Records or portions of records in the physical custody of NACIC which are investigatory in nature and compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of section (j)(2) of the Act, are, under the authority of section (k)(2), exempt from disclosure (section (d)); provided however, that if an individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit to which he/she is otherwise eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, then such material shall be provided to that individual except to the extent that the disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished the information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality;
</p><p>(e) Records or portions of records in the physical custody of NACIC which are maintained in connection with providing protective services to the President of the United States or other individuals pursuant to 18 U.S.C. section 3056 are, under the authority of section (k)(3), exempt from disclosure (section (d));
</p><p>(f) Records or portions of records in the physical custody of NACIC which are required by statute to be maintained and used solely as statistical records are, under the authority of section (k)(4), exempt from disclosure (section (d));
</p><p>(g) Records or portions of records in the physical custody of NACIC which are investigatory in nature and compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for federal civilian employment, military service, federal contracts, or access to classified information are, under the authority of section (k)(5), exempt from disclosure (section (d)); provided that and only to the extent that disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality;
</p><p>(h) And, records or portions of records in the physical custody of NACIC which are testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the federal service are, under the authority of section (k)(6), exempt from disclosure (section (d)); provided that and only to the extent that disclosure would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    
    
<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="32">
<heading> National Defense </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="VIII">
<heading> National Counterintelligence Center </heading>
<regulationsPart number="1801">
<heading> PUBLIC RIGHTS UNDER THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart A--General
</b></p>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>1801.1 Authority and purpose.
</p>
<p>1801.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>1801.3 Contact for general information and requests.
</p>
<p>1801.4 Suggestions and complaints.</p>
<p><b>Subpart B--Filing Of Privacy Act Requests
</b></p>
<p>1801.11 Preliminary information.
</p>
<p>1801.12 Requirements as to form.
</p>
<p>1801.13 Requirements as to identification of requester.
</p>
<p>1801.14 Fees.</p>
<p><b>Subpart C--Action On Privacy Act Requests
</b></p>
<p>1801.21 Processing requests for access to or amendment of records.
</p>
<p>1801.22 Action and determination(s) by originator(s) or any interested party.
</p>
<p>1801.23 Notification of decision and right of appeal.</p>
<p><b>Subpart D--Additional Administrative Matters
</b></p>
<p>1801.31 Special procedures for medical and psychological records.
</p>
<p>1801.32 Requests for expedited processing.
</p>
<p>1801.33 Allocation of resources; agreed extensions of time.</p>
<p><b>Subpart E--Action On Privacy Act Administrative Appeals
</b></p>
<p>1801.41 Appeal authority.
</p>
<p>1801.42 Right of appeal and appeal procedures.
</p>
<p>1801.43 Determination(s) by Office Chief(s).
</p>
<p>1801.44 Action by appeals authority.
</p>
<p>1801.45 Notification of decision and right of judicial review.
</p><p><b>Subpart F--Prohibitions
</b></p>
<p>1801.51 Limitations on disclosure.
</p>
<p>1801.52 Criminal penalties.
</p><p><b>Subpart G--Exemptions
</b></p>
<p>1801.63 Specific exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 64 FR 49884, Sept. 14, 1999, unless otherwise noted.
</p><p><b>Subpart A--General
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.1 Authority and purpose.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Authority.</i> This part is issued under the authority of and in order to implement the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a) and section 102 of the National Security Act of 1947, as amended (50 U.S.C. 403).
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Purpose in general.</i> This part prescribes procedures for a requester, as defined herein:
</p>
<p>(1) To request notification of whether the National Counterintellingence Center (NACIC) maintains a record concerning them in any non-exempt portion of a system of records or any non-exempt system of records;
</p>
<p>(2) To request a copy of all non-exempt records or portions of records;
</p>
<p>(3) To request that any such record be amended or augmented; and
</p>
<p>(4) To file an administrative appeal to any initial adverse determination to deny access to or amend a record.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Other purposes.</i> This part also sets forth detailed limitations on how and to whom NACIC may disclose personal information and gives notice that certain actions by officers or employees of the United States Government or members of the public could constitute criminal offenses.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For purposes of this part, the following terms have the meanings indicated:
</p>
<p><i>NACIC</i> means the United States National Counterintelligence Center acting through the NACIC Information and Privacy Coordinator;
</p>
<p><i>Days</i> means calendar days when NACIC is operating and specifically excludes Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays. Three (3) days may be added to any time limit imposed on a requester by this part if responding by U.S. domestic mail; ten (10) days may be added if responding by international mail;
</p>
<p><i>Control</i> means ownership or the authority of NACIC pursuant to federal statute or privilege to regulate official or public access to records;
</p>
<p><i>Coordinator</i> means the NACIC Information and Privacy Coordinator who serves as the NACIC manager of the information review and release program instituted under the Privacy Act;
</p>
<p><i>Federal agency</i> means any executive department, military department, or other establishment or entity included in the definition of agency in 5 U.S.C. 552(f);
</p>
<p><i>Interested party</i> means any official in the executive, military, congressional, or judicial branches of government, United States or foreign, or U.S. Government contractor who, in the sole discretion of NACIC, has a subject matter or physical interest in the documents or information at issue;
</p>
<p><i>Maintain</i> means maintain, collect, use, or disseminate;
</p>
<p><i>Originator</i> means the U.S. Government official who originated the document at issue or successor in office or such official who has been delegated release or declassification authority pursuant to law;
</p>
<p><i>Privacy Act</i> or <i>PA</i> means the statute as codified at 5 U.S.C. 552a;
</p>
<p><i>Record</i> means an item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by NACIC in a system of records;
</p>
<p><i>Requester</i> or <i>individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence who is a living being and to whom a record might pertain;
</p>
<p><i>Responsive record</i> means those documents (records) which NACIC has determined to be within the scope of a Privacy Act request;
</p>
<p><i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which the record is maintained;
</p>
<p><i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of NACIC from which records are retrieved by the name of an individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to that individual.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.3
 Contact for general information and requests.
</b></p>
<p>For general information on this part, to inquire about the Privacy Act program at NACIC, or to file a Privacy Act request, please direct your communication in writing to the Information and Privacy Coordinator, Executive Secretariat Office, National Counterintelligence Center, 3W01 NHB, Washington, DC 20505. Requests with the required identification statement pursuant to &#167; 1801.13 must be filed in original form by mail. Subsequent communications and any inquiries will be accepted by mail or facsimile at (703) 874-5844 or by telephone at (703) 874-4121. Collect calls cannot be accepted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.4
 Suggestions and complaints.
</b></p>
<p>NACIC welcomes suggestions or complaints with regard to its administration of the Privacy Act. Letters of suggestion or complaint should identify the specific purpose and the issues for consideration. NACIC will respond to all substantive communications and take such actions as determined feasible and appropriate.
</p><p><b>Subpart B--Filing Of Privacy Act Requests
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.11
 Preliminary information.
</b></p>
<p>Members of the public shall address all communications to the contact specified at &#167; 1801.3 and clearly delineate the communication as a request under the Privacy Act and this regulation. Requests and administrative appeals on requests, referrals, and coordinations received from members of the public who owe outstanding fees for information services at this or other federal agencies will not be accepted and action on existing requests and appeals will be terminated in such circumstances.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.12
 Requirements as to form.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> No particular form is required. All requests must contain the identification information required at &#167; 1801.13.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>For access.</i> For requests seeking access, a requester should, to the extent possible, describe the nature of the record sought and the record system(s) in which it is thought to be included. Requesters may find assistance from information described in the Privacy Act Issuances Compilation which is published biennially by the <i>Federal Register.</i> In lieu of this, a requester may simply describe why and under what circumstances it is believed that NACIC maintains responsive records; NACIC will undertake the appropriate searches.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>For amendment.</i> For requests seeking amendment, a requester should identify the particular record or portion subject to the request, state a justification for such amendment, and provide the desired amending language.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.13
 Requirements as to identification of requester.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> Individuals seeking access to or amendment of records concerning themselves shall provide their full (legal) name, address, date and place of birth, and current citizenship status together with a statement that such information is true under penalty of perjury or a notarized statement swearing to or affirming identity. If NACIC determines that this information is not sufficient, NACIC may request additional or clarifying information.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Requirement for aliens.</i> Only aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence (PRAs) may file a request pursuant to the Privacy Act and this part. Such individuals shall provide, in addition to the information required under paragraph (a) of this section, their Alien Registration Number and the date that status was acquired.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Requirement for representatives.</i> The parent or guardian of a minor individual, the guardian of an individual under judicial disability, or an attorney retained to represent an individual shall provide, in addition to establishing the identity of the minor or individual represented as required in paragraph (a) or (b) of this section, evidence of such representation by submission of a certified copy of the minor?s birth certificate, court order, or representational agreement which establishes the relationship and the requester?s identity.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Procedure otherwise.</i> If a requester or representative fails to provide the information in paragraph (a), (b), or (c) of this section within forty-five (45) days of the date of our request, NACIC will deem the request closed. This action, of course, would not prevent an individual from refiling his or her Privacy Act request at a subsequent date with the required information.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.14
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>No fees will be charged for any action under the authority of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a, irrespective of the fact that a request is or may be processed under the authority of both the Privacy Act and the Freedom of Information Act.
</p><p><b>Subpart C--Action On Privacy Act Requests
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.21
 Processing requests for access to or amendment of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> Requests meeting the requirements of &#167; 1801.11 through &#167; 1801.13 shall be processed under both the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552, and the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a, and the applicable regulations, unless the requester demands otherwise in writing. Such requests will be processed under both Acts regardless of whether the requester cites one Act in the request, both, or neither. This action is taken in order to ensure the maximum possible disclosure to the requester.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Receipt, recording and tasking.</i> Upon receipt of a request meeting the requirements of &#167;&#167; 1801.11 through 1801.13, NACIC shall within ten (10) days record each request, acknowledge receipt to the requester, and thereafter effect the necessary taskings to the office(s) reasonably believed to hold responsive records.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Effect of certain exemptions.</i> In processing a request, NACIC shall decline to confirm or deny the existence or nonexistence of any responsive records whenever the fact of their existence or nonexistence is itself classified under Executive Order 12958 and that confirmation of the existence of a record may jeopardize intelligence sources and methods protected pursuant to section 103(c)(6) of the National Security Act of 1947. In such circumstances, NACIC, in the form of a final written response, shall so inform the requester and advise of his or her right to an administrative appeal.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Time for response.</i> Although the Privacy Act does not mandate a time for response, our joint treatment of requests under both the Privacy Act and the FOIA means that the NACIC should provide a response within the FOIA statutory guideline of ten (10) days on initial requests and twenty (20) days on administrative appeals. However, the volume of requests may require that NACIC seek additional time from a requester pursuant to &#167; 1801.33. In such event, NACIC will inform the requester in writing and further advise of his or her right to file an administrative appeal.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.22
 Action and determination(s) by originator(s) or any interested party.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Initial action for access.</i> NACIC offices tasked pursuant to a Privacy Act access request shall search all relevant record systems within their cognizance. They shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Determine whether responsive records exist;
</p>
<p>(2) Determine whether access must be denied in whole or part and on what legal basis under both Acts in each such case;
</p>
<p>(3) Approve the disclosure of records for which they are the originator; and
</p>
<p>(4) Forward to the Coordinator all records approved for release or necessary for coordination with or referral to another originator or interested party as well as the specific determinations with respect to denials (if any).
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Initial action for amendment.</i> NACIC offices tasked pursuant to a Privacy Act amendment request shall review the official records alleged to be inaccurate and the proposed amendment submitted by the requester. If they determine that NACIC?s records are not accurate, relevant, timely or complete, they shall promptly:
</p>
<p>(1) Make the amendment as requested;
</p>
<p>(2) Write to all other identified persons or agencies to whom the record has been disclosed (if an accounting of the disclosure was made) and inform of the amendment; and
</p>
<p>(3) Inform the Coordinator of such decisions.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Action otherwise on amendment request.</i> If the NACIC office records manager declines to make the requested amendment (or declines to make the requested amendment) but agrees to augment the official records, that manager shall promptly:
</p>
<p>(1) Set forth the reasons for refusal; and
</p>
<p>(2) Inform the Coordinator of such decision and the reasons therefore.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Referrals and coordinations.</i> As applicable and within ten (10) days of receipt by the Coordinator, any NACIC records containing information originated by other NACIC offices shall be forwarded to those entities for action in accordance with paragraphs (a), (b), or (c) of this section and return. Records originated by other federal agencies or NACIC records containing other federal information shall be forwarded to such agencies within ten (10) days of our completion of initial action in the case for action under their regulations and direct response to the requester (for other NACIC records) or return to NACIC (for NACIC records).
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Effect of certain exemptions.</i> This section shall not be construed to allow access to systems of records exempted by the Director, NACIC pursuant to subsections (j) and (k) of the Privacy Act or where those exemptions require that NACIC can neither confirm nor deny the existence or nonexistence of responsive records.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.23
 Notification of decision and right of appeal.
</b></p>
<p>Within ten (10) days of receipt of responses to all initial taskings and subsequent coordinations (if any), and dispatch of referrals (if any), NACIC will provide disclosable records to the requester. If a determination has been made not to provide access to requested records (in light of specific exemptions) or that no records are found, NACIC shall so inform the requester, identify the denying official, and advise of the right to administrative appeal.
</p><p><b>Subpart D--Additional Administrative Matters
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.31
 Special procedures for medical and psychological records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> When a request for access or amendment involves medical or psychological records and when the originator determines that such records are not exempt from disclosure, NACIC will, after consultation with the Director of Medical Services, CIA, determine:
</p>
<p>(1) Which records may be sent directly to the requester and
</p>
<p>(2) Which records should not be sent directly to the requester because of possible medical or psychological harm to the requester or another person.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Procedure for records to be sent to physician.</i> In the event that NACIC determines, in accordance with paragraph (a)(2) of this section, that records should not be sent directly to the requester, NACIC will notify the requester in writing and advise that the records at issue can be made available only to a physician of the requester?s designation. Upon receipt of such designation, verification of the identity of the physician, and agreement by the physician:
</p>
<p>(1) To review the documents with the requesting individual,
</p>
<p>(2) To explain the meaning of the documents, and
</p>
<p>(3) To offer counseling designed to temper any adverse reaction, NACIC will forward such records to the designated physician.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Procedure if physician option not available.</i> If within sixty (60) days of paragraph (a)(2) of this section, the requester has failed to respond or designate a physician, or the physician fails to agree to the release conditions, NACIC will hold the documents in abeyance and advise the requester that this action may be construed as a technical denial. NACIC will also advise the requester of the responsible official and of his or her rights to administrative appeal and thereafter judicial review.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.32
 Requests for expedited processing.
</b></p>
<p>(a) All requests will be handled in the order received on a strictly "first-in, first-out" basis. Exceptions to this rule will only be made in circumstances that NACIC deems to be exceptional. In making this determination, NACIC shall consider and must decide in the affirmative on all of the following factors:
</p>
<p>(1) That there is a genuine need for the records; and
</p>
<p>(2) That the personal need is exceptional; and
</p>
<p>(3) That there are no alternative forums for the records sought; and
</p>
<p>(4) That it is reasonably believed that substantive records relevant to the stated needs may exist and be deemed releasable.
</p>
<p>(b) In sum, requests shall be considered for expedited processing only when health, humanitarian, or due process considerations involving possible deprivation of life or liberty create circumstances of exceptional urgency and extraordinary need. In accordance with established judicial precedent, requests more properly the scope of requests under the Federal Rules of Civil or Criminal Procedure (or equivalent state rules) will not be granted expedited processing under this or related (e.g., Freedom of Information Act) provisions unless expressly ordered by a federal court of competent jurisdiction.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.33
 Allocation of resources; agreed extensions of time.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> NACIC components shall devote such personnel and other resources to the responsibilities imposed by the Privacy Act as may be appropriate and reasonable considering:
</p>
<p>(1) The totality of resources available to the component,
</p>
<p>(2) The business demands imposed on the component by the Director, NACIC or otherwise by law,
</p>
<p>(3) The information review and release demands imposed by the Congress or other governmental authority, and
</p>
<p>(4) The rights of all members of the public under the various information review and disclosure laws.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Discharge of Privacy Act responsibilities.</i> Offices shall exercise due diligence in their responsibilities under the Privacy Act and must allocate a reasonable level of resources to requests under the Act in a strictly "first-in, first-out" basis and utilizing two or more processing queues to ensure that smaller as well as larger (i.e., project) cases receive equitable attention. The Information and Privacy Coordinator is responsible for management of the NACIC-wide program defined by this part and for establishing priorities for cases consistent with established law. The Director, NACIC shall provide policy and resource direction as necessary and shall render decisions on administrative appeals.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Requests for extension of time.</i> While the Privacy Act does not specify time requirements, our joint treatment of requests under the FOIA means that when NACIC is unable to meet the statutory time requirements of the FOIA, NACIC may request additional time from a requester. In such instances NACIC will inform a requester of his or her right to decline our request and proceed with an administrative appeal or judicial review as appropriate.
</p><p><b>Subpart E--Action On Privacy Act Administrative Appeals
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.41
 Appeal authority.
</b></p>
<p>The Director, NACIC will make final NACIC decisions from appeals of initial adverse decisions under the Privacy Act and such other information release decisions made under 32 CFR parts 1800, 1802, and 1803 of this chapter. Matters decided by the Director, NACIC will be deemed a final decision by NACIC.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.42
 Right of appeal and appeal procedures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Right of Appeal.</i> A right of administrative appeal exists whenever access to any requested record or any portion thereof is denied, no records are located in response to a request, or a request for amendment is denied. NACIC will apprise all requesters in writing of their right to appeal such decisions to the Director, NACIC through the Coordinator.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Requirements as to time and form.</i> Appeals of decisions must be received by the Coordinator within forty-five (45) days of the date of NACIC?s initial decision. NACIC may, for good cause and as a matter of administrative discretion, permit an additional thirty (30) days for the submission of an appeal. All appeals to the Director, NACIC shall be in writing and addressed as specified in &#167; 1801.3. All appeals must identify the documents or portions of documents at issue with specificity, provide the desired amending language (if applicable), and may present such information, data, and argument in support as the requester may desire.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Exceptions.</i> No appeal shall be accepted if the requester has outstanding fees for information services at this or another federal agency. In addition, no appeal shall be accepted if the information in question has been the subject of an administrative review within the previous two (2) years or is the subject of pending litigation in the federal courts.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Receipt, recording, and tasking.</i> NACIC shall promptly record each administrative appeal, acknowledge receipt to the requester in writing, and thereafter effect the necessary taskings to the office chief in charge of the office(s) which originated or has an interest in the record(s) subject to the appeal.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.43
 Determination(s) by Office Chiefs.
</b></p>
<p>Each Office Chief in charge of an office which originated or has an interest in any of the records subject to the appeal, or designee, is a required party to any appeal; other interested parties may become involved through the request of the Coordinator when it is determined that some or all of the information is also within their official cognizance. These parties shall respond in writing to the Coordinator with a finding as to the exempt or non-exempt status of the information including citations to the applicable exemption and/or their agreement or disagreement as to the requested amendment and the reasons therefore. Each response shall be provided expeditiously on a "first-in, first-out" basis taking into account the business requirements of the parties and consistent with the information rights of members of the general public under the various information review and release laws.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.44
 Action by appeals authority.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Preparation of docket.</i> The Coordinator shall provide a summation memorandum for consideration of the Director, NACIC; the complete record of the request consisting of the request, the document(s) (sanitized and full text) at issue, and the findings of any concerned office chiefs or designee(s).
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Decision by the Director, NACIC.</i> The Director, NACIC shall personally decide each case; no personal appearances shall be permitted without the express permission of the Director, NACIC.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.45
 Notification of decision and right of judicial review.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>In general.</i> The Coordinator shall promptly prepare and communicate the decision of the Director, NACIC to the requester. With respect to any decision to deny information or deny amendment, that correspondence shall state the reasons for the decision, identify the officer responsible, and include a notice of the right to judicial review.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>For amendment requests.</i> With further respect to any decision to deny an amendment, that correspondence shall also inform the requester of the right to submit within forty-five (45) days a statement of his or her choice which shall be included in the official records of NACIC. In such cases, the applicable record system manager shall clearly note any portion of the official record which is disputed, append the requester?s statement, and provide copies of the statement to previous recipients (if any are known) and to any future recipients when and if the disputed information is disseminated in accordance with a routine use.
</p><p><b>Subpart F--Prohibitions
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.51
 Limitations on disclosure.
</b></p>
<p>No record which is within a system of records shall be disclosed by any means of communication to any individual or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains, unless disclosure of the record would be:
</p>
<p>(a) To those officers and employees of NACIC which maintains the record who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties;
</p>
<p>(b) Required under the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552;
</p>
<p>(c) For a routine use as defined in &#167; 1801.02(m), as contained in the Privacy Act Issuances Compilation which is published biennially in the <i>Federal Register,</i> and as described in sections (a)(7) and (e)(4)(D) of the Act;
</p>
<p>(d) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity pursuant to the provisions of U.S.C. Title 13;
</p>
<p>(e) To a recipient who has provided NACIC with advance adequate written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred in a form that is not individually identifiable;
</p>
<p>(f) To the National Archives and Records Administration as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the United States Government, or for evaluation by the Archivist of the United States or designee to determine whether the record has such value;
</p>
<p>(g) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity if the activity is authorized by law, and if the head of that agency or instrumentality has made a written request to NACIC specifying the particular information desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought;
</p>
<p>(h) To a person pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual if upon such disclosure notification is transmitted to the last known address of such individual;
</p>
<p>(i) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee;
</p>
<p>(j) To the Comptroller General or any of his authorized representatives in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office; or
</p>
<p>(k) To any agency, government instrumentality, or other person or entity pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction of the United States or constituent states.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.52
 Criminal penalties.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Unauthorized disclosure.</i> Criminal penalties may be imposed against any officer or employee of NACIC who, by virtue of employment, has possession of or access to NACIC records which contain information identifiable with an individual, the disclosure of which is prohibited by the Privacy Act or by these rules, and who, knowing that disclosure of the specific material is so prohibited, willfully discloses the material in any manner to any person or agency not entitled to receive same.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Unauthorized maintenance.</i> Criminal penalties may be imposed against any officer or employee of NACIC who willfully maintains a system of records without meeting the requirements of section (e)(4) of the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a. The Coordinator and the Director of NACIC are authorized independently to conduct such surveys and inspect such records as necessary from time to time to ensure that these requirements are met.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Unauthorized requests.</i> Criminal penalties may be imposed upon any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual from NACIC under false pretenses.
</p><p><b>Subpart G--Exemptions

</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 1801.63
 Specific exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>Pursuant to authority granted in section (k) of the Privacy Act, the Director, NACIC has determined to exempt from section (d) of the Privacy Act those portions and only those portions of all systems of records maintained by NACIC that would consist of, pertain to, or otherwise reveal information that is:
</p>
<p>(a) Classified pursuant to Executive Order 12958 (or successor or prior Order) and thus subject to the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(1) and 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(1);
</p>
<p>(b) Investigatory in nature and compiled for law enforcement purposes, other than material within the scope of section (j)(2) of the Act; provided however, that if an individual is denied any right, privilege, or benefit to which they are otherwise eligible, as a result of the maintenance of such material, then such material shall be provided to that individual except to the extent that the disclosure would reveal the identity of a source who furnished the information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality;
</p>
<p>(c) Maintained in connection with providing protective services to the President of the United States or other individuals pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 3056;
</p>
<p>(d) Required by statute to be maintained and used solely as statistical records;
</p>
<p>(e) Investigatory in nature and compiled solely for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualifications for federal civilian employment, military service, federal contracts, or access to classified information, but only to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality;
</p>
<p>(f) Testing or examination material used solely to determine individual qualifications for appointment or promotion in the federal service the disclosure of which would compromise the objectivity or fairness of the testing or examination process; or
</p>
<p>(g) Evaluation material used to determine potential for promotion in the armed services, but only to the extent that the disclosure of such material would reveal the identity of a source who furnished information to the United States Government under an express promise of confidentiality, or, prior to the effective date of this section, under an implied promise of confidentiality.
</p>

</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
