<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>


<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>National Transportation Safety Board</name>
<abbrev>NTSB</abbrev>
    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-15/pdf/2021-24767.pdf</url>
        <title>Religious Accommodation Request Records. NTSB-34</title>
        <date year="21" month="11" day="15" />
    </previouslyPublished>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-12-27/pdf/2021-28022.pdf  </url>
        <title>Religious and Disability Reasonable Accommodation Records within the Office 365 MT system.</title>
        <date year="21" month="12" day="27" />
    </previouslyPublished>


    <routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>PREFATORY STATEMENT OF GENERAL ROUTINE USES 
</b></p><p>The following previously published routine uses apply to and are incorporated by reference into each system of records set forth below: 
</p><p>1. Referral to law enforcement agencies of violations of the law. 
</p><p>2. Disclosure for discovery purposes ordered by a court. 
</p><p>3. Disclosure to a congressional office of the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual. 
</p></xhtmlContent></routineUses>
<section id="ntsb2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Official Personnel Folders.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records on current Federal employees are located within the employing agency. Records maintained in paper may also be located at OPM or with personnel officers, or at other designated offices of local installations of the department or agency that employs the individual. When agencies determine that duplicates of these records need to be located in a second office, e.g., an administrative office closer to where the employee actually works, such copies are covered by this system. Some agencies have employed the Enterprise Human Resource Integration (EHRI) data system to store their records electronically. Although stored in EHRI, agencies are still responsible for the maintenance of their records. Former Federal employees' paper Official Personnel Folders (OPFs) are located at the National Personnel Records Center, National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63118. Former Federal employees' electronic Official Personnel Folders (eOPF) are located in the EHRI data system that is administered by NARA.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and certain former NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records include employee's name, Social Security number, date of birth, home address, home telephone number, and specialized education. Records reflect Federal service and work experience, including past and present positions held, grades, salaries, duty station locations, and notices of all personnel actions, such as appointments, promotions, reassignments, demotions, details, transfers, reductions-in-force, resignations, retirements, removal, and suspensions. Records also include information concerning election and/or waiver of Federal benefits, including employees' designation of beneficiaries for these and other programs.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301 <i>et seq.,</i> 1302, 2951, 3301, 4118, 8347; 5 CFR part 293; Executive Order Nos. 9,397, 9,830, and 12,107.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The OPF, which may exist in various approved media, and other general personnel records files, is the official repository of the records, reports of personnel actions, and the documentation required in connection with these actions affected during an employee's Federal service. The personnel action reports and other documents, some of which are filed in the OPF, give legal force and effect to personnel transactions and establish employee rights and benefits under pertinent laws and regulations governing Federal employment. These files and records are maintained by OPM and agencies in accordance with OPM regulations and instructions. They provide the basic source of factual data about a person's Federal employment while in the service and after his or her separation. Records in this system have various uses by agency personnel offices, including screening qualifications of employees; determining status, eligibility, and employee's rights and benefits under pertinent laws and regulations governing Federal employment; computing length of service; and other information needed to provide personnel services. These records may also be used to locate individuals for personnel research.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The OPF, which may exist in various approved media, and other general personnel records files, is the official repository of the records, reports of personnel actions, and the documentation required in connection with these actions affected during an employee's Federal service. The personnel action reports and other documents, some of which are filed in the OPF, give legal force and effect to personnel transactions and establish employee rights and benefits under pertinent laws and regulations governing Federal employment. These files and records are maintained by OPM and agencies in accordance with OPM regulations and instructions. They provide the basic source of factual data about a person's Federal employment while in the service and after his or her separation. Records in this system have various uses by agency personnel offices, including screening qualifications of employees; determining status, eligibility, and employee's rights and benefits under pertinent laws and regulations governing Federal employment; computing length of service; and other information needed to provide personnel services. These records may also be used to locate individuals for personnel research.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are maintained in file folders, on lists and forms, microfilm or microfiche, and in computer processable storage media such as personnel system databases, PDF forms and data warehouse systems.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are retrieved by the name, Social Security number, or date of birth of the individuals about whom they concern.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper or microfiche/microfilmed records are located in locked metal file cabinets or in secured rooms with access limited to those personnel whose official duties require access. Access to computerized records is limited, through use of user logins and passwords, access codes, and entry logs, to those whose official duties require access. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location.
</p><p>This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains records within this system for the period of the employee's service at the NTSB. When an employee leaves the NTSB to begin employment at another Federal agency, the NTSB transfers these records to the employee's new Federal agency. When an employee retires, resigns, or dies, the NTSB forwards the employee's record to the National Personnel Records Center for permanent storage, in accordance with General Records Schedule 1, item 1.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Manager, OCIO/RM, U.S. Office of Personnel Management, 1900 E Street NW., Washington, DC 20415.
</p><p>b. For current Federal employees, OPM has delegated to the employing agency the Privacy Act responsibilities concerning access, amendment, and disclosure of the records within this system notice. Chief, Human Resources Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p><p>a. Former Federal employees who want access to their Official Personnel Folders (OPF) should contact the National Personnel Records Center (Civilian), 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63118, regarding the records in this system. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>a. Full name.
</p><p>b. Date of birth.
</p><p>c. Social security number.
</p><p>d. Last employing agency (including duty station) and approximate date(s) of the employment (for former Federal employees).
</p><p>e. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system is obtained from the individual to whom the record pertains and NTSB officials responsible for pay, leave, and activity reporting requirements.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records is provided by:
</p><p>a. The individual on whom the record is maintained.
 
</p><p>b. Educational institutions.
</p><p>c. Agency officials and other individuals or entities.
</p><p>d. Other sources of information maintained in an employee's OPF, in accordance with Code of Federal Regulations part 293, and OPM's Operating Manual, "The Guide to Personnel Recordkeeping."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None. 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security and Investigative Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees, prospective employees, and potential contractors seeking access to sensitive materials or facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel security folders containing the results of name checks, inquiries, record checks, and investigations furnished by the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or a private service provider. Information in these records may contain dates and places of birth, citizenship, marital status, military status, and Social Security records. In addition, these records may contain investigative information concerning an individual's character, conduct, and behavior, as well as arrests, convictions, or judgments regarding any legal or regulatory violations. Records may also contain information from current and former supervisors, colleagues, associates, and educators; in addition, records may contain financial or medical records and any other information developed from the records listed above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order No. 10,450.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system to determine whether the employment of a job applicant, or retention of a current employee, is in the interest of the Government, as well as which persons may have access to classified or sensitive material and access to other facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to other Federal agencies when necessary to allow the individual to access classified or sensitive material that other Federal agencies maintain;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other Federal agencies or private organizations when necessary to allow the individual to visit a certain facility or site; and
</p><p>3. Disclosure to OPM, when necessary for an investigation, personnel matter, or an assessment of agency compliance with Federal personnel security and suitability program requirements.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored on paper in file folders within the Human Resources Division or Office of Management at the NTSB, at the address above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are retrieved by either the name or Social Security number of the individuals about whom they concern.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in locked metal file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains records within this system in accordance with OPM directives and General Records Schedule 18, item 22. In general, the NTSB destroys records in this system once the records are obsolete or no longer warrant retention, such as at the conclusion of three years following the year that the employee departed from the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Human Resources Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system is obtained from the individual to whom the record pertains, and may be obtained from NTSB officials, former employers, educational institutions, and individuals who are familiar with the individual, as well as officials from other Federal agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None. 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Travel Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. The National Business Center, which is a division of the Department of Interior, stores some information electronically off-site on behalf of the NTSB, at: National Business Center, DOI, Mail Stop D-2600, 7301 West Mansfield Avenue, Lakewood, Colorado 80235-2230. As described below, the National Business Center transfers the records to the Federal Records Center after the expiration of one year following the date of the employee's travel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees and invitational travelers who have traveled pursuant to authorized official business of the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel vouchers, which include receipts for various expenditures.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Travel Expense Amendments Act of 1975, Public Law 94-22, 89 Stat. 84 (codified at 5 U.S.C. 5701-5707).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system to determine and verify amounts to be paid to an employee or invitational traveler for reimbursement of travel expenses for authorized, official travel performed on behalf of the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine use:
</p><p>Disclosure to other Federal agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are system generated or scanned and saved in an electronic database. In addition, some copies of the records are stored on paper in file folders within the employee's office at the NTSB, at the address above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are indexed by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in a secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Pursuant to General Records Schedule 9, items 3 and 4, the NTSB maintains records relating to reimbursing individuals for six years after payment of the allowable travel expenses and maintains routine administrative records for two years.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Financial Officer, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza, SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza, SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
 
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system is obtained from the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Executive Branch Confidential Financial Disclosure Reports.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of General Counsel, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees who must submit confidential financial disclosure reports under the requirements of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (hereinafter "Ethics Act"), as amended, or to whom the Ethics Act otherwise applies. All such individuals are described in the categories listed in Government-wide system of records notice OGE/GOVT-2. The NTSB incorporates by reference the text of OGE/GOVT-2 into this Notice; as such, this Notice contains a summary of the information and provisions of OGE/GOVT-2 and descriptions of how NTSB-5 is consistent with OGE/GOVT-2, and identifies any differences between NTSB-5 and OGE/GOVT-2. OGE/GOVT-2 is available at 68 FR 3098 (Jan. 22, 2003), as updated at 68 FR 24744 (May 8, 2003).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains information that is necessary for administration of all provisions of the Ethics Act and the Ethics Reform Act of 1989, as amended, and Executive Order 12,674, as modified. In particular, this system contains statements and amended statements of personal and family holdings and other interests in property; income; gifts and reimbursements; liabilities; agreements and arrangements; outside positions; and other information related to conflict-of-interest determinations. These statements may consist of certifications of no new interests for the reporting period, and may be supplemental or alternative confidential report forms.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, Public Law 95-521, 92 Stat. 1824 (codified as amended 5 U.S.C. 7301, 7351, 7353, and other scattered sections of 5 U.S.C.); 5 CFR part 2634; Executive Order 12,674 (as modified by Executive Order 12,731).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB collects the records in this system in order to comply with the Ethics Act, and implementing Office of Government Ethics (OGE) regulations and applicable Executive Orders. The collection of these records is necessary to assure compliance with statutory and regulatory requirements, to determine if an actual or apparent conflict of interest exists between the employment of individuals by the Federal Government and their outside employment and financial interests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB notes that, when the Director or other authorized officials of OGE requests that the NTSB furnish OGE with records from this system, such disclosure will be in response to OGE's need for the records in the performance of their official duties under the Ethics Act, and other related statutes, regulations, and Executive Orders, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1). In addition to other disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine use:
</p><p>1. Disclosure of information to any source when necessary to obtain information relevant to a conflict-of-interest investigation or determination; and
</p><p>2. Disclosure of the confidential financial disclosure report or certificate of no new interests and any accompanying documents to reviewing officials in a new office, department, or agency when an employee transfers or is detailed from a covered position in one office, department, or agency to a covered position in another office, department, or agency.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB primarily maintains these records on paper in file folders. In addition, the Office of General Counsel maintains certain information about current and former employees in searchable electronic databases.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are indexed alphabetically by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: the Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with General Records Schedule 25, the NTSB retains these records for a period of six years after filing, or for such other period of time as set forth in Schedule 25 for certain types of ethics records. The NTSB may retain records needed in an ongoing investigation for a period that exceeds six years, until the investigation no longer requires such records. At the expiration of the retention period, the NTSB destroys these records by shredding them.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Designated Agency Ethics Official, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 East L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Designated Agency Ethics Official at the following address: National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza, SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees, or designated persons on behalf of such employees, such as trustees, attorneys, accountants, bankers, or relatives; Federal officials who review the records to make conflict-of-interest determinations; persons alleging conflicts of interest or violations of other ethics laws, and persons contacted during any investigation of the allegations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Payroll, Leave, and Attendance Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. The National Business Center, which is a division of the Department of Interior, stores some information electronically off-site on behalf of the NTSB, at: National Business Center, DOI, Payroll Operations Division, Mail Stop D-2600, 7301 West Mansfield Avenue, Lakewood, Colorado 80235-2230. In addition, the NTSB stores payroll records pertaining to individuals who have retired from the NTSB at the National Archives and Records Administration, National Personnel Records Center (Civilian Personnel Records Center), 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63118.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All current and former employees of the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The agency's system consists of four files. Official personnel files held by the NTSB are governed by the U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM)regulations, at 5 CFR parts 293 and 297.
</p><p>1. Official personnel file: This file consists of the forms and documents that record employees' Standard Form 50s, copies of benefits election forms, and applications used for qualification determinations. This is a paper file.
</p><p>2. Security File: This file is described at NTSB-3, above. Duplicates of the security records described in NTSB-3 may also exist in this system, designated as NTSB-6.
</p><p>3. Payroll file: This file consists of documents related to employees' pay and related payroll deductions that are not filed in the official personnel file. These files may contain copies of income tax forms, savings bond elections, net deposits and allotments, union dues elections, benefits elections, and records regarding garnishments. This is a paper file.
</p><p>4. Time and attendance reports: This system consists of credit hour records, biweekly summaries of hours worked and leave taken, flextime records, leave applications, authorized premium pay, danger pay requests, and corrections. This information is maintained in an electronic system, and some records may exist on microfiche.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 CFR Parts 293 and 297; Executive Order 12107.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB uses these records to establish and maintain employee qualifications, benefits and pay.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to the Treasury Department for payroll purposes or for the issuance of savings bonds;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management for retirement, health and life insurance purposes, and to carry out the Government-wide personnel management functions of the NTSB;
 
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the National Finance Center for the Thrift Savings Plan and Temporary Continuation of Coverage;
</p><p>4. Disclosure to the Social Security Administration for compliance with the Federal Insurance Compensation Act;
</p><p>5. Disclosure to the Internal Revenue Service for taxable earnings and withholding purposes, or for audit and inspection and investigation purposes;
</p><p>6. Disclosure to the Combined Federal Campaign for charitable contribution purposes;
</p><p>7. Disclosure to the American Federation of Government Employees for union dues;
</p><p>8. Disclosure to state and local government tax entities for income tax purposes;
</p><p>9. Disclosure to holders of judgment liens, for the purposes of garnishments; and
</p><p>10. Disclosure to arbitrators pursuant to a negotiated labor agreement or to Equal Employment Opportunity investigators who hear or investigate employee grievances or complaints of discrimination.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Official personnel files, security files, and payroll files and are kept in file folders, which the NTSB maintains within metal file cabinets in a locked office. Time and attendance reports are maintained in an electronic system, as described above.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Official personnel files, payroll files, and time and attendance reports are indexed by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in locked file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in a secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retains and disposes of records within this system as follows:
</p><p>1. The NTSB retains each employee's official personnel file until the end of the first thirty days following the date of the individual's separation from the NTSB if the individual is not thereafter employed by a Federal agency, pursuant to General Records Schedule 1, item 1. After expiration of the thirty-day period, the NTSB sends records to the National Archives and Records Administration, National Personnel Records Center, 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri. However, if following the separation from the NTSB, the individual is employed by another Federal agency, the NTSB maintains the records until that Federal agency requests the records from the NTSB;
</p><p>2. Security records are kept for three years following an employee's separation, as described at NTSB-3, above;
</p><p>3. The NTSB retains payroll records for three calendar years following the year in which the employee separates; and
</p><p>4. The NTSB retains time and attendance reports for six years after the year of the employee's separation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Human Resources Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza, SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals about whom the records concern, individuals' supervisors, and NTSB employees acting in their official capacities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) Discrimination Complaint Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Equal Employment Opportunity Diversity and Inclusion, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals, classes of individuals, or organizations which have consulted an EEO Counselor regarding discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, national origin, physical disability, genetic information, or age because of a determination, or decision made by a Safety Board official or which have filed a formal allegation of discrimination.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system of records contains information or documents concerning pre-complaint processing and formal allegations of discrimination. The records consist of counselors' reports, the initial allegations, letters or notices to the individual or organization, materials placed into the record to support or refute the decision or determination, statements of witnesses, investigative reports, instructions about action to be taken to comply with decisions, and related correspondence, opinions, recommendations, and final administrative actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order No. 11,478; 42 U.S.C. 2000e; 29 U.S.C. 633a; 29 CFR part 1614.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB uses these records to initiate, investigate, and resolve discrimination complaints within the NTSB. The NTSB may also use these records as a data source for management information for production of summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the NTSB collects and maintains the records, or for related personnel management functions or manpower studies. In addition, the NTSB may use these records to locate specific individuals for personnel research or other personnel management functions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management, Merit Systems Protection Board (including its Office of the Special Counsel), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority (including the General Counsel of the Authority and the Federal Service Impasses Panel), the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, and to an arbitrator, in carrying out their functions;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other Federal or foreign agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation of a civil, criminal, or regulatory violation or potential violation;
 
</p><p>3. A record from this system of records may be disclosed to a Federal, state or local agency maintaining civil, criminal or other relevant enforcement records or other pertinent records, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain a record relevant to an agency decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract or the issuance of a license, grant or other benefit;
</p><p>4. Disclosure to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, issuing a security clearance, conducting a security or suitability investigation of an individual, or classifying jobs, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decisions on the matter;
</p><p>5. Disclosure in response to a subpoena to the NTSB where Federal agencies having the power to subpoena other Federal agencies' records, such as the Internal Revenue Service or the Civil Rights Commission, have issued the subpoena;
</p><p>6. Where a contract between an NTSB office and a labor organization recognized under Executive Order No. 11,491 or 5 U.S.C. Chapter 71 provides that the agency will disclose personal records relevant to the organization's mission, the NTSB may disclose records in this system of records to such organization;
</p><p>7. Disclosure to a private entity with which the NTSB maintains a contractual relationship for the purposes of investigating discrimination claims or collating, analyzing, aggregating or otherwise refining records in this system, where the private entity is subject to a non-disclosure agreement and understands that it must honor Privacy Act safeguards with respect to such records;
</p><p>8. In the event of litigation where the defendant is (a) the NTSB, any component of the NTSB, or any employee of the NTSB in his or her official capacity; (b) the United States, where the NTSB determines that the claim, if successful, is likely to directly affect the operations of the NTSB or any of its components; or (c) any NTSB employee in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent such employee, the NTSB may disclose such records as it deems desirable or necessary to the Department of Justice to enable the NTSB to present an effective defense, provided such disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected;
</p><p>9. Records may be disclosed to student volunteers, individuals working under a personal services contract, and other individuals performing functions for the NTSB but technically not having the status of NTSB employees, if they need access to the records to perform their assigned agency functions.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are maintained in file folders, binders, and index cards.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are indexed by the names of the individuals or organizations concerning which the NTSB maintains them.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in lockable file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are retained for four years after final disposition of the EEO complaint. After the four-year period expires, the NTSB destroys the records, pursuant to General Records Schedule 1, item 25.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Equal Employment Opportunity Diversity and Inclusion, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
 
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains the records in this system from: The individual to whom the record pertains; the NTSB or other officials; NTSB employees or other witnesses; and the EEO director or other such persons or organizations who create or submit official documents relating to the counseling or formal allegation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>To the extent that any records in this system consist of attorney work product or attorney-client communications, 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(5) may apply to preclude access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">FOIA and Privacy Act Request Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Chief Information Officer, Records Management Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Persons who submit requests for NTSB records under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) or the Privacy Act (PA), and administrative appeals based on responses to those requests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Copies of written or electronic requests from individuals or organizations made under the provisions of the FOIA or PA, NTSB response letters, copies of requested records, and records concerning an administrative appeal of the response, where the requester has submitted such an appeal.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The Freedom of Information Act, as amended, (codified at 5 U.S.C. 552); the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (codified at 5 U.S.C. 552a).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains these records to process requests made under the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act of 1974.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to a court, or other deciding agency or official, when a requester has filed an appeal or court suit concerning a request; and
</p><p>2. Disclosure to another Federal agency when consultation or referral is required to process a request.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
 </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records of correspondence regarding a requester's request or appeal are stored manually in file folders and electronically, in a database. Records within the scope of a requester's request may be stored on audiotapes and/or videotapes, on computer disks, and electronically, in databases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retrieves records in this system by unique assigned number for each request, by the requester's name, or by the investigation number, where the requester seeks information from a particular accident investigation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in lockable file cabinets or shelving and computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB--24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retains the records in this system until disposition or destruction is authorized by title 44 of the United States Code or the National Archives and Records Administration's General Records Schedule 14. The NTSB also disposes of records within this system in accordance with General Records Schedule 14.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Freedom of Information Act Officer, National Transportation Safety Board, Attention: FOIA and Privacy Act Requester Service Center, CIO-40, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Subject of FOIA request or Privacy Act record;
</p><p>3. Date of FOIA or Privacy Act request; and
</p><p>4. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who submit requests and administrative appeals pursuant to FOIA and PA, agency records obtained in the process of responding to such requests and appeals and NTSB personnel who handle such requests and appeals. These requests are accepted by fax, public web, postal mail, and email.
 </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb10" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-10</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Records of Disciplinary Action, Adverse Action, and Grievance and Appeal Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former National Transportation Safety Board Federal employees against whom such action has been proposed or taken in accordance with 5 CFR parts 315 (subparts H and I), 432, 752, or 754.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former National Transportation Safety Board Federal employees against whom such action has been proposed or taken in accordance with 5 CFR parts 315 (subparts H and I), 432, 752, or 754, or who have filed grievances pursuant to 5 CFR part 771.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records and documents concerning: (1) the processing of disciplinary and adverse actions, performance-based reduction in grade and removal actions, and grievances and appeals of such actions; (2) the termination of employees serving initial appointment probation and return to their former grade of employees serving supervisory or managerial probation; and (3) grievances raised by agency employees, except EEO complaints and grievances filed under negotiated grievance procedures in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 7121. The records include, as appropriate: Copies of the notice of proposed action; materials upon which the NTSB relied to support the reasons in the notice; replies by the employee; statements of witnesses and affidavits; hearing notices; reports of investigations; agency decisions; and records of resolutions or settlement agreements, which may include reports of interviews and hearing examiners; findings and recommendations, copies of original decisions, related correspondence and exhibits, and records concerning reconsideration requests.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 1302, 3301, 3321, 4303, 4308, 5115, 5338, 7151, 7301, 7504, 7514, 7543, 7701, and 8347; 5 CFR part 771.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system of records regarding the proposal, processing, and documentation of disciplinary and adverse employment actions in order to comply with 5 CFR parts 315 (subparts H and I), 432, 752, or 754; in addition, the NTSB maintains grievance information in accordance with 5 CFR part 771.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to labor organization officials to provide information defined under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when the information is relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting working conditions;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other Federal or foreign agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation of a civil, criminal, or regulatory violation or potential violation;
</p><p>3. Disclosure to any source from which the NTSB requests additional information for processing any of the covered actions or in regard to an appeal or administrative review procedure, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested;
</p><p>4. Disclosure to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, issuing a security clearance, conducting a security or suitability investigation of an individual, or classifying jobs, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decisions on the matter;
</p><p>5. Disclosure to another Federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency, when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding;
</p><p>6. Disclosure to other agencies or contractors for other agencies, when disclosure is necessary to locate individuals for personnel research or survey response and in producing summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the other organization seeks to collect the record, or for related workforce studies; the NTSB notes that, while published statistics and studies do not contain individual identifiers, in some instances the selection of elements of data included in the study may be structured in such a way as to make the data individually identifiable by inference;
</p><p>7. Disclosure to a party engaged in litigation of information that is relevant to subject matter concerning a pending judicial or administrative proceeding, when such disclosure is subject to discovery or order from a court with competent jurisdiction; 
</p><p>8. Disclosure to the Merit System Protection Board in connection with appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of agency rules and regulations, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices, and such other functions, as promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, and as specified in 5 U.S.C. 7503(c) and 5 U.S.C. 7513(e), or as may be authorized by any other applicable statute.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains these records on paper in file folders within a lectriever in a locked file room.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retrieves records by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a locked file room that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the room where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB destroys these records five years after the closing of the case.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Human Resources Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains the records in this system from: NTSB employees and supervisors, NTSB Office of Administration; representatives of NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb11" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-11</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Parking Permit Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Administration, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB employees who apply for parking permits at the NTSB headquarters facility.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains parking applications, which include but are not limited to, the applicant's name, address, telephone number, division, grade level, vehicle, carpool, handicap information, and justifications for the priority of parking permits. The NTSB collects parking applications from each applicant on a regular annual basis.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>40 U.S.C. 121(c); 41 CFR 102-74.305; Executive Order No. 12,191, 45 FR 7,997 (Feb. 1, 1980).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system of records in order to provide parking for qualified NTSB employees located at the NTSB headquarters facility in Washington, DC.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to labor organization officials to provide information defined under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when the information is relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other Federal or foreign agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation of a civil, criminal, or regulatory violation or potential violation.
 
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains these records on paper in file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retrieves these records by searching either by the employee's name or by the individual parking permit number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in lockable file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>As stated above, the NTSB collects parking applications on a regular annual basis. The NTSB retains applications for a period of 3 years, after which the NTSB destroys the applications, pursuant to General Records Schedule 9.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Administrative Operations, Safety and Security Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB employees and supervisors, NTSB Administrative Operations, Safety and Security Division.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb12" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-12</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Travel Card Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Chief Financial Officer, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains credit card applications, a list of terms and conditions for use of credit cards, credit card training documentation, monthly reports regarding accounts, credit data, and related documentation, all of which may include an individual's name, Social Security number, and personal contact information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 5701; 31 U.S.C. 716, 1104, 3511-3512, 3701, 3711, 3717-3718, 3726; 41 CFR parts 301-304; Exec. Order No. 9,397, 8 FR 16,095 (Nov. 30, 1943); Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2005, Public Law 108-447, &#167; 639, 118 Stat. 2809 (2004).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB collects information for this system in order to facilitate the process of obtaining travel cards for NTSB employees. Such travel cards are necessary for the provision of funds for employees' official travel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to the General Services Administration and the Office of Management and Budget for periodic reporting required by statute, regulation, and/or Executive Order;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to the bank that issued the credit card, for necessary record-keeping purposes;
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the National Business Center of the Department of Interior, for facilitating collection of travel card delinquencies by employee salary offset; and
</p><p>4. Disclosure to a consumer reporting agency, for the purpose of obtaining the credit reports necessary to provide the credit cards, and not for the purposes listed at 5 U.S.C. 552(b)(12) (referring to Debt Collection Act).
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None, except as described at 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains the information in this system in file folders in an electronic database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are indexed by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Computerized records are maintained in a secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retains electronic records in this system until the NTSB no longer needs the records because the employee separates from Federal service and no pending claims on the employee's credit card exists, or until the retention period for the records has expired, pursuant to General Records Schedule 9.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Accounting Division, Office of Chief Financial Officer, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains information in this system from NTSB employees, the bank issuing the credit card, the consumer reporting agency, and outside vendors who have provided travel services or accommodations to an NTSB employee for the employee's official travel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb13" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-13</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Airman or Mariner Certificate Enforcement Actions.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Primary system: Office of Administrative Law Judges, NTSB, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Upon assignment of a case to an NTSB Administrative Law Judge (ALJ) located in Texas, the case file is maintained at 624 Six Flags Drive, Suite 150, Arlington, Texas 76011; upon assignment of a case to an NTSB ALJ in Colorado, the case file is maintained at 4760 Oakland Street, Suite 500, Denver, Colorado 80239. When a party appeals the decision of the NTSB ALJ, the Office of Administrative Law Judges transfers the case's docket file to the NTSB Office of General Counsel, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594, until the Safety Board has served a final ruling on the appeal, at which time the Office of General Counsel transfers the docket file back to the Office of Administrative Law Judges.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who hold airman certificates who have been subject to Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) enforcement actions, or to whom the FAA has denied certification; and mariners who hold maritime licenses, certificates, documents, or registers who have been subject to U.S. Coast Guard enforcement actions or certificate denials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The system includes, but is not limited to, the petition or appeal filed by an airman, pleadings from both parties in the case; motions and responses filed by the parties; relevant documents related to these actions (i.e., Orders of Revocation, Orders of Suspension, Orders of Assessment, Denials of applications for issuance of airman certificates); hearing notices, transcripts of hearings, exhibits introduced during hearings; and Administrative Law Judges' decisions. For cases that a party appeals to the full five-member Board, records will include the following additional categories: Notice of Appeal for review of the Judge's decision, and briefs in support of that appeal; the Board's Opinion and Order resulting from the review; and other correspondence that is initiated by the Board, or parties pertaining to the case. Where a case arises out of a U.S. Coast Guard action, records will include: hearing notices, pleadings from both parties in the case; motions and responses filed by the parties; in addition, if a hearing occurred, records will include the transcript of testimony and exhibits from the hearing; the decision of the Administrative Law Judge, the U.S. Coast Guard order; the Notice of Appeal of the Commandant's decision; parties' appeal briefs; and the Commandant's decision on appeal.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>44 U.S.C. 216B, 239-a-b; 49 U.S.C. 1133, 44106, 44703, 44709, 44710, and 46301.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system in order to fulfill Congress's statutory directive of deciding airman and mariner appeals, in accordance with 49 U.S.C. 1133; the NTSB manages the case load and tracks all documents related to cases in this system of records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure in response to discovery ordered by a court, in accordance with 49 U.S.C. 1153; and
</p><p>2. Publicly available records within the system, which the Privacy Act does not preclude from disclosure (e.g., final decisions issued by ALJs and the Board), are available on the NTSB Web site, <i>http://www.ntsb.gov.</i>
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are primarily maintained on paper in docket folders. In addition, the Office of Administrative Law Judges maintains certain information and documents regarding each case in a searchable electronic database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The electronic database is indexed by names of the certificate holder who is the subject of the action and by docket numbers, which are assigned when individual cases are received and docketed. Paper docket files are indexed by the airman's or mariner's surname.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in locked file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper docket files for one year following the disposition of the case. After the one-year period has expired, the NTSB sends files to the Federal Records Center, National Archives and Records Administration, which destroys the files after 15 years in cases for which a hearing occurred, or after 6 years in cases in which no hearing occurred.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Manager, ALJ Operations, National Transportation Safety Board, Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Certificate Number; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB primarily obtains information in the records from the individual to whom a record pertains, authorized representatives for these individuals, from information supplied by the certificate holder, and attorneys and other representatives from the FAA and the U.S. Coast Guard.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb14" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-14</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Information Request Database
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Chief Information Officer, Records Management Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals seeking publicly available information from the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains the individual's name, address, telephone number, email address, and a description of the requested records. The list may also include the requester's title, occupation, and institutional affiliation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552(a)(2); 49 U.S.C. 1131(e).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system in order to provide individuals and organizations, at their request, with publicly available information that the NTSB produces.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB may disclose information from this system of records in accordance with subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and as described in Appendix A, below.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained on paper and electronically in databases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retrieves records in this system by individual name, company name, accident date, accident location, accident investigation number and mailing list title.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in lockable file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retains these records until the request has been fulfilled and the individual requests removal from the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Records Management Officer, National Transportation Safety Board, Office of the Chief Information Officer, Records Management Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of correspondence; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who provide their name and mailing address directly to the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb15" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-15</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">NTSB Staff Database.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Chief Information Officer, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All individuals who have a domain account on the agency's network. These individuals include: Former and current NTSB employees, consultants, contractors, interns, and employees from other Federal agencies who are temporarily assigned to work at the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records within this system include the individual's name; photograph; personal or agency-issued cell phone number(s); and a history of the individual's previous employment positions and titles, including date ranges, contact information of the previous employer, and the individual's managerial status in such positions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Information Security Management Act, enacted as Title III of E-Government Act of 2002, Public Law 107-347, 116 Stat. 2899 (codified at 44 U.S.C. 3541 <i>et seq.</i>)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB uses the data in this system to control access to various NTSB applications that require a listing of employees by office and position. The NTSB also generates a listing of employees' names and offices for an internal office telephone directory from this list.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine use:
</p><p>Disclosure to other Federal agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB stores all records in this system electronically in a database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by name and office identifier, and can be retrieved using the web-based graphical user interface.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains these computerized records in a secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the username, date and time of any additions or edits is logged. The Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: the Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this data for the duration of the use of the applications for which the data supports. The NTSB marks inactive or former employees as such, but maintains the data for historical relevance and auditing purposes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Systems Support Division, Office of the Chief Information Officer, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains the information for records within this system from the individual, after the individual has provided the information to the NTSB Office of Administration, Human Resources Division.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb16" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-16</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Correspondence, Notations, and Safety Recommendations.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of the Managing Director, Safety Recommendations and Quality Assurance Division, Executive Secretariat, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Members of the public, other government agencies, Members of Congress, the White House, and members of private industry seeking information from or about the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains the individual's name, address, and other contact information, as well as a description of the subject of the correspondence or request, and a copy of the incoming correspondence. The record may also include the requester's title, occupation, and institutional affiliation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552(a)(2); 49 U.S.C. 1131(e).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system in order to verify receipt, generate a response, and establish a record of correspondence addressed to the head of the agency or that requires the signature of the Chairman or an NTSB office director.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB may disclose information in accordance with subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and as described in Appendix A, below.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB office that drafts the response to the correspondence stores an electronic copy in this system on a secure, password-protected computer network server; the NTSB Office of the Managing Director stores some categories of information electronically in the system. The NTSB may transmit some records to other offices within the NTSB when a response to the correspondence requires input from another office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by individual's name, organization, date of correspondence, date of response, and subject matter.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a secure, password protected computer network server. Access to and use of these records is limited to authorized users of the system whose official duties require such access. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: the Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB permanently maintains records in the electronic system. The NTSB maintains corresponding paper records within this system until the expiration of 3 years following the final response to the correspondence, after which the NTSB destroys the records by shredding them.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Secretariat, Office of the Managing Director, Safety Recommendations and Quality Assurance Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date and subject of correspondence; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who provide their name and mailing address directly to the NTSB in their correspondence.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb17" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-17</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of Transportation Disaster Assistance Family Member Database.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Transportation Disaster Assistance, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Family members of those fatally injured and survivors of transportation accidents that are or have been the subject of an NTSB investigation
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name and contact information of victims of transportation accidents, as well as the names and contact information for victims' family members and legal next-of-kin.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>49 U.S.C. 1136 and 49 U.S.C. 1139.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB uses this system to maintain mailing and telephone contact information in order to provide services and information to survivors of transportation accidents, and/or fatally injured family members and next-of-kin.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine use:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to other government agencies, when necessary to determine whether the victim and/or family member has received information or services in accordance with 49 U.S.C. 1136(c) and 49 U.S.C. 1139(c); and
 
</p><p>2. Disclosure to state police or other agencies, when necessary for safety of Federal employees;
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the FBI Office for Victim Assistance if the investigation becomes criminal in order to provide federal crime victim service under Victims' Right and Restitution Act (42 U.S.C. 10607) and the Crime Victims' Rights Act (18 U.S.C. 3771).
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB stores information electronically in a database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The database containing information in this system is searchable by NTSB investigation number and date and location of transportation accident.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The computerized records that compose this system of records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains the records in this system indefinitely, unless an individual requests removal from the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Transportation Disaster Assistance, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date, location, or NTSB investigation identifier pertaining to the accident investigation from which the NTSB created the record; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals directly submit their own contact information for inclusion in the database; the NTSB may also obtain information from other Federal agencies who provide assistance to victims and victims' family members, or from transportation operators who may have passenger lists.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb18" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-18</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Correspondence from Members of Congress.
 
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Communications, Government Affairs Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Senators, Members of Congress, and congressional staff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests and written correspondence from Senators, Members of Congress, and congressional staff, Safety Board responses to congressional correspondence, and records regarding the Safety Board's preparation of responses to congressional inquiries and correspondence.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 552(a)(2); 49 U.S.C. 1101-1155.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB utilizes this system to track and provide timely responses to inquiries and correspondence from Senators, Members of Congress, and congressional staff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine use:
</p><p>Disclosure to other government agencies, when necessary, to respond to congressional inquiries or correspondence from Members of Congress.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains these records in paper folders within file cabinets and in an electronic database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by the surname of the Senator or Member of Congress.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in a secure, password-protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains these documents until the Senator or Member of Congress is no longer serving in Congress, or until the NTSB determines that it no longer needs the record after the NTSB has responded to the request or inquiry. The NTSB destroys records by shredding them.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Communications, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Subject of original correspondence; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Senators, Members of Congress, congressional staff, and employees of other Federal agencies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb19" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-19</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Training Center Student Registration Database
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB Training Center, 45065 Riverside Parkway, Ashburn, Virginia 20147.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Students, members of the public, NTSB employees, and employees of state and Federal agencies who have registered to attend training course(s) at the NTSB Training Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records consist of course applications and the revenue collected for all training courses that are offered to the public and to NTSB employees. The applications include, but are not limited to, the registrant's name, address, telephone and fax number, email address, country, and payment information.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>49 U.S.C. 1115 and 1118(c).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB uses this system to register students, issue student transcripts and certificates of completion of training programs, and record associated tuition payment for training courses at the NTSB Training Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to the Department of Interior, National Business Center, for processing credit card or check payments for tuition, tuition refunds, or for collection of delinquencies;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to the Department of State or an embassy for passports or visas, or for responding to request for disclosing international students and associated countries, and tuition collected;
</p><p>3. Disclosure of limited information to an employer for verification of training completed;
</p><p>4. Disclosure of limited information to a college or university as students requesting student transcripts; and
</p><p>5. Disclosure to Congress for annual reporting requirements.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies: 
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB stores the electronic database in a system on a SQL server. The NTSB maintains some paper folders, which the NTSB keeps in a locked cabinet at the NTSB Training Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by registrant's name or by student identification code assigned by the Office of the Assistant to the Associate Managing Director for the NTSB Training Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in locked file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The Training Center maintains student records in the electronic system for 10 years and paper files for 7 years, in accordance with the budgeting and financial management policy.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Assistant to Associate Managing Director for NTSB Training Center, 45065 Riverside Parkway, Ashburn, Virginia 20147.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Employer;
</p><p>3. Description of course that the individual attended or applied to attend;
</p><p>4. Student identification number; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains information for this system from course applications that persons seeking to register for a training course submit to the NTSB Training Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb20" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-20</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Public Affairs Phone Log
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Public Affairs, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Journalists who contact the NTSB Public Affairs Office.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Name of caller, affiliation, phone number, email address, subject of the call, and additional relevant comments.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>49 U.S.C. 1101-1155; 49 CFR 800.2(b) and 831.13(a).
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system to keep a log of telephone activity for the Office of Public Affairs as it pertains to news media representatives.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB may disclose information in accordance with subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and as described in Appendix A, below.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains records within this system in an electronic database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The database containing these records is searchable by name, affiliation, subject matter, or NTSB public affairs officer who handled the telephone call.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains the computerized records in this system of records in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains the records in this system indefinitely.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Office of Public Affairs, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Subject of original correspondence; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Journalists who contact the NTSB Office of Public Affairs via telephone.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb21" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-21</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Respiratory Protection Program Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Administration, Administrative Operations, Safety and Security Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current employees who have received medical clearance and have been trained to don a half-face negative pressure respirator.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee name, date of birth, office location, job title, date of last medical clearance, date of last physical exam, medical clearance expiration date, suggested activity level while donning a respirator, date of training, date of fit test and type of respirator issued.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>29 U.S.C. 653, 655, and 657; 29 CFR 1910.134(m).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB uses this system to document employee medical qualifications and training for respirator usage pursuant to OSHA regulations, 29 CFR 1910.134(m).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
 
</p><p>1. Disclosure to other Federal agencies, such as the Department of Labor or the Office of Personnel Management, that need the information for an audit; and
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other Federal agencies when necessary for the investigation of a potential civil, criminal, or regulatory violation.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains these records in an electronic database and in paper file folders within a lockable file cabinet.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>All records in this system are indexed by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a lockable file cabinet that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retains records within this system indefinitely, but will destroy the records when the NTSB determines it no longer needs the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Occupational Safety and Health Specialist, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza, SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals to whom the records apply, the individual's supervisor (if the individual was referred to the program by his or her supervisor), and the Occupational Safety and Health Specialist.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb22" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-22</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Occupational Safety and Health Training Program.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Administration, Administrative Operations, Safety and Security Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All current NTSB employees, interns, volunteers, contractors, and employees from other Federal agencies who may be on assignment at the NTSB. In addition, this system may include records concerning former NTSB employees, depending upon when the employee separated from the NTSB, as described below.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Employee name, Social Security number, office location, job title, and indication of whether employee has completed necessary training under the NTSB Occupational Safety and Health Program.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>29 U.S.C. 668 and 673; 29 CFR 1960.59.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system in order to document employee safety and health training, as required by 29 CFR 1960.59.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB may disclose information from this system of records in accordance with subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains these records in an electronic database and in paper file folders within a lockable file cabinet.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>All records in this system are indexed by name, training course(s) assigned, and scores of quizzes administered during the training.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a lockable file cabinet that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retains electronic and paper records until the expiration of five years after the employee leaves the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Occupational Safety and Health Specialist, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza, SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security Number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals to whom the records apply, the individual's supervisor (if the individual was referred to the program by his or her supervisor), and the Manager of the Occupational Safety and Health Program.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb23" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-23</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Transit Subsidy Program Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Administration, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB employees who apply for transit subsidy benefits from the Federal government.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records consist of Transit Subsidy applications which include, but are not limited to, the applicant's name, address, telephone number, last four digits of Social Security number, office division, commuting costs, and employee certification. The NTSB collects these transit subsidy applications on a regular annual basis.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 7905; 26 U.S.C. 132(f)(2); IRS Revenue Procedure 2004-71, section 132(f)(2)(A).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system of records in order to provide transit subsidy benefits to eligible NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to the Department of Transportation, for administration of the transit subsidy program and distribution of benefits to eligible recipients;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to officials of labor organizations under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when relevant and necessary to the organizations' duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting working conditions; and
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the Internal Revenue Service for taxable earnings and withholding purposes, or for audit and inspection and investigation purposes, when necessary.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains records within this system in paper file folders within a lockable file cabinet and in an electronic database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by employee's name or last four digits of employee's Social Security number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a lockable file cabinet that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>As stated above, the NTSB collects transit subsidy applications on a regular annual basis. The NTSB retains applications for a period of 3 years, after which the NTSB destroys the applications, pursuant to General Records Schedule 9.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Administrative Operations, Safety and Security Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
 
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Last four digits of Social Security Number;
</p><p>3. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>4. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees who apply for transit subsidy benefits, applicants' supervisors, the NTSB Office of Administration, and the Department of Transportation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb24" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-24</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Facility Security Access Control System.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Administration, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All individuals and personnel that require access to NTSB Headquarters and regional office facilities. This includes NTSB employees, contractors, temporary employees, interns, property managers, volunteer workers, and any persons that the NTSB may permit to access NTSB facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records consist of electronic cardholder information, which includes, but is not limited to, the individual's name, keycard number, personal identification number, access level, and cardholder history and transaction reports.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Federal Information Security Management Act, enacted as Title III of E-Government Act of 2002, Public Law 107-347, 116 Stat. 2899 (codified at 44 U.S.C. 3541 <i>et seq.</i>)
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system to provide individuals with an electronic keycard to access secured office space and areas within the NTSB headquarters and regional office facilities.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to property managers for building maintenance and/or security purposes; and
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other Federal agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Sotrage:</p><p>The NTSB maintains this system in specialized electronic database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records within this system are indexed by individual's name, keycard number, personal identification number, and access level.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains the computerized records within this system in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and this System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB retains information in this database for periods of up to six months. The database runs on a regular schedule with regard to deleting records within the database after the passage of approximately six months; deletion of records older than six months occurs on a rolling basis.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Administrative Operations, Safety and Security Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who require access to NTSB headquarters and regional offices.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb25" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-25</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Purchase Card Holders.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Administration, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB employees who apply for and use NTSB-assigned purchase cards.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system includes personal information on individuals who apply for and use Federal charge cards, including individuals' names, Social Security numbers, business addresses (including city, state, country, and zip code), title or position, business telephone, business fax number, and business email address. This system also includes account processing and management information, such as purchase authorizations and vouchers, charge card applications, charge card receipts, terms and conditions for card use, charge card transactions, contractor monthly reports showing charges to individual account numbers, account balances, and other data needed to authorize, account for, and pay authorized purchase card expenses. The NTSB also maintains in this system a master list of open accounts that includes: Cardholder names; transaction and card limits; cardholder business address and business telephone number; and the name of the official who has approved purchases using the purchase card(s).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>40 U.S.C. 501-502; 41 U.S.C. chapter 4; Executive Order Nos. 9,397 and 12,931.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB uses this system to establish and maintain accurate records necessary for operating, controlling, and managing a purchase charge card program involving commercial purchases by authorized NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to a Federal, state, local, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or carrying out a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where an agency becomes aware of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to labor organization officials to provide information defined under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when the information is relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions;
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the Government Accountability Office (GAO) or other Federal agencies when such agencies require the information to carry out their respective missions, such as conducting an audit;
</p><p>4. Disclosure to an expert, consultant, or contractor in the performance of a Federal duty to which the information is relevant, including issuance of purchase cards; and
</p><p>5. Disclosure to the National Business Center of the Department of Interior, for facilitating collection of travel card delinquencies by employee salary offset.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>The NTSB may disclose records within this system to a consumer reporting agency when such disclosure is compliant with 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage: 
</p><p>The NTSB stores records within this system on paper in file folders, and stores certain information from the paper records in electronic media.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed by name, credit card number, credit limits and scores, and Social Security numbers.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a lockable file cabinet that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: the Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB destroys these records after the expiration of 3 years subsequent to the NTSB's final payment for the purchase, in accordance with subpart 4.805 of the Federal Acquisition Regulations and General Records Schedule 3, item 3a(1)(b).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Acquisition &amp; Lease Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains information in this system from individuals submitting Purchase Card applications, monthly contractor reports, purchase records, managers, other agencies, and non-Federal sources such as private firms.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb26" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-26</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Office of Workers' Compensation Claim Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. In addition, the NTSB may transfer records within this system to the Department of Labor, which maintains the records in accordance with DOL/GOVT-1.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current or former NTSB employees who report an occupational injury or illness.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system of records contains information regarding the location and descriptions of an employee's injury or illness, treatment, and disposition of the claim, as well as copies of Office of Workers' Compensation Program claim forms, adjudication decisions, and hearing transcripts.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 8101-8193.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system in accordance with statutory requirements regarding the availability of workers' compensation, and the handling of claims for workers' compensation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine use:
</p><p>Disclosure to the Department of Labor in accordance with an authorized representative under Department of Labor regulations, and to prepare periodic statistical reports on employees' health and injury status for transmission to and review by the Department of Labor (DOL).
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None, except as described at 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(12).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains these records on paper within file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The records within this system are indexed by employee name, organization, date of injury or illness, and assigned DOL claim number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a locked file cabinet that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB destroys employee case files 5 years after the disposition of the worker's compensation claim, in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration's General Records Schedule 1, item 34.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Human Resources Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains information for records in this system from: Claimants; NTSB supervisors or employees whose official duties require the processing of such claims; and Occupational Safety and Health Administration, within the Department of Labor.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb27" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-27</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Performance Folders.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records regarding current NTSB employees are located at: National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Records regarding former NTSB employees who have not transferred to another Federal agency are located at the National Personnel Records Center, National Archives and Records Administration, 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63118.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records within this system reflect Federal employees' annual performance appraisals, and documents in connection with incentive awards. All categories of records include identifying information, such as employee's name, social security number, and date of birth.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. chapter 43; 5 CFR part 293.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system of records to keep reports of incentive award personnel actions and employee's annual performance appraisals. This system of records is the repository of basic factual data about an employee's performance while in the service for the Federal government. Records in this system have various uses by the agency Human Resources Division, including employee relations purposes and audit purposes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to labor organization officials to provide information defined under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when the information is relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other Federal or foreign agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation of a civil, criminal, or regulatory violation or potential violation;
</p><p>3. Disclosure to any source from which the NTSB requests additional information for processing any of the covered actions or in regard to an appeal or administrative review procedure, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested;
</p><p>4. Disclosure to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with hiring or retaining an employee, issuing a security clearance, conducting a security or suitability investigation of an individual, or classifying jobs, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decisions on the matter;
</p><p>5. Disclosure to another Federal agency, to a court, or to a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal agency, when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding;
</p><p>6. Disclosure to other agencies or contractors for other agencies, when disclosure is necessary to locate individuals for personnel research or survey response and in producing summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the other organization seeks to collect the record, or for related workforce studies; the NTSB notes that, while published statistics and studies do not contain individual identifiers, in some instances the selection of elements of data included in the study may be structured in such a way as to make the data individually identifiable by inference;
</p><p>7. Disclosure to a party engaged in litigation of information that is relevant to subject matter concerning a pending judicial or administrative proceeding, when such disclosure is subject to discovery or order from a court with competent jurisdiction; and
</p><p>8. Disclosure to the Merit System Protection Board in connection with appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of agency rules and regulations, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices, and such other functions, as promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, and as specified in 5 U.S.C. 7503(c) and 7513(e), or as may be authorized by any other applicable statute.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>  
<p>The NTSB maintains these records on paper within file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are indexed by name, date of birth, and Social Security number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a locked file room that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains each employee's Employee Performance Folder for the period of the employee's service in the agency. When an employee transfers to another Federal agency, the NTSB transmits these records to the new agency. When an employee retires, resigns or dies, the NTSB forwards the employee's record to the National Personnel Records Center.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Administrative Services Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB employees, supervisors, officials with the NTSB Office of Administration and Human Resources Division, and management officials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb28" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-28</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Medical Folders.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Records regarding current NTSB employees are located at: National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. 
</p><p>Records regarding former NTSB employees who have not transferred to another Federal agency are located at the National Personnel Records Center, National Archives and Records Administration, 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63118.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records reflecting Federal employees' medical documentation and any documents pertaining to an employee's medical condition(s), including medical reports, forms, and reports generated as a result of requests for work accommodations or benefits related to a medical condition. All categories of records may include identifying information, such as employee's name, Social Security number, date of birth, and any medical condition.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 1302; 5 CFR 501-511.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system of records is the official repository of employees' medical records; the NTSB maintains the records in this system for employee relation purposes, for handling potential work performance issues, and for audit purposes. The NTSB also maintains the records in this system in order to ensure that all relevant, necessary, accurate, and timely data are available to support any medical-related employment decisions affecting the subject of the records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to labor organization officials to provide information defined under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when the information is relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other agencies or contractors for other agencies, when disclosure is necessary to locate individuals for personnel research or survey response and in producing summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the other organization seeks to collect the record, or for related workforce studies; the NTSB notes that, while published statistics and studies do not contain individual identifiers, in some instances the selection of elements of data included in the study may be structured in such a way as to make the data individually identifiable by inference; and
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the Merit System Protection Board in connection with appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of agency rules and regulations, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices, and such other functions, as promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, and as specified in 5 U.S.C. 7503(c) and 7513(e), or as may be authorized by any other applicable statute.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains the records in this system on paper within file folders.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are indexed by name, date of birth, and Social Security number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a locked file room that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the area where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: the Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The Employee Medical Folder is maintained for the period of the employee's service in the agency. When an employee leaves the agency, these records are either transferred with the employee to the new agency or once an employees either retires, resigns or dies, the record is forwarded to the National Personnel Records Center for permanent storage, in accordance with General Records Schedule 1, item 21.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Human Resources Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB employees, supervisors, officials with the NTSB Office of Administration and Human Resources Division, other Federal agencies, and management officials
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb29" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-29</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Job Application and Merit Promotion Files.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees; applicants for NTSB employment.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records regarding current NTSB employees and applicants for NTSB employment and merit promotion within the NTSB, including Form OF-612, applicants' names, Social Security numbers, home addresses, vacancy announcements, employment history, training and educational background, examination results, supervisors' evaluations, and other records relevant to an individual's application for a position or promotion at the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 3301-3397, 5101-5115.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system of records in order to process and respond to applications for employment or promotion at the NTSB.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to labor organization officials to provide information defined under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when the information is relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting work conditions;
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other agencies or contractors for other agencies, when disclosure is necessary to locate individuals for personnel research or survey response and in producing summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the other organization seeks to collect the record, or for related workforce studies; the NTSB notes that, while published statistics and studies do not contain individual identifiers, in some instances the selection of elements of data included in the study may be structured in such a way as to make the data individually identifiable by inference;
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the Merit System Protection Board in connection with appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of agency rules and regulations, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices, and such other functions, as promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, and as specified in 5 U.S.C. 7503(c) and 7513(e), or as may be authorized by any other applicable statute; and
</p><p>4. Disclosure to the Office of Federal Employees Life Insurance or to health insurance carriers to provide benefit information regarding NTSB employees.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies: </p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>The NTSB maintains the records in this system concerning merit promotions on paper within file folders. The NTSB maintains the records in this system concerning job applications in an electronic database.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records concerning merit promotions are indexed by name, date of birth, and Social Security number; records concerning applications for employment are indexed by applicant's name and by vacancy announcement number.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a locked file cabinet that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Computerized records are maintained in secure, password protected computer system. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB destroys records from this system concerning each vacancy or promotion under merit competition procedures after 2 years following either the date of the selection of a candidate for the position or the conclusion of an Office of Personnel Management audit, whichever is sooner, in accordance with General Records Schedule 1, item 32.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Administrative Services Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
 
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment or NTSB service; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Applicants for NTSB positions, NTSB employees, supervisors, officials with the NTSB Office of Administration and Human Resources Division, other Federal agencies, and management officials
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb30" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-30</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Training Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB Training Center, 45065 Riverside Parkway, Ashburn, Virginia 20147.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current NTSB employees.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records include employee's name and Social Security number, business and home address, and person to be notified in case of emergency. Records reflect career development plans, training courses that individuals seek to attend or have attended, and any related records concerning mentoring or career progression of employees. This system also includes employees' Individual Development Plans.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 301 <i>et seq.,</i> 2951, 3301, 4101-4121, 4302; 5 CFR part 293.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system in order to create and maintain a list of training needs for developing future training initiatives, and to assess individuals' training in the interest of evaluating individuals' skill levels.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to educational institutions on appointment of a recent graduate to a position in the Federal service; and
</p><p>2. Disclosure to officials of labor organizations under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when relevant and necessary to the organizations' duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting working conditions.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are stored on paper in file folders at the NTSB Training Center, at the address above. The NTSB may scan all paper records into a learning management system, which will function as the master database of all training activities and records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are indexed by name, within major topic categories. Once the NTSB begins using the aforementioned new database, records will be retrievable by name, office, keyword, class title, and date of training class.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in locked file cabinets that are further secured in locked rooms that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains records within this system for the period of the employee's service at the NTSB. When an employee leaves the NTSB to begin employment at another Federal agency, the NTSB transfers these records to the employee's new Federal agency. When an employee retires, resigns, or dies, the NTSB forwards the employee's record to the National Personnel Records Center. The NTSB or National Personnel Records Center will destroy these records by shredding them once they are either obsolete or 5 years old, in accordance with General Records Schedule 1, item 29b.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>NTSB Training Officer, 45065 Riverside Parkway, Ashburn, Virginia 20147.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Social Security number;
</p><p>3. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>4. Signature.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains information in this system from the individual to whom the record pertains and NTSB officials responsible for the individual's career development and training.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb31" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-31</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Labor-Management Relations Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Human Resources Division, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former National Transportation Safety Board employees and union representatives.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains files on grievances and arbitrations filed pursuant to grievance procedures negotiated in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 7121, including reports of interviews, correspondence with arbitrators, hearing transcripts, arbitration awards, exceptions (i.e., appeals) to the Federal Labor Relations Authority, and related correspondence and exhibits.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>5 U.S.C. 7101-7135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains this system of records in order to comply with 5 U.S.C. 7101-7135.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:
</p><p>1. Disclosure to labor organization officials to provide information defined under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71, when the information is relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting working conditions (but information covered by 5 U.S.C. 7114(b)(4)(c) need not be released to labor organizations);
</p><p>2. Disclosure to other agencies or contractors for other agencies, when disclosure is necessary to locate individuals for personnel research or survey response and in producing summary descriptive statistics and analytical studies in support of the function for which the other organization seeks to collect the record, or for related workforce studies; the NTSB notes that, while published statistics and studies do not contain individual identifiers, in some instances the selection of elements of data included in the study may be structured in such a way as to make the data individually identifiable by inference; and
</p><p>3. Disclosure to the Merit System Protection Board in connection with appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of agency rules and regulations, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel practices, and such other functions, as promulgated in 5 U.S.C. 1205 and 1206, and as specified in 5 U.S.C. 7503(c) and 7513(e), or as may be authorized by any other applicable statute.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Sotrage:</p><p>The NTSB maintains these records on paper in file folders within an automated file cabinet.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB indexes these records by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a locked file room that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the room where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: the Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB destroys these records 5 years after the final resolution of the case to which they apply, in accordance with General Records Schedule 1, item 28b.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief, Human Resources Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Date of birth;
</p><p>3. Social Security number;
</p><p>4. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>5. Signature.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB obtains the records in this system from NTSB employees and supervisors, NTSB Office of Administration, representatives of NTSB employees, arbitrators, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Service Impasse Panel, and the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>To the extent that any records in this system consist of attorney work product or attorney-client communications, 5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(5) may apply to preclude access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="ntsb32" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-32</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Public Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Name-Retrieved Ethics Program Records.
</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of General Counsel, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees who have filed financial disclosure statements under the requirements of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (hereinafter "Ethics Act"), as amended, or to whom the Ethics Act otherwise applies.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains information that is necessary for administration of all provisions of the Ethics Act and the Ethics Reform Act of 1989, as amended, and Executive Order 12,674, as modified. In particular, this system contains financial information, as well as information concerning: gifts received, certain liabilities, former employment, and assets placed in trust pending disposal. The NTSB incorporates by reference the text of OGE/GOVT-1 into this Notice; as such, this Notice contains a summary of the information and provisions of OGE/GOVT-1 and descriptions of how NTSB-5 is consistent with OGE/GOVT-1, and identifies any differences between NTSB-32 and OGE/GOVT-1. OGE/GOVT-1 is available at 68 FR 3098 (Jan. 22, 2003), as updated at 68 FR 24744 (May 8, 2003) and 76 FR 24489 (May 2, 2011).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, Public Law 95-521, 92 Stat. 1824 (codified as amended 5 U.S.C. 7301, 7351, 7353, and other scattered sections of 5 U.S.C.); 5 CFR part 2634; 31 U.S.C. 1353; Executive Order 12,674 (as modified by Executive Order 12,731).
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB collects the records in this system in order to comply with the Ethics Act, and implementing Office of Government Ethics (OGE) regulations and applicable Executive Orders. The collection of these records is necessary to assure compliance with statutory and regulatory requirements, and to preserve and promote the integrity of public officials and institutions. These requirements also include the NTSB's Designated Agency Ethics Official (DAEO) possession or maintenance of information that the DAEO researches or prepares for referral to an Inspector General or the Department of Justice, concerning employees or former employees of the Federal Government who are the subject of complaints of misconduct or alleged violations of ethics statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB notes that, when the Director or other authorized officials of OGE requests that the NTSB furnish OGE with records from this system, such disclosure will be in response to OGE's need for the records in the performance of their official duties under the Ethics Act, and other related statutes, regulations, and Executive Orders, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1). In addition to other disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, and described in Appendix A, below, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine use:
</p><p>1. Disclosure of information furnished by the reporting official, in accordance with provisions of section 105 of the Ethics Act, as amended, to any requesting person;
</p><p>2. Disclosure, in accordance with section 105 of the Ethics Act, as amended, and subject to the limitations contained in 18 U.S.C. 208(d)(1), of any determination granting an exemption pursuant to section 208(d)(1) or 18 U.S.C. 208(b)(3), to any requesting person;
</p><p>3. Disclosure of information to any source when necessary to obtain information relevant to a conflict-of-interest investigation or determination;
</p><p>4. Disclosure of public financial disclosure reports and any accompanying documents to reviewing officials in a new office, department, or agency when an employee transfers or is detailed from a covered position in one office, department, or agency to a covered position in another office, department, or agency.
</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:
</p><p>None.
 
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB primarily maintains these records on paper in file folders. In addition, the Office of General Counsel maintains certain information about current and former employees in searchable electronic databases.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are indexed alphabetically by name.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are maintained in locked file cabinets that are restricted through electronic keycards to enter the facility where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: The Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with General Records Schedule 25, the NTSB retains these records for a period of six years after filing, or for such other period of time as set forth in Schedule 25 for certain types of ethics records. The NTSB may retain records needed in an ongoing investigation for a period that exceeds six years, until the investigation no longer requires such records. At the expiration of the retention period, the NTSB destroys these records by shredding them.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Designated Agency Ethics Official, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 East L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Designated Agency Ethics Official at the following address: National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 5 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:
</p><p>1. Full name(s);
</p><p>2. Dates of employment; and
</p><p>3. Signature.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as "Notification Procedure."
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former NTSB employees, or designated persons on behalf of such employees, such as trustees, attorneys, accountants, bankers, or relatives; Federal officials who review the records to make conflict-of-interest determinations; persons alleging conflicts of interest or violations of other ethics laws, and persons contacted during any investigation of the allegations.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="ntsb33" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-33</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            Medical Investigation Catalog System (MEDICS).
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>National Transportation Safety Board, Office of Chief Information Officer, 490 L’Enfant Plaza SW, Washington, DC 20594.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Medical Officer(s), Office of Research and Engineering, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L’Enfant Plaza, SW, Washington, DC 20594, (202) 314-6031.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>49 U.S.C. chapter 11 and 49 CFR parts 802 and 831.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The purpose of MEDICS is to securely receive and store investigative health information records. The NTSB is an independent federal agency responsible for determining the probable cause of transportation accidents or incidents, conducting transportation safety research, promoting transportation safety, and assisting victims of transportation accidents and their families. In support of the agency’s statutory mandate, NTSB investigators, medical officers, and staff review health information records to  (1) determine the facts or circumstances of an accident or incident; (2) determine the probable cause of an accident or incident; (3) evaluate human performance or survival factors issues arising during an accident or incident investigation; (4) provide victim and family assistance following an accident or incident; (5) carry out special studies and investigations about transportation safety (including avoiding personal injury); and/or (6) examine techniques and methods of accident or incident investigation, and publish recommended procedures for accident or incident investigations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>MEDICS contains electronically recorded PII, including health information, which means any information that—</p>
                <p> (A) Is created or received by a health care provider, health plan, public health authority, employer, life insurer, school or university, health care clearinghouse, or federal, state, or local agency; and</p>
                <p> (B) Relates to the past, present, or future physical or mental health or condition of an individual; the provision of health care to an individual; and/or the past, present, or future payment for the provision of health care to an individual.</p>
                <p> MEDICS may also contain electronically recorded health information, as described by paragraph B above, from individuals, families, or other entities, whether created or received by or from one of the entities described in paragraph A above, and from accident sites and wreckage. For the NTSB’s purposes, health information includes any record of medical conditions or care, for example, notes from a health care provider; medical certification documentation such as Federal Aviation Administration blue ribbon files and commercial driver’s license long forms; results of any drug or toxicology tests; radiology images; autopsy reports; laboratory reports; prehospital patient care reports; ambulance run sheets or patient care reports; pharmacy records; billing and insurance information; results from a search of a prescription monitoring program; and any other official record related to an individual’s health or health care.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Health information is obtained from health care providers, insurers, employers, individuals, family members of accident victims, and the accident site and wreckage. The NTSB may also obtain health information from other federal, state, or local agencies.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> In addition to the disclosures permitted under the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b), the NTSB is establishing twelve routine uses under which the NTSB may disclose records contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected.</p>
                <p> 1. Records may be disclosed to a participant in an NTSB investigation, appointed pursuant to 49 CFR 831.11 to provide suitable technical expertise and assist in establishing the facts and circumstances of an accident. Participants may include representatives from operators or manufacturers involved in accidents or incidents, as well as representatives from federal, state, and local agencies. Participation is governed by 49 CFR part 831, and section 831.13 prohibits participants from further disseminating the information.</p>
                <p> 2. Records may be disclosed to other medical consultants or contractors not named under routine use number 1, as appropriate to enable consultation related to an NTSB investigation.</p>
                <p> 3. Records may be disclosed to a foreign government agency acting as an accredited representative to an NTSB investigation pursuant to Annex 13 of the International Convention on Civil Aviation, and any technical advisor assisting the accredited representative.  </p>
                <p> 4. Records may be disclosed to a foreign government agency when the NTSB is acting as an accredited representative to the foreign government agency’s investigation pursuant to Annex 13 of the International Convention on Civil Aviation.</p>
                <p> 5. Records may be disclosed to the public in a docket or report for an accident investigation, or in a safety study report. The NTSB is required to inform the public of the facts, circumstances, and probable cause of accidents, and to publish findings in safety studies and reports. 49 U.S.C. 1116, 1131(e). The NTSB will disclose a record or part of a record in a public docket or report only if (1) the subject of the record’s actions or decision making may have contributed to an accident or may be related to a safety hazard; (2) disclosure is reasonably necessary to support a finding, conclusion, and/or probable cause determination, or safety recommendation; and (3) the NTSB determines that the public’s and the NTSB’s interest in disclosure outweighs the individual’s privacy interest.</p>
                <p> 6. When information indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, records may be disclosed to the appropriate agency, whether federal, foreign, state, local, or tribal, or other public authority responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, if the information disclosed is relevant to any enforcement, regulatory, investigative or prosecutory responsibility of the receiving entity. This routine use  allows for disclosures other than those provided by the Privacy Act exemption for law enforcement activities, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(7). The law enforcement exemption requires the head of the agency requesting disclosure to make a written request specifying the records requested and the relevant law enforcement activity. The NTSB must be able to disclose a record relevant to a potential violation of law without a request from the agency to whom records are disclosed because the NTSB may be the first to discover the potential violation of law, and the NTSB must be able to confer with other agencies about whether it will relinquish investigative priority pursuant to 49 U.S.C. 1131(a)(2).</p>
                <p> 7. Records may be disclosed to a federal, foreign, state, local, or tribal agency that (1) performs safety related functions; (2) is not a participant to an NTSB investigation as described in routine use number1; and (3) is not conducting an investigation, enforcement action, or prosecution as described in routine use number 6, if the NTSB determines that disclosure would enable the receiving agency to take corrective action or address a safety risk.  </p>
                <p> 8. Records may be disclosed to an agency or organization that regulates, oversees, licenses, or accredits healthcare providers or organizations if the NTSB determines that a provider’s conduct or decision-making may warrant corrective action or creates a safety risk.</p>
                <p> 9. Records may be disclosed to the Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the NTSB is authorized to appear, when (1) the NTSB, or any component thereof; (2) any employee of the NTSB in his or her official capacity; (3) any employee of the NTSB in his or her individual capacity whom the Department of Justice or the NTSB has agreed to represent; or (4) the United States is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the NTSB determines that the records are both relevant and necessary to the litigation and the use of such records is deemed by the NTSB to be for a purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.</p>
                <p> 10. Records may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration or General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904, 2906.</p>
                <p> 11. Records may be disclosed to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the NTSB suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the NTSB has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the NTSB (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the NTSB’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p> 12. Records may be disclosed to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the NTSB determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>    MEDICS records are primarily maintained electronically in a database. Some paper records may also be kept, and their location will be identified in the database. Paper records whose location is identified in MEDICS will be secured in a locked file cabinet, a secure office, or both, and will be searchable only by NTSB accident investigation number, not by PII. Paper records that are uploaded to MEDICS are destroyed. The database may be accessed from NTSB approved computers. In the future, the database may become accessible from any computer that provides for an authorized user’s authentication.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>    Once an authorized user accesses MEDICS with his or her user ID and password, the MEDICS system is searchable by NTSB accident or incident number, accident city, accident state, accident country, and an individual’s name, age, and date of birth.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  MEDICS records that are disclosed in the NTSB’s public docket pursuant to routine use number 5 will be retained permanently. All other MEDICS records will be destroyed one year after the conclusion of the investigation or safety study to which the record relates, unless required to be retained under another record retention statute, regulation or court order.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals wishing to access information about themselves in this system of records may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L’Enfant Plaza, SW, Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, 49 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                <p>1. Full name(s)</p>
                <p>2. Date of birth</p>
                <p>3. If known, the date and location of the accident, incident, or occurrence, or the NTSB investigation identifier(s) for the investigation(s) in which the NTSB created or obtained the record</p>
                <p>4. Signature</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals wishing to amend their records should contact the agency office identified in the Record Access Procedure section and furnish such identifying information described in that section to identify the records to be amended. Individuals seeking amendment of their records must also follow the agency’s Privacy Act regulations, 49 CFR Part 802. Where the requested amendment implicates information provided by a third-party source, the agency will refer the individual to the source from which the agency obtained the information. The NTSB is not authorized to amend records from non-agency sources. Additionally, the NTSB is not authorized to direct a non-agency source to change or alter records.  Because medical practitioners may provide differing but equally valid medical judgments and opinions when making medical evaluations of an individual’s health status, review of requests from individuals seeking amendment of their medical records, beyond administrative correction such as association of a medical record with an incorrect individual, may be limited to consideration of including the differing opinion in the record rather than attempting to determine whether the original opinion is accurate.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the agency office listed in the Record Access Procedure section, and provide the identifying information described in that section.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>
                    None.
                </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>82 FR 23075.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="ntsb34" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-34</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>Religious Accommodation Request Records. NTSB-34.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records regarding prospective and current NTSB employees are located at: National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza SW., Washington, DC 20594. Records regarding former NTSB employees who have not transferred to another Federal agency are located at the National Personnel Records Center, National Archives and Records Administration, 111 Winnebago Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63118.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Director, Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, Diversity and Inclusion, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza East SW, Washington, DC 20594.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>5 U.S.C. 1302; 5 U.S.C. 301; 42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.; 42 U.S.C. 2000bb et seq.; 44 U.S.C. 3101; 29 C.F.R. part 1614; and E.O. 14043 (Sept. 9, 2021).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>This system of records contains information from prospective, current, and former NTSB employees who request or receive accommodations for sincerely held religious beliefs, practices, or observances. The NTSB maintains the records in this system to track and report the processing of requests for religious accommodations to comply with applicable laws and regulations and to preserve and maintain the confidentiality of religious information submitted by or on behalf of applicants or employees requesting an accommodation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Prospective, current, and former NTSB employees who request and/or receive a reasonable accommodation for a sincerely held religious belief, practice, or observance; and authorized individuals or representatives (e.g., family members or attorneys) who file a request for a religious accommodation on behalf of a prospective, current, or former employee.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Name and employment information of employees needing an accommodation; requestor’s name and contact information (if different than the employee who needs an accommodation); date request was initiated; information concerning the nature of the sincerely held religious belief, practice, or observance and the need for accommodation, including any appropriate documentation; details of the accommodation request, such as: type of accommodation requested, how the requested accommodation would assist in job performance, any additional information provided by the requestor related to the processing of the request, notes from or summaries of the interactive process, whether the request was approved or denied, including any alternative accommodation provided, and whether the accommodation was approved for a trial period; and notification(s) to the employee and his/her supervisor(s) regarding the accommodation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The individual to whom the record pertains and/or his or her representative; NTSB supervisors and management officials; officials with the NTSB Office of Administration and Human Resources Division and Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, Diversity and Inclusion; other Federal agencies; and religious officials or organizations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to the disclosures permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, the NTSB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the record was collected under the following routine uses:</p>
                <p>1. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management, Department of Labor, Merit Systems Protection Board, Office of the Special Counsel, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority (including the General Counsel of the Authority and the Federal Service Impasses Panel), the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, the White House and its executive offices, the Center for Disease Control and Prevention, the Department of Health &amp; Human Services, Federal Occupational Health, and the National Institutes of Health, and to an arbitrator, when that agency or office has jurisdiction or oversight over religious accommodation issues, in carrying out their functions, or to obtain advice regarding statutory, regulatory, policy, or other requirements, related to a religious accommodation;</p>
                <p>2. Disclosure to other Federal agencies that need the information for an audit or investigation of a civil, criminal, or regulatory violation or potential violation where a record, either on its face or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law;</p>
                <p>3. Where a contract between an NTSB office and a labor organization recognized under Executive Order No. 11,491 or 5 U.S.C. Chapter 71 provides that the agency will disclose personal records relevant to the organization's mission, the NTSB may disclose records in this system of records to such organization;</p>
                <p>4. Disclosure to a private entity with which the NTSB maintains a contractual relationship for the purposes of investigating discrimination claims, engaging in dispute resolution in connection with religious accommodations requests and/or discrimination claims, or collating, analyzing, aggregating or otherwise refining records in this system, where the private entity is subject to a non-disclosure agreement and understands that it must honor Privacy Act safeguards with respect to such records;</p>
                <p>5. In the event of litigation where the defendant is (a) the NTSB, any component of the NTSB, or any employee of the NTSB in his or her official capacity; (b) the United States, where the NTSB determines that the claim, if successful, is likely to directly affect the operations of the NTSB or any of its components; or (c) any NTSB employee in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent such employee, the NTSB may disclose such records as it deems relevant and necessary to the Department of Justice or NTSB’s outside counsel to enable the NTSB to present an effective defense, provided such disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected;</p>
                <p>6. Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained. The NTSB will not make such a disclosure until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request;</p>
                <p>7. To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the NTSB suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records, (2) the NTSB has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the NTSB (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the NTSB’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm;</p>
                <p>8. To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the NTSB determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The NTSB maintains the records in this system on paper within file folders and electronically, including on computer databases.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are indexed by employee or applicant name or the applicable NTSB office.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Religious Accommodation Request Records are maintained in accordance with General Records Schedule 2.3 (April 2020).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The NTSB maintains paper records within this system in a locked file room that is restricted through electronic keycards to enter the area where records are located. Access to and use of these records is limited to those persons whose official duties require such access, and the Facility Security Access Control System (NTSB-24) logs the date and time that each electronic keycard was used to enter the location. Electronic records are stored on protected computer networks that are accessible by authorized users with PIV cards and/or secure passwords. This system conforms to all applicable Federal laws and regulations, as well as NTSB policies and standards, as they relate to information security and data privacy. In this regard, the following laws and regulations may apply: the Privacy Act of 1974; the Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002; the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986; the E-Government Act of 2002; and corresponding regulations implementing these statutes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as "Notification Procedure."</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Same as "Notification Procedure."</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals wishing to inquire about whether this system of records contains information about them may contact the Chief, Records Management Division, National Transportation Safety Board, 490 L'Enfant Plaza East, SW., Washington, DC 20594. Individuals must comply with NTSB regulations regarding the Privacy Act, at 49 CFR part 802, and must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                <p>1. Full name(s);</p>
                <p>2. Dates of employment, NTSB service, or application; and</p>
                <p>3. Signature.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="office365MT" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-365</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> Religious and Disability Reasonable Accommodation Records within the Office 365 MT system.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Unclassified. </p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>395 E Street SW Washington, DC 20423, Office 365 MT is a multi-tenant cloud computing-based subscription service offering from Microsoft.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Greg Marzetta, Surface Transportation Board, 395 E Street SW, Suite 1027.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Rehabilitation Act of 1973; 29 U.S.C. Section 701 et seq.</p>
                <p>Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) as amended; 42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq. Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964; 42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</p>
                <p>Executive Order 13164 (July 28, 2000)</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>To allow the STB to collect, maintain and track records on current and former employees and applicants for employment with disabilities, who request and receive reasonable accommodation, as required by Sections 501, 504, and 701 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the ADA Amendments Act of 2008. In addition, to allow the STB to collect, maintain and track records on current and former employees and applicants and applicants who request religious accommodation as required by Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. The system will track the receipt, processing and disposition of requests for disability accommodation and religious accommodation to comply with applicable laws and regulations and to preserve and maintain confidentiality.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current and former</p>
                <p>Surface Transportation Board employees and applicants for employment at the Surface Transportation Board.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Case number, name, accommodation requested, date of request, job position, office/division, accommodation type, impairment, disability type, description of religious belief and/or practices, and case notes.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Information in this system comes from the employee/applicant to whom it applies (or their representative), members of the STB Reasonable Accommodation Advisory Panel, an employee’s supervisor, other required STB personnel and/or the treating physician(s) or medical institution.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to the disclosures  permitted under subsection (b) of the Privacy Act, the STB may disclose information contained in this system of records without the consent of the subject individual, if the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records was collected under the following routine uses:</p>
                a.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to provide information to OPM and/or MSPB for review, audit, or reporting purposes;</p>
                b.	<p>A record from this system of records that indicates a violation of civil or criminal law regulation or order may be referred as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency that has authority to investigate, enforce, implement or prosecute such laws;</p>
                c.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency, to obtain information relevant to an STB decision concerning hiring or retaining an employee, letting a contract, or issuing a security clearance, license, grant or other benefit;</p>
                d.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use, if it is relevant and necessary, in the course of discovery; in presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, administrative tribunal, or grand jury or pursuant to a qualifying order from any of those; in alternative dispute resolution proceedings, such as arbitration or mediation; or in the course of settlement negotiations;</p>
                e.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to a Congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the Congressional office made at the request of that individual;</p>
                f.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to STB experts or consultants, and those under contract with the STB on a "need-to-know" basis for a purpose within the scope of an STB task. This access will be granted to an STB contractor or employee of such contractor by a system manager only after satisfactory justification has been provided to the system manager;</p>
                g.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) STB suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the systems of records, (2) STB has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, STB (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to</p>
                <p>assist in connection with STB efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm; and</p>
                h.	<p>A record from this system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the STB determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding toa suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individual, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        i.	<subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Electronic records are stored on a secure server. Sensitive or confidential paper records are stored in a secured room or filing cabinet.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records are retrieved by employee/requester name or case number.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retained under the National Archives and Records Administration’s General Records Schedule 2.3: Employee Relations Records; 020 Reasonable Accommodation Case Files, Temporary. Destroy 3 years after employee separation from the agency or all appeals are concluded whichever is later, but longer retention is authorized if required for business use.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Only personnel</p>
                <p>with a "need to know" are authorized to access the records. Network access to electronic records is generally controlled by PIV-enabled or password-enabled authenticated user and limited according to job function. Additionally, access to the electronic records is only available from STB government furnished equipment. Access to hard-copy records is controlled by lock and key or by access to a secure area and is limited according to job function and "need to know".</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as "Notification Procedures".</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Same as "Notification Procedures"</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals seeking to determine whether this system of records contains information about them should write to the Freedom of Information Act or Privacy Act Officer at Surface Transportation Board, 395 E Street, SW, Washington, DC  20423,</p>
                <p>(202) 245-0458 (Fax), privacy@stb.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>






    <appendix id="app" toc="yes" letter="A">
<title> General Routine Uses Applicable to All Systems of Records </title>
<xhtmlContent><p>The NTSB may make the following disclosures of information from the above-listed systems of records.
</p><p><i>A. Disclosure for Law Enforcement Purposes  
</i></p><p>When information indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, disclosure may be made to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, foreign, State, local, or tribal, or other public authority responsible for enforcing, investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto, if the information disclosed is relevant to any enforcement, regulatory, investigative or prosecutive responsibility of the receiving entity. 
</p><p><i>B. Disclosure Incident to Requesting Information  
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to any source from which additional information is requested (to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and to identify the type of information requested), when necessary to obtain information relevant to an agency decision concerning retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a grant, or other benefit. 
</p><p><i>C. Disclosure to Requesting Agency  
</i></p><p>Disclosure may be made to a Federal, State, local, foreign, or tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other agency or licensing organization may then make a request supported by the written consent of the individual for the entire record if it so chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to another office within the agency or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action. 
</p><p><i>D. Disclosure to Congressional Offices  
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the written request of the individual about whom the record is maintained. The NTSB will not make such a disclosure until the congressional office has furnished appropriate documentation of the individual's request, such as a copy of the individual's written request. 
</p><p><i>E. Disclosure to Department of Justice  
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to the Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the NTSB is authorized to appear, when: 
</p><p>1. The NTSB, or any component thereof; or 
</p><p>2. Any employee of the NTSB in his or her official capacity; or 
</p><p>3. Any employee of the NTSB in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the NTSB has agreed to represent the employee; or 
</p><p>4. The United States is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the NTSB determines that the records are both relevant and necessary to the litigation and the use of such records is deemed by the NTSB to be for a purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected. 
</p><p><i>F. Disclosure to the National Archives and General Services Administration  
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration or General Services Administration for records management inspections conducted under 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906. 
</p><p><i>G. Disclosure to Contractors, Grantees, Etc.  
</i></p><p>Information may be disclosed to agency contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers who have been engaged to assist the agency in the performance of a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the NTSB related to this system of records and who need to have access to the records in order to perform the activity for the NTSB. This includes Federal agencies providing payroll, management, or administrative services to the NTSB. When appropriate, recipients shall be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974 as provided at 5 U.S.C. 552a(m). 
</p><p><i>H. Disclosures for Administrative Claims, Complaints and Appeals  
</i></p><p>Information from this system of records may be disclosed to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee or former employee, but only to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.
</p><p><i>I. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management  
</i></p><p>Information from this system of records may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to that agency's responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management. 
</p><p><i>J. Disclosure in Connection With Litigation  
</i></p><p>Information from this system of records may be disclosed in connection with litigation or settlement discussions regarding claims by or against the NTSB, including public filing with a court, to the extent that disclosure of the information is relevant and necessary to the litigation or discussions and except where court orders are otherwise required under section (b)(11) of the Privacy Act of 1974, codified at 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(11). 
</p><p><i>K. Disclosure to Persons or Entities in Response to an Actual or Suspected Compromise or Breach of Personally Identifiable Information  
</i></p><p>The NTSB may disclose information from any of the above-listed system of records to the appropriate agencies, entities, and/or persons when: (a) The NTSB suspects or has confirmed that the security or confidentiality of personally identifiable information in the system of records has been compromised; (b) the NTSB has determined that, as a result of the suspected or confirmed compromise, a risk of harm to economic or property interests, identity theft or fraud, or harm to the security or integrity of this system exists; and (c) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the NTSB's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed compromise and prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>
<appendix id="app" toc="yes" letter="B">
<title> General Routine Uses Applicable to All Systems of Records
</title>
	<xhtmlContent>
<p>As described in the above notices, some NTSB records may be located in the Government-wide systems of records listed below:
</p><p>1. EEOC/GOVT-1 Equal Employment Opportunity in the Federal Government Complaint and Appeal Records.
</p><p>2. DOL/GOVT-1 Office of Workers' Compensation Programs, Federal Employees' Compensation Act File.
</p><p>3. GSA/GOVT-3 Travel Charge Card Program.
</p><p>4. MSPB/GOVT-1 Appeals and Case Records.
</p><p>5. OGE/GOVT-1 Executive Branch Personnel Public Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Name-Retrieved Ethics Program Records.
</p><p>6. OGE/GOVT-2 Executive Branch Confidential Financial Disclosure Reports.
</p><p>7. OPM/GOVT-1 General Personnel Records.
</p><p>8. OPM/GOVT-2 Employee Performance File System Records.
</p><p>9. OPM/GOVT-3 Records of Adverse Actions, Performance Based Reduction in Grade and Removal Actions, and Termination of Probationers.
</p><p>10. OPM/GOVT-10 Employee Medical File System Records.
</p></xhtmlContent></appendix>
    
    
<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="49">
<heading> Transportation </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="VIII">
<heading> National Transportation Safety Board
</heading>
<regulationsPart number="802">
<heading> RULES IMPLEMENTING THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1974</heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart A--Applicability and Policy
</b></p>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>802.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>802.2 Definitions.
</p><p><b>Subpart B--Initial Procedures and Requirements
</b></p>
<p>802.5 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</p>
<p>802.6 Types of requests and specification of records.
</p>
<p>802.7 Requests: How, where, and when presented; verification of identity of individuals making requests; accompanying persons; and procedures for acknowledgement of requests.
</p><p><b>Subpart C--Initial Determinations
</b></p>
<p>802.8 Disclosure of requested information.
</p><p><b>Subpart D--Correction or Amending the Record
</b></p>
<p>802.10 Request for correction or amendment to record.
</p>
<p>802.11 Agency review of requests for correction or amendment of record.
</p>
<p>802.12 Initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
</p><p><b>Subpart E--Review of Initial Adverse Determination
</b></p>
<p>802.14 Review procedure and judicial review.
</p><p><b>Subpart F--Fees
</b></p>
<p>802.15 Fees.
</p><p><b>Subpart G--Penalties
</b></p>
<p>802.18 Penalties.
</p><p><b>Subpart H--Specific Exemptions
</b></p>
<p>802.20 Security records.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Privacy Act of 1974, Pub. L. 93-579, 88 Stat. 1896 (5 U.S.C. 552a); Independent Safety Board Act of 1974, Pub. L. 93-633, 88 Stat. 2166 (49 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.); and Freedom of Information Act, Pub. L. 93-502, November 21, 1974, amending 5 U.S.C. 552.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 41 FR 22358, June 3, 1976, unless otherwise noted.
</p><p><b>Subpart A--Applicability and Policy
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.1
 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>The purpose of this part is to implement the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a with respect to the availability to an individual of records of the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) maintained on individuals. NTSB policy encompasses the safeguarding of individual privacy from any misuse of Federal records and the provision of access to individuals to NTSB records concerning them, except where such access is in conflict with the Freedom of Information Act, or other statute.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 39758, Sept. 16, 1976]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>In this part:
</p>
<p><i>Board</i> means the five Members of the National Transportation Safety Board, or a quorum thereof;
</p>
<p><i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;
</p>
<p><i>National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB)</i> means the agency set up under the Independent Safety Board Act of 1974;
</p>
<p><i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained under the control of the NTSB pursuant to Federal law or in connection with the transaction of public business, including, but not limited to, education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history, and that contains a name, or an identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to an individual, such as a finger or voice imprint or photograph;
</p>
<p><i>Routine use</i> means the use of such record for a purpose compatible with the purpose for which it was collected, including, but not limited to, referral to law enforcement agencies of violations of the law and for discovery purposes ordered by a court referral to potential employers, and for security clearance;
</p>
<p><i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and which is not used wholly or partially in any determination concerning an identifiable individual;
</p>
<p><i>System Manager</i> means the agency official who is responsible for the policies and practices of his particular system or systems of record, as specified in the NTSB notices of systems or records; and
</p>
<p><i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of the NTSB from which information is retrieved by the name of an individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, whether presently in existence or set up in the future.
</p><p><b>Subpart B--Initial Procedures and Requirements
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.5
 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</b></p>
<p>The NTSB may not disclose any record to any person or other agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains, provided the record under the control of the NTSB is maintained in a system of records from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other particular assigned to such individual. Written consent is not required if the disclosure is:
</p>
<p>(a) To officers or employees of the NTSB who require the information in the official performance of their duties;
</p>
<p>(b) Required under 5 U.S.C. 552, Freedom of Information Act;
</p>
<p>(c) For a routine use compatible with the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(d) To the Bureau of the Census for uses pursuant to title 13, U.S.C.;
</p>
<p>(e) To a recipient who has provided the NTSB with advance adequate assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record and that it is to be transferred in a form not individually identifiable; or
</p>
<p>(f) Pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.6
 Types of requests and specification of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Types of requests.</i> An individual may make the following request respecting records about himself maintained by NTSB in any system of records subject to the Act:
</p>
<p>(1) Whether information concerning himself is contained in any system of records.
</p>
<p>(2) Access to a record concerning himself. Such request may include a request to review the record and/or obtain a copy of all or any portion thereof.
</p>
<p>(3) Correction or amendment of a record concerning himself.
</p>
<p>(4) Accounting of disclosure to any other person or Government agency of any record concerning himself contained in any system of records controlled by NTSB, except: (i) Disclosures made pursuant to the FOIA; (ii) disclosures made within the NTSB; (iii) disclosures made to another Government agency or instrumentality for an authorized law enforcement activity pursuant to subsection (b)(7) of the Act; and (iv) disclosures expressly exempted by NTSB from the requirements of subsection (c)(3) of the Act, pursuant to subsection (k) thereof.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Specification of records.</i> All requests for access to records must reasonably describe the system of records and the individual's record within the system of records in sufficient detail to permit identification of the requested record. Specific information regarding the system name, the individual's full name, and other information helpful in identifying the record or records shall be included. Requests for correction or amendment of records shall, in addition, specify the particular record involved, state the nature of the correction or amendment sought, and furnish justification for the correction or amendment.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Inadequate identification of record.</i> Requests which do not contain information sufficient to identify the record requested will be returned promptly to the requester, with a notice indicating what information is lacking. Individuals making requests in person will be informed of any deficiency in the specification of the records at the time the request is made. Individuals making requests in writing will be notified of any such deficiency when their request is acknowledged.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.7
 Requests: How, where, and when presented; verification of identity of individuals making requests; accompanying persons; and procedures for acknowledgment of requests.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Requests--general.</i> Requests may be made in person or in writing. Assistance regarding requests or other matters relating to the Act may be obtained by writing to the Director, Bureau of Administration, National Transportation Safety Board, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20594. The Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, on request, will aid an individual in preparing an amendment to the record or to an appeal following denial of a request to amend the record, pursuant to subsection (f)(4) of the Act.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Written requests.</i> Written requests shall be made to the Director, Bureau of Administration at the address given above, and shall clearly state on the envelope and on the request itself, "Privacy Act Request," "Privacy Act Statement of Disagreement," "Privacy Act Disclosure Accounting Request," "Appeal from Privacy Act Adverse Determination," or "Privacy Act Correction Request," as the case may be. Actual receipt by the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, shall constitute receipt.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Requests made in person.</i> Requests may be made in person during official working hours of the NTSB at the office where the record is located, as listed in the "Notice of Systems of Records" for the system in which the record is contained.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Verification of identity of requester.</i> (1) For written requests, the requester's identity must be verified before the release of any record, unless exempted under the FOIA. This may be accomplished by adequate proof of identity in the form of a driver's license or other acceptable item of the same type.
</p>
<p>(2) For requests in person, the requester's identity may be established by a single document bearing a photograph (such as a passport or identification badge) or by two items of identification containing name, address, and signature (such as a driver's license or credit card).
</p>
<p>(3) Where a request is made for reproduced records which are to be delivered by mail, the request must include a notarized statement verifying the requester's identity.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Inability to provide requisite documentation of identity.</i> A requester who cannot provide the necessary documentation of identity may provide a notarized statement, swearing or affirming his identity and the fact that he is aware of the penalties for false statement imposed pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 1001, and subsection (i)(3) of the Act. Where requested, the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, will assist the requester in formulating the necessary document.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Accompanying persons.</i> A requester may wish to have a person of his choice accompany him to review the requested record. Prior to the release of the record, the NTSB will require the requester to furnish the Director, Bureau of Administration or his designee, with a written statement authorizing disclosure of the record in the accompanying person's presence.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Acknowledgment of requests.</i> Written requests to verify the existence of, to obtain access to, or to correct or amend records about the requester maintained by NTSB in any system of records subject to the Act, shall be acknowledged in writing by the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, within 3 working days after the date of actual receipt of the request by the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee. The acknowledgment shall advise the requester of the need for any additional information to process the request. Wherever practicable, the acknowledgment shall notify the individual whether his request has been granted or denied. When a request is made in person, every effort will be made to determine immediately whether the request will be granted. If such decision cannot be made, the request will be processed in the same manner as a written request. Records will be made available for immediate inspection whenever possible.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 22358, June 3, 1976, as amended at 41 FR 43154, Sept. 30, 1976]
</p><p><b>Subpart C--Initial Determinations
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.8
 Disclosure of requested information.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The System Manager may initially determine that the request be granted. If so, the individual making the request shall be notified orally, or in writing, and the notice shall include:
</p>
<p>(1) A brief description of the information to be made available;
</p>
<p>(2) The time and place where the record may be inspected, or alternatively, the procedure for delivery by mail to the requesting party;
</p>
<p>(3) The estimated cost for furnishing copies of the record;
</p>
<p>(4) The requirements for verification of identity;
</p>
<p>(5) The requirements for authorizing discussion of the record in the presence of an accompanying person; and
</p>
<p>(6) Any additional requirements needed to grant access to a specific system of records or record.
</p>
<p>(b) Within 10 working days after actual receipt of the request by the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, in appropriate cases, the requester will be informed:
</p>
<p>(1) That the request does not reasonably describe the system of records or record sought to permit its identification, and shall set forth the additional information needed to clarify the request; or
</p>
<p>(2) That the system of records identified does not include a record retrievable by the requester's name or other identifying particulars.
</p>
<p>(c) The System Manager shall advise the requester within 10 working days after actual receipt of the request by the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, that the request for access has been denied, and the reason for the denial, or that the determination has been made to grant the request, either in whole or in part, in which case the relevant information will be provided.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 22358, June 3, 1976, as amended at 41 FR 43154, Sept. 30, 1976]
</p><p><b>Subpart D--Correction or Amending the Record
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.10
 Request for correction or amendment to record.
</b></p>
<p>All requests for correcting or amending records shall be made in writing to the Director, Bureau of Administration, National Transportation Safety Board, 800 Independence Avenue., SW., Washington, DC 20594, and shall be deemed received upon actual receipt by the Director, Bureau of Administration. The request shall clearly be marked on the envelope and in the letter with the legend that it is a "Privacy Act Correction Request." The request must reasonably set forth the portion of the record which the individual contends is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 22358, June 3, 1976, as amended at 41 FR 43154, Sept. 30, 1976]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.11
 Agency review of requests for correction or amendment of record.
</b></p>
<p>Within 10 working days after actual receipt of the request by the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, to correct or amend the record, the System Manager shall either make the correction in whole or in part, or inform the individual of the refusal to correct or amend the record as requested, and shall present the reasons for any denials.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 22358, June 3, 1976, as amended at 41 FR 43154, Sept. 30, 1976]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.12
 Initial adverse agency determination on correction or amendment.
</b></p>
<p>If the System Manager determines that the record should not be corrected or amended in whole or in part, he will forthwith make such finding in writing, after consulting with the General Counsel, or his designee. The requester shall be notified of the refusal to correct or amend the record. The notification shall be in writing, signed by the System Manager, and shall include--
</p>
<p>(a) The reason for the denial;
</p>
<p>(b) The name and title or position of each person responsible for the denial of the request;
</p>
<p>(c) The appeal procedures for the individual for a review of the denial; and
</p>
<p>(d) Notice that the denial from the System Manager is appealable within 30 days from the receipt thereof by the requester to the Board.
</p>
<p>The System Manager is allotted 10 working days (or within such extended period as is provided in the section concerning "unusual circumstances" <i>infra</i>) to respond to the request for review. If the requester does not receive an answer within such time, the delay shall constitute a denial of the request and shall permit the requester immediately to appeal to the Board, or to a district court.
</p><p><b>Subpart E--Review of Initial Adverse Determination
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.14
 Review procedure and judicial review.
</b></p>
<p>(a) A requester may appeal from any adverse determination within 30 days after actual receipt of a denial from the System Manager. The appeal must be in writing addressed to the Chairman, National Transportation Safety Board, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20594, and shall contain a statement on the envelope and in the appeal: "Appeal from Privacy Act Adverse Determination."
</p>
<p>(b) The Board shall make a determination with respect to the appeal within 30 working days after the actual receipt of the appeal by the Chairman, except as provided for in "unusual circumstances" infra.
</p>
<p>(c)(1) <i>Review of denial of access.</i> If the appeal upholds the denial of access to records, the Board shall: Notify the requester in writing, explaining the Board's determination; state that the denial is a final agency action and that judicial review is available in a district court of the United States in the district where the requester resides or has his principal place of business, or where the agency records are located, or in the District of Columbia; and request a filing with the Board of a concise statement enumerating the reasons for the requester's disagreement with the denial, pursuant to subsection (g) of the Act.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Review of denial of correction or amendment.</i> If the appeal upholds the denial in whole or in part for correction or amendment of the record, the same notification and judicial review privileges described in paragraph (c)(1) of this section shall apply.
</p>
<p>(d) If the denial is reversed on appeal, the Board shall notify the requester in writing of the reversal. The notice shall include a brief statement outlining those portions of the individual's record which were not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete, and corrections of the record which were made, and shall provide the individual with a courtesy copy of the corrected record.
</p>
<p>(e) Copies of all appeals and written determinations will be furnished by the System Manager to the Board.
</p>
<p>(f) In unusual circumstances, time limits may be extended by not more than 10 working days by written notice to the individual making the request. The notice shall include the reasons for the extension and the date on which a determination is expected to be forthcoming. "Unusual circumstances" as used in this section shall include circumstances where a search and collection of the requested records from field offices or other establishments are required, cases where a voluminous amount of data is involved, and cases where consultations are required with other agencies or with others having a substantial interest in the determination of the request.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Statements of Disagreement.</i> (1) Written Statements of Disagreement may be furnished by the individual within 30 working days of the date of actual receipt of the final adverse determination of the Board. They shall be addressed to the Director, Bureau of Administration, National Transportation Safety Board, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20594, and shall be clearly marked, both on the statement and on the envelope, "Privacy Act Statement of Disagreement."
</p>
<p>(2) The Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, shall be responsible for ensuring that:
</p>
<p>(i) The Statement of Disagreement is included in the system of records in which the disputed item of information is maintained; and
</p>
<p>(ii) The original record is marked to indicate the information disputed, the existence of the Statement of Disagreement, and its location within the relevant system of records.
</p>
<p>(3) The Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, may, if he deems it appropriate, prepare a concise Statement of Explanation indicating why the requested amendments or corrections were not made. Such Statement of Explanation shall be included in the system of records in the same manner as the Statement of Disagreement. Courtesy copies of the NTSB Statement of Explanation and the notation of dispute, as marked on the original record, shall be furnished to the individual who requested correction or amendment of the record.
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Notices of correction and/or amendment, or dispute.</i> After a record has been corrected or a Statement of Disagreement has been filed, the Director, Bureau of Administration, or his designee, shall within 30 working days thereof, advise all previous recipients of the affected record as to the correction or the filing of the Statement of Disagreement. The identity of such recipients shall be determined pursuant to an accounting of disclosures required by the Act or any other accounting previously made. Any disclosure of disputed information occurring after a Statement of Disagreement has been filed shall clearly identify the specific information disputed and shall be accompanied by a copy of the Statement of Disagreement and a copy of any NTSB Statement of Explanation.
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Disclosure to others of records concerning individuals.</i> Neither the Board nor other NTSB personnel shall disclose any record which is contained in a system of records maintained by NTSB, by any means of communication, including oral communication, to any person, or to another Government agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent, of the individual to whom the record pertains, unless disclosure of the record is:
</p>
<p>(1) To the Board and NTSB personnel who have a need for the record in the performance of their duties;
</p>
<p>(2) Required under the FOIA;
</p>
<p>(3) For a routine use published in the <i>Federal Register</i>;
</p>
<p>(4) To the Bureau of the Census for purposes of planning or carrying out a census or survey, or related activity pursuant to the provisions of title 13 of the U.S.C.;
</p>
<p>(5) To a recipient who has provided NTSB with adequate advance written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record and that the record is transferred in a form that is not identifiable with respect to individuals; \1
</p>
<p>\1 The advance written statement of assurance shall state the purpose for which the record is requested and certify that it will be used only for statistical purposes. Prior to release under this paragraph, the record shall be stripped of all personally identifiable information and reviewed to ensure that the identity of any individual cannot reasonably be determined by combining two or more statistical records.
</p>
<p>(6) To the National Archives of the United States as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the U.S. Government, or to the Administrator of the General Services Administration, or his designee, for evaluation to determine whether the record has such value;
</p>
<p>(7) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity if the activity is authorized by law, and if the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a written request to NTSB specifying the particular portion of the record desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought; \2
</p>
<p>\2 A record may be disclosed to a law enforcement agency at the initiative of NTSB if criminal conduct is suspected, provided that such disclosure has been established as a routine use by publication in the <i>Federal Register,</i> and the instance of misconduct is directly related to the purpose for which the record is maintained.
</p>
<p>(8) To any person upon a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of any individual;
</p>
<p>(9) To either House of Congress or, to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, to any committee, or subcommittee thereof, or to any joint committee of the Congress, or to any subcommittee of such joint committee;
</p>
<p>(10) To the Comptroller General, or any of his authorized representatives, in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office; or
</p>
<p>(11) Pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction.
</p>
<p>(j) <i>Notices of subpoenas.</i> When records concerning an individual are subpoenaed or otherwise disclosed pursuant to court order, the NTSB officer or employee served with the subpoena shall be responsible for assuring that the individual is notified of the disclosure within 5 days after such subpoena or other order becomes a matter of public record. The notice shall be mailed to the last known address of the individual and shall contain the following information: (1) The date the subpoena is returnable; (2) the court in which it is returnable; (3) the name and number of the case or proceeding; and (4) the nature of the information sought.
</p>
<p>(k) <i>Notices of emergency disclosures.</i> When information concerning an individual has been disclosed to any person under compelling circumstances affecting health or safety, the NTSB officer or employee who made or authorized the disclosure shall notify the individual at his last known address within 5 days of the disclosure. The notice shall contain the following information: (1) The nature of the information disclosed; (2) the person or agency to whom the information was disclosed; (3) the date of the disclosure; and (4) the compelling circumstances justifying the disclosure.
</p>
<p>[41 FR 22358, June 3, 1976, as amended at 41 FR 43154, Sept. 30, 1976]
</p><p><b>Subpart F--Fees
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.15
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>No fees shall be charged for providing the first copy of a record, or any portion thereof, to individuals to whom the record pertains. The fee schedule for other records is the same as that appearing in the appendix to part 801 of this chapter, implementing the FOIA, as amended from time to time, except that the cost of any search for and review of the record shall not be included in any fee under this Act, pursuant to subsection (f)(5) of the Act.
</p><p><b>Subpart G--Penalties
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.18
 Penalties.
</b></p>
<p>(a) An individual may bring a civil action against the NTSB to correct or amend the record, or where there is a refusal to comply with an individual request or failure to maintain any record with accuracy, relevance, timeliness and completeness, so as to guarantee fairness, or failure to comply with any other provision of 5 U.S.C. 552a. The court may order the correction or amendment. It may assess against the United States reasonable attorney fees and other costs, or may enjoin the NTSB from withholding the records and order the production to the complainant, and it may assess attorney fees and costs.
</p>
<p>(b) Where it is determined that the action was willful or intentional with respect to 5 U.S.C. 552(g)(1) (c) or (d), the United States shall be liable for the actual damages sustained, but in no case less than the sum of $1,000 and the costs of the action with attorney fees.
</p>
<p>(c) Criminal penalties may be imposed against an officer or employee of the NTSB who fully discloses material which he knows is prohibited from disclosure, or who willfully maintains a system of records without meeting the notice requirements, or who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual from an agency under false pretenses. These offenses shall be misdemeanors with a fine not to exceed $5,000.
</p><p><b>Subpart H--Specific Exemptions
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 802.20
 Security records.
</b></p>
<p>Pursuant to, and limited by, 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), the NTSB's system of records, which contains the Security Records of NTSB employees, prospective employees, and potential contractors, shall be exempt from disclosure of the material and the NTSB's handling thereof under subsections (d), (e)(1) and (e)(4) (H) and (I) of 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
