<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Postal Regulatory Commission</name>
<abbrev>
PRC
</abbrev>

    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-02/pdf/2021-23833.pdf</url>
        <title>Postal Regulatory Commission/PRC-03 Medical File System Records. </title>
        <date year="21" month="11" day="2" />
    </previouslyPublished> 
    

<section id="prc1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel, Pay, Leave, and Travel (PRC-1).

</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>1333 H Street NW., Suite 300, Washington, DC 20268-0001.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains records relating to personnel, pay, leave, and travel. This includes: Name; date of birth; social security number; home address; grade; salary; time and attendance; alternate work schedules; biographical information; leave accrual rate, usage, and balances; training; Civil Service Retirement and Federal Employees? Retirement System contributions; FICA withholdings; Federal, State, and local tax withholdings; Federal Employees? Group Life Insurance withholdings; Federal Employees? Health Benefits withholdings; charitable deductions; allotments to financial organizations; garnishment documents; savings bonds allotments; travel expenses; parking permits; carpools; building security records; employee locator; and information on the fare subsidy program.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Includes 39 U.S.C. 3603, 44 U.S.C. 3101, 5 U.S.C. ch. 57 (relating to travel, transportation, and subsistence), together with any amendments.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used to administer pay, leave, travel, parking, fare subsidies, and other administrative functions.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>A. Disclosure to the U.S. Postal Service

</p><p>The U.S. Postal Service handles payroll and other disbursements on behalf of the Postal Rate Commission. As a result, records related to payroll functions, travel, and other disbursements are disclosed as a routine use to the U.S. Postal Service. The records from the Commission are incorporated into Privacy Act systems of records maintained by the U.S. Postal Service and are routinely disclosed for purposes defined in those systems of records. The main systems of records at the U.S. Postal Service are Finance Records--Payroll System. (USPS 050.020), and Finance Records--Employee Travel Records (USPS 050.010).

</p><p>B. Disclosure for Law Enforcement Purposes

</p><p>Information may be disclosed to the appropriate Federal, State, local, or foreign agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, if the information indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation within the jurisdiction of the receiving entity.

</p><p>C. Disclosure Incident to Requesting Information

</p><p>Information may be disclosed to any source from which additional information is requested (to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and to identify the type of information requested), when necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning retention of an employee or other personnel action (other than hiring), retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a grant, or other benefit.

</p><p>D. Disclosure to Requesting Agency

</p><p>Disclosure may be made to a Federal, State, local, foreign, or tribal or other public authority of the fact that this system of records contains information relevant to the retention of an employee, the retention of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance or retention of a license, grant, or other benefit. The other authority may then make a request supported by the written consent of the individual for the record if it chooses. No disclosure will be made unless the information has been determined to be sufficiently reliable to support a referral to the authority or to another Federal agency for criminal, civil, administrative, personnel, or regulatory action.

</p><p>E. Disclosure to Office of Management and Budget

</p><p>Information may be disclosed to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.

</p><p>F. Disclosure to Congressional Offices

</p><p>Information may be disclosed to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of the individual.

</p><p>G. Disclosure During Litigation

</p><p>Information may be disclosed to the Department of Justice, or in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the Postal Rate Commission is authorized to appear, when:

</p><p>1. The Commission, or any component thereof; or

</p><p>2. Any employee of the Commission in his or her official capacity; or

</p><p>3. Any employee of the Commission in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the Commission has agreed to represent the employee; or

</p><p>4. The United States, when the Commission determines that litigation is likely to affect the Commission or any of its components is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the Commission is deemed by the Commission to be relevant and necessary to the litigation provided, however, that in each case it has been determined that the disclosure is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.

</p><p>H. Disclosure to the National Archives

</p><p>Information may be disclosed to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections.

</p><p>I. Disclosure to Contractors, Grantees, and Others

</p><p>Information may be disclosed to contractors, grantees, consultants, or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement, job, or other activity for the Postal Rate Commission and who need the information in the performance of their duties or activities for the Commission. If appropriate, recipients will be required to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1974 as provided in 5 U.S.C. 552a(m).

</p><p>J. Disclosures for Administrative Claims, Complaints, and Appeals

</p><p>Information from this system of records may be disclosed to an authorized appeal grievance examiner, formal complaints examiner, equal employment opportunity investigator, arbitrator or other person properly engaged in investigation or settlement of an administrative grievance, complaint, claim, or appeal filed by an employee, but only to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the proceeding. Agencies that may obtain information under this routine use include, but are not limited to, the Office of Personnel Management, Office of Special Counsel, Merit Systems Protection Board, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and Office of Government Ethics.

</p><p>K. Disclosure to the Office of Personnel Management

</p><p>Information from this system of records may be disclosed to the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to that agency?s responsibility for evaluation and oversight of Federal personnel management.

</p><p>L. Disclosure in Connection with Litigation

</p><p>Information from this system of records may be disclosed in connection with litigation or settlement discussions regarding claims by or against the Postal Rate Commission, including public filing with a court, to the extent that disclosure of the information is relevant and necessary to the litigation or discussions and except where court orders are otherwise required under section (b)(11) of the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(11).

</p><p>M. Disclosure for Child Support Enforcement

</p><p>The name, social security number, home address, date of birth, date of hire, quarterly earnings, employer identifying information, and State of hire for each employee may be disclosed to the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services for the purpose of locating individuals to establish paternity, establishing and modifying orders of child support, identifying sources of income, and for other child support enforcement actions as required by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act (Welfare Reform Law, Pub. L. 104-193).

</p><p>Disclosure to consumer reporting agencies:

</p><p>Information from this system of records may be disclosed to a consumer reporting agency as provided in 31 U.S.C. 3711.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Records are stored in paper, in folders, in file cabinets, and on the Postal Rate Commission?s computer network.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name, Social Security Number, or other identification number.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in locked file cabinets or combination safes and on computers and computer networks that use password protections and other system controls to prevent unauthorized access by Postal Rate Commission staff. Firewalls prevent access to internal Commission documents by outsiders. All records and computer facilities are maintained in Commission offices, and public access to Commission offices is controlled.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained for varying periods of time, in accordance with NARA General Records Schedules 2 (pay and leave) and 9 (travel).

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Administrative Officer, Postal Rate Commission, 1333 H Street NW., Suite 300, Washington, DC 20268-0001.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>All requests should be directed to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver?s license, employee identification card, or other identifying document, and dates of employment.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>All requests should be directed to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver?s license, employee identification card, or other identifying document, and dates of employment.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records is obtained from: the subject of the record; employment applications, references, and other employment-related sources; the official personnel file from the Office of Personnel Management; and internal Postal Rate Commission documents, including time and attendance records, leave slips, travel requests, performance evaluations, training records, and similar internal documents.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="prc2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Docket Room Records (PRC-2).

</subsection>
<subsection type="securityClassification"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>1333 H Street NW., Suite 300, Washington, DC 20268-0001.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals who intervene in Postal Rate Commission proceedings and individuals whose name and other identifying information appears in records filed in connection with Postal Rate Commission proceedings.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system contains names, addresses, and contact information for anyone who intervenes in a proceeding before the Postal Rate Commission; submissions, filings, answers, exhibits, and any other record provided to the Commission and made public under Commission rule 3001.42(b).

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>39 U.S.C. 3603.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used under the Postal Rate Commission?s rules and procedures in Commission proceedings, decisions, opinions, and other activities authorized by law.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>All records in this system are public and will be disclosed to any person upon request.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Records are stored in paper, in folders, in file cabinets, and on the Postal Rate Commission?s computer network.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records may be retrieved by name or docket number.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in the Postal Rate Commission?s docket room, on computer networks, and on the Commission website. All records and computer facilities are maintained in Commission offices, and public access to Commission offices is controlled.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are disposed of in accordance with approved record schedules. Most records pertaining to Commission decisions are retained permanently.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Administrative Officer, Postal Rate Commission, 1333 H Street NW., Suite 300, Washington, DC 20268-0001.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>All requests should be directed to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver?s license, employee identification card, or other identifying document, and dates of employment.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>All requests should be directed to the System Manager. Requesters will be required to provide adequate identification, such as a driver?s license, employee identification card, or other identifying document, and dates of employment.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records is obtained from intervenors in Postal Rate Commission proceedings and from Commission staff.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    <section id="prc3" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">Postal Regulatory Commission/PRC-03 Medical File System Records.</subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>The records are located at the PRC Headquarters in Washington, DC, and contractor-owned and operated facilities.  Additionally, records may be maintained electronically at a PRC data center. Records within this system of records may be transferred to a PRC-authorized cloud service provider within the Continental United States.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Secretary, Postal Regulatory Commission, HR@prc.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>39 U.S.C. 504(a); Executive Orders 12107 and 12196; Occupational Safety and Health Act (OSHA) of 1970, Public Law 91-596, Section 19(a) (29 U.S.C. 668(a)); Section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 247d; American with Disabilities Act, including 42 U.S.C. 12112(d)(3)(B) (allowing medical examination after an offer of employment has been made to a job applicant), 29 CFR 602.14, 1630.2(r), 1630.14(b)(1), (c)(1), (d)(4); 29 U.S.C. 668, 29 CFR part 1904, 29 CFR 1910.1020, 29 CFR 1960.66; Executive Order No. 14043, Requiring Coronavirus Disease 2019 Vaccination for Federal Employees; Executive Order 13164, Establishing Procedures to Facilitate the Provision of Reasonable Accommodation; EEOC, Enforcement Guidance on Reasonable Accommodation and Undue Hardship Under the Americans with Disabilities Act, 29 CFR part 1615; Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.; 29 U.S.C. 971; 29 CFR 1630; Title VII of the Civil Rights Act, 42 U.S.C. § 2000e.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system of records are maintained for a variety of purposes, which include the following:</p>
                <p>a.  To ensure that records required to be retained on a long-term basis to meet the mandates of law, Executive Order, or regulations (e.g., the Department of Labor's Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) and OWCP regulations), are so maintained.</p>
                <p>b.  To provide a legal document describing the health care administered and any exposure incident.</p>
                <p>c.  To provide a method for evaluating quality of health care rendered and job-health-protection including engineering protection provided, protective equipment worn, workplace monitoring, and medical exam monitoring required by OSHA or by good practice.</p>
                <p>d.  To ensure that all relevant, necessary, accurate, and timely data are available to support any medically-related employment decisions affecting the subject of the records (e.g., in connection with fitness-for-duty and disability retirement decisions).</p>
                <p>e.  To document claims filed with and the decisions reached by the Department of Labor's Office of Workers' Compensation Program (OWCP) and the individual's possible reemployment rights under statutes governing that program.</p>
                <p>f.  To document employees’ reporting of on-the-job injuries or unhealthy or unsafe working conditions, including the reporting of such conditions to OSHA and actions taken by that agency or by the employing agency.</p>
                <p>g.  To facilitate communication among members of an on-site health and wellness program and to the individual employee participating in the program.</p>
                <p>h.  To collect records when the PRC determines that collection is necessary to protect the health of PRC personnel (meaning employees, and interns).</p>
                <p>i.  To maintain records necessary and relevant to PRC activities responding to and mitigating COVID-19, other high-consequence public health threats, or diseases and illnesses relating to a public health emergency.</p>
                <p>j.  To provide a method by which the PRC can identify PRC employees who have requested "reasonable accommodations" in their office, work stations, other PRC facilities, and/or to access other benefits and privileges of employment. Information on the disposition of each request to also be maintained in this system.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current and former PRC personnel (meaning employees and interns).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records maintained in this system include:</p>
                <p>a.  Medical records, forms, and reports completed or obtained when an individual applies for a Federal job and is subsequently employed.</p>
                <p>b.  Medical records, forms, and reports completed during employment as a condition of employment, either by the employing agency or by another agency, State or local government entity, or a private sector entity under contract to the employing agency.</p>
                <p>c.  Reports of on-the-job injuries and medical records, forms, and reports generated as a result of the filing of a claim for Workers' Compensation, whether the claim is accepted or not.  The official compensation claim file is not covered by this system; rather, it is part OWCP system of records.</p>
                <p>d.  All other medical records, forms, and reports created on an employee during their period of employment, including any retained on a temporary basis (e.g., those designated to be retained only during the period of service with a given agency) and those designated for long-term retention (i.e., those retained for the entire duration of Federal service and for some period of time after).</p>
                <p>e.  Records resulting from participation in agency-sponsored health promotion and wellness activities, including health risk appraisals, biometric testing, health coaching, disease management, behavioral management, preventive services, fitness programs, and any other activities that could be considered part of a comprehensive worksite health and wellness program.</p>
                <p>f.  Health screening and contact tracing records, which may include identification and contact information (such as name, address, work or personal phone number(s), work or personal email address(es), work office/division, employee ID number, data watch information, medical reports, assessments, vaccination status, testing status (where and when it occurred; status of results), test type, test results, disease type, health status, approximate date of exposure, last date physically present in the PRC facility/at a PRC event, name of facility visited, areas of the PRC or other facility (if a PRC event at a non-PRC facility) traversed, areas and objects touched, workplace contacts, names of persons who had physical contact with or was in prolonged close physical proximity to infected/potentially infected persons, extended proximity event time and date, number of events, number of individuals in an event, number of individuals at location, dates and locations of domestic and international travel, and related information and documents collected for the purpose of screening and contact tracing;</p>
                <p>g.  Other individual information directly related and relevant to PRC activities responding to and mitigating a public health emergency;</p>
                <p>h.  The categories of records in this system include but are not limited to the information that current and former PRC personnel (meaning employees and interns) and applicants must provide by submitting a reasonable accommodation requests for medical and/or religious exceptions as required by law, as well as the underlying information necessary to evaluate and confirm the legal entitlement of the exception. This information may include the name  and employment information of the employee needing an accommodation; requestor's name and contact information (if different than the employee who needs an accommodation); date request was initiated; information concerning the nature of the disability and the need for accommodation, including appropriate medical documentation; information concerning the nature of the sincerely held religious belief, practice, or observance and the need for accommodation, including any appropriate documentation; details of the accommodation request and disposition, such as: type of accommodation requested, how the requested accommodation would assist in job performance, the sources of technical assistance consulted in trying to identify alternative reasonable accommodation, any additional information provided by the requestor related to the processing of the request; disposition of the request, whether the request was approved or denied; and notification(s) to the employee and his/her supervisor(s) regarding the accommodation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>RECORDS IN THIS SYSTEM ARE OBTAINED FROM:</p>
                <p>a.  The individual to whom the records pertain.</p>
                <p>b.  Federal and private sector medical practitioners and treatment facilities.</p>
                <p>c.  Supervisors/managers and other agency officials.</p>
                <p>d.  Other agency records.</p>
                <p>In addition, records are obtained through attestations, interviews, or electronically from the individuals working for the PRC; those individuals who are physically present in a PRC facility or at a PRC event; other Federal or state agencies; physicians (as allowed by law or with consent from the individual); PRC visitors or their employers; and PRC personnel and visitors who maintain (manually or electronically) a log or report of their close physical contacts (and the duration of that contact) while in PRC facilities to individuals designated by PRC.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under the Privacy Act of 1974, records and/or information or portions thereof maintained as part of this system may be disclosed outside PRC as a routine use as follows:</p>
                <p>a.  To disclose relevant information to the Department of Labor, Department of Veterans Affairs, Social Security Administration, Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board, or a national, state, or local social security type agency, when necessary to adjudicate a claim (filed by or on behalf of the individual) under a retirement, insurance, or health benefit program.</p>
                <p>b.  To disclose relevant information to a Federal, state, or local agency to the extent necessary to comply with laws governing reporting of communicable disease.</p>
                <p>c.  To disclose relevant and necessary information to another Federal, state, or local agency, to a court, or a party in litigation before a court or in an administrative proceeding being conducted by a Federal or state agency when the Government is a party to the judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
                <p>d.  To the United States Department of Justice ("DOJ"), for the purpose of representing or providing legal advice to the PRC in a proceeding before a court, adjudicative body, or other administrative body before which the PRC is authorized to appear, when the records are relevant and necessary to the proceeding, when such proceeding involves:</p>
                <p>1.  The agency, or any component thereof; or</p>
                <p>2.  Any employee of the agency in their official capacity; or</p>
                <p>3.  Any employee of the agency in their individual capacity where the DOJ or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or</p>
                <p>4.  The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the DOJ or the agency is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation.</p>
                <p>e.  To Federal agencies such as the Health and Human Services (HHS), State and local health departments, and other public health or cooperating medical authorities in connection with program activities and related collaborative efforts to deal more effectively with exposures to communicable diseases, and to satisfy mandatory reporting requirements when applicable.</p>
                <p>f.  To appropriate Federal, state, local, tribal, or foreign governmental agencies or multilateral governmental organizations, to the extent permitted by law, and in consultation with legal counsel, for the purpose of protecting the vital interests of a data subject or other persons, including to assist such agencies or organizations in preventing exposure to or transmission of a communicable or quarantinable disease or to combat other significant public health threats.</p>
                <p>g.  Where a record, either alone or in conjunction with other information, indicates a violation or potential violation of law – criminal, civil, or regulatory in nature – the relevant records may be disclosed to the appropriate federal, state, local, territorial, tribal, or foreign law enforcement authority or other appropriate entity charged with the responsibility for investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing such law.</p>
                <p>h.  To disclose information to the Federal Labor Relations Authority and its General Counsel, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, arbitrators, and hearing examiners to the extent necessary to carry out their authorized duties.</p>
                <p>i.  To disclose information to the Office of Federal Employees Group Life Insurance or Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board that is relevant and necessary to adjudicate claims.</p>
                <p>j.  To disclose information, when an individual to whom a record pertains is mentally incompetent or under other legal disability, to any person who is responsible for the care of the individual, to the extent necessary.</p>
                <p>k.  To disclose to the agency-appointed representative of an employee, all notices, determinations, decisions, or other written communications issued to the employee, in connection with an examination ordered by an agency under medical evaluation (formerly Fitness for Duty) examinations procedures.</p>
                <p>l.  To disclose information to a Federal, state, or local agency, in response to its request or at the initiation of the agency maintaining the records, in connection with the retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a suitability or security investigation of an individual, the classifying of jobs, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, or the lawful, statutory, administrative, or investigative purpose of the agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>m.  To disclose to any Federal, state, or local government agency, in response to its request or at the initiation of the agency maintaining the records, information relevant and necessary to the lawful, statutory, administrative, or investigatory purpose of that agency as it relates to individuals who might have contracted an illness or been exposed to or suffered from a health hazard while employed in the Federal workforce or the assurance of compliance with Federal, state, or local government laws on health and safety in the work environment.</p>
                <p>n.  To disclose information to contractors or volunteers performing or working on a contract, service, grant, cooperative agreement or job for the Federal Government.</p>
                <p>o.  To the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) pursuant to records management inspections being conducted under the authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>p.  To appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when (1) the PRC suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of PRC systems; (2) the PRC has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the PRC(including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the PRC’s efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>q.  To another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the PRC determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>r.  The PRC may disclose information to a Member of Congress or staff acting upon the Member's behalf when the Member or staff requests the information on behalf of, and at the written request of, the individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>PRC stores records in this system electronically or on paper in secure facilities in a locked drawer behind a locked door.  The records may be stored on magnetic disc, cloud storage, and digital media.  Medical information collected is maintained on separate forms and in separate medical files and are treated as confidential medical records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are retrieved by an individual's name or other identification information (such as email address, employee identification number, or SSN).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are managed in accordance with the PRC Records Schedule DAA-0458-2018-0001, and General Records Schedules (GRS) 2.7 Employee Health and Safety Records DAA-GRS-2017-0010-0012.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records in this system are safeguarded in accordance with applicable law, rules and policies, including all applicable PRC automated systems security and access policies.  Strict controls have been imposed to minimize the risk of compromising the information that is being stored.  Access to the computer system containing the records in this system is limited to those individuals who have a need to know the information for the performance of their official duties and who have appropriate clearances.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals seeking access to and notification of any record contained in this system of records referencing them, or seeking to contest its content, may submit a request in writing to the Secretary whose contact information can be found at https://www.prc.gov/foia under "PRC FOIA and Privacy Act Information."  If an individual believes more than one component maintains Privacy Act records concerning him or her, the individual may submit the request to the FOIA Public Liaison, Postal Regulatory Commission, 901 New York Ave NW, Suite 200, Washington, DC 202-789-6800.</p>
                <p>When an individual is seeking records about himself or herself from this system of records or any other PRC system of records, the individual's request must conform with the Privacy Act regulations set forth in 39 CFR Part 3006.  The individual must first verify their identity, meaning that the individual must provide their full name, current address, and date and place of birth.  The individual must sign the request, and the individual's signature must either be notarized or submitted under 28 U.S.C. 1746, a law that permits statements to be made under penalty of perjury as a substitute for notarization.  While no specific form is required, an individual may obtain forms for this purpose from the FOIA Public Liaison, available via https://www.prc.gov/foia or 202-789-6800.  In addition, the individual should:</p>
                <p>●  Explain why they believe the PRC would have information being requested;</p>
                <p>●  Identify which component(s) of the PRC they believe may have the information;</p>
                <p>●  Specify when the individual believes the records would have been created; and</p>
                <p>●  Provide any other information that will help the FOIA staff determine which PRC component may have responsive records;</p>
                <p>If the request is seeking records pertaining to another living individual, the request must include an authorization from the individual whose record is being requested, authorizing the release to the requester.</p>
                <p>Without the above information, the component(s) may not be able to conduct an effective search, and the individual's request may be denied due to lack of specificity or lack of compliance with applicable regulations.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals may make a request for amendment or correction of a record of the PRC about the individual by writing directly to the Secretary, unless the record is not subject to amendment or correction.  The request should identify each particular record in question, state the amendment or correction desired, and state why the individual believes that the record is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete.  The individual may submit any documentation that would be helpful.  The request should state whether the individual believes that the same record is in more than one system of records.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>See "Records Access Procedures" above.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>




    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="39">
<heading> Postal Service </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="III">
<heading>Postal Regulatory Commission
</heading>
<regulationsPart number="3003">
<heading>PRIVACY ACT RULES </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>3003.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>3003.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>3003.3 Procedures for requesting inspection, copying, or correction.
</p>
<p>3003.4 Response to a request.
</p>
<p>3003.5 Appeals of denials of access or amendment.
</p>
<p>3003.6 Fees.
</p>
<p>3003.7 Exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579), 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 64 FR 57982, Oct. 28, 1999, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p></p><p><b>Editorial Note:</b></p>
<p>Nomenclature changes for Part 3003 appear at 70 FR 48277, Aug. 17, 2005.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 3003.1 Purpose and scope.
</b></p>
<p>This part implements the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a) by establishing Commission policies and procedures that permit individuals to obtain access to and request amendment of information about themselves that is maintained in systems of records. This part does not expand or restrict any rights granted under the Privacy Act of 1974.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 3003.2 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For purposes of this part:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Commission</i> means the Postal Regulatory Commission.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Individual, record,</i> and <i>system of records</i> have the meanings specified in 5 U.S.C. 552a(a).
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Day</i> means a calendar day and does not include Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays.
</p>
<p>[64 FR 57982, Oct. 28, 1999, as amended at 72 FR 33165, June 15, 2007]
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 3003.3 Procedures for requesting inspection, copying, or correction.
</b></p>
<p>(a) An individual who--
</p>
<p>(1) Wishes to know whether a Commission system of records contains a record about him or her,
</p>
<p>(2) Seeks access to a Commission record about him or her that is maintained in a system of records (including the accounting of disclosures), or
</p>
<p>(3) Seeks to amend a record about him or her that is maintained in a system of records, may file a written request with the chief administrative officer of the Commission at the Commission?s current address (901 New York Avenue NW., Suite 200, Washington, DC 20268-0001). The request should state on the outside of the envelope and in the request that it is a Privacy Act request.
</p>
<p>(b) A request for amendment must describe the information sought to be amended and the specific reasons for the amendment.
</p>
<p>(c) A requester--
</p>
<p>(1) May request an appointment to inspect records at the Commission?s offices between the hours of 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m. on any day;
</p>
<p>(2) Must present suitable identification, such as a driver?s license, employee identification card, or Medicare card;
</p>
<p>(3) If accompanied by another individual, must sign a statement, if requested by the chief administrative officer, authorizing discussion of his or her record in the presence of that individual;
</p>
<p>(4) Who files a request by mail must include his or her date of birth, dates of employment at the Commission (if applicable), and suitable proof of identity, such as a facsimile of a driver?s license, employee identification card, or Medicare card; and
</p>
<p>(5) Must, if requested by the chief administrative officer, provide additional proof of identification.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 3003.4 Response to a request.
</b></p>
<p>(a) In the case of a request for notice of the existence of a record, the chief administrative officer shall respond within 10 days of receipt of a request and shall inform the individual whether a system of records maintained by the Commission contains such a record.
</p>
<p>(b) In the case of a request for access to a record or for a copy of a record, the chief administrative officer shall acknowledge the request within 10 days and shall promptly thereafter--
</p>
<p>(1) Fulfill the request by mail or arrange for an inspection by the requester in the Commission?s offices; or
</p>
<p>(2) If the request is denied, notify the requester of the denial, the reasons for the denial, the procedures for appealing the refusal, and the name and address of the Chairman of the Commission who will consider an appeal.
</p>
<p>(c) In the case of a request for amendment, the chief administrative officer shall:
</p>
<p>(1) Acknowledge the request in writing within 10 days;
</p>
<p>(2) Promptly review the record; and
</p>
<p>(3)(i) Make any requested amendment of a record found to be not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete; notify the requester of the change and provide a copy of the corrected record; and notify any previous recipient of the record (excluding Commission staff who obtained the record in the performance of their duties and recipients under the Freedom of Information Act) of any change; or
</p>
<p>(ii) Inform the requester of a refusal to amend the record, the reasons for the refusal, the procedures for appealing the refusal, and the name and address of the Chairman of the Commission who will consider an appeal.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 3003.5 Appeals of denials of access or amendment.
</b></p>
<p>(a) If a request for access to or amendment of a record is denied, the requester may file a written appeal with the Chairman of the Commission. The Chairman will decide each appeal within 30 days of receipt unless the Chairman has, for good cause, extended the period for another 30 days.
</p>
<p>(b) If an appeal is denied, the requester will be notified of the decision, the reasons for the denial, the right to file a concise statement of disagreement, the procedures for filing a statement of disagreement, the subsequent uses of a statement of disagreement, and of the right to seek judicial review in accordance with subsection (g) of the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 3003.6 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>The first copy of any record furnished under the Privacy Act of 1974 will be provided without charge. Additional copies will be charged at the cost of reproduction.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 3003.7 Exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>The Postal Regulatory Commission has not established any exempt system of records.</p>
<p>[64 FR 57982, Oct. 28, 1999, as amended at 72 FR 33165, June 15, 2007]</p>

</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
