<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>


<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>African Develpment Foundation</name>
<abbrev>
ADF
</abbrev> 

    
    

<routineUses id="routine" toc="yes">
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Notice of Systems of Records, Preliminary Statement </b></p>

<p><i>Official Personnel Files</i> </p>
<p>Official personnel files of Federal employees in the General Schedule in the custody of ADF are considered the property of OPM. Access to such files shall be in accordance with such notices as are published by OPM. Access to such files in the custody of ADF will be granted to individuals to whom such files pertain upon request to the Personnel Officer, ADF, Suite 600, 1626 Massachusetts Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p><p>Various ADF offices maintain files which contain miscellaneous copies of personnel material affecting ADF employees. This includes copies of standard personnel forms, evaluation forms, etc. These files are kept only for immediate office reference use and are considered by the Foundation to be part of the personnel file system. ADF's internal regulations provide that such information is part of the general personnel files and can only be disclosed through the Director of Personnel in order to ensure that any material disclosed is relevant, material, current, and fair to the individual employee. It is also ADF policy to limit the use of such files and to encourage the destruction of as many as possible. </p>

<p><i>Security Classification

</i></p><p>None of the files maintained by ADF contain classified information.

</p><p>Statement of General Routine Uses

</p><p>The following general routine uses are incorporated by this reference into each system of records set forth herein, unless such incorporation is specifically limited in the system description.

</p><p>1. In the event that a record in a system of records maintained by ADF indicates any violation or potential violation of the law, whether civil, criminal or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by statute, or by regulation, rule or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant record in this system of records may be referred as a routine use to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, state, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation, or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto. Such referral shall also include and be deemed to authorize any and all appropriate and necessary uses of such records in a court of law or before an administrative board or hearing.

</p><p>2. A record may be disclosed as a routine use to designated officers and employees of other agencies and departments of the Federal Government having an interest in the individual for employment purposes, including the hiring or retention of any employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of license, grant or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter involved.

</p><p>3. Routine Use for Disclosure to the Department of Justice for Use in Litigation:

</p><p>It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice when

</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or

</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or

</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice has agreed to represent the employee; or

</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.

</p><p><i>Routine Use for Agency Disclosure in Litigation</i>

</p><p>It shall be a routine use of records maintained by this agency to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when

</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or

</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or

</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or

</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the agency determines that use of such records is relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.

</p><p>4. Information from records systems may be disclosed to any source from which information is requested in the course of an investigation, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the nature and purpose of the investigation, and to identify the type of information requested.

</p><p>5. Information in any system of records may be disclosed to a Congressional office, in response to an inquiry from the office, made at the request of the individual to whom the record pertains.

</p><p>6. Any record from any system of records may be disclosed as a routine use to the National Archives and Records Administration, General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.

</p><p>7. Information from records systems may be released to auditors in the conduct of an audit of ADF operations or accounts, but only to the extent it is relevant and necessary to the conduct of the audit.

</p><p><i>Location of Files

</i></p><p>All files are located in the office indicated under "System Location"  at ADF headquarters in Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p><p><i>Notification

</i></p> <p>Individuals may inquire whether any system contains information pertaining to them by addressing the Director of Administration and Finance in person or in writing. If in writing, such request should include the individual's name and address, social security number, and any relevant data concerning the information sought which will assist in identifying the record. ADF may require that the individual furnish the Foundation with additional information to assure that he or she is properly identified.

</p><p><i>Access and Contest

</i></p><p>In response to a request by an individual, the Director of Administration and Finance shall arrange for access to the requested record, or advise the requester if no such record exists. If an individual wishes to contest the content of any record, he/she may do so by addressing a written request to the Director of Administration and Finance, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave., NW., Washington, DC 20036. The Director will provide all necessary information regarding such contest and appeal.
</p></xhtmlContent></routineUses>
<section id="adf1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Employee Pay and Leave Records.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administration and Finance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former employees of ADF.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records of current personnel status, amounts of pay, hours worked, leave accrued, allotments authorized, and benefits paid by the Government.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>GAO Policy and Procedures Manual; 31 U.S.C. 3512; and the Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system was established to record moneys paid, allotments authorized, leave earned and used, and retirement benefits accrued.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in these records are routinely provided as follows:

</p><p>1. To the Federal Agency designated through inter-agency agreement to perform payrolling services for ADF. The Department of Energy is currently performing this function.

</p><p>2. Through the Department of Energy, to the Treasury for payroll and savings bonds and other deduction purposes; to the Internal Revenue Service with regard to tax matters; and to participating insurance companies holding policies with respect to ADF employees.

</p><p>3. General routine uses listed in the Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Pay and leave records are maintained in looseleaf binders in metal file cabinets with key locks. Individual Time and Attendance records are maintained by the Personnel Officer in a separate metal file cabinet with a key lock. Microfiche pay and leave records are maintained in a Microfiche index which is kept in a metal file cabinet with a key lock.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed in alphabetical order by pay period.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to data in this system is restricted to ADF and Department of Energy staff, including employees, interns, consultants and contractors, with a need to know in connection with the performance of their official duties.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in this system are maintained for three years after the end of the fiscal year in which an employee terminates employment with ADF, and then retired to the Federal Records Center. The Time and Attendance sheets are maintained for three years and then destroyed.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Administration and Finance, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary Statement in this notice.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the Preliminary statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Record Access Procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>ADF employees and the individual to whom the record pertains.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="adf2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Locater Files.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the President and at agencywide desk top word processors.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Members of the ADF Board of Directors and Advisory Council, American Ambassadors and AID Mission Directors in Africa, ADF staff and personal services contractors, and press contacts.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These files contain names and current addresses and phone numbers.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The African Development Foundation Act, 22 U.S.C. 290h et seq.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of this system is to enable ADF to contact individuals whose names are on file either in writing or by phone.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The contents of these file are used by ADF staff, consultants and contractors to contact individuals whose names are in the file in connection with official ADF business. Information in the file is also available for routine uses 2 through 6 listed in the above Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Records are stored in disk packs with floppy diskette backup. These are filed and maintained in metal cabinets with key locks.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in these files are maintained in alphabetical order.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to the data in the files is through the use of a password. Only those with a need for the information in the files in connection with their regular duties have the password.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this file is kept current. Names and addresses of officials who no longer hold positions noted under "Categories of Individuals"  above are purged from the system.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Assistant to the President, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary Statement above.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as  Record Access Procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information contained in the system is obtained from the individuals listed in the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="adf3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Mailing List.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of the President, ADF, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Academicians; Federal, state, and local government employees; officials in private voluntary and religious organizations involved in overseas development; officers of corporations and financial institutions doing business in Africa, librarians, media people, and other individuals having an interest in, and/or a need to know information about grassroots development in Africa.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Names and current addresses.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The African Development Foundation Act, 22 U.S.C. 290h et seq.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system is maintained as an up to date mailing list for ADF publications.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The names and addresses maintained in this system allow the Foundation to carry out its purpose of disseminating information about grassroots development in Africa through the mailing of publications to persons and institutions involved in development and/or African affairs, both at the academic and practical level. Employees, interns, consultants and contractors having a need for the information in the course of updating the list or mailing the publications have access to it. Since mailing services are provided routinely through an outside contractor, that contractor and its employees will have periodic access to the system in order to prepare mailing labels. Information in the system is also subject to routine uses 2 through 6 as listed above in the Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>The information is stored on magnetic tape with a backup. The tapes are stored on the premises of the firm which has the mailing contract with ADF in a room designated as a tape library. Two hard copy printouts of the tapes are retained by ADF in metal cabinets with key locks.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are maintained in alphabetical order.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are being maintained by the contractor so as to permit access only to employees who have a need to know in connection with the provision of services under the contract. Similarly, access to the hard copies maintained by the Foundation is limited to ADF employees, interns, consultants with a need to know in connection with their duties.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>The records are updated semi-annually and obsolete names and/or addresses are deleted.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Assistant to the President, ADF, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the above Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Record Access Procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Some of the names and addresses of firms and individuals involved in grassroots development were furnished by the Agency for International Development. Others came from ADF employees, and the remainder were furnished by the individuals listed in the system.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="adf4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Paid Voucher Files.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administration and Finance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Employees, contractors, vendors, suppliers, consultants and grantees who have received payment from ADF.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records include paid vouchers, purchase orders, contracts, travel orders, and other obligating documents.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The African Development Foundation Act, 22 U.S.C. 290h et seq.; The Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; Accounting and Auditing Act of 1950; and the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>The purpose of this system is to maintain a record of all payments made by ADF pursuant to purchase orders, contracts, grants and other obligating documents.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are used by ADF staff and contractors to determine amounts to be paid, verify administrative authorizations and eligibility for payment, ensure that payments are made promptly and accurately, confirm costs, and ensure accuracy of accounting information. Other routine uses would be those listed in the above Preliminary Statement. The information is used by ADF employees, consultants, and contractors who have a need for the information in connection with the performance of their official duties.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Records are stored in metal filing cabinets with key locks.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are filed by fiscal year, alphabetically by the last name of the payee.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are available only to appropriate Administration and Finance personnel and other appropriate ADF officials with the need for such records in the performance of their duties.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are held for three years and retired to the Federal Records Center.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director, Administration and Finance, African Development Foundation, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary Statement above in this notice.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Record Access Procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data is obtained from documents </p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="adf5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Procurement/Contracting.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administration &amp;Finance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>All vendors, both companies and individuals, with whom ADF does or has done business, as well as organizations and individuals with whom the Foundation may wish to do business in the future. Included are the records pertaining to vendors, contractors, and consultants.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The system consists of purchase orders and contracts, as well as resumes and SF 171's, and invoices from contractors, vendors and consultants.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>48 CFR Ch. 1, subpart 4.8 (the Federal Acquisition Regulations), the African Development Foundation Act, 22 U.S.C. 290h et seq.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in the system is used to: (1) Provide a complete background as  a basis for informed decisions at each step in the acquisition process; (2) support actions taken; (3) provide information for reviews and investigations; (4) provide information on which to base future procurement decisions.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Disclosures may be made to ADF employees, contractors, consultants, and interns, performing services for ADF at ADF headquarters, with a need to know in order to make informed recommendations or decisions, or take actions, with regard to the procurement of goods or services.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Files are maintained in folders in metal file cabinets with key locks.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed alphabetically by fiscal year.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Information from records is only available to ADF staff who have a need to know in the performance of their official duties, and is usually provided through the Contracting Officer or, in his/her absence, the Director of Administration and Finance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are retained for three years and then reviewed, and either destroyed or forwarded to the Federal Record Center.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Contract Officer, Office of Administration and Finance, ADF, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary Statement in this notice.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Record Access Procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Data is obtained from documents provided by the individual or vendor and, on occasion, by other organizations within or without the Government who may have done business with the individual or organization.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="adf6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Security Files.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administration &amp;Finance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Past and present ADF employees and applicants for employment from 1988 onwards.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>These records contain investigative information regarding an individual's character, conduct, behavior in the community; arrests and convictions for any violations of the law; reports of interviews with former supervisors, co-workers, associates, educators, etc.; reports about the qualifications of an individual for a specific position; reports of inquiries to law enforcement agencies, former employers, educational institutions attended; and other similar information developed from the above.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 10450, and Federal Personnel Manual, Chapters 731, 732, and 736. In addition, there are various acts of Congress relating to personnel investigations authorizing the same by the Office of Personnel Management, which responsibility can, under Civil Service regulations and law, be delegated in whole or in part to agencies.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system was established to keep on record information used to determine eligibility or suitability for employment.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>The contents of these records may be disclosed and used as follows: 1. To the Office of Personnel Management as part of the central OPM personnel investigation records system; 2. to the Foundation's Security Officer and the President of the Foundation for the purposes of making employment suitability and eligibility determinations; and 3. subject to the general routine uses listed in the above Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Investigative folders are maintained in a fireproof, combination lock safe in a room accessible only to authorized personnel.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are indexed in alphabetical order.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Access to the records in this system is restricted to the Foundation Security Officer (the Personnel Officer) and the President, and to the General Counsel of ADF on a need to know basis.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Personnel Security Officer (Personnel Officer), Office of Administration &amp;Finance, African Development Foundation, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20036

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the Preliminary Statement in this notice.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the Preliminary Statement in this notice.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Record Access Procedure.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information contained in this system is obtained from the following categories of sources: 1. Applications and other forms and information furnished by the individual. 2. By personal investigation or written inquiry from such sources as employers, schools, references, neighbors, associates, police departments, courts, credit bureaus, medical records, probation officials, prison officials and other sources as may be developed.


</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
</section>
<section id="adf7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName"> Travel Advance Records.

</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Office of Administration and Finance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Any ADF employees, experts, consultants, contractors or others who have engaged in authorized official travel for ADF.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Manual and automated records of travel advances made to employees, consultants and others, and records of repayment or liquidation of such advances.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>The African Development Foundation Act, 22 U.S.C. 290h et seq.; the Budget and Accounting Act of 1921; the Accounting and Auditing Act of 1950; the Federal Claim Collection Act of 1966.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="purpose"><xhtmlContent><p>This system is maintained to provide a record to account for and issue payments due as the result of authorized official ADF travel; and for audit purposes to account for the expenditure of Federal funds.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>1. To ADF employees, interns, consultants, and contractors in the office of Administration and Finance, and senior management personnel who require access in the performance of their official duties.

</p><p>2. To the Federal Agency which is performing accounting services for ADF pursuant to inter-agency agreement, in this case the National Transportation Safety Board, in the event of a problem with the accounting system which requires the examination of individual transactions.

</p><p>3. Subject to the routine uses listed in the above Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:

</p><p>Manual records are kept in key locked metal filing cabinets. Automated records are on hard disks in the computer accessible only by password available to employees of the Office of Administration and Finance and NSTB employees responsible for systems maintenance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Manual records are maintained alphabetically by name. The automated records are maintained by social security number.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are available to only those with a need to know in connection with the performance of their duties. The records are accessible through the use of a password kept by the Director of Administration and Finance. It is changed every six months by the Director of Administration and Finance.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Records in the system are maintained for one year after the individual leaves the Foundation.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Director of Administration and Finance, Suite 600, 1625 Massachusetts Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Notification paragraph in the above Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>See the Access and Contest paragraph in the Preliminary Statement.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Same as Record Access Procedures.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information is furnished by the individual traveler, supervisors, or other ADF staff.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="22">
<heading> Foreign Relations </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XV">
<heading> African Development Foundation </heading>
<regulationsPart number="1507">
<heading> RULES SAFEGUARDING PERSONAL INFORMATION </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>1507.1 Purpose.
</p>
<p>1507.2 General policies.
</p>
<p>1507.3 Definitions.
</p>
<p>1507.4 Conditions of disclosure.
</p>
<p>1507.5 Accounting for disclosure of records.
</p>
<p>1507.6 Access to records.
</p>
<p>1507.7 Contents of record systems.
</p>
<p>1507.8 Fees.
</p>
<p>1507.9 Judicial review.
</p>
<p>1507.10 Exemptions.
</p>
<p>1507.11 Mailing list.
</p>
<p>1507.12 Criminal penalties.
</p>
<p>1507.13 Reports.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 522a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 53 FR 40411, Oct. 17, 1988, unless otherwise noted.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.1
 Purpose.
</b></p>
<p>The purpose of this part is to set forth the basic policies of the African Development Foundation ("the Foundation" or "ADF") governing the maintenance of systems of records containing personal information as defined in the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.2
 General policies.
</b></p>
<p>It is the policy of the Foundation to safeguard the right of privacy of any individual as to whom the Foundation maintains personal information in any records system, and to provide such individuals with appropriate and complete access to such records, including adequate opportunity to correct any errors in said records. It is further the policy of the Foundation to maintain its records in such a fashion that the information contained therein is, and remains, material and relevant to the purposes for which it is collected. Information in such records will be collected, maintained, used or disseminated in a manner that assures that such action is for a necessary and lawful purpose, and that adequate safeguards are provided to prevent misuse of such information. Exemptions from records requirements provided in 5 U.S.C. 552a will be permitted only where an important public policy need for such exemptions has been determined pursuant to specific statutory authority.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.3
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Record</i> means any document, collection, or grouping of information about an individual maintained by the Foundation, including but not limited to information regarding education, financial transactions, medical history, criminal or employment history, or any other personal information which contains the name or personal identification number, symbol, photograph, or other identifying particular assigned to such individual, such as a finger or voiceprint.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>System of Records</i> means a group of any records under the control of the Foundation from which information is retrieved by use of the name of an individual or by some identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Routine Use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose which is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected.
</p>
<p>(d) The term <i>Foundation</i> means the African Development Foundation or any component thereof.
</p>
<p>(e) The term <i>individual</i> means any citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted to permanent residence.
</p>
<p>(f) The term <i>maintain</i> includes the maintenance, collection, use or dissemination of any record.
</p>
<p>(g) The term <i>Act</i> means the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a) as amended from time to time.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.4
 Conditions of disclosure.
</b></p>
<p>The Foundation will not disclose any record contained in a system of records by any means of communication to any person or any other agency except by written request or prior written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains or his or her agent or attorney, unless such disclosure is:
</p>
<p>(a) To those officers and employees of the Foundation who have a need for the records in the official performance of their duties;
</p>
<p>(b) Required under the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552);
</p>
<p>(c) For a routine use of the record compatible with the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(d) To the Bureau of the Census for purpose of planning or carrying out a census or survey or related activity pursuant to title 13, United States Code;
</p>
<p>(e) To a recipient who has provided the Foundation with advance adequate written assurance that the record will be used solely as a statistical research or reporting record, and the record is to be transferred to a form that is not individually identifiable;
</p>
<p>(f) To the National Archives of the United States as a record which has sufficient historical or other value to warrant its continued preservation by the U.S. Government, or for evaluation by the Administrator of General Services, or designee, to determine whether the record has such value;
</p>
<p>(g) To another agency or to an instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity if the activity is authorized by law, and if the head of the agency or instrumentality has made a written request to the Foundation specifying the particular portion desired and the law enforcement activity for which the record is sought;
</p>
<p>(h) To a person, pursuant to a showing of compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual, if, promptly following such disclosure, notification is transmitted to the last known address of the individual to whom the record pertains;
</p>
<p>(i) To either House of Congress, or, to the extent of matters within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee of Congress or subcommittee of any such joint committee;
</p>
<p>(j) To the Comptroller General, or any authorized representative, in the course of the performance of the duties of the General Accounting Office; or
</p>
<p>(k) Pursuant to the order of a court of competent jurisdiction. If any record disclosed under compulsory legal process is subsequently made public by the court which issued it, the Foundation must make a reasonable effort to notify the individual to whom the record pertains of such disclosure.
</p>
<p>(l) To consumer reporting agencies as defined in 31 U.S.C. 370(a)(3) in accordance with 31 U.S.C. 3711, and under contracts for collection services as authorized in 31 U.S.C. 3718.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.5
 Accounting for disclosure of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) With respect to each system of records under ADF control, the Foundation will keep an accurate accounting of routine disclosures, except those made to employees of the Foundation in the normal course of duties or pursuant to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act. Such accounting shall contain the following:
</p>
<p>(1) The date, nature and purpose of each disclosure, and the name and address of the person or agency to whom the disclosure is made:
</p>
<p>(2) Sufficient information to permit the construction of a listing of all disclosures at appropriate periodic intervals; and
</p>
<p>(3) The justification or basis upon which any release was made including any written documentation required.
</p>
<p>(b) The Foundation will retain the accounting made under this section for at least 5 years or the life of the record, whichever is longer, after the disclosure for which the accounting is made.
</p>
<p>(c) Except for disclosure made under paragraph (g) of &#167; 1503.3, the Foundation will make the accounting under paragraph (a) of this section available to the individual named in the record at his or her request.
</p>
<p>(d) The Foundation will inform any person or other agency about any correction or notation of dispute made by the agency of any record that has been disclosed to the person or agency if an accounting of the disclosure was made.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.6
 Access to records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Except as otherwise provided by law or regulation, any individual, upon request made either in writing or in person during regular business hours, shall be provided access to his or her record or to any information pertaining to him or her which is contained in a system of records maintained by the Foundation. The individual will be permitted to review the record and have a copy made of all or any portion thereof in a form comprehensible to him or her. Nothing in 5 U.S.C. 552a, however, allows an individual access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding.
</p>
<p>(b) An individual will be notified, upon request, if any Foundation system of records contains a record pertaining to him or her. Such request may be made in person during regular business hours, or in writing over the signature of the person making the request. Individuals requesting the information will be required to identify themselves by providing their names, addresses, and a signature. If they are requesting disclosure in person, they are also required to show an identification card, such as a drivers license, containing a photo and a sample signature. If the request is received through the mail, the Foundation may request such information as may be necessary to assure that the requesting individual is properly identified. This may include a requirement that the request be notarized with a notation that the notary received an acknowledgement of identity from the requester.
</p>
<p>(c) A record may be disclosed to a representative of the person to whom a record relates when the representative is authorized in writing by such person to have access.
</p>
<p>(d) Requests for access to or copies of records should contain, at a minimum, identifying information needed to locate any given record, and a brief description of the item or items of information required. If the individual wishes access to specific documents, the request should identify or describe, as nearly as possible, such documents. The request should be made to the Director, Administration and Finance, African Development Foundation, 1625 Massachusetts Avenue NW., Suite 600, Washington, DC 20036. Personal contacts should normally be made during the regular duty hours of the officer concerned, which are 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. Monday through Friday.
</p>
<p>(e) A request made in person will be promptly complied with if the records sought are in the immediate custody of the Foundation. Mail or personal requests for documents which are not in the immediate custody of ADF or which are otherwise not immediately available, will be acknowledged within ten working days of receipt, and the records will be provided as promptly thereafter as possible.
</p>
<p>(f) Special procedures may be established by the President of the Foundation governing the disclosure to an individual of his or her medical records, including psychological records.
</p>
<p>(g) Any individual may request the Director, Administration and Finance, to amend any Foundation record pertaining to him or her. Not later than 10 working days after the date of receipt of such request, the Director, Administration and Finance, or his/her designee, will acknowledge such receipt in writing. Promptly after acknowledging receipt of a request, the Director, Administration and Finance or his/her designee will:
</p>
<p>(1) Correct any portion of the record which the individual believes is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete; or
</p>
<p>(2) Inform the individual of the Foundation's refusal to amend the record in accordance with the request, the reason for the refusal, the procedures by which the individual may request a review of that refusal by the President of the Foundation, or his/her designee, and the name and address of such official; or
</p>
<p>(3) Refer the request to the agency that has control of and maintains the record when the record requested is not the property of the Foundation, but of the controlling agency.
</p>
<p>(h) Any individual who disagrees with the refusal of the Director, Administration and Finance to amend his or her record may request a review of that refusal. Such request for review must be made within 30 days after receipt by the requester of the initial refusal to amend. The President of the Foundation, or designee, will complete such review not later than 30 working days from the date on which the individual requests such review, and make a final determination, unless for good cause shown, the President or designee extends such 30-day period and notifies the requester in writing that additional time is required to complete the review. If, after review, the President or designee refuses to amend the record in accordance with the request, the individual will be advised of the right to file with the Foundation a concise statement setting forth the reasons for his or her disagreement with the refusal, and also advised of the provisions in the Act for judicial review of the President's determination.
</p>
<p>(i) In any disclosure containing information about which the individual has filed a statement under paragraph (g) of this section, the Foundation will clearly note any part of the record which is disputed and provide copies of the statement and, if the Foundation deems it appropriate, copies of a concise statement of the Foundation's reasons for not making the amendment requested, to persons or other agencies to whom the disputed record has been disclosed.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.7
 Contents of records systems.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Foundation will maintain in its records only such information about an individual as is accurate, relevant, and necessary to accomplish the purpose for which it was acquired as authorized by statute or Executive Order.
</p>
<p>(b) The Foundation will collect information, to the greatest extent practicable, directly from the individual to whom the record pertains when the information may result in adverse determinations about the individual's rights, benefits and privileges under Federal programs.
</p>
<p>(c) The Foundation will inform each individual whom it asks to supply information on any form which it uses to collect the information, or on a separate form that can be retained by the individual, of:
</p>
<p>(1) The authority which authorizes the solicitation of the information and whether provision of such information is mandatory or voluntary;
</p>
<p>(2) The purpose or purposes for which the information is intended to be used;
</p>
<p>(3) The routine uses which may be made of the information, as published pursuant to paragraph (d) of this section; and
</p>
<p>(4) The effects on the individual, if any, of not providing all or any part of the requested information.
</p>
<p>(d) Subject to the provisions of paragraph (k) of this section, the Foundation will publish in the <i>Federal Register,</i> at least a notice of the existence and character of its sytem(s) of records upon establishment or revision. This notice will include:
</p>
<p>(1) The name and location of the system or systems;
</p>
<p>(2) The categories of individuals on whom records are maintained in the system or systems;
</p>
<p>(3) The categories of records maintained in the system or sytems;
</p>
<p>(4) Each routine use of the records contained in the system or systems, including the categories of users, and the purpose of such use;
</p>
<p>(5) The policies and practices of the Foundation regarding storage, retrievability, access controls, retention, and disposal of the record;
</p>
<p>(6) The title and business address of the Foundation official or officials responsible for the system or systems of records;
</p>
<p>(7) The Foundation's procedures whereby an individual can be notified at his or her request if the system or systems of records contains a record pertaining to him or her;
</p>
<p>(8) The Foundation's procedures whereby an individual can be notified at him or her request how he or she can gain access to any record pertaining to him or her contained in the system or systems of records, and how he or she can contest its content; and
</p>
<p>(9) The categories of sources of records in the system or systems.
</p>
<p>(e) All records used by the Foundation in making any determination about any individual will be maintained with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to assure fairness to the individual in the determination.
</p>
<p>(f) Before disseminating any record about an individual to any person other than an agency or pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552, the Foundation will make reasonable efforts to assure that such records are accurate, complete, timely, and relevant for Foundation purposes.
</p>
<p>(g) The Foundation will maintain no record describing how any individual exercises rights guaranteed by the First Amendment of the Constitution of the United States unless expressly authorized by statute or by the individual about whom the record is maintained, or unless pertinent to, and within the scope of, an authorized law enforcement activity.
</p>
<p>(h) The Foundation will establish rules of conduct for persons involved in the design, development, operation, or maintenance of any system of records, or in maintaining any record. Each such person will be instructed regarding such rules and the requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a. The instruction will include any other rules and procedures adopted pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a, and the penalties provided for noncompliance.
</p>
<p>(i) The Foundation will establish appropriate administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to insure the security and confidentiality of records and to protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to their security or integrity which could result in substantial harm, embarrassment, inconvenience, or unfairness to any individual on whom information is maintained.
</p>
<p>(j) At least 30 days prior to the publication of the notice in the <i>Federal Register</i> regarding the routine use of the records contained in the Foundation's system or systems of records, including the categories of users and the purpose of such use pursuant to paragraph (d) of this section, the Foundation will also:
</p>
<p>(1) Publish a notice in the <i>Federal Register</i> of any new or revised use of the information in the system or systems maintained by the Foundation; and
</p>
<p>(2) Provide an opportunity for interested persons to submit written data, views, or arguments to the Foundation.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.8
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>Fees to be charged, if any, to any individual for making copies of his or her record will be as follows:
</p>
<p>(a) Photocopy reproductions from all types of copying processes, each reproduction image, $0.10 per page.
</p>
<p>(b) Where the Foundation undertakes to perform for an individual making a request, or for any other person, services which are very clearly not required to be performed under section 552a, title 5, United States Code, either voluntarily or because such services are required by some other law (e.g., the formal certification of records as true copies, attestation under the seal of the Foundation, etc.), the question of charging fees for such services will be determined by the Director of Administration and Finance, in light of the Federal user charge statute (31 U.S.C. 483a), and any other applicable law.
</p>
<p>(c) No fees shall be charged for search time expended by the Foundation to produce a record.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.9
 Judicial review.
</b></p>
<p>Any person may file a complaint against the Foundation in the appropriate U.S. district court, as provided in 5 U.S.C. 552a(g), whenever the Foundation:
</p>
<p>(a) Makes a determination not to amend an individual's record in accordance with his or her request, or fails to make such review in conformity with that section; or
</p>
<p>(b) Refuses to comply with an individual's request; or
</p>
<p>(c) Fails to maintain any record concerning an individual with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is necessary to assure fairness in any determination relating to the qualifications, character, rights or opportunities of, or benefits to the individual that may be made on the basis of such record, and consequently a determination is made which is adverse to the individual; or
</p>
<p>(d) Fails to comply with any other provision of 5 U.S.C. 552a, or any Foundation regulation promulgated thereunder, in any such a way as to have an adverse effect on an individual.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.10
 Exemptions.
</b></p>
<p>No Foundation system or systems of records, as such, are exempted from the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a, as permitted under certain conditions by 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) and (k).

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.11
 Mailing list.
</b></p>
<p>An individual's name and address may not be sold or rented by the Foundation unless such action is specifically authorized by law. This section does not require the withholding of names and addresses otherwise permitted to be made public.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.12
 Criminal penalties.
</b></p>
<p>Section 552a(e), title 5, United States Code, provides that:
</p>
<p>(a) Any officer or employee of the Foundation, who, by virtue of his or her employment or official position, has possession of, or access to, Foundation records which contain individually identifiable information, the disclosure of which is prohibited by 5 U.S.C. 552a, and who knowing that disclosure of the specific material is so prohibited, willfully discloses the material in any manner to any person or agency not entitled to receive it, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.
</p>
<p>(b) Any officer or employee of the Foundation who willfully maintains a system of records without meeting the notice requirements of 5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(4) shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.
</p>
<p>(c) Any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any record concerning an individual from the Foundation under false pretenses shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1507.13 Reports.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Foundation shall provide to Congress and the Office of Management and Budget advance notice of any proposal to establish or alter any system or records as defined herein. This report will be submitted in accordance with guidelines provided by the Office of Management and Budget.
</p>
<p>(b) If at any time Foundation system or systems of records is determined to be exempt from the application of 5 U.S.C. 552a in accordance with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552a (j) and (k), the records contained in such system or systems will be separately listed and reported to the Office of Management and Budget in accordance with the then prevailing guidelines and instructions of that office.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
