<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>




<pai>
    <agency toc="yes">
        <name>Millennium Challenge Corporation </name>
        <abbrev>
            MCC
        </abbrev>
            
            

            <section id="mcc001" toc="yes">
                <systemNumber>mcc-001</systemNumber>
                <subsection type="systemName">MCC–Business Relations System (MCC-BRS), MCC – 001
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="securityClassification">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Unclassified</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records in this system process information on international and domestic contracting firm owners and employees, small to medium business owners and employees; and other individuals that are contacts or leads for potential vendors.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>The categories include: 1.  Personally identifiable information (PII); such as, name, company name, job title, business address, business phone number, country or country region, email, and notes on a meeting or event; and 2.  Meeting notes.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>22 U.S.C. 7705, Chapter 84 – Millennium Challenge</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="purpose">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>MCC staff will use the system to collect, store, and process business contact information that will contain PII.  The information collected achieves MCC’s core functions of reducing global poverty through economic growth by aligning business contacts with MCC’s mission.  The PII information collected is similar to the information on a business card.  Using a customer relations management (CRM) increases accuracy and business efficiencies.  In addition, MCC will utilize the system to process, store, and retain personal notations on meeting or business events.  Personal notations can include information that promotes efficiencies in previous contact meetings, discussions, or events that have transpired in the past.  Additionally, the system utilizes encrypted links to provide efficiencies in communications campaigns through mass email distribution, and event engagement opportunities to event attendees, or vendor groups.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>In addition to those disclosures  generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, all or a portion of the records or information contained in this system may be disclosed to authorized  entities,  as determined  to be relevant and necessary, outside MCC as a routine  use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</p>
                        <p>&#149; Financial project monitoring or collections;</p>
                        <p>&#149; Due diligence background checks and screening;</p>
                        <p>&#149; Litigation or arbitration purposes;</p>
                        <p>&#149; Outside organizations contracted with OPIC for specific authorized activities;</p>
                        <p>&#149; National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) for records management purposes;</p>
                        <p>&#149; Contractors, interns, and government detailed personnel to perform OPIC authorized activities;</p>
                        <p>&#149; Audits and oversight;</p>
                        <p>&#149; Congressional inquiries;</p>
                        <p>&#149; Investigations of potential violations of law.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Storage:</p>
                        <p>This system is electronically stored in a government cloud service centrally located at a Salesforce GSA data center.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="safeguards">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>MCC safeguards the information in accordance with applicable laws, rules and policies, including the Federal Information Security Modernization Act of 2014; OMB Circular A-130, Management of Federal Resources; Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP); and MCC policies and procedures.  MCC protects records from unauthorized access through appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards.  These safeguards include restricting access to authorized personnel who have need-to-know, and the process of authentication using user identifications (IDs) and passwords that function as an identity and authentication method of access.  Personnel with authorized access to the system have received training in the proper handling of Privacy Act information and in information security requirements for both paper copies and electronically stored information.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>MCC retains records in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), General Records Schedule (GRS).</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="retrievability">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Records are retrievable by personal name, project name, or a combination of search functions available in the Salesforce CRM tool.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="systemManager">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Jason Bauer, Director of Finance, Investment and Trade (FIT), Department of Compact Operations, 1099 Fourteenth Street, N.W. Suite 700, Washington, DC, 20005-3550.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Individuals seeking knowledge of the system’s records must submit a written request to the MCC Privacy Officer, at the above mailing address, clearly marked as “Privacy Act Request” on the envelope and letter.  The request must include the requestor’s full name, current address, the name or number of the system to be searched, and if possible, the record identification number.  The request must be signed by either notarized signature or by signature under penalty of perjury under 28 U.S.C. 1746.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Same as notification procedures.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>Same as the notification procedure above; the request should also clearly and concisely describe the information contested, the reasons for contesting it, and the proposed amendment sought, pursuant to 45 CFR 5b.7.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>The federal employee collects and imports the contact information or event information directly to the system. Additionally, the www.MCC.gov public website events webform will import the contact information directly to the system.</p>
                    </xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
                <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                    <xhtmlContent>
                        <p>None.</p>
                        </xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
  </agency></pai>
