<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Office of Government Ethics</name>
<abbrev>
OGE</abbrev>

    <previousPubs id="systems" toc="yes">
        <title>Systems of Records Published Between January 2, 2020 and December 31, 2021</title>
    </previousPubs>
    <previouslyPublished>
        <url> https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-10/pdf/2021-24567.pdf</url>
        <title> OGE/INTERNAL-1, 3, 4, and 4 Amended; OGE/INTERNAL-2 rescinded </title>
        <date year="21" month="11 " day="10 " />
    </previouslyPublished>

    <section id="govt1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>/GOVT-1</systemNumber>
    <subsection type="systemName">
        OGE/GOVT-1, Executive Branch Personnel Public Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Name-Retrieved Ethics Program Records.
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemLocation">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917, and designated agency ethics offices.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="systemManager">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p>a. For records filed directly with the Office of Government Ethics by non-OGE employees: General Counsel, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917.</p>
                    <p>b. For records filed with a Designated Agency Ethics Official (DAEO) or the head of a department or agency: The DAEO at the department or agency concerned.</p>
                    <p>c. For records filed with the Federal Election Commission (FEC) by candidates for President or Vice President: The General Counsel, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW, Washington, DC 20463.</p>
                    <p>d. For general questions about this system of records, contact the OGE Senior Agency Official for Privacy, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005–3917.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> 5 U.S.C. 7301, 7351, 7353; 5 U.S.C. App. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); 31 U.S.C. 1353; E.O. 12674 (as modified by E.O. 12731); E.O. 13770 or any superseding Executive order; Representative Louise McIntosh Slaughter Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act (STOCK Act), Pub. L. No. 112-105 (2012); 5 CFR part 2634.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="purpose">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> All records are collected and maintained in accordance with the requirements of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 and the Ethics Reform Act of 1989, as amended, and Executive Order 12674, as modified, and OGE and agency regulations thereunder. These records include the filing of financial disclosure reports and ethics agreements, waivers issued to an officer or employee pursuant to section 208 of title 18 or Executive order, and certificates of divestiture issued pursuant to section 502 of the Ethics Reform Act. Such reports and related records are required to assure compliance with ethics laws and regulations, and to determine if an actual or apparent conflict of interest exists between the employment of individuals by the Federal Government and their outside employment and financial interests.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> This system of records contains records about individuals whose positions have been designated as public financial disclosure filing positions in accordance with 5 U.S.C. app. 101 and 5 CFR 2634.202. This system of records includes both former and current employees in these categories who have filed financial disclosure statements under the requirements of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, as amended, or who otherwise come under the requirements of the Ethics in Government Act. This system of records also contains information that is necessary for administering all provisions of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 and the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 (Pub. L. 101-194), as amended, and E.O. 12674, as modified, on any current or former officer or employee of the executive branch.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> This system of records contains: Financial information such as salary, dividends, retirement benefits, interests in property, deposits in a bank and other financial institutions; information on gifts received; information on certain liabilities; information about positions as an officer, director, trustee, general partner, proprietor, representative, employee, or consultant of any corporation, company, firm, partnership, or other business, non-profit organization, labor organization, or educational institution; information about non-Government employment agreements, such as leaves of absence to accept Federal service, continuation of payments by a non-Federal employer; and information about assets placed in trust pending disposal. This system of records also includes other documents developed or information and material received by the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, or agency ethics officials in administering the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 or the Ethics Reform Act of 1989, as amended, which are retrieved by name or other personal identifier. Such other documents or information may include, but will not be limited to: ethics agreements, documentation of waivers issued to an officer or employee by an agency pursuant to section 208(b)(1) or section 208(b)(3) of title 18, U.S.C., or pursuant to Executive orders; certificates of divestiture issued by the President or by the Director of OGE pursuant to section 502 of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989; information necessary for the rendering of ethics counseling, advice or formal advisory opinions, or the resolution of complaints; the actual opinions issued; and records of referrals and consultations regarding current and former employees who are or have been the subject of conflicts of interest or standards of conduct inquiries or determinations, or employees who are alleged to have violated department, agency or Federal ethics statutes, rules, regulations or Executive orders. Such information may include correspondence, documents or material concerning an individual's conduct, reports of investigations with related exhibits, statements, affidavits or other records obtained during an inquiry. The information does not include information from confidential financial disclosure reports, which is maintained in OGE/GOVT-2, Executive Branch Confidential Financial Disclosure Reports.</p>
                    <p> These records may include information related to personal and family financial and other business interests, positions held outside the Government and acceptance of gifts. The records may also contain reports of action taken by the agency and decisions and reports on legal or disciplinary action resulting from any referred administrative action or prosecution.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Information in this system of records is provided by:</p>
                    <p>a. The subject individual or by a designated person, such as a trustee, attorney, accountant, banker, or relative.</p>
                    <p>b. Federal officials who review the statements to make conflict of interest determinations.</p>
                    <p>c. Persons alleging conflict of interests or violations of other ethics laws and persons contacted during any investigation of the allegations.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> These records and information in these records may be used:</p>
                    <p>a. To disclose information furnished in accordance with sections 105 and 402(b)(1) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, 5 U.S.C. app., as amended, and subject to the limitations contained therein, to any requesting person.</p>
                    <p> b. To disclose to any requesting person, in accordance with section 105 of the Ethics in Government Act, as amended, and subject to the limitations contained in section 208(d)(1) of title 18, U.S.C., any determination granting an exemption pursuant to 208(b)(1) or 208(b)(3) of title 18, U.S.C. These determinations are commonly called "conflict of interest waivers."</p>
                    <p>c. To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                    <p>d. To disclose information to any source when necessary to obtain information relevant to a conflict-of-interest investigation or determination.</p>
                    <p>e. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration or the General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                    <p>f. To disclose information to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.</p>
                    <p>g. To disclose information when the disclosing agency determines that that the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body; or in a proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                    <p>h. To disclose the public financial disclosure report and any accompanying documents, including statements notifying an employee’s supervising ethics office of the commencement of negotiations for future employment or compensation or of an agreement for future employment or compensation pursuant to section 17 of the STOCK Act (Pub. L. 112-105), to reviewing officials in a new office, department or agency when an employee transfers or is detailed from a covered position in one office, department or agency to a covered position in another office, department or agency.</p>
                    <p>i. To disclose information to a Member of Congress or a congressional office in response to an inquiry made on behalf of, and at the request of, an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                    <p>j. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, detailees, and other non-Government employees performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the Federal Government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                    <p>k. To disclose on the OGE website and to otherwise disclose to any person, including other departments and agencies, any written ethics agreements, including certifications of ethics agreement compliance, filed with the Office of Government Ethics, pursuant to 5 CFR 2634.803, by an individual nominated by the President to a position requiring Senate confirmation when the position also requires the individual to file a public financial disclosure report.</p>
                    <p>l. To disclose on the OGE website and to otherwise disclose to any person, including other departments and agencies, any certificate of divestiture issued by the Office of Government Ethics, pursuant to 26 U.S.C. 1043.</p>
                    <p>m. To disclose on the OGE website and to otherwise disclose to any person, including other departments and agencies, any waiver issued by the President or the President’s designee of the restrictions contained in Executive Order 13770 "Ethics Commitments by Executive Branch Appointees" (January 28, 2017) or any superseding Executive order.</p>
                    <p>n. To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) the agency maintaining the records suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the agency maintaining the records has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                    <p>o. To disclose information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the agency maintaining the record determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                    <p><b> Note: </b>When an agency is requested to furnish records in this system of records to the Director or other authorized officials of the Office of Government Ethics (OGE), such a disclosure is to be considered as made to those officers and employees of the agency which co-maintains the records who have a need for the records in the performance of their official duties in accordance with the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, 5 U.S.C. app., and other ethics-related laws, Executive orders and regulations conferring pertinent authority on OGE, pursuant to the provisions of the Privacy Act at 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1).
                    </p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> These records are maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retrievability">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individual about whom they are maintained.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> In accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 2.8 Employee Ethics Records, these records are generally retained for a period of six years after filing, or for such other period of time as is provided for in that schedule for certain specified types of ethics records. In cases where records are filed by, or with respect to, a nominee for an appointment requiring confirmation by the Senate when the nominee is not appointed and Presidential and Vice-Presidential candidates who are not elected, the records are generally destroyed one year after the date the individual ceased being under Senate consideration for appointment or is no longer a candidate for office. However, if any records are needed in an ongoing investigation, they will be retained until no longer needed in the investigation. Destruction is by shredding or electronic deletion.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="safeguards">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> These records are maintained in file cabinets which may be locked or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Access to the data in the executive branch-wide Integrity public financial disclosure information system and OGE electronic systems is protected by electronic controls, such as multifactor authentication and password protection. Access to the systems is controlled based on user roles and responsibilities. Executive branch agencies control their users’ access to information in Integrity and are responsible for properly safeguarding the records maintained in their systems.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals wishing to request access to their records should contact the appropriate office as shown in the Notification Procedure section. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                    <p>a. Full name.</p>
                    <p>b. Department or agency and component with which employed or proposed to be employed.</p>
                    <p>c. Dates of employment.</p>
                    <p>d. A reasonably specific description of the record content being sought.</p>
                    <p> Individuals requesting access to records maintained at OGE must also follow OGE's Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and access to records (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Because the information in these records is updated on a periodic basis, most record corrections can be handled through established administrative procedures for updating the records. However, individuals can obtain information on the procedures for contesting the records under the provisions of the Privacy Act by contacting the appropriate office shown in the Notification Procedure section.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about them should contact, as appropriate:</p>
                    <p>a. For records filed directly with OGE by non-OGE employees, contact the General Counsel, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917;</p>
                    <p>b. For records filed with a Designated Agency Ethics Official (DAEO) or the head of a department or agency, contact the DAEO at the department or agency concerned; and</p>
                    <p>c. For records filed with the FEC by candidates for President or Vice President, contact the FEC General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW, Washington, DC 20463.</p>
                    <p> Individuals wishing to make such an inquiry must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                    <p>a. Full name.</p>
                    <p>b. Department or agency and component with which employed or proposed to be employed.</p>
                    <p>c. Dates of employment.</p>
                    <p> Individuals seeking to determine if an OGE system of records contains information about them must also follow OGE's Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> None.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
            </subsection>
            <subsection type="history">
                <xhtmlContent>
                    <p> This system of records was originally published in full at 55 FR 6327 (Feb. 22, 1990) and subsequently amended by the following notices: 68 FR 3097 (Jan. 22, 2003); 68 FR 24744 (May 8, 2003); 76 FR 24489 (May 2, 2011); 77 FR 45353 (July 31, 2012); 78 FR 73863 (Dec. 9, 2013).</p>
                </xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.

</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="govt2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>/GOVT-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">OGE/GOVT-2, Executive Branch Confidential Financial Disclosure Reports.
</subsection>
    <subsection type="securityClassification">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Unclassified.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemLocation">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Individual agency ethics offices or other designated agency offices.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="systemManager">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> These records are maintained in the department or agency where the reports are filed. For questions about a particular report, contact the Designated Agency Ethics Official (DAEO) at the department or agency concerned. For general questions about this system of records, contact the OGE Senior Agency Official for Privacy, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005–3917.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> 5 U.S.C. app. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); E.O. 12674 (as modified by E.O. 12731); 5 CFR part 2634.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="purpose">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> These records are collected and maintained to meet the requirements of Executive Order 12674, as modified, 5 CFR part 2634, and agency regulations thereunder, as well as section 107 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, as amended, concerning the filing of confidential financial disclosure reports. Such reports are required to assure compliance with ethics laws and regulations, and to determine if an actual or apparent conflict of interest exists between the employment of individuals by the Federal Government and their outside employment and financial interests.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Officers and employees in the executive branch whose positions have been designated as confidential financial disclosure filing positions in accordance with 5 CFR 2634.904 and 5 U.S.C. app. 107. In addition, all executive branch special Government employees (SGE) as defined in 18 U.S.C. 202(a) and 5 CFR 2634.105(s) are required to file unless they are required to file public financial disclosure reports or their positions have been excluded from filing. The system of records includes both current and former Federal employees in these categories.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> These records contain statements and amended statements of personal and family holdings and other interests in property; income; gifts and reimbursements; liabilities; agreements and arrangements; outside positions; and other information related to conflict of interest determinations. These statements include completed copies of the OGE Form 450 and completed copies of agency supplemental or alternative confidential report forms.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Information in this system of records is provided by:</p>
            <p>a. The subject individual or by a designated person such as a trustee, attorney, accountant, banker, or relative.</p>
            <p>b. Federal officials who review the statements to make conflict of interest determinations.</p>
            <p>c. Persons alleging conflicts of interests or other violations of ethics laws and persons contacted during any investigation of the allegations.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> These confidential records and the information contained therein may be used:</p>
            <p>a. To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, where the disclosing agency becomes aware of an indication of a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
            <p>b. To disclose information to any source when necessary to obtain information relevant to a conflict-of- interest investigation or determination.</p>
            <p>c. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration or the General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
            <p>d. To disclose information to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A-19.</p>
            <p>e. To disclose information when the disclosing agency determines that that the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body; or in a proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
            <p>f. To disclose the confidential financial disclosure report or certificate of no new interests and any accompanying documents to reviewing officials in a new office, department or agency when an employee transfers or is detailed from a covered position in one office, department or agency to a covered position in another office, department or agency.</p>
            <p>g. To disclose information to a Member of Congress or a congressional office in response to an inquiry made on behalf of, and at the request of, an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
            <p>h. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, detailees, and other non-Government employees performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the Federal Government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
            <p>i.  To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) the agency maintaining the records suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) the agency maintaining the records has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with the agency's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
            <p>j. To disclose information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when the agency maintaining the record determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            <p>
                <b>Note: </b>When an agency is requested to furnish records in this system of records to the Director or other authorized officials of the Office of Government Ethics (OGE), such a disclosure is to be considered as made to those officers and employees of the agency which co- maintains the records who have a need for the records in the performance of their official duties in accordance with the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, 5 U.S.C. app., and other ethics-related laws, Executive orders, and regulations conferring pertinent authority on OGE, pursuant to the provisions of the Privacy Act at 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(1).
            </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> These records are maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retrievability">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> These records are retrieved by the name or other programmatic identifier assigned to the individual on whom they are maintained.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> In accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule 2.8 Employee Ethics Records, these records generally are retained for six years after filing, except when filed by or with respect to a nominee and the nominee ceases to be under consideration for the position. However, if any records are needed in an ongoing investigation, they will be retained until no longer needed in the investigation. Destruction is by shredding or electronic deletion. </p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="safeguards">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> With regard to OGE records, these records are located in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods. Executive branch agencies are responsible for properly safeguarding the records maintained in their systems.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p>Individuals wishing to request access to their records should contact the DAEO or designee at the agency where the reports were filed. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
            <p>a. Full name.</p>
            <p>b. Department or agency and component with which employed or proposed to be employed.</p>
            <p>c. Dates of employment.</p>
            <p>d. A reasonably specific description of the record content being sought.</p>
            <p>Individuals requesting access to records maintained at OGE must also follow OGE's Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and access to records (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Because the information in these records is updated on a periodic basis, most record corrections can be handled through established administrative procedures for updating records. However, individuals can obtain information on the procedures for contesting the records under the provisions of the Privacy Act by contacting the DAEO or designee at the agency where the reports were filed.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about them should contact the DAEO at the department or agency concerned. For records maintained at OGE, contact the OGE Senior Agency Official for Privacy, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005–3917.</p>
            <p> Individuals wishing to make such an inquiry must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
            <p>a. Full name.</p>
            <p>b. Department or agency and component where employed or where proposed to be employed.</p>
            <p>c. Dates of employment.</p>
            <p> Individuals seeking to determine if an OGE system of records contains information about them must also follow OGE's Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> None.</p>
        </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
    <subsection type="history">
        <xhtmlContent>
            <p> This system of records was originally published in full at 55 FR 6327 (Feb. 22, 1990) and subsequently amended by 68 FR 3097 (Jan. 22, 2003) and 68 FR 24744 (May 8, 2003).</p>
        </xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="exemptionsClaimed"><xhtmlContent><p>None.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
    <section id="internal1" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/INTERNAL-1</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p>OGE/INTERNAL-1, Pay, Leave, Travel, and Reasonable Accommodation Records.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Deputy Director for Compliance, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917, email: usoge@oge.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. 5525; 5 U.S.C. App. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); 44 U.S.C. 3101, 3102; 29 U.S.C. 701 et seq. (Rehabilitation Act of 1973); 42 U.S.C. Section 2000e (Title VII of the Civil Rights Act).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  These records are used to administer the pay, leave, and travel requirements of the Office of Government Ethics, including the administration of the transit fare subsidy program. The records are also used to collect and maintain records on employees who request or receive reasonable accommodation as required by the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and Title VII of the Civil Rights Act.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Current employees of the Office of Government Ethics. The records may be retained after an employee leaves the Office of Government Ethics.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains various records relating to pay, leave, travel and requests for reasonable accommodations pursuant to the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and Title VII of the Civil Rights Act. This includes information such as: name; date of birth; social security number; home address; grade; employing organization; disability status, religious affiliation, accommodation requested and/or granted, timekeeper number; salary; pay plan; number of hours worked; leave accrual rate, usage, and balances; Civil Service Retirement and Federal Employees Retirement System contributions; FICA withholdings; Federal, state, and local tax withholdings; Federal Employee’s Group Life Insurance withholdings; Federal Employee’s Health Benefits withholdings; charitable deductions; allotments; garnishment documents; travel expenses; and information on the leave transfer program and fare subsidy program.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Information in this system of records is obtained from:</p>
                <p>a. The individual to whom the record pertains.</p>
                <p>b. Office of Government Ethics officials responsible for pay, leave, and travel requirements.</p>
                <p>c. Other official personnel documents of the Office of Government Ethics.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>ROUTINE USES:</b>
                </p>
                <p>a. To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible (hereinafter "responsible agency") for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the record either alone or in conjunction with other information indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p>b. To disclose information when OGE determines that that the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body; or in a proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>c. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration or the General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>d. To disclose information to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A–19.</p>
                <p>e. To disclose information to a Member of Congress or a congressional office in response to an inquiry made on behalf of, and at the request of, an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                <p>f. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, detailees, and other non-OGE employees performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the Federal Government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                <p>g. To disclose information to the Department of Labor in connection with a claim filed by an employee for compensation due to a job-connected injury or illness.</p>
                <p>h. To disclose information to the Social Security Administration (SSA) and the Department of the Treasury as required in accordance with their authorized functions, including Federal Insurance Collections Act withholding and benefits for the SSA and the issuance of paychecks and savings bonds for the Treasury.</p>
                <p>i. To disclose information to State offices of unemployment compensation.</p>
                <p>j. To disclose information to Federal Employees Group Life Insurance or Health Benefits carriers in connection with survivor annuity or health benefits claims or records reconciliations.</p>
                <p>k. To disclose information to the Internal Revenue Service and State and local tax authorities.</p>
                <p>l. To disclose information to any source from which additional information is requested relevant to an OGE determination concerning an individual’s pay, leave, or travel expenses, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and to identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p>m. To disclose information to a Federal agency, in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a suitability or security investigation of an individual, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency’s decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>n. To disclose information to the authorized employees of another Federal agency that provides the Office of Government Ethics with manual and automated assistance in processing pay, leave, and travel.</p>
                <p>o. To disclose information to officials of the Office of Special Counsel, Office of Personnel Management, Federal Labor Relations Authority, Merit Systems Protection Board or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in the performance of their authorized duties, including respectively in connection with cases and appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of personnel matters and practices, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel and discrimination practices, Hatch Act matters, whistleblower protections, compliance with employee selection procedures and investigations of allegations of unfair labor practices or matters before the Federal Service Impasses Panel.</p>
                <p>p. To disclose information in compliance with orders, interrogatories, and other information requests relevant to garnishment orders that OGE is required to comply with in accordance with 42 U.S.C. 659 (support garnishment) and 5 U.S.C. 5520a (commercial garnishment) to a court of competent jurisdiction, an authorized official, or to an authorized State agency as defined in 5 CFR parts 581 and 582.</p>
                <p>q. To provide information to officials of labor organizations recognized under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71 when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting working conditions.</p>
                <p>r. To disclose the names, social security numbers, home addresses, date of birth, date of hire, quarterly earnings, employer identifying information, and State of hire of employees to the Office of Child Support Enforcement, Administration for Children and Families, Department of Health and Human Services for the purposes of locating individuals to establish paternity, establishing and modifying orders of child support, identifying sources of income, and for other child support enforcement actions as required by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act, Pub. L. 104–193, as amended.</p>
                <p>s. To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) OGE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) OGE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with OGE's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>t. To disclose information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when OGE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retrieved by the name, social security number, or other identifier assigned to the individual on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule (GRS) as follows:</p>
                <p>a. GRS 2.3: Employee Relations Records;</p>
                <p>b. GRS 2.4:  Employee Compensation and Benefits Records; and</p>
                <p>c. GRS 1.1:  Financial Management and Reporting Records.</p>
                <p>Disposal of paper records is by shredding, and disposal of electronic records is by deletion.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records are maintained in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals requesting access to this system of records must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals wishing to request amendment of records about themselves should contact the System Manager. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                <p>a. Full name.</p>
                <p>b. Social Security Number.</p>
                <p>c. Dates of employment.</p>
                <p>Individuals requesting amendment must also follow OGE’s Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and amendment of records (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about themselves must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 68 FR 3097.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="internal3" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/INTERNAL-3</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> OGE/INTERNAL-3, Grievance Records.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Deputy Director for Compliance, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917, email: usoge@oge.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. App. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); 5 U.S.C. 7121; 5 CFR part 771.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  These records are used to process grievances submitted by OGE employees for personal relief in a matter of concern or dissatisfaction.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current or former OGE employees who have filed grievances under OGE’s administrative grievance procedures or under a negotiated grievance procedure.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The system contains records relating to grievances filed by OGE employees under administrative procedures authorized by 5 CFR part 771, and records of negotiated grievance and arbitration systems that OGE has or may establish through negotiations with recognized labor organizations in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 7121. These files contain all documents related to the grievance, which may include statements of witnesses, reports of interviews and hearings, examiner’s findings and recommendations, a copy of the original decision, and related correspondence and exhibits, employment history, arbitrator’s decision or report, record of appeal to the Federal Labor Relations Authority, and a variety of employment and personnel records associated with the grievance.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Information in this system of records is obtained from:</p>
                <p>a. The individual on whom the record is maintained.</p>
                <p>b. Testimony of witnesses.</p>
                <p>c. OGE officials.</p>
                <p>d. Related correspondence from organizations or persons.</p>
                <p>e. Union officials (if information deals with a negotiated grievance matter).</p>
                <p>f. Department of Labor, Federal Labor Relations Authority, or arbitrators involved in the grievance (if information deals with a negotiated grievance matter).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>ROUTINE USES:</b>
                </p>
                <p> a. To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible (hereinafter "responsible agency") for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the record either alone or in conjunction with other information indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p>b. To disclose information when OGE determines that that the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body; or in a proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>c. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration or the General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>d. To disclose information to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A–19.</p>
                <p>e. To disclose information to a Member of Congress or a congressional office in response to an inquiry made on behalf of, and at the request of, an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                <p>f. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, detailees, and other non-OGE employees performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the Federal Government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                <p>g. To disclose information to any source from which additional information is required in the course of processing a grievance, to the extent necessary to identify the individual, inform the source of the purpose(s) of the request, and identify the type of information requested.</p>
                <p>h. To disclose information to a Federal agency in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conducting of a security or suitability investigation of an individual, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to requesting the agency’s decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>i. To disclose information to officials of the Merit Systems Protection Board; the Office of Special Counsel; the Federal Labor Relations Authority; or the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission when requested in performance of their authorized duties, including respectively in connection with cases and appeals, special studies of the civil service and other merit systems, review of personnel matters and practices, investigations of alleged or possible prohibited personnel and discrimination practices, Hatch Act matters, whistleblower protections, compliance with employee selection procedures and investigations of allegations of unfair labor practices or matters before the Federal Service Impasses Panel.</p>
                <p>j. To provide information to officials of labor organizations recognized under 5 U.S.C. chapter 71 when relevant and necessary to their duties of exclusive representation concerning personnel policies, practices, and matters affecting working conditions.</p>
                <p>k. To provide information the Department of Labor in carrying out its functions regarding labor-management relations in the Federal service.</p>
                <p>l.  To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) OGE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) OGE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with OGE's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>m. To disclose information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when OGE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retrieved by the names of the individuals on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule (GRS) 2.3 Employee Relations Records. Disposal of paper records is by shredding, and disposal of electronic records is by deletion.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records are maintained in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals requesting access to this system of records must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Review of requests from individuals seeking amendment of their records which have been the subject of an administrative, judicial, or quasi-judicial action will be limited in scope. Review of amendment requests of these records will be restricted to determining if the record accurately documents the ruling on the case, and will not include a review of the merits of the action, determination, or finding. Individuals wishing to request amendment of their records to correct factual errors should contact the OGE Office of Administration and Information Management. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                <p>a. Name.</p>
                <p>b. Approximate date of closing of the case and kind of action taken.</p>
                <p>c. Organizational component involved.</p>
                <p>Individuals requesting amendment must also follow OGE’s Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and amendment of records (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about them must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 68 FR 3097.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="internal4" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/INTERNAL-4</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> OGE/INTERNAL-4, Computer Systems Activity and Access Records.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Chief Information Officer, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917, email: usoge@oge.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. App. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); 40 U.S.C. 1441 note.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  The data in this system of records is used by OGE systems and security personnel, or persons authorized to assist these personnel, to plan and manage system services, to monitor for improper use, and to otherwise perform their official duties.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals who access OGE network computers or servers, including individuals who send and receive electronic communications, access Internet sites, or access system databases, files, or applications from OGE computers or who send electronic communications to OGE computers; and individuals attempting to access OGE computers or systems without authorization.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Records in this system of records may include: records on the use of OGE e-mail systems, including the e-mail address of the sender and receiver of the e-mail message, subject, date, and time; records on user access to OGE’s office networks; records relating to verification or authorization of an individual’s access to systems, files, or applications, such as user IDs, user names, title, and agency.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Information in this system of records is obtained from:</p>
                <p>a. Individuals who access the systems.</p>
                <p>b. Office of Government Ethics employees and contractors responsible for managing the systems.</p>
                <p>c. Computer activity logs and tracking systems.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>ROUTINE USES:</b>
                </p>
                <p>a. To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible (hereinafter "responsible agency") for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the record either alone or in conjunction with other information indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
                <p>b. To disclose information when OGE determines that that the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body; or in a proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>c. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration or the General Services Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>d. To disclose information to the Office of Management and Budget at any stage in the legislative coordination and clearance process in connection with private relief legislation as set forth in OMB Circular No. A–19.</p>
                <p>e. To disclose information to contractors, grantees, experts, consultants, detailees, and other non-OGE employees performing or working on a contract, service, or other assignment for the Federal Government, when necessary to accomplish an agency function related to this system of records.</p>
                <p>f. To disclose information to a Member of Congress or a congressional office in response to an inquiry made on behalf of, and at the request of, an individual who is the subject of the record.</p>
                <p>g. To disclose information to a Federal, State, local, tribal or foreign agency, or a private contractor, in response to its request in connection with the hiring or retention of any employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the conduct of a security or suitability investigation, the reporting of an investigation on an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant, license, or other benefit to an employee by the agency, but only to the extent that the information disclosed is relevant and necessary to the agency’s decision on the matter.</p>
                <p>i. To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) OGE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) OGE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with OGE's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>j. To disclose information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when OGE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records may be retrieved by user name, user ID, e-mail address, or other identifying search term employed, depending on the record category.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retained in accordance with General Records Schedule (GRS) 3.2 Information Systems Security Records. Disposal of paper records is by shredding, and disposal of electronic records is by deletion.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are located in locked storage areas with controlled entry, or automated systems to which only authorized personnel have access. The use of password protection identification features and other automated data processing system protection methods also restrict access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals requesting access to this system of records must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals wishing to request amendment of records about themselves should contact the System Manager. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                <p>a. Full name.</p>
                <p>b. Assigned computer location.</p>
                <p>c. Description of information being sought (including the time frame during which the record(s) may have been generated).</p>
                <p>Individuals requesting amendment must also follow OGE’s Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and amendment of records (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about themselves must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 68 FR 3097.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="internal5" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/INTERNAL-5</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> OGE/INTERNAL-5, Employee Locator and Emergency Notification Records.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Unclassified.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Deputy Director for Compliance, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20005-3917, email: usoge@oge.gov.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. App. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Information is collected for this system in order to identify an individual for OGE officials to contact, should an emergency of a medical or other nature involving the employee occur while the employee is on the job. Also, these records may be used by authorized OGE personnel to contact individuals working from home or at an authorized alternative worksite or, on infrequent occasions, to contact individuals absent from work about work-related issues.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Current employees of the Office of Government Ethics.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system contains information regarding the organizational location, telephone extension, and hours of duty of individual OGE employees. The system also contains the home address and telephone number of the employee and the name, relationship, and telephone number of an individual or individuals to contact in the event of a medical or other emergency involving the employee. The system contains an additional freeform "note" field for personal medical information for employees who choose to voluntarily complete it.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>  Information in this system of records is obtained from:</p>
                <p>a. The individual on whom the record is maintained.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>ROUTINE USES:</b>
                </p>
                <p>a. To disclose information when OGE that that the records are arguably relevant to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body; or in a proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>c. To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) OGE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) OGE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with OGE's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>d. To disclose information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when OGE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                <p>e. To disclose pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, or local agency responsible (hereinafter "responsible agency") for investigating, prosecuting, enforcing, or implementing a statute, rule, regulation, or order, when the record either alone or in conjunction with other information indicates a violation or potential violation of civil or criminal law or regulation.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Records are maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retrieved by the name of the individual on whom they are maintained.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records are retained in accordance with the National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule (GRS) 5.3: Continuity and Emergency Planning Records. Disposal of paper records is by shredding, and disposal of electronic records is by deletion.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Paper records are maintained in locked file storage areas or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are maintained in a secured electronic system accessible only to on-site OGE employees. An individual OGE employee has access only to his or her own record. In addition, individual records in the system are available to authorized OGE personnel whose duties require access.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals requesting access to this system of records must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> OGE employees have full access to and complete control over their individual record and may amend information at any time, or they may contact the System Manager. Individuals must furnish the following information for their records to be located and identified:</p>
                <p>a. Full name.</p>
                <p> Individuals requesting amendment must also follow OGE’s Privacy Act regulations regarding verification of identity and amendment of records (5 CFR part 2606).</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about themselves must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 68 FR 3097.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section id="internal6" toc="yes">
        <systemNumber>/INTERNAL-6</systemNumber>
        <subsection type="systemName">
            <p> Online Registration for OGE-Hosted Meetings and Events.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="securityClassification">
            <xhtmlContent>
               <p>Unclassified.</p></xhtmlContent>
                </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemLocation">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Office of Government Ethics, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Suite 500, Washington, DC 20005-3917. Records may be kept in commercial third-party applications, including Pay.gov, located at the Department of the Treasury, Bureau of the Fiscal Service, 401 14th Street, SW, Washington DC 20227.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="systemManager">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Nicole Stein, Chief, Agency Assistance Branch, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20005–3917.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="authorityForMaintenance">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> 5 U.S.C. app. § 402 (Ethics in Government Act of 1978); 44 U.S.C. 3101.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="purpose">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> The purpose is to collect information on participants who register for an OGE-hosted meeting or event, which can be used to administratively organize a meeting or event. For example, OGE may need to track the collection of registration fees, create printed materials such as nametags, tent cards, and event programs and directories, or contact presenters to provide information.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Federal employees in the executive branch, and/or members of the public who register to attend or otherwise participate in OGE-hosted meetings and events.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> This system of records contains personally identifiable information (PII) collected from individuals registering to attend or otherwise participate in OGE-hosted meetings and events. The PII collected includes name, agency/organization, address, telephone number, email address, state, city or town, country, number of years worked in the field of ethics, and special accommodations requests.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordSourceCategories">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Information in this system of records is provided by the individual on whom the record is maintained, or by the individual’s organization if the organization is registering an individual on his or her behalf.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records and the information contained therein may be used:</p>
                <p>a. To disclose information to all event participants for the purposes of displaying names and other personal information on event materials such as name badges, tent cards, or event programs or directories.</p>
                <p>b. To disclose information to vendors, venues, or other Federal agencies for the purposes of event planning and/or venue security.</p>
                <p>c. To disclose information when OGE determines that the records are arguably relevant and necessary to a proceeding before a court, grand jury, or administrative or adjudicative body; or in a proceeding before an administrative or adjudicative body when the adjudicator determines the records to be relevant and necessary to the proceeding.</p>
                <p>d. To disclose information to the National Archives and Records Administration in records management inspections conducted under authority of 44 U.S.C. 2904 and 2906.</p>
                <p>e. To disclose information to appropriate agencies, entities, and persons when: (1) OGE suspects or has confirmed that there has been a breach of the system of records; (2) OGE has determined that as a result of the suspected or confirmed breach there is a risk of harm to individuals, the agency (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security; and (3) the disclosure made to such agencies, entities, and persons is reasonably necessary to assist in connection with OGE's efforts to respond to the suspected or confirmed breach or to prevent, minimize, or remedy such harm.</p>
                <p>f. To disclose information to another Federal agency or Federal entity, when OGE determines that information from this system of records is reasonably necessary to assist the recipient agency or entity in (1) responding to a suspected or confirmed breach or (2) preventing, minimizing, or remedying the risk of harm to individuals, the recipient agency or entity (including its information systems, programs, and operations), the Federal Government, or national security, resulting from a suspected or confirmed breach.</p>
                </xhtmlContent>
    </subsection>
        <subsection type="policiesAndPractices">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>These records are maintained in paper and/or electronic form.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retrievability">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> These records may be retrieved by name or other data elements such as an individual’s agency.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="retentionAndDisposal">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> In accordance with General Records Schedule 6.4, item 010, Public affairs-related routine operational records, the records are destroyed when 3 years old, or no longer needed, whichever is later.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="safeguards">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Hardcopy records are maintained in file cabinets which may be locked or in specified areas to which only authorized personnel have access. Electronic records are maintained either on the OGE network, in OGE internal applications, or in third party applications like Pay.gov, which is used to manage paid registrations. They are protected from unauthorized access through password identification procedures, limited access, firewalls, and other system-based protection methods.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="recordAccessProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals requesting access to this system of records must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>Individuals wishing to request amendment of records about themselves must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="notificationProcedure">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> Individuals wishing to inquire whether this system of records contains information about them must follow the procedures set forth in OGE's Privacy Act regulations at 5 CFR part 2606.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="exemptionsClaimed">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p> None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
        <subsection type="history">
            <xhtmlContent>
                <p>None.</p>
            </xhtmlContent>
        </subsection>
    </section>


    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="5">
<heading> Administrative Personnel </heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XVI">
<heading> Office of Government Ethics </heading>
<regulationsPart number="2606">
<heading> PRIVACY ACT RULES </heading>
<xhtmlContent>
<p><b>Subpart A--General Provisions
</b></p>
<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>2606.101 Purpose.
</p>
<p>2606.102 Definitions.
</p>
<p>2606.103 Systems of records.
</p>
<p>2606.104 OGE and agency responsibilities.
</p>
<p>2606.105 Rules for individuals seeking to ascertain if they are the subject of a record.
</p>
<p>2606.106 OGE employee Privacy Act rules of conduct and responsibilities.
</p><p><b>Subpart B--Access to Records and Accounting of Disclosures
</b></p>
<p>2606.201 Requests for access.
</p>
<p>2606.202 OGE or other agency action on requests.
</p>
<p>2606.203 Granting access.
</p>
<p>2606.204 Request for review of an initial denial of access.
</p>
<p>2606.205 Response to a request for review of an initial denial of access.
</p>
<p>2606.206 Fees.
</p>
<p>2606.207 Accounting of disclosures.
</p><p><b>Subpart C--Amendment of Records
</b></p>
<p>2606.301 Requests to amend records.
</p>
<p>2606.302 OGE or other agency action on requests.
</p>
<p>2606.303 Request for review of an initial refusal to amend a record.
</p>
<p>2606.304 Response to a request for review of an initial refusal to amend; disagreement statements.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> 5 U.S.C. 552a, 5 U.S.C. App. (Ethics in Government Act of 1978).
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 68 FR 27891, May 22, 2003, unless otherwise noted.</p>
<p><b>Subpart A--General Provisions
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.101 Purpose.
</b></p>
<p>This part sets forth the regulations of the Office of Government Ethics (OGE) implementing the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552a). It governs access, maintenance, disclosure, and amendment of records contained in OGE's executive branch Governmentwide and internal systems of records, and establishes rules of conduct for OGE employees who have responsibilities under the Act.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.102
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For the purpose of this part, the terms listed below are defined as follows:
</p>
<p><i>Access</i> means providing a copy of a record to, or allowing review of the original record by, the data subject or the requester's authorized representative, parent or legal guardian;
</p>
<p><i>Act</i> means the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 5 U.S.C. 552a;
</p>
<p><i>Amendment</i> means the correction, addition, deletion, or destruction of a record or specific portions of a record;
</p>
<p><i>Data subject</i> means the individual to whom the information pertains and by whose name or other individual identifier the information is maintained or retrieved;
</p>
<p><i>He, his,</i> and <i>him</i> include she, hers and her.
</p>
<p><i>Office</i> or <i>OGE</i> means the U.S. Office of Government Ethics;
</p>
<p><i>System manager</i> means the Office or other agency official who has the authority to decide Privacy Act matters relative to a system of records;
</p>
<p><i>System of records</i> means a group of any records containing personal information controlled and managed by OGE from which information is retrieved by the name of an individual or by some personal identifier assigned to that individual;
</p>
<p><i>Working day</i> as used in calculating the date when a response is due means calendar days, excepting Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.103
 Systems of records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Governmentwide systems of records.</i> The Office of Government Ethics maintains two executive branch Governmentwide systems of records: the OGE/GOVT-1 system of records, comprised of Executive Branch Personnel Public Financial Disclosure Reports and Other Name-Retrieved Ethics Program Records; and the OGE/GOVT-2 system of records, comprised of Executive Branch Confidential Financial Disclosure Reports. These Governmentwide systems of records are maintained by OGE, and through Office delegations of authority, by Federal executive branch departments and agencies with regard to their own employees, applicants for employment, individuals nominated to a position requiring Senate confirmation, candidates for a position, and former employees.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>OGE Internal systems of records.</i> The Office of Government Ethics internal systems of records are under OGE's physical custody and control and are established and maintained by the Office on current and former OGE employees regarding matters relating to the internal management of the Office. These systems of records consist of the OGE/INTERNAL-1 system, comprised of Pay, Leave and Travel Records; the OGE/INTERNAL-2 system, comprised of Telephone Call Detail Records; the OGE/INTERNAL-3 system, comprised of Grievance Records; the OGE/INTERNAL-4 system, comprised of Computer Systems Activity and Access Records; and the OGE/INTERNAL-5 system, comprised of Employee Locator and Emergency Notification Records.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.104
 OGE and agency responsibilities.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The procedures in this part apply to:
</p>
<p>(1) All initial Privacy Act access and amendment requests regarding records contained in an OGE system of records.
</p>
<p>(2) Administrative appeals from an Office or agency denial of an initial request for access to, or to amend, records contained in an OGE system of records.
</p>
<p>(b) For records contained in an OGE Governmentwide system of records, each agency is responsible (unless specifically excepted by the Office) for responding to initial requests for access or amendment of records in its custody and administrative appeals of denials thereof.
</p>
<p>(c) For records and material of another agency that are in the custody of OGE, but not under its control or ownership, OGE may refer a request for the records to that other agency, consult with the other agency prior to responding, or notify the requester that the other agency is the proper agency to contact.

</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.105
 Rules for individuals seeking to ascertain if they are the subject of a record.
</b></p>
<p>An individual seeking to ascertain if any OGE system of records contains a record pertaining to him must follow the access procedures set forth at &#167; 2606.201(a) and (b).
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.106
 OGE employee Privacy Act rules of conduct and responsibilities.
</b></p>
<p>Each OGE employee involved in the design, development, operation, or maintenance of any system of records, or in maintaining any record covered by the Privacy Act, shall comply with the pertinent provisions of the Act relating to the treatment of such information. Particular attention is directed to the following provisions of the Privacy Act:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(7).</i> The requirement to maintain in a system of records no record describing how any individual exercises rights guaranteed by the First Amendment of the Constitution of the United States unless expressly authorized by statute or by the individual about whom the record is maintained or unless pertinent to and within the scope of an authorized law enforcement activity.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(b).</i> The requirement that no agency shall disclose any record which is contained in a system of records by any means of communication to any person or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request by, or with the prior written consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains, except under certain limited conditions specified in subsections (b)(1) through (b)(12) of the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(1).</i> The requirement for an agency to maintain in its systems of records only such information about an individual as is relevant and necessary to accomplish a purpose of the agency required to be accomplished by statute or by Executive order.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(2).</i> The requirement to collect information to the greatest extent practicable directly from the subject individual when the information may result in adverse determinations about an individual's rights, benefits, and privileges under Federal programs.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(3).</i> The requirement to inform each individual asked to supply information to be maintained in a system of records the authority which authorizes the solicitation of the information and whether disclosure of such information is mandatory or voluntary; the principal purpose or purposes for which the information is intended to be used; the routine uses which may be made of the information; and the effects on the individual, if any, of not providing all or any part of the requested information.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(b) and (e)(10).</i> The requirement to comply with established safeguards and procedures to ensure the security and confidentiality of records and to protect personal data from any anticipated threats or hazards to their security or integrity which could result in substantial harm, embarrassment, inconvenience, or unfairness to an individual on whom information is maintained in a system of records.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(1), (c)(2) and (c)(3).</i> The requirement to maintain an accounting of specified disclosures of personal information from systems of records in accordance with established Office procedures.
</p>
<p>(h) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(e)(5) and (e)(6).</i> The requirements to maintain all records in a system of records which are used by the agency in making any determination about an individual with such accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness as is reasonably necessary to assure fairness to the individual in the determination; and to make reasonable efforts to assure that such records are accurate, complete, timely, and relevant for agency purposes, prior to disseminating any record about an individual to any person other than an agency (unless the dissemination is required by the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552).
</p>
<p>(i) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(d)(1), (d)(2) and (d)(3).</i> The requirement to permit individuals to have access to records pertaining to themselves in accordance with established Office procedures and to have an opportunity to request that such records be amended.
</p>
<p>(j) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(c)(4) and (d)(4).</i> The requirement to inform any person or other agency about any correction or notation of dispute made by the agency in accordance with subsection (d) of the Act of any record that has been disclosed to the person or agency if an accounting of the disclosure was made; and, in any disclosure of information about which an individual has filed a statement of disagreement, to note clearly any portion of the record which is disputed and to provide copies of the statement (and if the agency deems it appropriate, copies of a concise statement of the reasons of the agency for not making the amendments requested) to persons or other agencies to whom the disputed record has been disclosed.
</p>
<p>(k) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(n).</i> The requirement for an agency not to sell or rent an individual's name or address, unless such action is specifically authorized by law.
</p>
<p>(l) <i>5 U.S.C. 552a(i).</i> The criminal penalties to which an employee may be subject for failing to comply with certain provisions of the Privacy Act.</p>
<p><b>Subpart B--Access to Records and Accounting of Disclosures
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.201
 Requests for access.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Records in an OGE Governmentwide system of records.</i> An individual requesting access to records pertaining to him in an OGE Governmentwide system of records should submit a written request, which includes the words "Privacy Act Request" on both the envelope and at the top of the request letter, to the appropriate system manager as follows:
</p>
<p>(1) <i>Records filed directly with OGE by non-OGE employees:</i> The Deputy Director, Office of Agency Programs, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20005-3917;
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Records filed with a Designated Agency Ethics Official (DAEO) or the head of a department or agency:</i> The DAEO at the department or agency concerned; or
</p>
<p>(3) <i>Records filed with the Federal Election Commission by candidates for President or Vice President:</i> The General Counsel, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Records in an OGE Internal System of Records.</i> An individual requesting access to records pertaining to him in an OGE internal system of records should submit a written request, which includes the words "Privacy Act Request" on both the envelope and at the top of the request letter, to the Deputy Director, Office of Administration and Information Management, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20005-3917.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Content of request.</i> (1) A request should contain a specific reference to the OGE system of records from which access to the records is sought. Notices of OGE systems of records subject to the Privacy Act are published in the <i>Federal Register,</i> and copies of the notices are available on OGE's Web site at <i>http://www.usoge.gov,</i> or upon request from OGE's Office of General Counsel and Legal Policy. A biennial compilation of such notices also is made available online and published by the Office of Federal Register at the GPO Access Web site (<i>http://www.access.gpo.gov/su_docs/aces/PrivacyAct.shtml</i>) in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(f) of the Act.
</p>
<p>(2) If the written inquiry does not refer to a specific system of records, it should include other information that will assist in the identification of the records for which access is being requested. Such information may include, for example, the individual's full name (including her maiden name, if pertinent), dates of employment, social security number (if any records in the system include this identifier), current or last place and date of Federal employment. If the request for access follows a prior request to determine if an individual is the subject of a record, the same identifying information need not be included in the request for access if a reference is made to that prior correspondence, or a copy of the response to that request is attached.
</p>
<p>(3) The request should state whether the requester wants a copy of the record, or wants to examine the record in person.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.202
 OGE or other agency action on requests.
</b></p>
<p>A response to a request for access should include the following:
</p>
<p>(a) A statement that there is a record or records as requested or a statement that there is not a record in the system of records;
</p>
<p>(b) The method of access (if a copy of all the records requested is not provided with the response);
</p>
<p>(c) The amount of any fees to be charged for copies of records under &#167; 2606.206 of this part or other agencies' Privacy Act regulations as referenced in that section;
</p>
<p>(d) The name, title, and telephone number of the official having operational control over the record; and
</p>
<p>(e) If the request is denied in whole or in part, or no record is found in the system, a statement of the reasons for the denial, or a statement that no record has been found, and notice of the procedures for appealing the denial or no record finding.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.203
 Granting access.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The methods for allowing access to records, when such access has been granted by OGE or the other agency concerned are:</p>
<p>(1) Examination in person in a designated office during the hours specified by OGE or the other agency;
</p>
<p>(2) Providing photocopies of the records; or
</p>
<p>(3) Transfer of records at the option of OGE or the other agency to another more convenient Federal facility.
</p>
<p>(b) When a requester has not indicated whether he wants a copy of the record, or wants to examine the record in person, the appropriate system manager may choose the means of granting access. However, the means chosen should not unduly impede the data subject's right of access. A data subject may elect to receive a copy of the records after having examined them.
</p>
<p>(c) Generally, OGE or the other agency concerned will not furnish certified copies of records. When copies are to be furnished, they may be provided as determined by OGE or the other agency concerned.
</p>
<p>(d) When the data subject seeks to obtain original documentation, the Office and the other agencies concerned reserve the right to limit the request to copies of the original records. Original records should be made available for review only in the presence of the appropriate system manager or his designee.
</p>
<p><b>Note to paragraph (d) of &#167; 2606.203:</b> Section 2071(a) of title 18 of the United States Code makes it a crime to conceal, remove, mutilate, obliterate, or destroy any record filed in a public office, or to attempt to do so.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Identification requirements</i>--(1) <i>Access granted in person</i>--(i) <i>Current or former employees.</i> Current or former employees requesting access to records pertaining to them in a system of records may, in addition to the other requirements of this section, and at the sole discretion of the official having operational control over the record, have their identity verified by visual observation. If the current or former employee cannot be so identified by the official having operational control over the records, adequate identification documentation will be required, e.g., an employee identification card, driver's license, passport, or other officially issued document with a picture of the person requesting access.
</p>
<p>(ii) <i>Other than current or former employees.</i> Individuals other than current or former employees requesting access to records pertaining to them in a system of records must produce adequate identification documentation prior to being granted access. The extent of the identification documentation required will depend on the type of records to be accessed. In most cases, identification verification will be accomplished by the presentation of two forms of identification with a picture of the person requesting access (such as a driver's license and passport). Any additional requirements are specified in the system notices published pursuant to subsection (e)(4) of the Act.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Access granted by mail.</i> For records to be accessed by mail, the appropriate system manager shall, to the extent possible, establish identity by a comparison of signatures in situations where the data in the record is not so sensitive that unauthorized access could cause harm or embarrassment to the individual to whom they pertain. No identification documentation will be required for the disclosure to the data subject of information required to be made available to the public by 5 U.S.C. 552, the Freedom of Information Act. When, in the opinion of the system manager, the granting of access through the mail could reasonably be expected to result in harm or embarrassment if disclosed to a person other than the individual to whom the record pertains, a notarized statement of identity or some similar assurance of identity may be required.
</p>
<p>(3) <i>Unavailability of identification documentation.</i> If an individual is unable to produce adequate identification documentation, the individual will be required to sign a statement asserting identity and acknowledging that knowingly or willfully seeking or obtaining access to records about another person under false pretenses may result in a criminal fine of up to $5,000 under subsection (i)(3) of the Act. In addition, depending upon the sensitivity of the records sought to be accessed, the appropriate system manager or official having operational control over the records may require such further reasonable assurances as may be considered appropriate, e.g., statements of other individuals who can attest to the identity of the data subject. No verification of identity will be required of data subjects seeking access to records which are otherwise available to any person under 5 U.S.C. 552.
</p>
<p>(4) <i>Inadequate identification.</i> If the official having operational control over the records in a system of records determines that an individual seeking access has not provided sufficient identification documentation to permit access, the official shall consult with the appropriate system manager prior to denying the individual access. Whenever the system manager determines, in accordance with the procedures herein, that access will not be granted, the response will also include a statement of the procedures to obtain a review of the decision to deny access in accordance with &#167; 2606.205.
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Access by the parent of a minor, or legal guardian.</i> A parent of a minor, upon presenting suitable personal identification as otherwise provided under this section, may access on behalf of the minor any record pertaining to the minor in a system of records. A legal guardian, upon presentation of documentation establishing guardianship and suitable personal identification as otherwise provided under this section, may similarly act on behalf of a data subject declared to be incompetent due to physical or mental incapacity or age by a court of competent jurisdiction. Minors are not precluded from exercising on their own behalf rights given to them by the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p>(g) <i>Accompanying individual.</i> A data subject requesting access to his records in a system of records may be accompanied by another individual of the data subject's choice during the course of the examination of the record. The official having operational control of the record may require the data subject making the request to submit a signed statement authorizing the accompanying individual's access to the record.
</p>
<p>(h) <i>Access to medical records.</i> When a request for access involves medical or psychological records that the appropriate system manager believes requires special handling, the data subject should be advised that the material will be provided only to a physician designated by the data subject. Upon receipt of the designation and upon verification of the physician's identity as otherwise provided under this section, the records will be made available to the physician, who will disclose those records to the data subject.
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Exclusion.</i> Nothing in these regulations permits a data subject's access to any information compiled in reasonable anticipation of a civil action or proceeding (<i>see</i> subsection (d)(5) of the Act).
</p>
<p>(j) <i>Maximum access.</i> This regulation is not intended to preclude access by a data subject to records that are available to that individual under other processes, such as the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552) or the rules of civil or criminal procedure, provided that the appropriate procedures for requesting access thereunder are followed.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.204
 Request for review of an initial denial of access.
</b></p>
<p>(a)(1) A data subject may submit a written appeal of the decision by OGE or the other agency to deny an initial request for access to records or a no record response.
</p>
<p>(i) For records filed directly with OGE, the appeal must be submitted to the Director, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20005-3917.
</p>
<p>(ii) For records in OGE's executive branch Governmentwide systems of records that are filed directly with an agency (including the Federal Election Commission) other than OGE, the appeal must be submitted to the Privacy Act access appeals official as specified in the agency's own Privacy Act regulations or the respective head of the agency concerned if it does not have any Privacy Act regulations.
</p>
<p>(2) The words "Privacy Act Appeal" should be included on the envelope and at the top of the letter of appeal.
</p>
<p>(b) The appeal should contain a brief description of the records involved or copies of the correspondence from OGE or the agency in which the initial request for access was denied. The appeal should attempt to refute the reasons given by OGE or the other agency concerned in its decision to deny the initial request for access or the no record finding.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.205
 Response to a request for review of an initial denial of access.
</b></p>
<p>(a) If the OGE Director or agency reviewing official determines that access to the records should be granted, the response will state how access will be provided if the records are not included with the response.
</p>
<p>(b) Any decision that either partially or fully affirms the initial decision to deny access shall inform the requester of the right to seek judicial review of the decision in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552a(g) of the Privacy Act.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.206
 Fees.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Fees for records filed with OGE</i>--(1) <i>Services for which fees will not be charged:</i>
</p>
<p>(i) The search and review time expended by OGE to produce a record;
</p>
<p>(ii) The first copy of the records provided; or
</p>
<p>(iii) The Office of Government Ethics making the records available to be personally reviewed by the data subject.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Additional copies of records.</i> When additional copies of records are requested, an individual may be charged $.15 per page.
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Notice of anticipated fees in excess of $25.00.</i> If the charge for these additional copies amounts to more than $25.00, the requester will be notified and payment of fees may be required before the additional copies are provided, unless the requester has indicated in advance his willingness to pay fees as high as those anticipated.
</p>
<p>(ii) <i>Advance payments.</i> An advance payment before additional copies of the records are made will be required if:
</p>
<p>(A) The Office estimates or determines that the total fee to be assessed under this section is likely to exceed $250.00. When a determination is made that the allowable charges are likely to exceed $250.00, the requester will be notified of the likely cost and will be required to provide satisfactory assurance of full payment where the requester has a history of prompt payment of Privacy Act fees, or will be required to submit an advance payment of an amount up to the full estimated charges in the case of requesters with no history of payment; or
</p>
<p>(B) The requester has previously failed to pay a Privacy Act fee charged in a timely fashion (<i>i.e.,</i> within 30 days of the date of the billing). In such cases, the requester may be required to pay the full amount owed plus any applicable interest as provided by paragraph (a)(2)(iii) of this section, and to make an advance payment of the full amount of the estimated fee before the Office begins to process a new request.
</p>
<p>(iii) <i>Interest charges.</i> Interest charges on an unpaid bill may be assessed starting on the 31st day following the day on which the billing was sent. Interest shall be at the rate prescribed in 31 U.S.C. 3717 and shall accrue from the date of billing. To collect unpaid bills, the Office will follow the provisions of the Debt Collection Act of 1982, as amended (96 Stat. 1749 <i>et seq.</i>) and the Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996 (110 Stat. 1321-358 <i>et seq.</i>), including the use of consumer reporting agencies, collection agencies, and offset.
</p>
<p>(iv) <i>Remittance.</i> Remittance should be made by either a personal check, bank draft or a money order that is payable to the Department of the Treasury of the United States.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Fees for records filed with agencies other than OGE.</i> An agency shall apply its own Privacy Act fee schedule for records in OGE's executive branch Governmentwide systems that are filed directly with the agency. An agency that does not have a Privacy Act fee schedule may apply the fee schedule in this section.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.207
 Accounting of disclosures.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Office of Government Ethics or the other agency concerned will maintain an accounting of disclosures in cases where records about the data subject are disclosed from OGE's system of records except--
</p>
<p>(1) When the disclosure is made pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552); or
</p>
<p>(2) When the disclosure is made to those officers and employees of OGE or the other agency which maintains the records who have a need for the records in the performance of their duties.
</p>
<p>(b) This accounting of disclosures will be retained for at least five years or for the life of the record, whichever is longer, and will contain the following information:
</p>
<p>(1) A brief description of the record disclosed;
</p>
<p>(2) The date, nature, and purpose for the disclosure; and
</p>
<p>(3) The name and address of the individual, agency, or other entity to whom the disclosure is made.
</p>
<p>(c) Under sections 102 and 105 of the Ethics in Government Act, 18 U.S.C. 208(d) and 5 CFR parts 2634 and 2640 of OGE's executive branch regulations, a requester other than the data subject must submit a signed, written application on the OGE Form 201 or agency equivalent form to inspect or receive copies of certain records, such as SF 278 Public Financial Disclosure Reports, Certificates of Divestiture, 18 U.S.C. 208(b)(1) and (b)(3) waivers, and OGE certified qualified blind and diversified trust instruments and other publicly available qualified trust materials. The written application requests the name, occupation and address of the requester as well as lists the prohibitions on obtaining or using the records. These applications are used as the accounting of disclosures for these records.
</p>
<p>(d) Except for the accounting of a disclosure made under subsection (b)(7) of the Privacy Act for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity that is authorized by law, the accounting of disclosures will be made available to the data subject upon request in accordance with the access procedures of this part.
</p><p><b>Subpart C--Amendment of Records
</b></p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.301
 Requests to amend records.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Amendment request.</i> A data subject seeking to amend a record or records that pertain to him in a system of records must submit his request in writing in accordance with the following procedures, unless this requirement is waived by the appropriate system manager. Records not subject to the Privacy Act will not be amended in accordance with these provisions.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Addresses</i>--(1) <i>Records in an OGE Governmentwide system of records.</i> A request to amend a record in an OGE Governmentwide system of records should be sent to the appropriate system manager as follows:
</p>
<p>(i) <i>Records filed directly with OGE by non-OGE employees:</i> The Deputy Director, Office of Agency Programs, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20005-3917;
</p>
<p>(ii) <i>Records filed with a Designated Agency Ethics Official (DAEO) or the head of a department or agency:</i> The DAEO at the department or agency concerned; or
</p>
<p>(iii) <i>Records filed with the Federal Election Commission by candidates for President or Vice President:</i> The General Counsel, Office of General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.
</p>
<p>(2) <i>Records in an OGE internal system of records.</i> A request to amend a record in an OGE internal system of records should include the words "Privacy Act Amendment Request" on both the envelope and at the top of the request letter, and should be sent to the Deputy Director, Office of Administration and Information Management, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20005-3917.
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Contents of request.</i> (1) A request to amend a record in an OGE Governmentwide system of records or an OGE internal system of records should include the words "Privacy Act Amendment Request" on both the envelope and at the top of the request letter.
</p>
<p>(2) The name of the system of records and a brief description of the record(s) proposed for amendment must be included in any request for amendment. In the event the request to amend the record(s) is the result of the data subject's having gained access to the record(s) in accordance with the provisions concerning access to records as set in subpart B of this part, copies of previous correspondence between the requester and OGE or the agency will serve in lieu of a separate description of the record.
</p>
<p>(3) The exact portion of the record(s) the data subject seeks to have amended should be indicated clearly. If possible, proposed alternative language should be set forth, or, at a minimum, the reasons why the data subject believes his record is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete should be set forth with enough particularity to permit OGE or the other agency concerned not only to understand the data subject's basis for the request, but also to make an appropriate amendment to the record.
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Burden of proof.</i> The data subject has the burden of proof when seeking the amendment of a record. The data subject must furnish sufficient facts to persuade the appropriate system manager of the inaccuracy, irrelevance, untimeliness, or incompleteness of the record.
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Identification requirement.</i> When the data subject's identity has been previously verified pursuant to &#167; 2606.203, further verification of identity is not required as long as the communication does not suggest a need for verification. If the data subject's identity has not been previously verified, the appropriate system manager may require identification validation as described in &#167; 2606.203.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.302
 OGE or other agency action on requests.
</b></p>
<p>(a) <i>Time limit for acknowledging a request for amendment.</i> To the extent possible, OGE or the other agency concerned will acknowledge receipt of a request to amend a record or records within 10 working days.
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Initial determination on an amendment request.</i> The decision of OGE or the other agency in response to a request for amendment of a record in a system of records may grant in whole, or deny any part of the request to amend the record(s).
</p>
<p>(1) If OGE or the other agency concerned grants the request, the appropriate system manager will amend the record(s) and provide a copy of the amended record(s) to the data subject. Where an accounting of disclosure has been maintained, the system manager shall advise all previous recipients of the record that an amendment has been made and give the substance of the amendment. Where practicable, the system manager shall send a copy of the amended record to previous recipients.
</p>
<p>(2) If OGE or the other agency concerned denies the request in whole or in part, the reasons for the denial will be stated in the response letter. In addition, the response letter will state:</p>
<p>(i) The name and address of the official with whom an appeal of the denial may be lodged; and
</p>
<p>(ii) A description of any other procedures which may be required of the data subject in order to process the appeal.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.303
 Request for review of an initial refusal to amend a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a)(1) A data subject may submit a written appeal of the initial decision by OGE or an agency denying a request to amend a record in an OGE system of records.
</p>
<p>(i) For records which are filed directly with OGE, the appeal must be submitted to the Director, Office of Government Ethics, Suite 500, 1201 New York Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20005-3917.
</p>
<p>(ii) For records which are filed directly with an agency (including the Federal Election Commission) other than OGE, the appeal must be submitted to the Privacy Act amendments appeals official as specified in the agency's own Privacy Act regulations, or to the respective head of the agency concerned if it does not have Privacy Act regulations.
</p>
<p>(2) The words "Privacy Act Appeal" should be included on the envelope and at the top of the letter of the appeal.
</p>
<p>(b) The request for review should contain a brief description of the record(s) involved or copies of the correspondence from OGE or the agency in which the request to amend was denied, and the reasons why the data subject believes that the disputed information should be amended.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 2606.304
 Response to a request for review of an initial refusal to amend; disagreement statements.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The OGE Director or agency reviewing official should make a final determination in writing not later than 30 days from the date the appeal was received. The 30-day period may be extended for good cause. Notice of the extension and the reasons therefor will be sent to the data subject within the 30-day period.
</p>
<p>(b) If the OGE Director or agency reviewing official determines that the record(s) should be amended in accordance with the data subject's request, the OGE Director or agency reviewing official will take the necessary steps to advise the data subject, and to direct the appropriate system manager:
</p>
<p>(1) To amend the record(s), and
</p>
<p>(2) To notify previous recipients of the record(s) for which there is an accounting of disclosure that the record(s) have been amended.
</p>
<p>(c) If the appeal decision does not grant in full the request for amendment, the decision letter will notify the data subject that he may:
</p>
<p>(1) Obtain judicial review of the decision in accordance with the terms of the Privacy Act at 5 U.S.C. 552a(g); and
</p>
<p>(2) File a statement setting forth his reasons for disagreeing with the decision.
</p>
<p>(d)(1) A data subject's disagreement statement must be concise. The appropriate system manager has the authority to determine the "conciseness" of the statement, taking into account the scope of the disagreement and the complexity of the issues.
</p>
<p>(2) In any disclosure of information about which an individual has filed a statement of disagreement, the appropriate system manager will clearly note any disputed portion(s) of the record(s) and will provide a copy of the statement to persons or other agencies to whom the disputed record or records has been disclosed and for whom an accounting of disclosure has been maintained. A concise statement of the reasons for not making the amendments requested may also be provided.
</p>
</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
