<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pai.xsl" xmlns="http://www.fdsys.gov/pai/2013"?>

<pai>
<agency toc="yes">
<name>Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation</name>
<abbrev>FCSIC</abbrev>

    
<section id="fcsis1" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-1</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">FCSIC Internal Automated Personnel System.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are located at the Farm Credit Administration with copies at the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Corporation employees since March 1988.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
 <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information from Personnel Management Information and Telecommunications System of the Department of Treasury, including the employee's occupational series, grade, salary, position title, geographic location, work schedule, date of birth, sex, and similar information. The source for this data is the National Finance Center's United States Department of Agriculture Personnel Payroll System.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>12 U.S.C. 2277a-7, 2277a-8.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this record system may be used to furnish internal statistical reports and trend analyses for managing human resources</p>
<p>(1) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(2) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of and investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter</p>
<p>(4) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(5) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected</p>
<p>(6) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>

<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Information stored electronically.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Electronically retrievable by name, social security number, and other identifiers such as sex, geographic location, occupational series, etc.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept in a secure area with access limited to those whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule requirements.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of records shall be addressed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records either comes from the individual to whom it applies or comes from information supplied by agency officials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fcsis2" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-2</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Reports of Financial Interests and Employment--FCSIC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are located at the Farm Credit Administration with copies at the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Corporation employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>"Public Financial Disclosure Report" and "Confidential Statement of Employment and Financial Interests" required of certain employees. Contains statement of financial interests of the employee and of members of his or her immediate household as well as any other statements or memorandums concerning other employment or financial interests of the Corporation employee.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 12674, as amended by Executive Order 12731, and 5 U.S.C. App. 201, 205.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this record system may be used by authorized personnel for ascertaining conflicts or apparent conflicts of interest, recommending or taking appropriate action, monitoring the agency's ethics program</p>
<p>(1) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(2) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of an investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter</p>
<p>(4) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(5) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>(6) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained alphabetically by name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are kept in a locked cabinet except when being used by authorized personnel who are instructed as to their confidentiality and permitted use.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule requirements for employee reports of financial interests and employment.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Designated Agency Ethics Official, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of records shall be addressed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records either comes from the employee to whom it applies or comes from information supplied by agency officials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
	<section id="fcsis3" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-3</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee attendance, leave, personnel actions, and payroll records--FCSIC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are located at the Farm Credit Administration with copies at the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Corporation employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records consist of paper, electronic, and microfiche files containing payroll-related information for Corporation employees reported on a biweekly, year-to-date, and, in some cases, an annual basis. The records contain payroll and leave data for each employee including rate and amount of pay, personnel actions during payroll periods, hours worked, tax and retirement deductions, life insurance and health insurance deductions, savings allotments, savings bond and charity deductions, other financial deductions, mailing addresses, and home addresses. Records produced electronically utilize software provided by the National Finance Center's United States Department of Agriculture Personnel Payroll System.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>12 U.S.C. 2277a-7, 2277a-8.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this record system may be used to prepare payroll and to meet Government payroll record keeping and reporting requirements, and for retrieving and supplying payroll and leave information as required for agency needs. In addition, information in this record system is used to furnish certain information (name, permanent or temporary status, most recent position, grade, or salary) to other Government agencies, commercial or credit organizations, or verification of employment to prospective employers</p>
<p>(1) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to Federal, State, and local taxing authorities concerning compensation to employees or contractors for personal services; to the Office of Personnel Management, Department of the Treasury, Department of Labor, and other Federal agencies concerning pay, benefits, and retirement of employees; to Federal employees health benefits carriers concerning health insurance of employees; to financial organizations concerning employee savings account allotments and net pay to checking accounts; to State human resource offices administering unemployment compensation programs; to educational and training organizations concerning employee qualifications and identity for specific courses; and to heirs, executors, and legal representatives of beneficiaries</p>
<p>(2) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(4) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of and investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter</p>
<p>(5) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(6) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected.
</p><p>(7) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in locked cabinets or electronically.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are filed alphabetically by name. Electronic records are accessed by social security number. Microfiche records are arranged by social security number within a pay period.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are kept in areas which are locked after business hours. Access to records is limited to authorized individuals.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule requirements for payroll-related records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of records shall be addressed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records comes from the employee to whom it applies or comes from information supplied by Corporation employees and other authorized personnel.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fcsis4" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-4</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Employee Travel--FCSIC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Corporation employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper and electronic records relating to travel vouchers and supporting documentation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>12 U.S.C. 2277a-7, 2277a-8.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information contained in this system of records is used to provide records of reimbursement to employees for expenses incurred while in official travel status</p>
<p>(1) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(2) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of and investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter</p>
<p>(4) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(5) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected</p>
<p>(6) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in cabinets or electronically.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are filed alphabetically by name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper files are kept in areas which are locked after business hours. Access to electronic system is limited to authorized employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule requirements for financial records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Administrative Specialist, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Corporation employees and other individuals executing records.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fcsis5" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-5</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Financial Management Records--FCSIC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are located at the Farm Credit Administration, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Corporation employees and individuals conducting business with the Corporation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Records consist of paper, electronic, and microfiche files supporting the Corporation financial management system, including employee travel advance records, records of budget formulation and execution, the Corporation administrative expenses, and other financial records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>12 U.S.C. 2277a-7, 2277a-8.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>This system of records serves as the source for collecting and recapping financial data to provide control over assets and liabilities, collection of revenues and disbursement of expenses and reports necessary for management and for other Government agencies</p>
<p>(1) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(2) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of and investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency?s decision on the matter</p>
<p>(4) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(5) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected</p>
<p>(6) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are stored in cabinets or electronically.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper records are arranged by SF1166a (Voucher and Schedule of Payments) voucher number within each year. Automated system can retrieve by name, vendor number, or social security number as applicable.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Paper files are kept in file cabinets in areas which are locked after business hours. Access to electronic system is limited to authorized employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule requirements for financial records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of records shall be addressed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Corporation employees and other individuals doing business with Corporation.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fcsis6" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-6</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Procurement Records--FCSIC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are located at the Farm Credit Administration, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals, corporations, and governmental entities who provide or may provide supplies or services to the Corporation by contract or purchase order.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Bids, offers, lease agreements, purchase orders, requisitions, and other pertinent written information related to purchase transactions.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>12 U.S.C. 2277a-7, 2277a-8; 40 U.S.C. 471 et seq.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information contained in this system of records is used by the Corporation as the basis for maintaining control of purchase transactions and to provide a minimum of opportunity for fraud as well as the maximum feasible opportunity for audit as related to the purchase of supplies and services obtained</p>
<p>(1) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(2) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of and investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency?s decision on the matter</p>
<p>(4) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(5) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected</p>
<p>(6) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records filed: (1) In numerical order by purchase order or contract number; and (2) alphabetically by the name of the vendor.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Maintained in area which is locked after business hours. Access to this record system is limited to employees and persons with contractual authority within the Corporation and the FCA.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule requirements for procurement records.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of records shall be addressed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Individuals, corporations, or governmental entities who make bids or offers to the Corporation or enter into lease or other agreements with the Corporation. Employees who prepare contractual actions.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fcsis7" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-7</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Personnel Security Files--FCSIC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>These records are located at the Farm Credit Administration, McLean, Virginia 22102-5090.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Corporation employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Case files compiled during background investigations of employees in sensitive positions. The files include:
</p><p>(a) Security forms (SF 86, "Security Investigation Data for Sensitive Position"; and OPM Form 329-B, "Authority for Release of Information and Redisclosure");
</p><p>(b) Investigative report which includes credit check, check of police record, and interviews with neighbors, former supervisors, and coworkers;
</p><p>(c) Determination of suitability for security clearance by agency security officer; and
</p><p>(d) Issuance of clearance statement.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>Executive Order 10450.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records is used to determine suitability for holding a sensitive position within the Corporation and to issue security clearance</p>
<p>(1) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(2) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of and investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency?s decision on the matter</p>
<p>(4) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(5) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected</p>
<p>(6) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are arranged alphabetically by name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a locked safe in an area that is secured after business hours. Access to records is restricted to those employees whose official duties require access.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>Files are transferred to OPM when employee leaves the agency.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of records shall be addressed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records comes from the individual to whom it applies, credit bureaus, police, neighbors, former supervisors and coworkers, etc.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemsExempted"><xhtmlContent><p>This system is subjected to a specific exemption pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(2), to the extent there is included in the system investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>
<section id="fcsis8" toc="yes">
<systemNumber>-8</systemNumber>
<subsection type="systemName">Correspondence Files--FCSIC.</subsection>
<subsection type="systemLocation"><xhtmlContent><p>Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="categoriesOfIndividuals"><xhtmlContent><p>Current and former Corporation employees.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection> <subsection type="categoriesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>Letters, memorandums, and other documents pertaining to the operations of the Corporation.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="authorityForMaintenance"><xhtmlContent><p>12 U.S.C. 2277a-7, 2277a-8.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="routineUsesOfRecords"><xhtmlContent><p>(1) In the event that information in this record system indicates a violation or potential violation of law, whether civil, criminal, or regulatory in nature, and whether arising by general statute or particular program statute, or by regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate agency, whether Federal, State, local, or foreign, charged with the responsibility of investigating or prosecuting such violation or charged with enforcing or implementing the statute, or rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant thereto</p>
<p>(2) Information in this record system may be disclosed as a routine use to a Federal, State, or local agency maintaining civil, criminal, or other relevant enforcement information or other pertinent information, such as current licenses, if necessary to obtain information relevant to a decision concerning the hiring or retention of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a grant or other benefit</p>
<p>(3) Information in this record system may be disclosed to a Federal agency, in response to its request, in connection with the hiring or retention of an employee, the issuance of a security clearance, the reporting of and investigation of an employee, the letting of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency, to the extent that the information is relevant and necessary to the requesting agency's decision on the matter</p>
<p>(4) Disclosure may be made to a congressional office from the record of an individual in response to an inquiry from the congressional office made at the request of that individual</p>
<p>(5) It shall be a routine use of the records in this system of records to disclose them to the Department of Justice or to disclose them in a proceeding before a court or adjudicative body before which the agency is authorized to appear, when
</p><p>(a) The agency, or any component thereof; or
</p><p>(b) Any employee of the agency in his or her official capacity; or
</p><p>(c) Any employee of the agency in his or her individual capacity where the Department of Justice or the agency has agreed to represent the employee; or
</p><p>(d) The United States, where the agency determines that litigation is likely to affect the agency or any of its components, is a party to litigation or has an interest in such litigation, and the use of such records by the Department of Justice or the use of such records in the proceeding is deemed by the agency to be relevant and necessary to the litigation, provided, however, that in each case, the agency determines that disclosure of the records to the Department of Justice or the disclosure of such records in the proceeding is a use of the information contained in the records that is compatible with the purpose for which the records were collected</p>
<p>(6) In the event that information in this record system is needed in the course of presenting evidence to a court, magistrate, or administrative tribunal, the relevant records may be referred, as a routine use, to the appropriate person to use as evidence.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="policiesAndPractices"><xhtmlContent><p>Storage:</p>
<p>Records are maintained in file folders.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retrievability"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are arranged alphabetically by name.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="safeguards"><xhtmlContent><p>Records are maintained in a locked cabinet in an area that is secured after business hours.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="retentionAndDisposal"><xhtmlContent><p>In accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Records Schedule requirements.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="systemManager"><xhtmlContent><p>Administrative Specialist, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="notificationProcedure"><xhtmlContent><p>All inquiries about this system of records shall be addressed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordAccessProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for access to a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.3.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="contestingRecordProcedures"><xhtmlContent><p>Requests for amendments of a record shall be directed to: Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, as provided in 12 CFR 1403.7.</p></xhtmlContent></subsection>
<subsection type="recordSourceCategories"><xhtmlContent><p>Information in this system of records either comes from the individual to whom it applies or comes from information supplied by agency officials.
</p></xhtmlContent></subsection></section>

    
    <regulations id="reg" toc="yes">
<regulationsTitle number="12">
<heading>Banks and Banking</heading>
<regulationsChapter number="XIV">
<heading>Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation</heading>
<regulationsPart number="1403">
<heading>Privacy Act Regulations</heading>
<xhtmlContent>

<p>Sec.
</p>
<p>1403.1 Purpose and scope.
</p>
<p>1403.2 Definitions.
</p>
<p>1403.3 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</p>
<p>1403.4 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</p>
<p>1403.5 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</p>
<p>1403.6 Special procedures for medical records.
</p>
<p>1403.7 Request for amendment to record.
</p>
<p>1403.8 Agency review of request for amendment of record.
</p>
<p>1403.9 Appeal of an initial adverse determination of a request to amend a record.
</p>
<p>1403.10 Fees for providing copies of records.
</p>
<p>1403.11 Criminal penalties.
</p>
<p>1403.12 Exemptions.
</p>
<p><b>Authority:</b> Secs. 5.58, 5.59 of the Farm Credit Act (12 U.S.C. 2277a-7, 2277a-8); 5 U.S.C. app. 3, 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>Source:</b> 59 FR 53084, Oct. 21, 1994, unless otherwise noted.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.1 Purpose and scope.</b></p>
<p>(a) This part is published by the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974 (Pub. L. 93-579, 5 U.S.C. 552a) which requires each Federal agency to promulgate rules to establish procedures for notification and disclosure to an individual of agency records pertaining to that person, and for review of such records.
</p>
<p>(b) The records covered by this part include:
</p>
<p>(1) Personnel and employment records maintained by the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation not covered by &#167;&#167; 293.101 through 293.108 of the regulations of the Office of Personnel Management (5 CFR 293.101 through 293.108); and
</p>
<p>(2) Other records contained in record systems maintained by the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation.
</p>
<p>(c) This part does not apply to any records maintained by the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation in its capacity as a receiver or conservator.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.2
 Definitions.
</b></p>
<p>For the purposes of this part:
</p>
<p>(a) <i>Agency</i> means the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation. It does not include the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation when it is acting as a receiver or a conservator;
</p>
<p>(b) <i>Individual</i> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;
</p>
<p>(c) <i>Maintain</i> includes maintain, collect, use, or disseminate;
</p>
<p>(d) <i>Record</i> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by an agency including, but not limited to, that person?s education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history, and that contains that person's name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print or photograph;
</p>
<p>(e) <i>Routine use</i> means, with respect to the disclosure of a record, the use of such record for a purpose that is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected;
</p>
<p>(f) <i>Statistical record</i> means a record in a system of records maintained for statistical research or reporting purposes only and not used in whole or in part in making any determination about an identifiable individual, except as provided by 13 U.S.C. 8;
</p>
<p>(g) <i>System of records</i> means a group of any records under the control of any agency from which information is retrieved by the name of an individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.3
 Procedures for requests pertaining to individual records in a record system.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Any present or former employee of the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation seeking access to that person's official civil service records maintained by the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation shall submit a request in such manner as is prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management.
</p>
<p>(b) Individuals shall submit their requests in writing to the Privacy Act Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826, when seeking to obtain the following information from the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation:
</p>
<p>(1) Notification of whether the agency maintains a record pertaining to that person in a system of records;
</p>
<p>(2) Notification of whether the agency has disclosed a record for which an accounting of disclosure is required to be maintained and made available to that person;
</p>
<p>(3) A copy of a record pertaining to that person or the accounting of its disclosure; or
</p>
<p>(4) The review of a record pertaining to that person or the accounting of its disclosure.
</p>
<p>The request shall state the full name and address of the individual, and identify the system or systems of records believed to contain the information or record sought.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.4
 Times, places, and requirements for identification of individuals making requests.
</b></p>
<p>The individual making written requests for information or records ordinarily will not be required to verify that person's identity. The signature upon such requests shall be deemed to be a certification by the requester that he or she is the individual to whom the record pertains, or the parent of a minor, or the duly appointed legal guardian of the individual to whom the record pertains. The Privacy Act Officer, however, may require such additional verification of identity in any instance in which the Privacy Act Officer deems it advisable.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.5
 Disclosure of requested information to individuals.
</b></p>
<p>(a) The Privacy Act Officer shall, within a reasonable period of time after the date of receipt of a request for information of records:
</p>
<p>(1) Determine whether or not such request shall be granted;
</p>
<p>(2) Notify the requester of the determination, and, if the request is denied, of the reasons therefor; and
</p>
<p>(3) Notify the requester that fees for reproducing copies of records may be charged as provided in &#167; 1403.10.
</p>
<p>(b) If access to a record is denied because the information therein has been compiled by the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation in reasonable anticipation of a civil or criminal action proceeding, the Privacy Act Officer shall notify the requester of that person's right to judicial appeal under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g).
</p>
<p>(c)(1) If access to a record is granted, the requester shall notify the Privacy Act Officer whether the requested record is to be copied and mailed to the requester or whether the record is to be made available for personal inspection.
</p>
<p>(2) A requester who is an individual may be accompanied by an individual selected by the requester when the record is disclosed, in which case the requester may be required to furnish a written statement authorizing the discussion of the record in the presence of the accompanying person.
</p>
<p>(d) If the record is to be made available for personal inspection, the requester shall arrange with the Privacy Act Officer a mutually agreeable time in the offices of the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation for inspection of the record.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.6
 Special procedures for medical records.
</b></p>
<p>Medical records in the custody of the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation which are not subject to Office of Personnel Management regulations shall be disclosed either to the individual to whom they pertain or that person's authorized or legal representative or to a licensed physician named by the individual.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.7
 Request for amendment to record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) If, after disclosure of the requested information, an individual believes that the record is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete, that person may request in writing that the record be amended. Such a request shall be submitted to the Privacy Act Officer and shall identify the system of records and the record or information therein, a brief description of the material requested to be changed, the requested change or changes, and the reason for such change or changes.
</p>
<p>(b) The Privacy Act Officer shall acknowledge receipt of the request within 10 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) and, if a determination has not been made, advise the individual when that person may expect to be advised of action taken on the request. The acknowledgment may contain a request for additional information needed to make a determination.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.8
 Agency review of request for amendment of record.
</b></p>
<p>Upon receipt of a request for amendment of a record, the Privacy Act Officer shall:
</p>
<p>(a) Correct any portion of a record which the individual making the request believes is not accurate, relevant, timely, or complete and thereafter inform the individual in writing of such correction, or
</p>
<p>(b) Inform the individual in writing of the refusal to amend the record and of the reasons therefor, and advise that the individual may appeal such determination as provided in &#167; 1403.9.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.9
 Appeal of an initial adverse determination of a request to amend a record.
</b></p>
<p>(a) Not more than 10 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after receipt by an individual of an adverse determination on the individual's request to amend a record or otherwise, the individual may appeal to the Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826.
</p>
<p>(b) The appeal shall be by letter, mailed or delivered to the Chief Operating Officer, Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, McLean, Virginia 22102-0826. The letter shall identify the records involved in the same manner they were identified to the Privacy Act Officer, shall specify the dates of the request and adverse determination, and shall indicate the expressed basis for that determination. Also, the letter shall state briefly and succinctly the reasons why the adverse determination should be reversed.
</p>
<p>(c) The review shall be completed and a final determination made by the Chief Operating Officer not later than 30 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) from receipt of the request for such review, unless the Chief Operating Officer extends such 30-day period for good cause. If the 30-day period is extended, the individual shall be notified of the reasons therefor.
</p>
<p>(d) If the Chief Operating Officer refuses to amend the record in accordance with the request, the individual shall be notified of the right to file a concise statement setting forth that person's disagreement with the final determination and that person's right under 5 U.S.C. 552a(g)(1)(A) to a judicial review of the final determination.
</p>
<p>(e) If the refusal to amend a record as requested is confirmed, there shall be included in the disputed portion of the record a copy of the concise statement filed by the individual together with a concise statement of the reasons for not amending the record as requested. Such statements will be included when disclosure of the disputed record is made to persons and agencies as authorized under 5 U.S.C. 552a.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.10
 Fees for providing copies of records.
</b></p>
<p>Fees for providing copies of records shall be charged in accordance with &#167;&#167; 1402.22 and 1402.24 of this chapter.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.11
 Criminal penalties.
</b></p>
<p>Section 552a(i)(3) of the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(i)(3)) makes it a misdemeanor, subject to a maximum fine of $5,000, to knowingly and willfully request or obtain any record concerning any individual from an agency under false pretenses. Sections 552a(i) (1) and (2) of the Act (5 U.S.C. 552a(i) (1), (2)) provide penalties for violation by agency employees of the Act or regulations established thereunder.
</p>
<p><b>&#167; 1403.12
 Exemptions.
</b></p>
<p><i>Specific.</i> Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(k)(5), the investigatory material compiled for law enforcement purposes in the following system of records is exempt from subsections (c)(3), (d), (e)(1), (e)(4) (G), (H), and (I), and (f) of 5 U.S.C. 552a and from the provisions of this part:</p>

<p>Personnel Security Files--FCSIC.
</p>

</xhtmlContent>
</regulationsPart>
</regulationsChapter>
</regulationsTitle>
</regulations>
</agency>
</pai>
