<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="govman.xsl"?>
<GovernmentManual>
    <accessId>GOVMAN-2022-12-31-159</accessId>
    <Entity EntityId="159" ParentId="0" SortOrder="64">
        <EntityType>Parent</EntityType>
        <Category>Executive Branch: Independent Agencies and Government Corporations</Category>
        <IntroductoryHeader/>
        <IntroductoryParagraph/>
        <AgencyName>National Mediation Board</AgencyName>
        <Addresses>
            <Address EntityAddressId="96" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Address>1301 K Street NW., Suite 250 East, Washington, DC 20005</Address>
                <Phone>202-692-5000</Phone>
                <Phone2/>
                <Fax/>
            </Address>
        </Addresses>
        <LeaderShipTables>
            <LeaderShipTable EntityLeaderShipTableId="79" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header/>
                <HeaderParagraph/>
                <NameColumnHeader/>
                <ShowFootNote>Yes</ShowFootNote>
                <ShowHeader>Yes</ShowHeader>
                <ShowHeaderParagraph>Yes</ShowHeaderParagraph>
                <ShowNameColumnHeader>Yes</ShowNameColumnHeader>
                <ShowTitleColumnHeader>Yes</ShowTitleColumnHeader>
                <TitleColumnHeader/>
                <LeaderShipTableValues>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="4813" SortOrder="1">
                        <NameColumnValue/>
                        <TitleColumnValue>BOARD MEMBERS</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="1419" SortOrder="2">
                        <NameColumnValue>Linda A. Puchala</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>CHAIR</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="1420" SortOrder="3">
                        <NameColumnValue>Harry R. Hoglander</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Member</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="4812" SortOrder="4">
                        <NameColumnValue/>
                        <TitleColumnValue>-----------------------------</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="4814" SortOrder="5">
                        <NameColumnValue/>
                        <TitleColumnValue>EXECUTIVE DIRECTORS</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="1421" SortOrder="6">
                        <NameColumnValue>Daniel Rainey</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Chief of Staff</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="1422" SortOrder="7">
                        <NameColumnValue>Mary L. Johnson</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>General Counsel, Office of Legal Affairs</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="4811" SortOrder="8">
                        <NameColumnValue/>
                        <TitleColumnValue>-----------------------------</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="1423" SortOrder="9">
                        <NameColumnValue>Samantha T. Jones</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Assistant Chief of Staff, Administration</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="1424" SortOrder="10">
                        <NameColumnValue>Roland Watkins</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Director, Arbitration Services</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="1425" SortOrder="11">
                        <NameColumnValue>Michael Kelliher</NameColumnValue>
                        <TitleColumnValue>Deputy Chief of Staff, Mediation</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                    <Values EntityLeadershipTableValuesId="4810" SortOrder="12">
                        <NameColumnValue/>
                        <TitleColumnValue>-----------------------------</TitleColumnValue>
                    </Values>
                </LeaderShipTableValues>
            </LeaderShipTable>
        </LeaderShipTables>
        <MissionStatement>
            <Heading/>
            <Record>
                <Paragraph MissionStatmentId="42" SortOrder="1">The National Mediation Board facilitates labor-management relations within the railroad and airline industries.</Paragraph>
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Footer/>
                </FooterDetails>
            </Record>
        </MissionStatement>
        <OrganizationChart>https://govmanual.gpo.gov/ReadLibraryItem.ashx?SFN=VfUPe7zJomch1pvVoPQPSQ==&amp;SF=PAmu4nDRyaoCugTKvsXyXx/6G6ZqqOY1fk7ZHZboqk4=</OrganizationChart>
        <LegalAuthority>
            <Heading/>
        </LegalAuthority>
        <OrganizationStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </OrganizationStatement>
        <ProgramAndActivities>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="298" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName/>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="659" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading/>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1026">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The National Mediation Board (NMB) is an independent agency
                                established by the 1934 amendments to the Railway Labor Act of 1926
                                (45 U.S.C. 151-158, 160-162, 1181-1188). The Board comprises three
                                members whom the President appoints and the Senate confirms. The
                                Board designates a Chair on a yearly basis.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1027">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/about-nmb/nmb-overview</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>NMB dispute-resolution processes are designed to resolve
                                disputes over the negotiation of new or revised collective
                                bargaining agreements and the interpretation or application of
                                existing agreements. The Board also effectuates employee rights of
                                self-organization where a representation dispute exists.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="299" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName>Activities</ProgramName>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="661" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading>Mediation and Alternative Dispute Resolution</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1029">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Following receipt of an application for mediation, the NMB
                                assigns a mediator to assist the parties in reaching an agreement.
                                The NMB is obligated to use its best efforts to bring about a
                                peaceful resolution to the dispute. If such efforts do not settle
                                the dispute, the NMB advises the parties and offers interest
                                arbitration as an alternative approach to resolve the remaining
                                issues. If either party rejects this offer, the NMB releases the
                                parties from formal mediation. This release triggers a 30-day
                                cooling off period. During this period, the NMB continues to work
                                with the parties to achieve a consensual resolution. If, however, an
                                agreement is not reached by the end of the 30-day period, the
                                parties are free to exercise lawful self-help, such as
                                carrier-imposed working conditions or a strike by the union or
                                organization.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="2068">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/services/mediation</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>In addition to traditional mediation services, the NMB also
                                provides voluntary Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) services.
                                ADR services include facilitation, training, grievance mediation,
                                and an online dispute resolution component, which applies technology
                                to the dispute resolution process. The purpose of the ADR program is
                                to assist the parties in learning and applying more effective, less
                                confrontational methods for resolving their disputes and to help
                                them resolve more of them without outside intervention.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="662" SortOrder="2">
                    <Heading/>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1032">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph/>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="663" SortOrder="3">
                    <Heading>Presidential Emergency Board</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1033">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>If the NMB determines that a dispute threatens to deprive
                                substantially any section of the country of essential transportation
                                service, it notifies the President. The President, at his
                                discretion, may establish a Presidential Emergency Board (PEB) to
                                investigate and report back within 30 days. After the PEB has been
                                created and for 30 days after it has made its report to the
                                President, neither party to the dispute may exercise
                                self-help.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1035">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/services/pebmenu</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>There are also special emergency procedures for unresolved
                                disputes affecting publicly funded and operated commuter railroads
                                and their employees. If the mediation procedures are exhausted, the
                                parties to the dispute or the Governor of any State where the
                                railroad operates may request that the President establish a PEB.
                                The President is required to establish such a board if requested. If
                                no settlement is reached within 60 days following the creation of
                                the PEB, the NMB is required to conduct a public hearing on the
                                dispute. If there is no settlement within 120 days after the
                                creation of the PEB, either party or the Governor of any affected
                                state may request a second, final-offer PEB. No self-help is
                                permitted pending the exhaustion of these emergency
                                procedures.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="665" SortOrder="4">
                    <Heading>Representation</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1036">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/services/representation</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>When a labor organization or individual files an application
                                with the NMB to represent employees, the Agency assigns an
                                investigator to conduct a representation investigation. Should the
                                applicant meet the requirements, the NMB continues the
                                investigation, usually with a secret telephone or Internet election.
                                The NMB is responsible for ensuring that the requirements for a fair
                                election process have been maintained. If the employees vote to be
                                represented, the NMB issues a certification that commences the
                                carrier's statutory duty to bargain with the certified
                                representative.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="667" SortOrder="5">
                    <Heading>Arbitration</Heading>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1038">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The NMB provides both grievance arbitration and interest
                                arbitration. Grievance arbitration is a process for resolving
                                disputes regarding the interpretation or application of an existing
                                collective bargaining agreement. Grievances must be handled through
                                grievance arbitration if not otherwise resolved, and they cannot be
                                used by the parties to trigger self-help actions. The NMB has
                                significant administrative responsibilities for grievance
                                arbitration in the railroad industry, which includes those before
                                the National Railroad Adjustment Board (NRAB), as well as the two
                                types of arbitration panels established by the labor-management
                                parties at each railroad: public law boards (PLBs) and special
                                boards of adjustment (SBAs). Grievance arbitration in the airline
                                industry is accomplished at the various system boards of adjustment
                                created jointly by labor and management at the parties' expense. The
                                NMB furnishes panels of prospective arbitrators for the parties'
                                selection in both the airline and railroad industries. The NMB also
                                pays the salary and travel expenses of the arbitrators for railroad
                                arbitration proceedings. Grievance arbitration decisions are final
                                and binding with very limited grounds for judicial
                                review.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1040">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/services/arbitration</WebAddress>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>Interest arbitration is a process to establish the terms of a
                                new or modified collective bargaining agreement through arbitration
                                rather than through negotiations. Unlike grievance arbitration, its
                                use is not statutorily required. The NMB offers the parties the
                                opportunity to use binding interest arbitration when the agency has
                                determined that further mediation efforts will not be successful. In
                                addition, the parties may directly agree to resolve their collective
                                bargaining dispute or portions of their dispute through interest
                                arbitration. The NMB generally provides the parties with panels of
                                potential arbitrators from which they choose an individual to
                                resolve their dispute. In some instances, however, the parties agree
                                to allow the NMB to appoint an arbitrator directly. Interest
                                arbitration decisions are final and binding with very narrow grounds
                                for judicial appeal.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
        </ProgramAndActivities>
        <SourceOfInformationDetails>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="420" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/about-nmb/jobs</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Employment</Header>
                <Paragraph>Job openings are posted online.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="421" SortOrder="2">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://knowledgestore.nmb.gov/ks/build.html</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Knowledge Store</Header>
                <Paragraph>The Knowledge Store contains over 100,000 documents—including arbitration awards, representation decisions, annual reports, PEB reports, industry contracts, and union constitutions and bylaws—in an easily searchable format.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="1202" SortOrder="3">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/resources/open</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Open Government</Header>
                <Paragraph>The NMB supports the Open Government initiative, which requires Federal executive departments and agencies to implement principles of collaboration, participation, and transparency.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="422" SortOrder="4">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/resources/docs</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Publications</Header>
                <Paragraph>The annual reports of the National Mediation Board are available on its "NMB Documents On-Line" Web page and in the Knowledge Store.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
            <EntitySourceOfInformation EntitySourceOfInformationId="423" SortOrder="5">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress>http://knowledgestore.nmb.gov/ks/build.html</WebAddress>
                </FooterDetails>
                <Header>Virtual Reading Room</Header>
                <Paragraph>Copies of collective bargaining agreements between labor and management of various rail and air carriers and NMB Determinations dating from October 1, 1998, and some even earlier, are available in the Knowledge Store.</Paragraph>
            </EntitySourceOfInformation>
        </SourceOfInformationDetails>
        <FooterDetails>
            <Footer>For further information, contact the Public Information Officer, National
                Mediation Board, Suite 250 East, 1301 K Street NW., Washington, DC 20005-7011.
                Phone, 202-692-5050.</Footer>
            <Email/>
            <WebAddress>http://www.nmb.gov/press-and-contacts/key-contacts</WebAddress>
        </FooterDetails>
    </Entity>
</GovernmentManual>
