<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="govman.xsl"?>
<GovernmentManual>
    <accessId>GOVMAN-2022-12-31-086</accessId>
    <Entity EntityId="86" ParentId="81" SortOrder="5">
        <EntityType>SubEntityLevelOne</EntityType>
        <Category>Judicial Branch</Category>
        <IntroductoryHeader/>
        <IntroductoryParagraph/>
        <AgencyName>United States Court of International Trade</AgencyName>
        <Addresses/>
        <LeaderShipTables/>
        <MissionStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </MissionStatement>
        <OrganizationChart/>
        <LegalAuthority>
            <Heading/>
        </LegalAuthority>
        <OrganizationStatement>
            <Heading/>
        </OrganizationStatement>
        <ProgramAndActivities>
            <ProgramAndActivity ProgramAndActivitiesId="373" SortOrder="1">
                <FooterDetails>
                    <Email/>
                    <Footer/>
                    <WebAddress/>
                </FooterDetails>
                <MainParagraph/>
                <PointOfContact/>
                <ProgramName/>
                <Activity ProgramAndActivitiesId="907" SortOrder="1">
                    <Heading/>
                    <Details>
                        <Detail SortOrder="1" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1488">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>This court was originally established as the Board of
                                        United States General Appraisers by act of June 10, 1890,
                                        which conferred upon it jurisdiction theretofore held by the
                                        district and circuit courts in actions arising under the
                                        tariff acts (19 U.S.C. ch. 4). The act of May 28, 1926 (19
                                        U.S.C. 405a), created the United States Customs Court to
                                        supersede the Board; by acts of August 7, 1939, and June 25,
                                        1948 (28 U.S.C. 1582, 1583), the court was integrated into
                                        the United States court structure, organization, and
                                        procedure. The act of July 14, 1956 (28 U.S.C. 251),
                                        established the court as a court of record of the United
                                        States under Article III of the Constitution. The Customs
                                        Court Act of 1980 (28 U.S.C. 251) constituted the court as
                                        the United States Court of International Trade.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="2" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1489">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The Court of International Trade has jurisdiction
                                        over any civil action against the United States arising from
                                        Federal laws governing import transactions. This includes
                                        classification and valuation cases, as well as authority to
                                        review certain agency determinations under the Trade
                                        Agreements Act of 1979 (19 U.S.C. 2501) involving
                                        antidumping and countervailing duty matters. In addition, it
                                        has exclusive jurisdiction of civil actions to review
                                        determinations as to the eligibility of workers, firms, and
                                        communities for adjustment assistance under the Trade Act of
                                        1974 (19 U.S.C. 2101). Civil actions commenced by the United
                                        States to recover customs duties, to recover on a customs
                                        bond, or for certain civil penalties alleging fraud or
                                        negligence are also within the exclusive jurisdiction of the
                                        court.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="3" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1490">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The court is composed of a chief judge and eight
                                        judges, not more than five of whom may belong to any one
                                        political party. Any of its judges may be temporarily
                                        designated and assigned by the Chief Justice of the United
                                        States to sit as a court of appeals or district court judge
                                        in any circuit or district. The court has a clerk and deputy
                                        clerks, a librarian, court reporters, and other supporting
                                        personnel. Cases before the court may be tried before a
                                        jury. Under the Federal Courts Improvement Act of 1982 (28
                                        U.S.C. 1295), appeals are taken to the U.S. Court of Appeals
                                        for the Federal Circuit, and ultimately review may be sought
                                        in appropriate cases in the Supreme Court of the United
                                        States.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                        <Detail SortOrder="4" TypeOfProgramAndActivitiesDetailsId="1491">
                            <FooterDetails>
                                <Email/>
                                <Footer/>
                                <WebAddress/>
                            </FooterDetails>
                            <Heading/>
                            <Paragraph>The principal offices are located in New York, NY,
                                        but the court is empowered to hear and determine cases
                                        arising at any port or place within the jurisdiction of the
                                        United States.</Paragraph>
                        </Detail>
                    </Details>
                </Activity>
            </ProgramAndActivity>
        </ProgramAndActivities>
        <SourceOfInformationDetails/>
        <FooterDetails>
            <Footer>For further information, contact the Clerk, United States Court of
                        International Trade, One Federal Plaza, New York, NY 10278-0001. Phone,
                        212-264-2814.</Footer>
            <Email/>
            <WebAddress>http://www.cit.uscourts.gov</WebAddress>
        </FooterDetails>
    </Entity>
</GovernmentManual>
